<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04822974</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TTV-CART-IPC 2020-063</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04822974</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TORQUETENOVIRUS IN CAR-T THERAPY: PREDICTION OF THE CRS</brief_title>
  <acronym>TTV-CART</acronym>
  <official_title>TORQUETENOVIRUS IN CAR-T THERAPY: PREDICTION OF THE RISK OF CYTOKINE RELEASE SYNDROME AND DIFFERENTIAL DIAGNOSIS WITH INFECTION</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut Paoli-Calmettes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Clínico Universitario de Valencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut Paoli-Calmettes</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Torque Teno Virus (TTV) prevalence in the general population is very high (&gt;90%) and has not&#xD;
      been consistently confirmed to cause any disease. Kidney transplant studies seem to indicate&#xD;
      that an elevated viremia could predict the risk of de-veloping an infectious process in the&#xD;
      following weeks. An study of the influence of TTV as a predictive marker of infection in&#xD;
      kidney transplant recipi-ents showed higher TTV levels, even 3 months before the infectious&#xD;
      process, allowing the authors to postulate that the quantification of TTV could help to&#xD;
      modulate the treatment of patients at risk. Publications of subsequent studies seem to&#xD;
      confirm these data.In the field of hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) few studies&#xD;
      have analyzed the replication kinetics of TTV. There seems to be a drop in TTV plasma load&#xD;
      after conditioning treatment, with a progressive increase in the first months&#xD;
      post-transplant, in parallel with the number of lymphocytes. In early stages of HSCT, a&#xD;
      relation-ship between TTV replication kinetics and the probability of developing an infection&#xD;
      by CMV has also been described. Likewise, the possible relationship of TTV with other&#xD;
      complications of HSCT, such as Epstein-Barr virus infection (EBV) or graft-versus-host&#xD;
      disease (GvHD), have been reported. However, not every study conducted to date show this line&#xD;
      of results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Torque Teno Virus (TTV) is the prototype of the Anelloviridae family-single chain and&#xD;
      circular viruses. These viruses form about 70% of the human virome. TTV prevalence in the&#xD;
      general population is very high (&gt;90%) and has not been consistently confirmed to cause any&#xD;
      disease. Kidney transplant studies seem to indicate that an elevated viremia could predict&#xD;
      the risk of de-veloping an infectious process (bacterial, viral or fungal) in the following&#xD;
      weeks. A group of research analyzed the influence of TTV as a predictive marker of infection&#xD;
      in 169 kidney transplant recipi-ents. Patients with infection showed higher TTV levels, even&#xD;
      3 months before the infectious process, allowing its authors to postulate that the&#xD;
      quantification of TTV could help to modulate the treatment of patients at risk (reducing&#xD;
      immunosuppression, introducing or prolonging antimi-crobial prophylaxis). Publications of&#xD;
      subsequent studies with greater number of patients seem to confirm these data. Likewise, in&#xD;
      the specific case of CMV infection, the quantification of TTV in the early stages of kidney&#xD;
      or liver transplantation also allows identification of patients at risk of developing a CMV&#xD;
      infection. In the field of hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) few studies have&#xD;
      analyzed the replication kinetics of TTV. There seems to be a drop in TTV plasma load after&#xD;
      conditioning treatment, with a progressive increase in the first months post-transplant, in&#xD;
      parallel with the number of lymphocytes. In early stages of HSCT, a relation-ship between TTV&#xD;
      replication kinetics and the probability of developing an infection by CMV has also been&#xD;
      described. Likewise, the possible relationship of TTV with other complications of HSCT, such&#xD;
      as Epstein-Barr virus infection (EBV) or graft-versus-host disease (GvHD), have been&#xD;
      reported. However, not every study conducted to date show this line of results. An other&#xD;
      research analyzed 2054 blood samples from 123 patients undergoing HSCT, finding no&#xD;
      significant differences between TTV and post-transplant complications, such as viral&#xD;
      reactivations (CMV, EBV or adenovirus), acute GvHD, relapse or mortality&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma viral load and TTV replication kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>d0, d1, d3, d5, d7, d10, d14, d21, d28, d60 and d90 after CAR-T Cell treatment</time_frame>
    <description>comparaition between before during and after CART</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma viral load and CMV replication kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>d0, d14, d28, d60 and d90 after CAR-T Cell treatment</time_frame>
    <description>comparaition between before during and after CART</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>infections</measure>
    <time_frame>100 days</time_frame>
    <description>Reported infections during the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokines</measure>
    <time_frame>d0, d3, d7, d10 and d14 after CAR-T Cell treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Cytokines comparison between samples</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematologic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>STUDY ARM</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>blood samples collection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>blood collection</intervention_name>
    <description>longitudinally collection of blood samples for each patient included.</description>
    <arm_group_label>STUDY ARM</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult patients (&gt;=18 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient going to be treated by CAR-T Cell therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient affiliated to the national &quot;Social Security&quot; regimen or beneficiary of this&#xD;
             regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnancy/breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient considered socially or psychologically unable to comply with the treatment and&#xD;
             the required medical follow-up.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>DOMINIQUE GENRE, DR</last_name>
    <phone>0491223778</phone>
    <email>drci.up@ipc.unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

