<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04822805</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H2CH2020M504</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04822805</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Anlotinib in the Treatment of Recurrent High-grade Glioma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anlotinib in the Treatment of Recurrent High-grade Glioma： an Open-label Single-arm, Phase 2 Trials</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>First People's Hospital of Hangzhou</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chia Tai Tianqing Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>First People's Hospital of Hangzhou</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II, open-label, single center study, aiming to investigate safety and&#xD;
      efficacy of anlotinib in treatment of recurrent high-grade glioma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Glioma is a common primary central nervous system malignant tumor that originates from glial&#xD;
      cells. High grade glioma (HGG) refers to grade III and IV gliomas in the central nervous&#xD;
      system tumor classification of the World Health Organization (WHO), accounting for&#xD;
      approximately 67% of newly diagnosed cases. The maximum safety resection of the tumor&#xD;
      followed by radiotherapy and chemotherapy is the HGG standard initial treatment strategy.&#xD;
      However, glioma cells grow aggressively, and most patients will relapse after initial&#xD;
      treatment. Recurrent high-grade glioma (r-HGG) is difficult to treat, lacking treatment&#xD;
      standards and having a poor prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no standard treatment plan for patients with recurrent high-grade cancer. Studies&#xD;
      have shown that gliomas highly express a variety of pro-angiogenic factors and have a large&#xD;
      number of abnormally proliferated blood vessels, VEGF especially playing an important role in&#xD;
      the formation of GBM neovascularization. VEGF is almost not expressed in normal tissues, but&#xD;
      it is highly expressed (about 96%) in malignant gliomas and surrounding tissues, especially&#xD;
      VEGF-A is highly expressed in glioblastomas. Therefore, VEGF It can be used as an effective&#xD;
      target for anti-angiogenesis treatment of malignant glioma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anlotinib hydrochloride is a multi-target receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor that has&#xD;
      significant inhibitory activity against angiogenesis related kinases such as VEGFR1/2/3,&#xD;
      FGFR1/2/3, and other tumor related kinases such as PDGFR /, C-Kit, Ret, etc. (e.g., Met,&#xD;
      FGFR1/2/3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the above theory , the purpose of this study was to explore the efficacy and safety&#xD;
      of anlotinib in treatment of recurrent high-grade glioma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients with recurrent high-grade gliomas are being enrolled , treated with anlotinib , and being observed the disease-related outcomes of the patients.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5months</time_frame>
    <description>The time interval from the randomization of the patient to the first disease progression or death from any cause</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent High-grade Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with Anlotinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with recurrent high-grade gliomas are being enrolled , treated with anlotinib 12mg once daily for 14 days every 3 weeks until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.The dose can be adjusted to 10mg or 8mg according to the specific conditions of the patient.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anlotinib hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with recurrent high-grade gliomas are being enrolled , treated with anlotinib 12mg once daily for 14 days every 3 weeks until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.The dose can be adjusted to 10mg or 8mg according to the specific conditions of the patient.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with Anlotinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Anlotinib</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥18 years old (calculated on the day of signing the informed consent), regardless&#xD;
             of gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Karnofsky score (KPS score) ≥60.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. According to Rano criteria, there are evaluable intracranial lesions, and recurrent&#xD;
             high-grade gliomas have been confirmed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients have undergone surgery and relapsed after receiving standard radiotherapy and&#xD;
             chemotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The toxicity has returned to ≤1 grade If have received chemotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Expected survival ≥ 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The patient has no major organ dysfunction. Specific laboratory indicators are&#xD;
             required: white blood cells ≥3.0×109/L, platelets ≥75×109/L, hemoglobin ≥10g/dl, and&#xD;
             serum bilirubin not greater than 1.5 times the maximum normal value; ALT and AST are&#xD;
             not more than 2 times the maximum normal value; blood creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Men and women of gestational age must agree to take adequate contraceptive measures&#xD;
             throughout the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The patient voluntarily joined the study and signed a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who have multiple factors that affect oral medications (such as inability to&#xD;
             swallow, chronic diarrhea, intestinal obstruction, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with any severe and/or uncontrollable disease, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1) Patients with unsatisfactory blood pressure control (systolic blood pressure ≥150 mmHg,&#xD;
        diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg); 2) Patients with myocardial ischemia or myocardial&#xD;
        infarction above grade I, arrhythmia (including QTC ≥480ms), and grade ≥2 congestive heart&#xD;
        failure (New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification); 3) Active or uncontrolled&#xD;
        serious infection (≥CTC AE Grade 2 infection); 4) Liver cirrhosis, decompensated liver&#xD;
        disease, active hepatitis or chronic hepatitis require antiviral treatment; 5) Renal&#xD;
        failure requires hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis; 6) Have a history of&#xD;
        immunodeficiency, including HIV positive or other acquired or congenital immunodeficiency&#xD;
        diseases, or a history of organ transplantation; 7) Diabetes is poorly controlled (fasting&#xD;
        blood glucose (FBG)&gt; 10mmol/L); 8) Urine routines suggest that urine protein is ≥++, and&#xD;
        the 24-hour urine protein quantification is more than 1.0 g; 9) Patients who have seizures&#xD;
        and need treatment; 3. Received major surgical treatment, open biopsy or obvious traumatic&#xD;
        injury within 28 days before enrollment; 4. Patients whose imaging shows that the tumor has&#xD;
        invaded important blood vessels or the researcher judges that the tumor is likely to invade&#xD;
        important blood vessels causing fatal hemorrhage during the follow-up study; 5. Regardless&#xD;
        of the severity, patients with any signs of bleeding or medical history; within 4 weeks&#xD;
        before enrollment, patients with any bleeding or bleeding event ≥ CTCAE level 3, unhealed&#xD;
        wounds, ulcers or fractures; 6. Those who have had arterial/venous thrombosis within 6&#xD;
        months, such as cerebrovascular accidents (including temporary ischemic attacks), deep vein&#xD;
        thrombosis and pulmonary embolism; 7. Those who have a history of psychotropic drug abuse&#xD;
        and cannot be quit or have mental disorders; 8. Participated in clinical research of other&#xD;
        anti-tumor drugs within four weeks; 9. Have received the treatment of small molecule&#xD;
        anti-angiogenesis targeted drugs (such as regorafenib, perzopanib, apatinib, etc.); 10.&#xD;
        Those considered by the researcher to be unsuitable for inclusion。&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hui Dai</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hangzhou Cancer Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hui Dai</last_name>
    <phone>13968855810</phone>
    <phone_ext>0571-56006322</phone_ext>
    <email>124186159@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hangzhou Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <zip>310000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hui Dai</last_name>
      <phone>13968855810</phone>
      <phone_ext>0574-56006326</phone_ext>
      <email>124186159@qq.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

