<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04821479</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0208-16-HMO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04821479</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Repeated Mesenchymal Stem Cell Injections in ALS</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety and Clinical Effects of Repeated Intrathecal Injections of Autologous Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hadassah Medical Organization</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hadassah Medical Organization</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An open-label, single-center clinical trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of repeated&#xD;
      intrathecal administrations of autologous bone marrow derived mesenchyme stem cells in ALS&#xD;
      patients. The study includes 20 subjects (age: 20-70) with definite diagnosis of ALS and&#xD;
      ALS-FRS-R score of at least 20 and disease-duration of less than 3 years. The treatment&#xD;
      protocol includes four intrathecal injections of MSC, at intervals of 3 months between the&#xD;
      injections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoints are safety and tolerability. Several efficacy measures are assessed as&#xD;
      secondary endpoints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      An open-label, single-center clinical trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of repeated&#xD;
      intrathecal administrations of autologous bone marrow derived mesenchyme stem cells in ALS&#xD;
      patients. The study includes 20 subjects (age: 20-70) with definite diagnosis of ALS and&#xD;
      ALS-FRS-R score of at least 20 and disease-duration of less than 3 years. The treatment&#xD;
      protocol includes four intrathecal injections of MSC, at intervals of 3 months between the&#xD;
      injections. The primary endpoints are safety and tolerability. Several efficacy measures are&#xD;
      assessed as secondary endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Applications from patients are received in our centre. An independent selective committee set&#xD;
      by hospital's administration examines anonymously, according to the predefined inclusion and&#xD;
      exclusion criteria. After inclusion and screening visit, patients are followed up for a&#xD;
      &quot;run-in&quot; period of 6 months before the first visit (visit 1), to evaluate the progression&#xD;
      rate of their disease. and for six months following the last transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One month after inclusion, patients undergo bone Marrow Aspiration (BMA) procedure and MSC&#xD;
      cells are produced from the bone marrow aspirate. On the treatment visit, the patients are&#xD;
      transplanted with an intrathecal (IT) injection of MSC (1 million cells per kg of body&#xD;
      weight) and thereafter with additional injections every 3-6 months. After the MSC&#xD;
      transplantation patients are examined on a bimonthly basis and evaluated for ALSFRSr scoring&#xD;
      and forced vital capacity of the lungs (FVC) for a total follow up period of 3 months post&#xD;
      last MSC-injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To establish the progression rate of the disease the monthly changes in the functional ALS&#xD;
      score: ALSFRSr will be calculated during the 6 months-&quot;run in period&quot; and for the whole&#xD;
      duration of the study, ending at 3 months following the last injection of MSC stem cells. The&#xD;
      progression rate (as evidenced by the monthly changes in ALSFRSr and FVC) during the study&#xD;
      (calculated at last visit time point, 3 months after the last MSC-injection) will be compared&#xD;
      to the progression rate during the &quot;run-in&quot; period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The follow up visits include observation for side effects, full neurological evaluation and&#xD;
      muscle chart, ALS score and forced vital capacity (FVC) test. The safety is assessed&#xD;
      following treatment with MSC, using measurements of the following variables: physical&#xD;
      examination, vital signs (HR, BP, RR, body temperature), and clinical laboratory parameters:&#xD;
      WBC with differential and platelet count, hemoglobin (Hb), hematocrit (Ht), blood chemistry&#xD;
      for electrolytes, creatinine and liver enzymes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All selected patients undergo bone marrow aspiration under light general anaesthesia and an&#xD;
      inoculum of crude bone marrow cells (150 ml) is obtained and two thirds of it kept frozen.&#xD;
      One third is cultured under GCP conditions at the human cell cultures clean room facility of&#xD;
      Hadassah HMO. The MSCs are obtained from the bone marrow of each patient and prepared using&#xD;
      our previously described protocol with slight modification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One month later the patient is hospitalized and a lumbar puncture performed under standard&#xD;
      conditions and local anaesthesia at the L4-5 lumbar level and 3 ml of CSF are removed and the&#xD;
      cultured purified MSCs (1x106/kg of body weight) resuspended in 3 ml of normal saline are&#xD;
      injected in the CSF, using a 20-gauge needle and 3-way cannula.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single center open label study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of multiple intrathecal MSC administration. Incidence of adverse events following multiple intrathecal MSC injections during 2 years follow-up period</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months: starting from inclusion until 3 months after the last MSC-injection</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety of 4 successive intrathecal administrations of autologous MSC cells administered every three months in ALS patient.&#xD;
Patients will be follow-up every 3 months for change in their neurological status and the incidence of adverse events. Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.0</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of repeated intrathecal MSC injections on the progression rate (monthly changes) of ALSFRSr</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months: starting from inclusion until 3 months after the last MSC-injection.</time_frame>
    <description>Degree of change in the rate of progression (calculation of monthly change in ALSFRSr score: 0-48, higher scores are better) between the run-in period to 3 months post last MSC-injection</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of repeated intrathecal MSC injections on the progression rate (monthly changes) of respiratory forced vital capacity FVC</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months: starting from inclusion until 3 months after the last MSC-injection.</time_frame>
    <description>Degree of change in the rate of progression (calculation of monthly change in FVC score: 0-100%, higher numbers are better) between the run-in period to 3 months post last MSC-injection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Repeated MSCs treatment in ALS patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Four intrathecal (IT) administrations of autologous MSC cells administered every 3 months in ALS patients. the IT treatment will be administered through a regular lumbar puncture at a dose of 1x10^6 MSCs per kg body weight in 3 ml saline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mesenchymal stem cells (MSC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Intrathecal injections of autologous bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells</description>
    <arm_group_label>Repeated MSCs treatment in ALS patients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>stem cells</other_name>
    <other_name>Stromal cells</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males and females ages 18 to 70 years old, at the Screening Visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Sporadic or familial ALS diagnosed patients fulfilling the El Escorial clinical&#xD;
             criteria for definite.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Capable of providing informed consent and willing and able to follow study procedures,&#xD;
             including willingness to undergo multiple/repeated lumbar punctures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ALSFRS-R ≥15 at the Screening Visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with severe cognitive decline or inability to understand and sign the&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participation in another clinical trial within 1 year prior to start of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with active infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Positive test for Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C, and/or HIV per laboratory evaluations at&#xD;
             the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any history of solid malignancy including any malignancy affecting the central nervous&#xD;
             system within 5 years of the Screening Visit&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dimitrios Karussis, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hadassah HMO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ALS</keyword>
  <keyword>Mesenchymal stem cells</keyword>
  <keyword>ALSFRSr</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

