<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01531985</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHW 10/51; GC 1069</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01531985</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Urine and Serum Biomarkers for Early Detection of Acute Kidney Injury</brief_title>
  <official_title>Urine and Serum Biomarkers for Early Detection of Acute Kidney Injury Following Cardiopulmonary Bypass Surgery for Congenital Heart Disease in Children and Adults: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical College of Wisconsin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Children's Hospital and Health System Foundation, Wisconsin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical College of Wisconsin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find out whether a combination of new urine tests and blood&#xD;
      tests can show kidney injury in its early stages, before kidney failure sets in. If the&#xD;
      investigators find new tests that show kidney injury in early stages, the investigators hope&#xD;
      to start treating people with kidney injury earlier, to prevent kidney failure. You/your&#xD;
      child are at higher risk for kidney injury and kidney failure than most other people, because&#xD;
      of having operations with cardiopulmonary bypass (a machine that pumps your/your child's&#xD;
      blood during the operation). This research is being done because there are no tests yet&#xD;
      proven to show kidney injury before it leads to kidney failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The urine and blood tests the investigators are studying have each been shown to indicate&#xD;
      some degree of kidney injury in certain people, but not with the accuracy needed to diagnose&#xD;
      disease. The investigators think that the combination of urine and blood tests being tried in&#xD;
      this research study may provide enough information to better diagnose kidney injury at an&#xD;
      earlier stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      About 20 persons over 2 years old up to adults will take part in this study. All will be from&#xD;
      the Herma Heart Center of Children's Hospital of Wisconsin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: This will assess whether sensitive tests for urine or serum biomarkers are able to&#xD;
      detect acute kidney injury following cardiopulmonary bypass surgery in the context of&#xD;
      congenital heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background: Acute kidney injury (AKI) is defined as an abrupt decrease in renal function&#xD;
      resulting in retention of nitrogenous (urea and creatinine) and non-nitrogenous waste&#xD;
      products. AKI is a common complication following cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) surgery,&#xD;
      occurring in up to 30% of adult patients following CPB surgery, increasing morbidity,&#xD;
      mortality, and resource utilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with cyanotic heart disease who undergo CPB surgery are also at risk of developing&#xD;
      AKI. These patients require multiple surgeries over the course of their lifetime to correct&#xD;
      their congenital cardiac lesions. Cyanosis alone causes a glomerulopathy characterized&#xD;
      clinically by sub-nephrotic range proteinuria, with higher prevalence related to length of&#xD;
      time prior to initial corrective procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmacological strategies for treatment of AKI have shown little efficacy in previous&#xD;
      studies. Thus, recent studies have aimed to evaluate novel plasma and urinary biomarkers for&#xD;
      early diagnosis of AKI, based on the hypothesis that outcomes may improve if AKI were&#xD;
      identified and treatment initiated earlier. Urinary IL-18 and NGAL have been shown to be&#xD;
      predictive markers of AKI after cardiopulmonary surgery in a pediatric population with a&#xD;
      variety of congenital heart defects. This ultimately reduced detection time from 40 hours&#xD;
      with conventional serum creatinine assays, to 4-6 hours with urinary IL-18 and NGAL. Serum&#xD;
      Cystatin C has also been shown to be as reliable as serum creatinine in predicting kidney&#xD;
      filtration levels, particularly for subjects with reduced muscle mass such as a population&#xD;
      with congenital heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, no study has evaluated the utility of such markers in a combined pediatric and adult&#xD;
      congenital heart disease population. These patients are unique because of the multitude of&#xD;
      CPB surgeries required throughout their lifetime, degree of life spent cyanotic and, thus,&#xD;
      may differ in their susceptibility to cardiac surgery associated AKI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our long term goal is to evaluate the value of urinary and serum biomarkers for early&#xD;
      detection of AKI in this unique patient population. Currently, the investigators propose to&#xD;
      perform a pilot study to evaluate the feasibility of the study methods and to obtain&#xD;
      preliminary data to assist in power calculations for a larger study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The investigators will enroll a total of 20 patients undergoing pulmonary valve&#xD;
      replacement. All patients will have a history of a conotruncal anomaly with previous&#xD;
      corrective surgery requiring cardiopulmonary bypass. Enrollment will occur at the time of&#xD;
      cardiology or cardiovascular surgery consultation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After informed consent and assent is obtained, urine and serum samples will be collected for&#xD;
      the study protocol. Urine specimens for creatinine, NGAL, and IL-18 will be collected&#xD;
      pre-operatively for baseline measurement in addition to post-operatively at 6, 12, 24, and 72&#xD;
      hours. Cystatin C will be measured pre-operatively to assess chronic renal function. Serum&#xD;
      creatinine will be measured pre-operatively and post-operatively at 12 hours and daily as&#xD;
      part of usual clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed for 7 days after surgery or until the day of hospital discharge,&#xD;
      whichever occurs first. Data collected from the hospital chart will include: demographics,&#xD;
      medical and surgical history, type of surgical procedure, underlying congenital heart&#xD;
      disease, baseline serum creatinine and renal function, serum creatinine(s) throughout&#xD;
      hospitalization, daily urine output, need for dialysis, date of death or discharge. The&#xD;
      primary endpoint is development of AKI based on serum creatinine reaching double baseline or&#xD;
      requirement for acute dialysis, as described in the RIFLE- Risk, Injury, Failure, Loss, and&#xD;
      End Stage Renal Disease- model of renal insufficiency.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Congenital Heart Disease</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Urine samples will be collected after the operation at 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 72&#xD;
      hours. The urine samples will be collected from your/your child's urinary catheter if one is&#xD;
      in place for your/your child's regular hospital care, or by urine collected in a cup if&#xD;
      you/your child do not have a urinary catheter. This study requires one blood samples of about&#xD;
      1 teaspoon, before surgery. The blood sample will be collected when other blood samples are&#xD;
      drawn, to avoid extra needle sticks for blood. The extra blood collected, totaling about 1&#xD;
      teaspoon, is a safe amount for children over 2 years old.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators will enroll a total of 20 patients undergoing pulmonary valve replacement&#xD;
        with CPB. All patients will have a history of a conotruncal anomaly with previous&#xD;
        corrective surgery requiring CPB.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients 2 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing pulmonary valve replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of conotruncal anomaly ( including tetralogy of fallot, pulmonary atresia/VSD,&#xD;
             truncus arteriosus, double outlet right ventricle)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to provide/obtain informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  solid organ transplant recipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  estimated baseline GFR &lt; 30 ml/min (by MDRD-2)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael G Earing, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical College of Wisconsin/Children's Hospital of Wisconsin</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Buelow MW, Dall A, Regner K, Weinberg C, Bartz PJ, Sowinski J, Rudd N, Katzmark L, Tweddell JS, Earing MG. Urinary interleukin-18 and urinary neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin predict acute kidney injury following pulmonary valve replacement prior to serum creatinine. Congenit Heart Dis. 2012 Sep-Oct;7(5):441-7. doi: 10.1111/j.1747-0803.2012.00662.x. Epub 2012 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>22537138</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 9, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 13, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 7, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 7, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 8, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical College of Wisconsin</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael Earing</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor, Pediatrics, Cardiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Congenital Heart Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Kidney Injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiopulmonary Bypass</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

