<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00172913</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9461700324</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00172913</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Aberration-Free Refraction Correction</brief_title>
  <official_title>National Taiwan University Hospital</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the interest of improving visual quality after LASIK we have designed a multifaceted study&#xD;
      to test the theoretical, physical, biomechanical and functional effects of commercial and&#xD;
      independently designed aspherical ablation profiles.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The quality of an image on the retina is determined by the optical system of the eyeball,&#xD;
      which is dominated by the refractive contribution of the optically powerful cornea. The large&#xD;
      difference in refractive index between air and the cornea is the basis for anterior corneal&#xD;
      refractive surgery such as Laser in situ Keratomileusis (LASIK) which reshapes the naturally&#xD;
      aspherical cornea to correct a patient's vision. In addition to correcting refractive errors,&#xD;
      current spherical LASIK treatments have been shown to increase ocular wavefront aberrations&#xD;
      which can reduce visual quality postoperatively. Modifications of the corneal-ablation&#xD;
      algorithm have been suggested to correct this issue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Until recently, most ablation algorithms have relied on the Munnerlyn formula, which assumes&#xD;
      the anterior corneal surface to be spherical before and after refractive surgery. One concept&#xD;
      for customized ablation is to apply an ablation during the surgical procedure which has been&#xD;
      adapted to the patient's own aberration pattern. Since custom ablation algorithms are&#xD;
      proprietary and we do not know how they consider the role of asphericity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Precisely altering the corneal asphericity after refraction surgery is a complex phenomenon&#xD;
      which includes biomechanical effects. Thus, knowledge of the cornea's response to the&#xD;
      different aspherical ablation profiles is vital for understanding corneal properties and&#xD;
      prediction of surgical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will involve computer simulation of ablation profiles for the respective lasers,&#xD;
      interferometric analysis of actual ablation profiles on PMMA plates, optimization for visual&#xD;
      correction, functional studies of the short and long term effects of the profiles on in vivo&#xD;
      human corneas, and quantitative subjective (questionnaire and visual tests) and objective&#xD;
      analysis (calculation of retinal image quality metrics) and comparison of the effects&#xD;
      aspherical ablation profiles on visual quality. The completion of the project will lead to&#xD;
      objective evaluation of current ablation profiles as well as the development and evaluation&#xD;
      of new optimized laser refractive surgery procedures with improved outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date>July 2008</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Defined Population</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>60</enrollment>
  <condition>Myopia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  This will be a prospective study including at least 60 patients. The initial study&#xD;
             group will include 6-10 patients. Both eyes of enrolled patients should be included in&#xD;
             the study unless exclusion criteria prevent it. The primary efficacy variables for&#xD;
             this study are wavefront error, visual acuity, autorefraction and contrast&#xD;
             sensitivity. Subjects will be followed over a 3 month period. A proposed examination&#xD;
             schedule is listed in Table 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Eyes will also be divided into groups by refractive error: Low myopia 0-3D, moderate myopia&#xD;
        3-6D, and high myopia 6-9 D and very high myopia &gt; 9D MSRE. The size of the Optical Zone&#xD;
        and Transitional Zone is measured, and results are compared for patients of similar&#xD;
        refractive error (+/- 0.5 S +/- 0.5 C). Analysis is carried out using a matrix analysis of&#xD;
        the total refractive error, comparison of Visual Acuity, Contrast Sensitivity and Responses&#xD;
        on a Questionnaire to assess the patient's quality of vision.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Equal numbers of eyes from each of the four refractive error groups and from each of the&#xD;
        three treatment groups (OATZ profile 5, OATZ profile 6, conventional) will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        We will consider patients operated on by the same doctor (Dr. Lin). We will also compare&#xD;
        treatments of patients and wavefront maps of patients who have similar spherical and&#xD;
        cylindrical refractive errors.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Table 1. Examination Schedule (Definitions) Visit Time Preoperative Within 30 days of&#xD;
        surgery Operative Day Day of surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        1 Month postop 3-5 weeks following surgery 3 Months postop 10-14 weeks following surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will be excluded if they have a history of ocular pathology, previous ocular&#xD;
             surgery, thin corneas (preoperatively calculated minimal residual bed &lt; 250um) or fit&#xD;
             into the group of the usual exclusionary criteria (e.g. irregular astigmatism,&#xD;
             asymmetric astigmatism, unstable refraction).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Possible additional exclusion criteria include no previous refractive surgery, no&#xD;
        hyperopia, preop BSCVA 20/25 or better, ages from 21-60 years old, astigmatism above 2D,&#xD;
        difficult cases and equal numbers of men and women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>I-Jong Wang, MD,PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospiyal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>I-Jong Wang, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>886-2-23123456</phone>
    <phone_ext>5729</phone_ext>
    <email>ijong@ha.mc.ntu.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>I-Jong Wang, MD, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>886-2-23123456</phone>
      <phone_ext>5729</phone_ext>
      <email>ijong@ha.mc.ntu.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 12, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 12, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 15, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 12, 2005</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 12, 2005</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 15, 2005</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Wavefront Aberration</keyword>
  <keyword>LASIK</keyword>
  <keyword>Contrast Sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Visual Performance</keyword>
  <keyword>Ablation Profile</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myopia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

