<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00175747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>USPHS Grant N01-CN85188</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00175747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase IIb Trial of Pulmicort Turbuhaler (Budesonide)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Phase IIb Trial of Pulmicort Turbuhaler (Budesonide) in People With Dysplasia of the Bronchial Epithelium</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Studies in animals suggest that inhaled budesonide may prevent the occurrence of lung cancer.&#xD;
      We conducted a clinical trial to determine the effects of inhaled budesonide in smokers who&#xD;
      had precancerous lesions in the breathing tubes (i.e. bronchial dysplasia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lung cancer is the most common cause of cancer death worldwide: the mortality rate of lung&#xD;
      cancer exceeds that of colon, breast, and prostate cancers combined. Former heavy smokers&#xD;
      retain an elevated risk for lung cancer even years after they stop smoking. Given the large&#xD;
      number of current and former smokers and the increasing incidence of lung cancers among&#xD;
      women, lung cancer will remain a major health issue for the next several decades.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One potential strategy to inhibit the development of invasive cancer in those who are at risk&#xD;
      of developing lung cancer is to use chemopreventive agents that can regress existing&#xD;
      intraepithelial neoplastic lesions, prevent the progression of these lesions to cancer, or&#xD;
      prevent the development of new lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We performed a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase IIb clinical trial to&#xD;
      determine the efficacy and safety of inhaled budesonide (Pulmicort Turbuhaler) as a&#xD;
      chemopreventive agent in smokers with premalignant lesions in their bronchial epithelia. The&#xD;
      primary end point was change in the histopathologic grade on repeat biopsy of the same sites&#xD;
      at the end of 6 months. The secondary end points of this study aimed to gather additional&#xD;
      insight into the potential effects of budesonide on the central bronchial epithelial lung&#xD;
      compartment, on the peripheral lung that could not be directly assessed through bronchoscopic&#xD;
      biopsy, and on drug effect biomarkers that reflect the ability of inhaled budesonide to reach&#xD;
      its target. Thus, the balance between proliferation and apoptosis was examined through&#xD;
      immunohistochemical analysis of the expression of the proliferative marker MIB-1 and the&#xD;
      antiapoptotic protein BclII. Expression of the tumor suppressor p53, which functions to&#xD;
      maintain the integrity of the human genome, is a major determinant of cell survival, is&#xD;
      frequently mutated in lung cancer, and was assessed in bronchial biopsies. Examination of&#xD;
      peripheral pulmonary nodules via spiral computed tomography (CT) was performed to assess, for&#xD;
      the first time, the potential usefulness of spiral CT in response to chemopreventive&#xD;
      interventions. Finally, prostaglandin E2 (PGE2), a prostaglandin derived from arachidonic&#xD;
      acid metabolism whose synthesis is inhibited by glucocorticoids, was measured in the&#xD;
      bronchoalveolar lavage fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study subjects were recruited using television programs, radio broadcasts, and local&#xD;
      newspapers between June 1, 2000, and November 1, 2001. Eligibility included age &gt; 40 years,&#xD;
      smoking history of 30 pack-years, and normal organ function. Sputum samples were obtained&#xD;
      using simultaneous high-frequency chest wall oscillation with a ThAIRapy Vest (Advanced&#xD;
      Respiratory, Inc., St. Paul, MN) and inhalation of 3% hypertonic saline from an ultrasonic&#xD;
      nebulizer for 12 minutes. The subjects were instructed to cough intermittently during the&#xD;
      induction procedure and for at least 2 hours afterward to produce sputum samples. The sputum&#xD;
      samples were fixed in 50% etomidate, cytospun onto glass slides, and stained with&#xD;
      Feulgen-thionin. The DNA content, the size, shape, and DNA distribution of at least 3000&#xD;
      epithelial cell nuclei per sample were measured using automated high-resolution image&#xD;
      cytometry (Cyto-Savant system; Perceptronix Medical, Inc., Vancouver, British Columbia,&#xD;
      Canada; refs. 13 , 14 ). Cells were classified as either epithelial, inflammatory, or&#xD;
      pyknotic based on these features, and an experienced cytotechnologist confirmed the automated&#xD;
      classifications. Diploid DNA had a DNA index of 1.0. Atypia was defined as the presence of&#xD;
      more than or equal to five cells having a DNA index &gt; 1.2. This criterion was based on a&#xD;
      retrospective analysis of 1885 apparently healthy volunteer smokers who underwent sputum&#xD;
      quantitative cytometry as part of the Lung Health Study at the British Columbia Cancer Agency&#xD;
      since 1990. Participants were followed by repeat chest X-ray and autofluorescence&#xD;
      bronchoscopy if they were in a National Cancer Institute-sponsored chemoprevention trial or&#xD;
      through the British Columbia Cancer Registry and the Medical Services Plan Hospital Registry.&#xD;
      Using the threshold of more than or equal to five cells with a DNA index &gt; 1.2, the&#xD;
      sensitivity of detecting lung cancer in the initial screening or on follow-up was 94%, with a&#xD;
      specificity of 38% after a mean follow-up of 3.2 years. This threshold was adopted in the&#xD;
      current study to identify smokers with the highest risk for lung cancer for bronchoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Autofluorescence bronchoscopy was performed in subjects with sputum atypia who agreed to&#xD;
      undergo bronchoscopy to localize areas of dysplasia using the LIFE-Lung device (Xillix&#xD;
      Technologies Corp., Richmond, British Columbia, Canada). Biopsy samples were taken from areas&#xD;
      with abnormal fluorescence that were at least 1.2 mm in size, as well as from at least two&#xD;
      control areas of normal fluorescence. The median number of biopsy samples obtained per&#xD;
      subject was 6 (range, 4-14 samples). Bronchoalveolar lavage was performed using standard&#xD;
      techniques. The collected fluid (30 mL per participant) was immediately placed at 4°C, and a&#xD;
      differential cell count was obtained within 1 hour of collection. The fluid was separated&#xD;
      from the cells by centrifugation and frozen at -160°C for subsequent PGE2 assays.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The biopsy samples were fixed in buffered formalin, embedded in paraffin, and serially&#xD;
      sectioned. H&amp;E-stained sections were systematically reviewed by two pathologists who were&#xD;
      blinded to intervention assignments (J. leRiche, A. Gazdar). All biopsy samples were&#xD;
      classified into one of the following seven groups (normal, basal cell hyperplasia,&#xD;
      metaplasia, mild/moderate/severe dysplasia, or carcinoma in situ) according to WHO criteria.&#xD;
      Because individual biopsies frequently contained more than one histologic cell type, the&#xD;
      diagnosis was based on the most advanced histology present.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The two pathologists resolved minor (i.e., one grade) differences in sample classification by&#xD;
      telephone consultation. If the histopathology diagnosis differed by two or more grades, both&#xD;
      pathologists reviewed the slides again and, if necessary, reached a consensus diagnosis after&#xD;
      verbal communication by phone or e-mail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One hundred fifty-one subjects (27% of subjects who underwent bronchoscopy) had one or more&#xD;
      sites of bronchial dysplasia with a surface diameter &gt; 1.2 mm (i.e., greater than the size of&#xD;
      a bronchial biopsy using standard biopsy forceps). Only subjects with dysplastic lesions &gt;&#xD;
      1.2 mm were enrolled onto the chemoprevention trial to minimize the effect of mechanical&#xD;
      removal of these lesions by the biopsy procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants were randomly assigned to receive either budesonide (Pulmicort Turbuhaler;&#xD;
      AstraZeneca, Lund, Sweden) at a dose of 800 µg twice daily by inhalation or placebo for 6&#xD;
      months. The placebo turbuhalers were identical to the ones containing the active drug.&#xD;
      Randomization was stratified according to smoking status (current versus former) and gender.&#xD;
      All study personnel were blinded to the study codes, as was confirmed by independent review.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants were interviewed monthly for compliance and drug-related adverse events.&#xD;
      Compliance was determined from a drug diary and from estimation of the number of doses&#xD;
      remaining in the turbuhaler. Toxicity was monitored according to the National Cancer&#xD;
      Institute Common Toxicity Criteria, version 2.0.10 Dose modification was performed for any&#xD;
      grade 2 toxicity or for evidence of cortisol suppression (ante meridiem (AM) plasma cortisol&#xD;
      &lt; 140 nmol/L/L). For grade 3 or 4 toxicity, therapy was discontinued until toxicity resolved&#xD;
      to grade 1 or less. At that time, the use of the study drug was resumed with a 75% dose&#xD;
      reduction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants underwent a second fluorescence bronchoscopy with bronchoalveolar lavage&#xD;
      after 6 months on study medication and biopsies were obtained from the same sites biopsied at&#xD;
      baseline. Biopsy samples were also taken from new areas that displayed abnormal fluorescence.&#xD;
      The bronchoscopist was blinded to the intervention assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current smokers were encouraged to stop smoking and were invited to take part in the Fresh&#xD;
      Start Program at the British Columbia Cancer Agency. The Clinical Investigations Committees&#xD;
      of the British Columbia Cancer Agency and the University of British Columbia approved this&#xD;
      study. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2000</start_date>
  <completion_date>December 2002</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of progression of bronchial dysplasia</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of pulmonary nodules on thoracic CT scanning and BCL-2 and p53 expression in the bronchial epithelial cells.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>120</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inhaled Budesonide 800 µg twice daily</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt; 40 years; smoking history of 30 pack-years or more; normal organ function;&#xD;
             sputum atypia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  general debility that would prevent completion of 6 month follow-up; existing cancer&#xD;
             diagnosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stephen Lam, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>British Columbia Cancer Agency</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V5Z 4E6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lam S, leRiche JC, McWilliams A, Macaulay C, Dyachkova Y, Szabo E, Mayo J, Schellenberg R, Coldman A, Hawk E, Gazdar A. A randomized phase IIb trial of pulmicort turbuhaler (budesonide) in people with dysplasia of the bronchial epithelium. Clin Cancer Res. 2004 Oct 1;10(19):6502-11.</citation>
    <PMID>15475437</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 13, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 15, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2005</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2005</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 15, 2005</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>dysplasia</keyword>
  <keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>chemoprevention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Budesonide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

