<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00173381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9461700657</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00173381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Role of Lymphangiogenesis in Head and Neck Cancer Metastasis</brief_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of lymphangiogenesis in the metastasis&#xD;
      of head and neck cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Head and neck cancer is a major, worldwide cause of morbidity and mortality. As long as the&#xD;
      neoplasm is confined to its organ of origin, the patient can be cured through surgical&#xD;
      removal of the tumor mass. Unfortunately, many cancers metastasize to other sites in the&#xD;
      body, and metastasis is the leading cause of death in cancer patients. In principle, cancer&#xD;
      cells can spread within the body by different mechanisms, such as direct invasion of&#xD;
      surrounding tissues (per continuitatem), spread via the blood vascular system (hematogenous&#xD;
      metastasis) and spread via the lymphatic system (lymphatic metastasis). Tumor cells can&#xD;
      invade either the blood or lymphatic vessels to access the general circulation and then&#xD;
      establish themselves in other tissues. Clinicopathological data suggest that the lymphatics&#xD;
      are an initial route for the spread of solid tumors. Infiltration of lymphatic vessels by&#xD;
      tumor cells has been found at the periphery of many experimental and human tumors, and the&#xD;
      lymphatic system has been recognized as a conduit for tumor cell dissemination. Though the&#xD;
      significance of angiogenesis for tumor progression has been well documented, the molecular&#xD;
      mechanisms regulating the growth and function of lymphatic vessels are largely unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vascular endothelial growth factors, first identified in 1989, are well-known angiogenic&#xD;
      agents and targets for anti-cancer therapies. Now it appears that VEGF-C, one recently-cloned&#xD;
      member of the vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) family, is also involved in&#xD;
      developmental and tumor-induced lymphangiogenesis. VEGF signals through two tyrosine kinase&#xD;
      receptors, VEGFR-1 and VEGFR-2, which are expressed predominantly but not exclusively on&#xD;
      vascular endothelial cells. As neither VEGFR-1 nor VEGFR-2 appears to be highly expressed in&#xD;
      lymphatic endothelium, it was not surprising that a third VEGF receptor, VEGFR-3, was found&#xD;
      to be predominantly expressed on lymphatic vessels during development. What was surprising,&#xD;
      however, was that VEGF was not found to bind to VEGFR-3. Instead, VEGF-C was discovered to be&#xD;
      ligand for VEGFR-3. Research groups provide direct evidence that VEGF-C is not only an&#xD;
      important regulator of lymph vessel growth (lymphangiogenesis) in vivo but it also enhances&#xD;
      lymphatic metastasis. Using experimental approaches, Mäkinen et al., Skobe et al., as well as&#xD;
      Mandriota et al. demonstrate an important role of VEGFR-3 and its ligand, VEGF-C, in&#xD;
      developmental and tumor-induced lymphangiogenesis. In normal adult human tissues, the VEGF-C&#xD;
      receptor VEGFR-3 (FLT-4) is predominantly expressed by lymphatic endothelia. Expression of&#xD;
      VEGF-C occurs in a variety of human tumors such as breast, colon, lung, thyroid, gastric,&#xD;
      squamous cell cancers, mesotheliomas, neuroblastomas, sarcomas and melanomas. Moreover,&#xD;
      expression of VEGF-C mRNA has recently been shown to correlate with the rate of metastasis to&#xD;
      lymph nodes in breast, colorectal, gastric, thyroid, lung and prostate cancers. To date,&#xD;
      however, lymphangiogenesis has not been causally linked to tumor metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) enzyme catalyzes the synthesis of prostaglandins. COX-2 is an&#xD;
      immediate-early response gene induced by inflammation, growth factors, tumor promoters,&#xD;
      oncogenes, and carcinogens. Increased levels of COX-2 may contribute to carcinogenesis by&#xD;
      modulating xenobiotic metabolism, apoptosis, immune surveillance, and angiogenesis. Any&#xD;
      significant increase in tumor mass must be preceded by an increase in vascular supply to&#xD;
      deliver nutrients and oxygen to the tumor. Recently, levels of COX-2 were found to correlate&#xD;
      with both VEGF expression and tumor vascularization in HNSCC. This finding in human tissues&#xD;
      is consistent with prior evidence that overexpression of COX-2 in epithelial cells led to&#xD;
      enhanced production of VEGF and the formation of capillary-like networks. Although COX-2&#xD;
      contributes to the regulation of angiogenesis, its role in lymphangiogenesis is not clear.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IL-6 is a secreted, multifunctional glycoprotein. Through binding to α-chain (IL-6-R, gp80)&#xD;
      and subsequently recruiting the β-chain (gp130) of the receptor, IL-6 performs various&#xD;
      biological functions. The diversity of IL-6 signaling mediated via gp130 explains its&#xD;
      functional pleiotropy. IL-6 regulates inflammatory reactions, immune responses, hepatic&#xD;
      acute-phase protein synthesis, and several other important physiological processes.&#xD;
      Interestingly, the influence of IL-6 in human cancers is varied depending on the cell types.&#xD;
      For example, IL-6 has been demonstrated to promote growth of multiple myeloma, Kaposi's&#xD;
      sarcoma, and prostatic cancer cells, while inhibiting the proliferation of lung and breast&#xD;
      cancer cells. Previous investigations have confirmed that IL-6 is important in both&#xD;
      physiological and pathological angiogenesis. Additionally, recent study supports the&#xD;
      hypothesis that IL-6 facilitates tumorigenesis of cervical cancer via VEGF-mediated&#xD;
      angiogenesis. Nevertheless, whether IL-6 could regulate the expression of VEGF-C and what is&#xD;
      its role in lymphangiogenesis still need to be clarified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inhibition of angiogenesis is currently considered one of the most promising therapeutic&#xD;
      strategies to inhibit cancer growth because it presumably can act on any tumor type, does not&#xD;
      induce resistance of tumor cells (and can therefore be used in repeated therapeutic cycles)&#xD;
      and has little effect on normal tissues. It now needs to be determined whether the same holds&#xD;
      true for tumor lymphangiogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metastases of head and neck cancers occur frequently through the lymphatic system, and the&#xD;
      extent of lymph node involvement is a key prognostic factor for the diseases. In this study,&#xD;
      we will conduct a systematic analysis of VEGF-C, COX-2 and IL-6 expressions and will try to&#xD;
      find the correlation between their expressions, lymphatic metastases and patient survival.&#xD;
      Next, we will investigate the relationship between VEGF-C, COX-2 and IL-6, and further&#xD;
      clarify their effects on tumor growth. Undoubtedly, the findings of this study will help us&#xD;
      understand whether lymphangiogenesis could be a focal point of anti-cancer research. If HNSCC&#xD;
      tumors that express high levels of VEGF-C show a consistently higher incidence of lymphatic&#xD;
      metastasis, then inhibition of VEGFR-3 function may be a novel approach to inhibit lymphatic&#xD;
      metastasis in patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>August 2004</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Natural History</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>100</enrollment>
  <condition>Oral Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Laryngeal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Hypopharyngeal Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Head and neck squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other pathological type&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ching-Ting Tan, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ching-Ting Tan, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>886-2-23123456</phone>
    <phone_ext>5222</phone_ext>
    <email>christin@ha.mc.ntu.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>100</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ching-Ting Tan, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>886-2-23123456</phone>
      <phone_ext>5222</phone_ext>
      <email>christin@ha.mc.ntu.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2005</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 12, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 12, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 15, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 30, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>lymphangiogenesis</keyword>
  <keyword>head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC)</keyword>
  <keyword>vascular endothelial growth factor-C (VEGF-C)</keyword>
  <keyword>cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2)</keyword>
  <keyword>interleukin-6 (IL-6)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mouth Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

