<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01923870</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZA-105</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01923870</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Androxal in Male Subjects With Impaired Hepatic Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics and Safety Profile of Androxal in Male Subjects With Impaired Hepatic Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Repros Therapeutics Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Repros Therapeutics Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      -  To determine and compare the pharmacokinetics (PK) of a single dose of 25 mg Androxal in&#xD;
           overweight male subjects with hepatic impairment and in volunteers with normal hepatic&#xD;
           function.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the safety profile of a single dose of 25 mg Androxal in overweight male&#xD;
           subjects with hepatic impairment and in volunteers with normal hepatic function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic parameters calculated as a ratio of hepatically impaired to normal of a single dose of 25 mg Androxal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Secondary Hypogonadism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate Hepatic Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Males age 18-70 with a BMI between 25-42 kg/m^2 with moderate hepatic impairment (Child-Pugh Class B)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Males age 18-70 with a BMI between 25-42 kg/m^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Androxal 25 mg</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Moderate Hepatic Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>enclomiphene citrate</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with Normal Hepatic Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak, read, and understand English or Spanish and is willing and able to provide&#xD;
             written informed consent on an Institutional review Board (IRB)-approved form prior to&#xD;
             the initiation of any study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male, between the ages of 18 and 70 years with Body Mass Index (BMI) between 25 and&#xD;
             42, inclusive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects in the control group, generally matched for age and BMI to patients enrolled&#xD;
             in the test group: should be ± 15 years of the mean of the population with impaired&#xD;
             hepatic function included in the study and ± 15% of the average BMI of subjects with&#xD;
             impaired hepatic function;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with creatinine clearance &gt;80 mL/min;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No significant abnormal findings at the screening physical examination as evaluated by&#xD;
             the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal laboratory values at screening as determined by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing to remain in the clinic for the screening visit and for two&#xD;
             treatment visits (approximately 3 days for each treatment visit);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No tobacco (nicotine products) use for at least 3 months prior to the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to swallow gelatin capsules;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with Moderately Impaired Hepatic Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with moderately impaired hepatic function must meet the criteria for normal&#xD;
             hepatic function subjects specified above with the following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with moderate hepatic insufficiency must meet the Class B level of the&#xD;
             Child-Pugh criteria. Hepatic impairment will be determined by the Investigator.&#xD;
             Substantiation for the diagnosis must be indicated in source documents;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have evidence of stable hepatic impairment as determined by the&#xD;
             Investigator. Stability is defined as no change in Class determination (A,B,C) based&#xD;
             on the Child-Pugh criteria assessed during the screening visit and prior to the first&#xD;
             dosing;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If on medications for treatment of the complications of liver disease, and other&#xD;
             concomitant chronic illnesses, subjects must have been taking the medications at a&#xD;
             stable dose for at least 10 days prior to the first dosing date and are then to be&#xD;
             continued at the same dose for the duration of the study. The medications must be&#xD;
             recorded in source documents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-smokers are preferred, but as this is a very restricted population light to&#xD;
             moderate smoking will be allowed (no more than 10 cigarettes/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects between the age of 18 and 48 years are preferred; however, up to 70 years old&#xD;
             of subjects may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with Normal Hepatic Function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to Clomid;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal screening visit vital signs or clinical laboratory evaluation considered&#xD;
             clinically significant by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical examination finding of ascites;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with abnormal liver function;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of/or physical examination finding of abdominal or peripheral varicosities;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with a significant organ abnormality or disease as determined by the&#xD;
             Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A physical illness within 1 year of the study that would interfere with the study as&#xD;
             determined by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a clinical trial with investigational medication within 30 days prior&#xD;
             to study medication administration;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An acute illness within 5 days of study medication administration;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine drug or infectious disease screen at the screening visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A mental condition rendering the subject unable to understand the nature, scope, and&#xD;
             possible consequences of the study and/or evidence of an uncooperative attitude, as&#xD;
             determined by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of venous thromboembolic disease (e.g. deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary&#xD;
             embolism);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myocardial infarction, unstable angina, symptomatic heart failure,&#xD;
             ventricular dysrhythmia, or known history of corrected QT (QTc) interval prolongation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The use of prohibited concomitant medications: drugs that interfere with cytochrome&#xD;
             P450 2D6 (CYP2D6) activity must cease for seven (7) days prior to first dose of study&#xD;
             drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An employee or family member of an employee of the study site or the Sponsor;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension based on the Investigator's assessment at baseline. Subjects&#xD;
             treated for Type II diabetes will be allowed into the study. Newly diagnosed diabetics&#xD;
             need to be treated for at least 48 hours before being enrolled into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with Moderately Impaired Hepatic Function&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with moderately impaired hepatic function must meet the criteria for normal&#xD;
        hepatic function subjects specified above with the following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with diseases that may cause hepatic impairment as determined by the&#xD;
             Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a clinical, physical and laboratory findings that are related to hepatic&#xD;
             impairment as determined by the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with medications necessary to manage hepatic impairment as determined by the&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33014</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.reprosrx.com</url>
    <description>Sponsor web site</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 13, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 16, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 23, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 23, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 24, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypogonadism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Enclomiphene</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Clomiphene</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zuclomiphene</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

