<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01926678</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00062853</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R21AT007090</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01926678</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Swedish Massage Therapy on Cancer-related Fatigue in Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Swedish Massage Therapy on Cancer-related Fatigue in Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health (NCCIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      With approximately 12 million cancer survivors today in the United States alone, increased&#xD;
      attention is being given to quality of life after cancer treatment. Cancer-related fatigue&#xD;
      (CRF) is one of the most prevalent and debilitating symptoms experienced by people with&#xD;
      cancer. It can persist for months or years after cancer therapy is completed and has a&#xD;
      negative impact on all areas of function. Meaningful evidence-based treatment options for CRF&#xD;
      are extremely limited and finding safe, inexpensive, and effective interventions for managing&#xD;
      this distressing symptom are urgently needed. Basic research has shown that activation of the&#xD;
      immune system can cause potent changes in behavior including reduced activity, fatigue, and&#xD;
      decreased social behavior. Furthermore, research over the last decade has found a&#xD;
      relationship between levels of CRF with increased inflammation. Thus, study of therapies that&#xD;
      may decrease immune system activation in the setting of CRF represents a possible target for&#xD;
      intervention. Massage therapy is one of the fastest growing alternative therapies and has a&#xD;
      high rate of acceptance for symptom management among cancer patients. Massage has been shown&#xD;
      in smaller studies with cancer patients to modulate the immune system. Moreover, massage has&#xD;
      been demonstrated to significantly decrease markers of immune system activation in normal&#xD;
      subjects. There are no published randomized controlled trials examining either the role of&#xD;
      massage as an intervention primarily for CRF or investigating whether massage related&#xD;
      decreases in immune system activation are responsible for improvement in CRF. This proposal&#xD;
      investigates the effects of massage therapy on CRF among breast cancer survivors. The&#xD;
      investigators' primary hypothesis is that Swedish Massage Therapy (SMT) will decrease CRF&#xD;
      compared to a light touch condition and wait list control. The investigators' secondary&#xD;
      hypothesis is that SMT will decrease CRF by reducing immune system activation. The&#xD;
      investigators' main exploratory hypothesis is that a decrease in CRF will increase quality of&#xD;
      life among cancer survivors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cancer-Related Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The primary aim of this study is to determine whether a 6-week Swedish massage therapy (SMT) intervention can decrease cancer-related fatigue, as measured by the Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory (MFI), among breast cancer survivors who have received both radiation and chemotherapy and have CRF. We hypothesize that SMT will decrease fatigue more than light touch (LT) or a wait list control (WLC) condition as assessed by the MFI.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary aim of this study is to determine whether the hypothesized decrease in cancer-related fatigue is due to Swedish massage therapy modulating the immune system of subjects with cancer-related fatigue to decrease chronic inflammation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">66</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer Related Fatigue</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Swedish massage therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Swedish massage therapy once per week for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Light touch therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Light touch therapy once per week for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wait list</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>A 6 week wait list, followed by randomization to massage therapy or light touch therapy once per week for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Swedish massage therapy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Swedish massage therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wait list</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Light touch therapy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Light touch therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wait list</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ages 18 to 65 (women above the age of 65 may be included at PI discretion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • with Stage 0-III breast cancer, status-post surgery treated with standard&#xD;
             chemotherapy/chemoprevention and/or radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients will be between 3 months and 4-years post treatment. Ongoing&#xD;
             chemoprevention therapy is permissible. Based on ICD-10 proposed criteria, a diagnosis&#xD;
             of CRF will require evidence from the history, physical exam, and laboratory findings&#xD;
             that the fatigue is a consequence of cancer or cancer therapy and not primarily a&#xD;
             consequence of comorbid psychiatric disorders (schizophrenia, depression, generalized&#xD;
             anxiety disorder, bipolar disorder, dementia, delirium or OCD).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brief Fatigue Inventory (BFI) score of &gt;25.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Satisfactory results of screening safety labs, urine pregnancy test and drug test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand study procedures and to comply with them for the entire length&#xD;
             of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of reproductive capability will be enrolled, but each woman needs to discuss&#xD;
             with the study team the method of birth control used and if the method is a reliable&#xD;
             and effective method for her. If a woman becomes pregnant during the course of active&#xD;
             study participation, she must agree prior to enrolling in the study that she will&#xD;
             report the pregnancy to the study team. With a confirmed pregnancy, the subject will&#xD;
             no longer receive the assigned treatment, but will continue to be followed per&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to lay supine for one hour at a time, given the nature of the massage&#xD;
             intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are actively suicidal or homicidal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical conditions felt to be clinically contributing to fatigue based on the&#xD;
             investigator's history, physical examination, and assessment: anemia (hemoglobin less&#xD;
             than 10 g/dl), hypothyroidism (thyroid stimulating hormone greater than 4.6 MCU/mL),&#xD;
             uncontrolled pain, medical problems associated with fatigue: chronic obstructive&#xD;
             pulmonary disease, congestive heart failure, renal disease, hepatic dysfunction,&#xD;
             autoimmune disease, neurological disorders such as multiple sclerosis or Parkinson's&#xD;
             disease, and sleep apnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications felt to be clinically contributing to fatigue based on the investigator's&#xD;
             history, physical examination, and assessment including: opioids, sedating&#xD;
             anti-histamines, antidepressants, anxiolytics or neuroleptics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body-mass index less than 18.5 (kg/m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Treatment with high dose systemic corticosteroids or continuous use of other&#xD;
             immunosuppressants within the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to comply with the protocol for any reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and aspirin is allowed but must be&#xD;
             tracked.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other exclusion criteria include: illicit drug use, shift work, current dieting,&#xD;
             excessive regular use of alcohol (more than two 5 ounce glasses of wine or&#xD;
             equivalents/day) or a history of binge drinking (more than 7 drinks/24 hour period)&#xD;
             within the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have used massage as a therapeutic modality (medical or psychological) at&#xD;
             any point in their lives for the treatment of medical conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have massages on a regular basis. Regular massage usage will be&#xD;
             operationally defined as receiving 4 or more massages/year for the last 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects currently employing any other CAM manual therapy and/or holistic therapies to&#xD;
             treat a perceived health problem. However, since past experience with CAM therapies&#xD;
             should not confound any of the analyses of the experiments proposed in this study, we&#xD;
             will not exclude individuals who have engaged in a CAM manual therapy in the past, nor&#xD;
             will we exclude individuals who practice yoga or meditation for well-being, take&#xD;
             vitamins or use nicotine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults over the age of 65 will generally be excluded from the study. This population&#xD;
             tends to undergo changes in the physiological parameters we are evaluating. Therefore,&#xD;
             inclusion of this population would skew various biological measures and this pilot&#xD;
             investigation does not have a large enough sample size to control for such variability&#xD;
             it. Older subjects could be included at the discretion of the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People unable to read and understand the informed consent document because of language&#xD;
             difficulties.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who become pregnant while enrolled will be discontinued from the study and will&#xD;
             be instructed to exercise, which is the standard recommendation for cancer-related&#xD;
             fatigue. Inability or unwillingness of individual to give written informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark H Rapaport, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 21, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 11, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mark H. Rapaport</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor and Chairman</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>swedish massage</keyword>
  <keyword>fatigue</keyword>
  <keyword>light touch</keyword>
  <keyword>inflammation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

