<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03996733</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JugulerUsgMaket</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03996733</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Using A Gelatin-Based Model In USG-Guided Jugular Venous Catheter Placement Training</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness Of Using A Gelatin-Based Model In Ultrasonography Guided Jugular Central Venous Catheter Placement Training</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zeki Tuncel Tekgul</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An education model with a homemade jugular venous catheterization model will be compared to&#xD;
      the conventional training model for ultrasound-guided central jugular line catheterization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will include 60 residents to be divided into two groups with stratified random&#xD;
      sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training session for the control group (Group 2) will include a lecture about the subject, a&#xD;
      demo video presentation, and practice of visualization of right jugular vein on a real human&#xD;
      subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training session for the model group (Group 1) will include the same as GControl with the&#xD;
      addition of the puncture practice on the homemade jugular venous catheterization model(HJVCM)&#xD;
      with ultrasound guidance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both groups will be tested with another HJVCM individually and the results of the success and&#xD;
      fail parameters will be compared.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      According to the latest guidelines, ultrasound guidance has become the golden standard in&#xD;
      Jugular Central Venous Catheter applications. This reveals the necessity of theoretical and&#xD;
      practical training on USG for jugular central venous catheter training. Models for jugular&#xD;
      venous catheterization training are few in number and also expensive. Thus, the investigators&#xD;
      built an Homemade Jugular Venous Catheterization Model which meant to be cheap and easy to&#xD;
      make and transport. With this study, the investigators will test whether this model will&#xD;
      provide any benefit to the success of the training on USG Guided Jugular Venous&#xD;
      Catheterization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two different training sessions are planned as one will include the training model and the&#xD;
      other will not. The study will be conducted with resident physicians without any experience&#xD;
      on jugular venous catheterization or ultrasound-guided interventions of any kind.&#xD;
      Participants will be divided into two groups with stratified random sampling (According to&#xD;
      specialties and years of residency) and the both will attend to a 30 minutes lecture on&#xD;
      jugular venous catheterization with US guidance and basic ultrasound principles including a&#xD;
      demo video illustrating the procedure. Later, the participants will practice ultrasound&#xD;
      imaging of right jugular vein on a real human subject. The model training group will be named&#xD;
      Group 1 and control group will be named Group 2. Group 1 will also practice jugular vein&#xD;
      puncture on the training model. After training sessions, each participant will be tested with&#xD;
      a different model placed in a manikin. The assessment session will include successful&#xD;
      visualization of the jugular vein, puncture of the jugular vein, and insertion of the guide&#xD;
      wire. Evaluation of the success and fail parameters (explained in outcome parameters) will be&#xD;
      monitored by four educated supervisors. The sessions for both of the groups are planned to&#xD;
      take 120 minutes in total and the assessment will be limited to five minutes individually.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 15, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Success Of The Catheterization</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Successful visualization of the jugular vein in long axis, successful puncture and draining the fluid in the jugular vein, successful visualization of insertion of the guide wire. All required.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Successful Visualization</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Successful visualization of the jugular vein in long axis. Yes or No.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time Of The Successful Visualization</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Total time from puncture of the model's skin to the successful visualization of the jufular vein in long axis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Puncture Count</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Total count of punctures on model skin.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number Of Changes Of Needle Angle During The Procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Retraction and orientation of the needle at different angles before the puncture of the jugular vein.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Puncture Time</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Total time from puncture of the model's skin to the successful puncture of the jugular vein.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fail Of The Procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Any of these four endpoints;&#xD;
Puncture of pleura&#xD;
Puncture of carotid artery&#xD;
Puncture of the base(Too deep needle advancement)&#xD;
Exceeding five minutes, before successful jugular venous catheterization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">61</enrollment>
  <condition>Central Venous Catheters</condition>
  <condition>Vascular Access Devices</condition>
  <condition>Education</condition>
  <condition>Simulation Training</condition>
  <condition>Ultrasonography, Interventional</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GControl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will attend the lecture for 30 minutes and watch a demo video showing the procedure. Later, they will practice ultrasound imaging of right jugular vein on a real human subject.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GModel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will attend the lecture for 30 minutes and watch a demo video showing the procedure. Later, they will practice ultrasound imaging of right jugular vein on a real human subject.&#xD;
Participants in this group will also practice jugular vein puncture on our homemade jugular central venous catheterization training model.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lecture</intervention_name>
    <description>Principal investigator of the study will lecture about the ultrasound guided jugular central venous catheterization according to latest guidelines.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GControl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GModel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Demo Video</intervention_name>
    <description>Investigators of the study prepared a detailed demo-video showing insertion of a jugular central venous catheter with USG guidance. Principal investigator will vocalize the video in real-time.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GControl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GModel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>UltrasoundImaging</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will exercise the proper visualisation of the right jugular vein at T6 level with USG guidance on a human subject.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GControl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GModel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ModelTraining</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will exercise the proper punction of juguler vein with USG guidance on the homemade jugular venous catheterization training model.&#xD;
Training model will include carotid artery, trachea and plaure in accordance with the real anatomy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GModel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any experience on jugular venous catheterization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experience of ultrasound guided interventions of any kind.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Izmir Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karabaglar</city>
        <state>İzmir</state>
        <zip>35170</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 19, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 25, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bozyaka Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zeki Tuncel Tekgul</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof. Dr</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Education</keyword>
  <keyword>Homemade</keyword>
  <keyword>Model</keyword>
  <keyword>Central Venous Catheterization</keyword>
  <keyword>Ultrasound Guidance</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

