<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03994419</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRAS 248493</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03994419</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PErioperAtive CHildhood ObesitY</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEACHY</acronym>
  <official_title>PErioperAtive CHildhood obesitY (PEACHY): A Prospective Observational Cohort Study Investigating the Proportion of Overweight and Obese Children Presenting for a Procedure Under General Anaesthesia in the UK and the Incidence of Perioperative Adverse Outcomes in This Patient Group</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Association of Paediatric Anaesthetists of Great Britain &amp; Ireland (APAGBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Aberdeen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Paediatric Anaesthesia Trainee Research Network (PATRN)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of childhood obesity is at epidemic levels and increasing in the UK. Obese&#xD;
      adults are considered a high-risk group of patients for general anaesthesia with published&#xD;
      national guidelines on the best practice management. The proportion of children presenting&#xD;
      for a procedure under general anaesthesia in the UK who are overweight or obese is currently&#xD;
      unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obese children are perceived to be at greater risk of complications from general anaesthesia.&#xD;
      Previous non-UK studies suggest they take longer to recover from anaesthesia, require more&#xD;
      medications to combat nausea and vomiting and are at greater risk of complications that may&#xD;
      threaten their airway and breathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study involves reviewing the anaesthetic care record and patient notes to collect&#xD;
      information relating to general anaesthesia and basic demographic data in children aged 2-16&#xD;
      years presenting for a procedure under general anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aims of this study are to establish the prevalence of obesity in the paediatric surgical&#xD;
      population (i.e. the proportion of children attending UK hospitals for procedures under&#xD;
      general anaesthesia who are overweight or obese) and to ascertain whether obese children are&#xD;
      at increased risk compared to their healthy weight counterparts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This information will be used with the goal of reducing avoidable harm both at national and&#xD;
      local level in the future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      IRAS 248493 REC 18/WM/0394 NIHR CPMS ID 40368&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Overweight and obese children commonly present for procedures under general anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Obese children are at higher risk of perioperative adverse events compared to their&#xD;
           healthy-weight counterparts.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. There is wide variation in paracetamol drug dosing amongst obese children.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Obese children may be more likely to present for certain surgery compared to their&#xD;
           healthy-weight counterparts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This observational cohort study will take place in NHS hospitals in the UK with trainee&#xD;
      anaesthetists affiliated to the Paediatric Anaesthesia Trainee Research Network (PATRN). To&#xD;
      increase coverage of sites in the UK, the project will be advertised through other trainee&#xD;
      research networks including Research and Audit Federation of Trainees (RAFT) and through the&#xD;
      Association of Paediatric Anaesthetists of Great Britain and Ireland (APAGBI) linkmen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each hospital taking part will have a nominated anaesthetic consultant and trainees who will&#xD;
      act as local investigators collecting data. Data will be collected for all children aged 2-16&#xD;
      years weighing &gt;12kg presenting for a procedure involving general anaesthesia during the&#xD;
      defined study period. This will be one week (7 consecutive days). Using previous PATRN audit&#xD;
      projects as a guide, we aim to enrol approximately 90 local sites which will give an&#xD;
      estimated total of 7590 children attending for a procedure under general anaesthesia during&#xD;
      the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be identified by local trainee investigators (independent of delivery of&#xD;
      anaesthesia but part of the anaesthetic department of the hospital) from operating department&#xD;
      lists on the days of the study. Data will be collected on all eligible patients who undergo a&#xD;
      procedure under general anaesthesia during the study period. Similar data collection tools&#xD;
      have been used in previous PATRN audit projects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be collected from the paper or electronic anaesthetic record and clinical notes.&#xD;
      Only routine clinical data will be included and where this is unavailable the domain will be&#xD;
      left blank. Data will be collected using a single paper case report form (CRF) per patient.&#xD;
      This will be initiated by the anaesthetist in the operating theatre and completed by recovery&#xD;
      staff in PACU. Patient identifiable data in the form of hospital number and date of birth&#xD;
      will be collected on the CRF for traceability in terms of missing data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To calculate BMI, age (to the nearest month), gender, height and weight are required for each&#xD;
      patient. It is anticipated that all hospitals would routinely measure weight but some&#xD;
      hospitals may not routinely measure height prior to a procedure under general anaesthesia.&#xD;
      NICE guidelines currently recommend that clinical judgement should be used to decide when to&#xD;
      measure a person's height and weight, including at routine health checks. The preoperative&#xD;
      setting is a specific health check prior to undergoing general anaesthesia and therefore an&#xD;
      appropriate time to measure a child's height and weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Height will be measured with shoes removed to the nearest 0.1cm using a height measure with&#xD;
      the child's head positioned so that the Frankfurt plane is horizontal. Body weight will be&#xD;
      measured with patients lightly clad, to the nearest 0.1kg using a calibrated electronic&#xD;
      weighing scale. If the local site is unable to collect age, gender, height and weight we will&#xD;
      ask for the case to be logged and uploaded but for no other data to be collected. It is&#xD;
      important to know how many cases we are unable to include in the analysis due to incomplete&#xD;
      data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other information that would routinely be recorded within the clinical notes relating to the&#xD;
      patients physical status, surgery, anaesthetic and specific perioperative adverse events will&#xD;
      also be collected on the CRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The completed CRF will be taken directly to a secure location accessible by the local&#xD;
      investigator. The data will be entered electronically via a secure encrypted connection into&#xD;
      an online portal managed by Aberdeen University. The software used for data capture will be&#xD;
      REDCap (Research Electronic Data Capture - http://www.project-redcap.org). REDCap is a&#xD;
      mature, secure web application for building and managing online surveys and databases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each dataset entered will generate a unique identifier (ie the data will be pseudonymised);&#xD;
      local investigators will be asked to keep a log of their unique identifiers linked to local&#xD;
      hospital identification numbers. The hospital number will remain within the respective&#xD;
      trusts, meaning only the local NHS staff responsible for care have access to personal&#xD;
      identifying information. The study database will be closed for data entry a number of weeks&#xD;
      after the study completion date. The anonymised responses from participating hospitals across&#xD;
      the country will be analysed by a team of researchers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 9, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 6, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 6, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of overweight and obesity in UK children attending for surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>One week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of overweight and obesity in UK children aged 2-16 years attending hospitals for a procedure under general anaesthesia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>One week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of defined adverse events occurring in obese children as compared to healthy weight children attending for a procedure under general anaesthesia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Paracetamol dosing variation</measure>
    <time_frame>One week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The variation in paracetamol dosing in obese children in the UK perioperative setting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgery types</measure>
    <time_frame>One week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of obese children presenting for certain types of surgery compared to their healthy weight counterparts.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison with the UK National Child Measurement Programme</measure>
    <time_frame>One week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the proportion of overweight and obesity in the perioperative setting compared to that from the UK National Child Measurement Programme (NCMP).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">8000</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Obesity, Childhood</condition>
  <condition>Overweight and Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Perioperative/Postoperative Complications</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anaesthesia for surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Observational study observing proportion of obese and overweight children attending for surgery. Observing adverse events following general anaesthesia for surgery in obese versus healthy weight children.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All children aged 2-16 years and weighing &gt;12kg presenting for a procedure under general&#xD;
        anaesthesia in registered sites across the UK (England, Wales, Scotland and Northern&#xD;
        Ireland) during the study period.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All children aged greater than or equal to two years and less than 16 years presenting&#xD;
             for a procedure under general anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elective cases, day case and emergency cases will all be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Private cases being undertaken in NHS hospitals will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MRI, radiology, oncology and dental cases will be included provided the patient&#xD;
             receives a general anaesthetic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Procedures performed under sedation or local anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children aged less than two years since the 0-24 month age group has separate growth&#xD;
             charts, which are not currently recommended for interpretation of BMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children weighing less than 12kg as these are not included on the growth charts for&#xD;
             interpretation of BMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children requiring general anaesthesia purely as part of intensive care treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children who are already anaesthetised in the intensive care setting being transferred&#xD;
             for a scan or procedure without any intervention to their airway planned.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children 16 years or more may be counted as children in some hospitals but not for the&#xD;
             purposes of this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Edwards</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital Southampton NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zoe A Burton, MBBCh</last_name>
    <phone>00447921865041</phone>
    <email>UHS.PEACHY@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rachael Meering</last_name>
    <phone>00442381205044</phone>
    <email>Rachael.meering@uhs.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 20, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 20, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 20, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Paediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Anaesthesia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

