<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03994835</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL.68056.091.18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03994835</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>2000 HIV Human Functional Genomics Partnership Program</brief_title>
  <acronym>2000HIV</acronym>
  <official_title>2000 HIV Human Functional Genomics Partnership Program</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Radboud University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ViiV Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Elisabeth-TweeSteden Ziekenhuis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Erasmus Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Onze Lieve Vrouwe Gasthuis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Radboud University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background Chronic HIV infection leads to a dysregulated immune system, even when full viral&#xD;
      suppression is achieved. HIV causes persistent immune activation, relating to an array of&#xD;
      common non-AIDS-related diseases such as cardiovascular disease (CVD) and non-alcoholic fatty&#xD;
      liver disease (NAFLD). On the other hand, accelerated ageing of the immune system hinders&#xD;
      effective immunity against infectious diseases and cancer. Likewise, this derailed&#xD;
      inflammatory balance creates a niche for persistent viral replication and reservoir, and&#xD;
      prevents cure or functional cure. Mechanisms behind this phenomenon are poorly understood.&#xD;
      Inclusion of a larger cohort of HIV-infected patients allows for a more precise assessment of&#xD;
      the factors underlying the immune dysregulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Identify a set of candidate biomarkers that correlate with particular non-AIDS-related&#xD;
           comorbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Unravel biological processes associated with extreme HIV clinical phenotypes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Find therapeutic targets to identify novel assets or for repurposing of clinical phase&#xD;
           assets from other disease areas for HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluate potential relationship of host/immune profiles on efficacy, safety, and&#xD;
           tolerability of standard care regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluate the contribution of age, sex, and genetics in host-immune profiles that are:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  distinct to HIV infection relative to controls in other cohorts;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  associated with non-AIDS-related comorbidities in HIV infection relative to non-HIV&#xD;
                chronic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design 2000 HIV patients will be included in the cohort. The investigators estimate a&#xD;
      2-year inclusion and 2-year follow-up period and will strive for the inclusion of several&#xD;
      clinical phenotypes and classical risk group patients. Patients will be recruited from four&#xD;
      Dutch HIV treatment centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Collection of metadata using questionnaires and patient medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Asses co-pathology (CVD and NAFLD)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Blood will be drawn for genetic, epigenetic, proteomic, metabolomic, microbiome,&#xD;
           immunological, and virological analyses&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 2 years follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Collection of metadata using questionnaires and patient medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Asses co-pathology (CVD and NAFLD)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Blood samples will be collected for biomarker and infection/inflammation parameter&#xD;
           analysis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study population A cohort with a total of 2000 HIV patients will be built, consisting of a&#xD;
      discovery cohort (n=1200) and confirmation cohort (n=800). The investigators estimate a&#xD;
      2-year inclusion and 2-year follow-up period and will strive for the inclusion of several&#xD;
      clinical phenotypes such as long-term non-progressors (~2-3%), immunologic non-responders&#xD;
      (~3%), and rapid progressors (~4-5%) and classical risk group patients such as men who have&#xD;
      sex with men (MSM), females, and subjects from Sub-Sahara Africa. Patients will be recruited&#xD;
      from the following Dutch HIV Treatment Centers: Radboudumc (Nijmegen), Erasmus MC&#xD;
      (Rotterdam), OLVG (Amsterdam), Elisabeth Twee-Steden Ziekenhuis (Tilburg).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A sample size calculation cannot be provided due to the variable frequencies of the various&#xD;
      traits in genome-microbiome interaction, and their effect on cytokine production. Because of&#xD;
      the explorative nature of this study, the size calculation will be variable depending on the&#xD;
      type of polymorphism analyzed. The frequencies of the various microorganism classes in the&#xD;
      colonizing microbiome is not known in our study population, and therefore power calculations&#xD;
      are impossible to be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Earlier studies in the Human Functional Genomics Project have assessed microbiome traits in&#xD;
      250-500 individuals. An earlier HFGP study included a uniform cohort of 200 HIV-infected&#xD;
      individuals (all MSM). The present study will also include HIV-infected patients with a more&#xD;
      extreme phenotype, females and subjects originating from Sub-Sahara Africa. Because of this,&#xD;
      the investigators decided to increase the number of individuals tested to 2000, consisting of&#xD;
      a discovery cohort of 1200 subjects, and a confirmation cohort of 800 participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study visits and procedures At inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The investigators will collect metadata using questionnaires on lifestyle, health and&#xD;
           clinical symptoms, including neuropsychiatric symptoms. Relevant data will also be&#xD;
           collected from the patients records in the medical centers and the HIV Monitoring&#xD;
           Foundation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Co-pathology will be assesed:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cardiovascular risk scores (D:A:D risk score and Framingham CVD score) will be&#xD;
                collected as well as ECG and intima-media thickness (IMT) measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) assessment through liver ultrasound and&#xD;
                FibroScan.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Blood will be drawn (90 ml):&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  DNA will be isolated for genetic and epigenetic analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The function of the immune system will be analyzed at several levels using&#xD;
                circulating white blood cells from venous blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Metabolism and proteomics will be analyzed&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Virological analysis, characterizing the HIV reservoir, HIV resistance and viral&#xD;
                sequences in circulating DNA and RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Microbiome analysis will be performed on stool and saliva samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Urine sample will be collected for creatinine measurements and microbiome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 2 years follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The investigators will collect metadata using questionnaires on lifestyle, health and&#xD;
           clinical symptoms, including neuropsychiatric symptoms. Relevant data will also be&#xD;
           collected from the patients records in the medical centers and the HIV Monitoring&#xD;
           Foundation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Co-pathology will be assesed:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cardiovascular risk scores (D:A:D risk score and Framingham CVD score) will be&#xD;
                collected as well as ECG.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) assessment through liver ultrasound and&#xD;
                FibroScan.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Blood samples (10ml) will be collected for biomarker and infection/inflammation&#xD;
           parameter analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient informed consent procedure Patients will always be approached first by a treating&#xD;
      physician or specialized nurse. They will be provided with information and will be asked if a&#xD;
      physician-researcher may contact the patient. If there is oral consent for this, the&#xD;
      researcher contacts the patient in one week to ask if they are interested in participating in&#xD;
      the study. the physician-researcher will answer any questions the patient may have and plan&#xD;
      the first visit. The informed consent procedure will be conducted during the patient's first&#xD;
      visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient registry procedures All patient data will be recorded only in coded form in a secure&#xD;
      database with audit and edit trail (CASTOR EDC). During the informed consent procedure, the&#xD;
      patient is given a study code. The identifying patient data and study code is kept in a&#xD;
      password-protected key file, only accessible to the local research team. No&#xD;
      patient-identifying data will leave the local medical center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the questionnaires and eCRFs in CASTOR, the investigators will enter as many data checks&#xD;
      as possible&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biomaterials All biomaterial (blood, stool, urine, saliva) will be transported to and&#xD;
      processed in the laboratory of Experimental Internal Medicine of the Radboudumc in Nijmegen.&#xD;
      Here, all the biomaterial will also be stored collectively. All materials will be handled and&#xD;
      stored only under the patient's study code.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring Monitoring will be performed by an independent monitor according to the latest&#xD;
      guidelines of the The Netherlands Federation of University Medical Centers. An initiation and&#xD;
      close-out visit will be planned in plenary form with all the centers in Radboudumc. There&#xD;
      will be one extra visit per center. During these visits informed consents will be checked, as&#xD;
      well as inclusion and exclusion criteria and source data verification in a small subset of&#xD;
      total participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection for patient registry&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline data collected from electronic patient files or the HIV Monitoring Foundation during&#xD;
      inclusion visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Inclusion date&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Length and weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Last known blood pressure (and date measured)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Seroconversion date (if known)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Date first HIV-positive test&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Date start cART&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. HIV transmission risk behavior:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  MSM&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Heterosexual&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Injecting drug use&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Contaminated blood products&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Unknown&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. First CD4 count&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. CD4 nadir&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. CD4/CD8 ratio pre-cART&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. HIV stadium at start cART according to CDC criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Pre-cART HIV RNA zenith&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Opportunistic conditions before start cART&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  MTB&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Fungal infections&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Parasitic infections,&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bacterial infections&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Malignancies before start cART&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If yes, specify what kind, when and treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Other known medical problems before start cART, which require long-term treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If yes, specify what kind, when and treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Response cART:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Period between start cART and viral load &lt; 500 (months)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Viral loads:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Undetectable after 24 weeks: yes/no&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Number/frequency of residual viremia (positive test with signal &lt;50 copies):&#xD;
                     last year and last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Number of viral blips (50-200): last year and last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Number of viremia: 200-1000: last year and last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Number of failing cART (&gt;1000): last year and last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Resistance associated mutations pre-cART and following failure&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  CD4 reconstitution&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  CD4/CD8 ratio and normalization &gt;1 yes/no after cART initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. IRIS, yes/no&#xD;
&#xD;
       18. Opportunistic conditions after start cART (if known)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  MTB&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Fungal infections&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Parasitic infections,&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bacterial infections&#xD;
&#xD;
       19. Malignancies after start cART (if known)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If yes, specify what kind, when and treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
       20. Vascular diseases after start cART:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Stroke/ TIA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Claudicatio intermittens&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Venous thrombo-embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Other …&#xD;
&#xD;
       21. SOAs&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HAV: yes/no, if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HBV:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Infected: active infection (PCR+) or non-active infection&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Vaccination: No/Yes&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Once with anti-HBs&gt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Two times vaccination leading to&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  anti-HBs&gt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  anti-HBs&lt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  No infection&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HCV: yes/no, if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Lues: yes/ no: if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Chlamydia/Go: yes/ no: if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HPV&#xD;
&#xD;
       22. COVID-19 infection before or after start cART:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Was a COVID-19 test done and if so type of test if known (PCR or antigen test),&#xD;
                date of test and result of laboratory test for COVID-19 (positive or negative)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  COVID-19 Serology results&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Register COVID-19-related hospital admissions&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  COVID-19 vaccination: type and date(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Side effects of COVID-19 vaccination:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Mild: overall malaise, fatigue, muscle ache, pain at injection site, shivers,&#xD;
                     headache.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Moderate: mild symptoms to the extend (self)medication/pain relief is&#xD;
                     required.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Severe: fever &gt;38.5 degrees Celsius and/or one or more days bedridden&#xD;
&#xD;
       23. cART regimes&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Reasons for switching&#xD;
&#xD;
       24. Prescribed co-medication&#xD;
&#xD;
       25. Full current medication list&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs of Kaposi sarcoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lymphadenopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For determination of medication levels: when was the last date and time HIV-medication&#xD;
           was taken?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other abnormalities: …&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular risk profile:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  D:A:D (R) and Framingham scores&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory results of date closest to inclusion date (standard care at least once a year&#xD;
      according to Dutch guidelines):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full blood count&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Liver enzymes (ALAT, AF, bilirubin)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Creatinine&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HIV-RNA&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CD4 and CD8 counts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Glucose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lipid profile&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TPHA/VDRL&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HCV serology (for all at risk, such as MSM and i.v. drug users)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If positive, HCV PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HPV diagnostics in females (PAP, PCR)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine diagnostics (if available): α1-microglobulin, protein, albumin, phosphate,&#xD;
           creatinin&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline data collected from electronic patient files or the HIV Monitoring Foundation during&#xD;
      2-year follow-up visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history last 2 years:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Date of 2 year follow-up visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Last known blood pressure (and date measured)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Response cART last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Number of residual viremia: last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Number of viral blips (20-200): last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Number of viremia (200-1000): last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Number of failing cART (&gt;1000): last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CD4 count&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CD4/CD8 ratio (if known)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Opportunistic conditions last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  MTB&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Fungal infections&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Parasitic infections,&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bacterial infections&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Malignancies in the last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If yes, specify what kind, when and treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Signs/symptoms of cardiovascular diseases in the last 2 years:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Stroke/ TIA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Claudicatio intermittens&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Venous thrombo-embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Other …&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. New SOAs in the last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HAV: yes/no, if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HBV:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Infected: active infection (PCR+), non-active infection,&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Vaccination: No/Yes&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Once with anti-HBs&gt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
                       -  Two times vaccination leading to&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  anti-HBs&gt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  anti-HBs&lt; 100&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  No infection&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HCV: yes/no, if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Lues: yes/ no: if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Chlamydia/Go: yes/ no: if yes: treatment and how often&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. COVID-19 infection before or after start cART:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Was a COVID-19 test done and if so type of test if known (PCR or antigen test),&#xD;
                date of test and result of laboratory test for COVID-19 (positive or negative)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  COVID-19 Serology results&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Register COVID-19-related hospital admissions&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  COVID-19 vaccination: type and date(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Side effects of COVID-19 vaccination:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Mild: overall malaise, fatigue, muscle ache, pain at injection site, shivers,&#xD;
                     headache.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Moderate: mild symptoms to the extend (self)medication/pain relief is&#xD;
                     required.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Severe: fever &gt;38.5 degrees Celsius and/or one or more days bedridden&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. cART regimes in the last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Reasons for switching available from 'Stichting HIV Monitoring'&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Prescribed co-medication&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Full current medication list&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs of Kaposi sarcoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lymphadenopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For determination of medication levels: when was the last date and time HIV-medication&#xD;
           was taken?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other abnormalities: …&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular risk profile:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  D:A:D (R) and Framingham scores&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory results of date closest to follow-up visit date:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full blood count&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Liver enzymes (ALAT, AF, bilirubin)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Creatinine&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HIV-RNA&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CD4 and CD8 counts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Glucose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lipid profile&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TPHA/VDRL&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HCV serology&#xD;
&#xD;
           o If positive, HCV PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HPV diagnostics in females (PAP, PCR)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine diagnostics&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 16, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in liver fibrosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Change: 2-year value - baseline value</time_frame>
    <description>Change in liver fibrosis measurement by FibroScan (method by Echosens)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in liver steatosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Change: 2-year value - baseline value</time_frame>
    <description>Change in liver steatosis measurement by FibroScan (method by Echosens) and liver ultrasound (method developed by Radboudumc)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiovascular risk score (Framingham score)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change: 2-year value - baseline value</time_frame>
    <description>Framingham score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiovascular risk score (D:A:D score)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change: 2-year value - baseline value</time_frame>
    <description>D:A:D score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and type of cardiovascular events</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of events over 2 years between baseline and 2-year time point</time_frame>
    <description>Recoring of cadiovascular diseases from patient file:&#xD;
Stroke/ TIA&#xD;
Angina pectoris&#xD;
Myocardial infarction&#xD;
Claudicatio intermittens&#xD;
Venous thrombo-embolism&#xD;
Other …</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Genetic data</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Genome-wide genotype data including &gt;8 million SNPs per individual</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Colonizing microbiome profile</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Colonizing microbiome profile will be generated from stool and saliva samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Transcriptomics</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>RNA-sequencing will be performed in PBMCs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantification of a wide range of metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Metabolomics analysis by multiplex immunoassays will be performed in plasma or serum</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokine production of PBMCs in ex vivo stimulation experiments</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Ex vivo cytokine responses of isolated PBMCs to a range of stimuli (TLR ligands, killed pathogens and viral antigen stimuli)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune phenotyping</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Extensive phenotyping of circulating immune cells by flow cytometry analysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>ECG paramater changes between baseline and 2-year time visit</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized signs of myocardial infarction with MEANS ECG software, as extensively described elsewehere. In addition, we will look at the full list of ECG output measurements as described elsewhere*: in brief, MEANS reliably provides output on interpretation of the ECG rhythm and morphology. The morphological interpretation consists of separate analyses of the P wave, QRS complex, and ST-T segment. Reference: Van den Berg ME, Rijnbeek PR, Niemeijer MN, et al. Normal values of corrected heart-rate variability in 10-second electrocardiograms for all ages. Front Physiol. 2018;9:424</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intima-media thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline only</time_frame>
    <description>Ultrasound measurement of intima-media thickness in the carotid artery as a measure for atherosclerosis and cardiovasculr disease risk.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1909</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood for DNA isolation (no sequencing, only SNP array) Stool for microbiome analysis Saliva&#xD;
      for microbiome analysis Plasma and serum for metabolomics Urine for creatinine analysis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        HIV-infected patients (n=2000) will be recruited from the following Dutch HIV Treatment&#xD;
        Centres: Radboudumc (Nijmegen), ErasmusMC (Rotterdam), Onze Lieve Vrouwe Gasthuis&#xD;
        (Amsterdam), Elisabeth-TweeSteden Ziekenhuis (Tilburg). Our aim is to include approximately&#xD;
        20% females, 20% of Sub-Sahara African origin, elite controllers (~2-3%), immunologic&#xD;
        non-responders (~3%), and rapid progressors (~4-5%) The total number of adult HIV patients&#xD;
        under care in these treatment centers is 7000, of which 80% is male and 70% is of Caucasian&#xD;
        origin. There is wide age distribution among the adult HIV population.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV-infected,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged ≥18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  on cART ≥6 months with an HIV-RNA load &lt;200 copies/mL, *Apart from the above-mentioned&#xD;
             subjects, elite controllers that are not on cART, are also eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient communication because of language or other problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B/C or signs of acute infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Quirijn de Mast, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Radboud University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Annelies Verbon, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erasmus MC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Willem Blok, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Onze Lieve Vrouwe Gasthuis</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marvin Berrevoets, Drs.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Elisabeth Twee-Steden ziekenhuis</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Onze Lieve Vrouwe Gasthuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <zip>1091AC</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboudumc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <zip>6525GA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus MC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <zip>3015GD</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Elisabeth Twee-Steden ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tilburg</city>
        <zip>5042AD</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 22, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 19, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Omics data</keyword>
  <keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

