<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03771703</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EK Nr. 1363/2016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03771703</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sex Differences in Chronic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Study in Three Parts to Determine Sex-Specific Differences in Chronic Kidney Disease Recognition, Progression and Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assoc. Prof. Dr. Manfred Hecking, MD PhD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Vienna</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to describe sex specific differences of the hemodialysis population in&#xD;
      Austria, to quantify sex specific differences in treatment and outcomes in hospitalized&#xD;
      patients with chronic kidney disease and to examine decision making by doctors and patients&#xD;
      with regards to hemodialysis initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To adequately serve the needs of these research questions, the study is divided into 3 parts&#xD;
      (sub-studies).&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Description and analysis of sex-specific differences in renal replacement therapy in&#xD;
           Austria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Description and analysis of the competing risks of death versus renal replacement&#xD;
           therapy initiation in the chronic kidney disease population by sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Analysis of sex differences in renal replacement therapy initiation decisions,&#xD;
           emphasizing patient perception and socio-economic differences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      2.1-A Renal Replacement Therapy: Description and analysis of sex-specific differences in&#xD;
      hemodialysis patients and the associated male-to-female mortality in Austria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are sex-specific differences in hemodialysis incidence/prevalence and mortality among&#xD;
      hemodialysis patients in Austria. There are differences in male-to-female mortality among&#xD;
      hemodialysis patients as compared to the general population in Austria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data extraction will be performed from the Austrian Dialysis registry which holds complete&#xD;
      longitudinal entries of all Austrian hemodialysis patients since 1970 and contains data of&#xD;
      all patients undergoing hemodialysis in Austria since the year 1965.Demographic data,&#xD;
      laboratory values, clinical characteristics and hemodialysis specific data will be collected&#xD;
      for every patient registered in the Austrian Dialysis registry between 1965 and 2015.Male and&#xD;
      female population structure and mortality data of the Austrian general population will be&#xD;
      retrieved from the ´Statistik Austria´ registry.Additional data of the Austrian general&#xD;
      population will be retrieved from the SYSKID project and electronic medical records retrieved&#xD;
      in the course of an epidemiologic study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard descriptive statistics will be used for tabulations of patient characteristics by&#xD;
      sex and decade, of the Austrian hemodialysis population versus general population by sex and&#xD;
      age group over time. The unadjusted male-to-female mortality rate ratio in the hemodialysis&#xD;
      population will be compared with that of the Austrian general population. Adjusted hazard&#xD;
      ratios for the male-to-female mortality risk in hemodialysis patients, by region will be&#xD;
      performed using Cox regression analysis. Statistical modeling will closely follow a&#xD;
      previously published study of hemodialysis data, analyzed by sex and country/region. All&#xD;
      obtained p-values will be considered exploratory in nature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1-B Renal Replacement Therapy: Description and analysis of sex-specific differences in&#xD;
      transplantation rates in Austria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (i) Women in Austria have lower access to transplantation with a deceased donor organ.(ii)&#xD;
      Living kidney donor transplantation is not unfair towards women. (iii) Kidney allograft&#xD;
      survival is sex-dependent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic and clinical characteristics, laboratory values, and hemodialysis specific data&#xD;
      will be extracted from the Austrian Dialysis and Transplant registry for all patients&#xD;
      registered between 1965 and 2018. Data regarding the time intervals between initiation of&#xD;
      dialysis, entry to transplantation waiting list, transplantation, potential graft failure and&#xD;
      potential death will be retrieved. Further, data regarding sex of donors and recipients will&#xD;
      be extracted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis (i), sex differences in the time to waiting-list entry and time on waiting list,&#xD;
      male-to-female hazard ratios will be calculated from competing risk Cox proportional hazards&#xD;
      models. The models will include age and relevant comorbidities as adjusting covariates and&#xD;
      death will be considered as competing event to transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis (ii), a logistic regression model will be fit to explain the probability for a&#xD;
      dialysis patient to receive a living-donor kidney transplant by sex and a comprehensive set&#xD;
      of further potential explanatory variables. These will include age, comorbidities,&#xD;
      serological markers, and marital status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The model will be used to calculate covariate adjusted male-to-female odds ratios. In case of&#xD;
      a &quot;fair&quot; treatment of men and women, the observed adjusted effect of sex is expected to be&#xD;
      close to zero whereas inter-individual differences in the probability to receive a&#xD;
      living-donor transplant should be explained through individual, none sex-related covariate&#xD;
      values.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis (iii), Cox proportional hazard models will be applied for the competing events&#xD;
      graft failure and death, with sex as main predictor and demographic and clinical data on&#xD;
      donor and recipient as covariates. In a second model sex differences regarding a combined&#xD;
      endpoint comprising graft failure and death will be studied as sensitivity analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Description and analysis of the competing risks of death versus renal replacement therapy&#xD;
      initiation in the chronic kidney disease population by sex&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are sex-specific differences in the competing risks of death versus renal replacement&#xD;
      therapy initiation in the chronic kidney disease population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal data source from Europe is the Stockholm CREAtinine Measurements (SCREAM)&#xD;
      cohort. In the SCREAM cohort, 1 Million adult individuals residing in the region of&#xD;
      Stockholm/Sweden and undergoing one or more routine serum creatinine assessment between 2006&#xD;
      and 2011 were included. This number of individuals corresponds to 66% coverage of the&#xD;
      complete population in the region. The advantages of using the SCREAM cohort are (a)&#xD;
      universal healthcare access of the included individuals, (b) the fact that all laboratory&#xD;
      values of the included individuals are provided through the central repository of laboratory&#xD;
      data (no other laboratory values than the included ones have ever been taken), (c) complete&#xD;
      coverage on ICD diagnoses (including primary care) and death, (d) availability of&#xD;
      socio-economic information. The most complex part of SCREAM, linking the laboratory data to&#xD;
      regional healthcare utilization data was solved by involving the administrative health data&#xD;
      register of the region, entitled Vårdanalysdatabasen, (i.e. the Stockholm regional healthcare&#xD;
      data warehouse). As SCREAM remains without loss to follow-up and is likely one of the largest&#xD;
      and most complete healthcare utilization cohorts in Europe, it is an ideally suited database&#xD;
      to answer the research questions laid out here above. The research results obtained by the US&#xD;
      team from analyzing USRDS datasets (NHANES, Optum, CMS) will complement the analyses in&#xD;
      SCREAM and will either be published back-to-back, or within the same publication. Additional&#xD;
      data will be retrieved from international databases (e.g. NHANES, USRDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this model the hazard ratios for three possible transitions (RRT, disease progression,&#xD;
      death) are estimated separately for each CKD stage. The model will further account for the&#xD;
      influence of covariates such as comorbidities and socio-economic factors. In case of&#xD;
      time-varying covariates the last observed value will be utilized in each estimation step. To&#xD;
      support a causal conclusion of sex-related effects, a matched-pairs analysis will be&#xD;
      performed. Pairs of one woman and one man will be formed using nearest neighbour matching&#xD;
      based on potentially confounding covariates and stratified Cox models, treating each pair as&#xD;
      stratum, will be fit to calculate the cause-specific hazard ratios between men and woman for&#xD;
      RRT, disease progression and death. Further, sex differences in disease progression will be&#xD;
      analyzed by comparing the average rates of eGFR decline with time and the hazard rates for&#xD;
      reaching secondary endpoints such as doubling of serum creatinine and a decline in eGFR of&#xD;
      more than 30%. The rates of referral to a nephrologist and the frequencies of CKD related&#xD;
      diagnoses (defined by appropriate CKD-10 codes) will be analyzed and contrasted between&#xD;
      sexes. As an important side-effect, we will attempt to define criteria for the &quot;predialysis&#xD;
      stage&quot; outside of acutely life-threatening conditions such as hyperkalemia and pulmonary&#xD;
      congestion. After the transition of subjects into our defined &quot;predialysis stage&quot;, RRT or&#xD;
      death may be the consequence and the competing risks for either, as a function of time, will&#xD;
      also be analyzed separately between men and women, and subsequently compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Analysis of sex differences in RRT initiation decisions, emphasizing patient perception&#xD;
      and socio-economic differences&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are sex-specific differences in decision-making of doctors and patients with end-stage&#xD;
      renal disease with regards to renal replacement therapy initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative study: Criteria for participation in our study will be (i) a diagnosis of CKD&#xD;
      (eGFR &lt;60 mL/min/1.73 m2, while 50% of all interviews will be conducted among patients with&#xD;
      eGFR &lt;15 mL/min/1.73 m2) and (ii) appropriate language skills. In order to gain a holistic&#xD;
      perspective on the topic and in addition to the interviews with the patients, we will invite&#xD;
      a family member and/or caregiver per patient to participate in an additional interview.&#xD;
      Furthermore, we will interview two health professionals who are clinical experts in CKD from&#xD;
      different professions in each center regarding their perspectives on gender differences in&#xD;
      CKD and access to dialysis. Data collection will be undertaken through semi-structured&#xD;
      interviewing. The first interview will start with an open question regarding the most&#xD;
      important area in daily life that the health condition has affected. Patients will be&#xD;
      encouraged to consider not only present experiences, but also prior experiences from their&#xD;
      life stories. The subsequent interview questions will be based on the World Health&#xD;
      Organization International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health&#xD;
      (http://www.who.int/classifications/icf/en/) and the Canadian Occupational Performance&#xD;
      Measure (http://www.thecopm.ca/) to cover comprehensively all areas of functioning in daily&#xD;
      life. The semi-structure interview guide will be adapted for the family members, care givers&#xD;
      and health professionals. Two interviews will be performed with each participant. The purpose&#xD;
      of the second interview is to give the researcher and the interviewee time to reflect about&#xD;
      what was said in the previous interviews. Interviews will be digitally tape-recorded and&#xD;
      transcribed verbatim. The analysis will be supported by using appropriate software, e.g.&#xD;
      NVivo or AtlasTi. In order to ensure accuracy and rigor of the qualitative analysis, all&#xD;
      interviews will be performed according to a pre-determined standard procedure. 10-15% of the&#xD;
      results of the different steps of the analysis will be reviewed by a senior researcher with&#xD;
      extensive prior experience in the field of qualitative research and one patient research&#xD;
      partner. Triangulation will be achieved by comparison of the results, especially new and&#xD;
      unexpected findings to literature, also in other diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on prior work, we are estimating that a total number of 1000 patient questionnaires&#xD;
      will yield adequate information. This sample size will be modified, depending on the results&#xD;
      of the qualitative study. For the longitudinal follow-up, we assume that we will be able to&#xD;
      reach 50% of the baseline patients who will agree to fill in the follow-up questionnaire as&#xD;
      well. We are planning to include up to 10 representative Nephrology clinics in Austria. Data&#xD;
      of the returned questionnaires will either be entered into an IBM SPSS statistics database or&#xD;
      analyzed in R (www.r-project.org). The analysis of the survey will include descriptive&#xD;
      statistics for all variables which will be depicted according to their distribution, as well&#xD;
      as sub-group analyses for gender/sex-differences with interferential statistical tests&#xD;
      depending again on the distribution of each variable. Graphical illustrations will be&#xD;
      performed, as needed. For multiple testing, Bonferroni corrections will be applied. Based on&#xD;
      the concepts identified in the qualitative analysis, their meaning and their relationship to&#xD;
      each other, we will select the dependent and the independent variables and fit a regression&#xD;
      model to explore the relationship between the concepts/variables of the survey in qualitative&#xD;
      terms&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sex-specific mortality among incident patients undergoing hemodialysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, the expected average follow-up being 4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>&quot;Incident&quot; hemodialysis patients are all those who have entered the Dialysis Registry (they will constitute the study population).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1100</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Diseases</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        as specified in the detailed study description&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Austrian Dialysis Registry Patient or outpatient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria for participation in the survey will be (i) a diagnosis of CKD (eGFR &lt;60&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m2) [50% &lt;15]) and (ii) appropriate language skills to fill in a survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not an Austrian Dialysis Registry Patient or not an outpatient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rainer Oberbauer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of Vienna</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of Vienna</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vienna</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 2, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 8, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Vienna</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Assoc. Prof. Dr. Manfred Hecking, MD PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 28, 2016</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/03/NCT03771703/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

