<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03167450</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999917081</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>17-HG-N081</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03167450</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Examining the Knowledge, Attitudes, and Beliefs of Sickle Cell Disease Patients, Parents of Patients With Sickle Cell Disease, and Providers Towards the Integration of CRISPR in Clinical Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Examining the Knowledge, Attitudes, and Beliefs of Sickle Cell Disease Patients, Parents of Patients With Sickle Cell Disease, and Providers Towards the Integration of CRISPR in Clinical Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sickle cell disease (SCD) is caused by a genetic defect that affects how hemoglobin is made.&#xD;
      Due to this, people with SCD have abnormally-shaped red blood cells, which can result in poor&#xD;
      oxygen transport in the body and increase risk of blood clots. CRISPR Cas9 is a new tool&#xD;
      which allows scientists to snip and edit genes in a way that is faster, cheaper, and more&#xD;
      precise than other gene-editing tools. Recently, research has been done using CRISPR Cas9 to&#xD;
      correct the sickle cell gene in animal models and human cells. Researchers want to understand&#xD;
      the views of those with SCD, parents of people with SCD, and the providers of these patients&#xD;
      regarding use of CRISPR Cas9 in clinical trials and treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To study the attitudes, beliefs, and opinions of those with SCD, parents of those with SCD,&#xD;
      and providers on the use of CRISPR Cas9 gene-editing. An additional purpose of this study is&#xD;
      to assess the utility of an educational tool for improving understanding of CRISPR Cas9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 18 and older who speak English and either have SCD, are a parent of someone with&#xD;
      SCD, or are a physician for people with SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened via phone. Those with SCD will be screened with data from their&#xD;
      SCD genotype.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation lasts about 2 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will fill out three surveys.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will watch a video about CRISPR Cas9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will engage in a focus group session. This will be audiotaped and analyzed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data from the survey questions and focus groups may be used for future research. However,&#xD;
      all personally identifiable information will be removed before data is shared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants data will be identified with a code number instead of their name.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be invited to join future studies of SCD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The CRISPR/Cas9 gene-editing technique is taking the scientific research and healthcare&#xD;
      community by storm with the promise it holds to cure and ease the burden of debilitating&#xD;
      diseases. However, there is limited knowledge regarding the implications of using this type&#xD;
      of tool in human research and medicine. Researchers need to understand the viewpoints of&#xD;
      patients, their families, and their providers, to ensure that the approach taken towards&#xD;
      gene-editing is inclusive and respectful of different interests and concerns. The dialogue,&#xD;
      thus far, has been dominated by scientific researchers, physician scientists, ethicists,&#xD;
      public health and policy experts. It is important to the advancement of the science to study&#xD;
      the patient s perspective about the use of the technology. In addition, parents often play&#xD;
      important roles in the decision-making process; in this regard, understanding the views and&#xD;
      questions of this group of individuals regarding CRISPR/Cas9 human use is essential. We&#xD;
      conduct a qualitative study with a mixed methods component to investigate the knowledge,&#xD;
      attitudes and beliefs of patients living with sickle cell disease (SCD), the parents of&#xD;
      patients with SCD, and the physicians of this patient population regarding the use of&#xD;
      CRISPR/Cas9 technology. The study is designed to measure these three cohorts baseline overall&#xD;
      genetic literacy, CRISPR-specific literacy, and general attitudes and beliefs toward&#xD;
      gene-editing/CRISPR Cas9(in both somatic and germline cells); to evaluate the utility of an&#xD;
      educational tool in improving one s understanding of this innovative technique; and to gauge&#xD;
      how attitudes and beliefs toward gene-editing, specifically CRISPR Cas9, perhaps shift or&#xD;
      remain intact after the educational video, as well as within a focus group space.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 28, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 5, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Family-Based</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Focus group interviews related to attitudes, beliefs, and opinions of those with SCD, parents of those with SCD, and providers on the use of CRISPR Cas9 gene-editing.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the day of inclusion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the utility of an educational tool for improving understanding of CRISPR Cas9.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the day of inclusion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">109</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adults have sickle cell disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Parents</arm_group_label>
    <description>Parents with children/adults who have sickle cell disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physicians</arm_group_label>
    <description>Physicians who have delivered healthcare to individuals living with sickle cell disease for at least a year</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults with sickle cell disease; parent of a child with sickle cell disease or physicians&#xD;
        who have delivered healthcare to individuals living with sickle cell disease for at least a&#xD;
        year&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The inclusion criteria for patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. must have a diagnosis of sickle cell disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. must be 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. must be English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        The inclusion criteria for parents of patients with SCD:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. must have a child with sickle cell disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. must be 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. must be English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Lastly, the inclusion criteria for physicians:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. must care for sickle cell patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. must have cared for sickle cell patients for a minimum of 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. must have been the caregiver for at least five adult patients and/or five pediatric&#xD;
             patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. must be 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. must be English-speaking.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The participants need to be 18 years or older in order to provide informed consent. It is&#xD;
        necessary that participants speak English due to the nature of the study. Because a&#xD;
        moderated conversation will take place, it is essential that all participants and&#xD;
        researchers speak the same language to allow for interactive discourse and comprehension.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vence L Bonham, J.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 30, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CRISPR</keyword>
  <keyword>Gene Editing</keyword>
  <keyword>Qualitative</keyword>
  <keyword>Participation Clinical Trials</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetic Literacy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

