<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03169946</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>kirtika perio 2015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03169946</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chlorhexidine-Metronidazole Combination as an Intracanal Medicament on Periodontal Healing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Chlorhexidine-Metronidazole Combination as an Intracanal Medicament on Periodontal Healing in Concurrent Endodontic Periodontal Lesions With Communication: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Dental Sciences Rohtak</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Dental Sciences Rohtak</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Considering the beneficiary properties of both Chlorhexidine (CHX) and Metronidazole (MTZ)&#xD;
      such as property of substantivity and diffusion of these drugs on the external surfaces&#xD;
      through the anatomical communication channels in between the root canals and periodontium,&#xD;
      may be utilized as an alternative approach for the delivery of drug ( intracanal medicament)&#xD;
      in the deep periodontal pockets in concurrent endodontic- periodontic lesion with&#xD;
      communication lesions. Thus the aim of study is to conduct a prospective randomized&#xD;
      controlled clinical trial to evaluate and compare the effects of CHX-MTZ combination with&#xD;
      chlorhexidine alone as an intracanal medicament on periodontal healing in concurrent&#xD;
      endodontic- periodontic lesion with communication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pulp tissue within the tooth and surrounding periodontium are interrelated to each other&#xD;
      due to structural, functional and microbiological similarities. Cross infection of bacterial&#xD;
      colonies take place in between these sites through dentinal tubules, apical foramen, lateral&#xD;
      and accessory canals.Concurrent endodontic- periodontic lesions are those lesions where both&#xD;
      endodontic and periodontal diseases occurring at same time in relation to single tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endodontic infection present in tooth is responsible for more bone loss, attachment loss and&#xD;
      results in impaired healing of periodontium and vice versa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Complete elimination of microorganisms from infected root canal is very challenging and&#xD;
      complicated task. It has been reported that bacteria may survive within the root canal even&#xD;
      after chemomechanical preparation, these remaining bacteria again multiply within the root&#xD;
      canal. So, intracanal medicament is used as an adjunct to mechanical preparation in&#xD;
      disinfection of root canal system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chlorhexidine (CHX) is widely used as an intracanal medicament because of its high&#xD;
      antimicrobial action, against gram positive and gram negative bacteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antibacterial substantivity of CHX is significantly higher than other medicaments. Various&#xD;
      microbiological studies found the reduction in bacterial adherence, lager zones of microbial&#xD;
      inhibition after application of CHX as an intracanal medicament. Raheja et al described that&#xD;
      2% CHX gel as an intracanal medicament provide substantive antibacterial activity for&#xD;
      sufficiently long periods of time and helps in better healing of endodontic periodontal&#xD;
      lesions without communication in their clinical study. Although, CHX is very effective as an&#xD;
      intracanal medicament, but can't be used as an final irrigant due to it allergic,&#xD;
      hypersensitive reaction, precipitation formation with sodium hypochlorite, EDTA, saline and&#xD;
      ethanol and its inability to dissolve necrotic tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In endodontic and periodontal treatment, antibiotics are valuable adjunctive for management&#xD;
      of bacterial infections. Local application of antibiotics is considered more effective than&#xD;
      systemic administration because of potential risk of adverse effects associated with systemic&#xD;
      application.Metronidazole(MTZ) is nitroimidazole compound having broad antibacterial spectrum&#xD;
      of bactericidal action mainly against anaerobic microorganisms. MTZ is given along with&#xD;
      ciprofloxacin and minocycline as a combination in 3M antibiotic paste in the form of&#xD;
      intracanal medicament. Kargul et al in a clinical study showed that there was no abscess&#xD;
      formation and pathologic mobility when metronidazole is used as an intracanal&#xD;
      medicament.Observations based on in vitro study showed that MTZ-CHX combination was better&#xD;
      than calcium hydroxide as an intracanal medicament against E.faecalis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keeping in mind the above observations and considering the beneficiary properties of both CHX&#xD;
      and MTZ such as property of substantivity and diffusion of these drugs on the external&#xD;
      surfaces through the anatomical communication channels in between the root canals and&#xD;
      periodontium, may be utilized as an alternative approach for the delivery of drug (&#xD;
      intracanal medicament) in the deep periodontal pockets in these lesions. Thus the aim of&#xD;
      study is to conduct a prospective randomized controlled clinical trial to evaluate and&#xD;
      compare the effects of CHX-MTZ combination with chlorhexidine alone as an intracanal&#xD;
      medicament on periodontal healing in concurrent endodontic- periodontic lesion with&#xD;
      communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIAL AND METHOD&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be conducted in Department of Periodontics and Oral Implantology in&#xD;
      collaboration with Department of Conservative Dentistry and Endodontics, Post Graduate&#xD;
      Institute of Dental Sciences (PGIDS), Rohtak. The study protocol is according to the ethical&#xD;
      standards of Helinski declaration 1975 as revised in 2013.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY POPULATION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited from regular outpatient department of the periodontics,&#xD;
      endodontics and oral medicine PGIDS, Rohtak. The study will be conducted as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventional study: This randomized controlled clinical trial will include minimum 36&#xD;
      patients which will be further divided into two groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test Group (n≈ 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment involves endodontic treatment using intracanal medicament (chlorhexidine&#xD;
      metronidazole combination) along with open flap debridement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive Control Group (n≈ 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment involves endodontic treatment using chlorhexidine alone as an intracanal medicament&#xD;
      along with surgical periodontal therapy in form of open flap debridement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomly allocated to control and test groups. The study will be conducted&#xD;
      as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Presurgical therapy: which will be including&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Oral hygiene instructions and patient motivation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Full mouth supragingival and subgingival scaling and root planning with ultrasonic&#xD;
                scaler (EMS Piezon 250, Switzerland), hand scaler and curettes (Hu-Friedy) will be&#xD;
                completed in two sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Root canal therapy will be initiated in both the groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In Test group- Metronidazole-chlorhexidine combination (metronidazole-15mg,&#xD;
                chlorhexidine gluconate-0.5%w/w)as an intracanal medicament and in positive control&#xD;
                group 2% chlorhexidine gel will be placed in root canals. In both groups, total&#xD;
                duration for medicament placement will be of 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Surgical therapy : After 2 weeks of intracanal medicament placement in both test group&#xD;
           and in control group, periodontal surgical procedure in the form of open flap&#xD;
           debridement will be performed in both groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. At the time of periodontal surgical procedure, intracanal medicament will be replaced&#xD;
           with fresh one and will be remained in the root canals further for 2 weeks (medicament&#xD;
           placed for total duration of 4 weeks), after that obturation will be done in both&#xD;
           groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A probing stent will be fabricated for every patient irrespective of the group, relative to&#xD;
      which attachment level, pocket probing depth will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CLINICAL PARAMETERS&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Full mouth indices to be recorded at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Plaque index(PI)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Gingival index(GI)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bleeding on probing(BOP)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Probing Pocket depth(PPD)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Clinical attachment loss(CAL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Site specific indices&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Plaque index(PI)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Gingival index(GI)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Relative Probing Pocket depth(RPPD)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Relative Attachment Loss (RAL)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bleeding on probing (BOP)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Tooth mobility&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Relative Gingival Marginal Level (RGML)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using UNC 15 periodontal probe at 6 sites (mesiobuccal, distobuccal, mesiolingual,&#xD;
      distolingual, and median points at buccal and at lingual aspects) per tooth except 3 rd&#xD;
      molars for PPD, BOP, GML and CAL while 4 surfaces (mesial, distal, median points at buccal&#xD;
      and lingual aspect) will be measured for PI, GI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Customized bite blocks and parallel angle technique will be used to obtain radiographs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical parameters will be recorded at baseline, 2 weeks of endodontic treatment and at 3&#xD;
      months, 6 months of periodontal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PERIODONTAL NON SURGICAL PROCEDURE&#xD;
&#xD;
      This involves supragingival and subgingival scaling and root planing to be performed with&#xD;
      ultrasonic scaler, hand scaler and curette and will be completed in minimum two sessions&#xD;
      along with patient education and motivation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ENDODONTIC PROCEDURE&#xD;
&#xD;
      After achieving local anaesthesia, access opening will be made with the help of round bur.&#xD;
      Then the root canal will be thoroughly debride followed by copious irrigation and&#xD;
      subsequently prepared with the help of endo files. After preparation of the canal,&#xD;
      chlorhexidine- metronidazole combination as an intracanal medicament will be placed in test&#xD;
      group, chlorhexidine medicament in positive control group and access cavity will be sealed&#xD;
      with suitable sealer and medicament left inside for the above mentioned time period.&#xD;
      Obturation will be performed with gutta percha and zinc oxide eugenol based sealer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PERIODONTAL SURGICAL PROCEDURE&#xD;
&#xD;
      After administration of local anaesthesia, buccal and lingual/palatal intracrevicular&#xD;
      incision will be made and mucoperiosteal flaps will be reflected including at least one tooth&#xD;
      ahead and another behind the tooth. Meticulous defect debridement and root planing will be&#xD;
      carried out using area specific curettes and scalers to remove all the granulation tissue.&#xD;
      After instrumentation, the root surfaces will be washed with saline solution in attempt to&#xD;
      remove any remaining detached fragments from the defect and surgical field. After debridement&#xD;
      mucoperiosteal flaps will be repositioned and secured by using 3-0 non absorbable black silk&#xD;
      surgical suture. The surgical area will be protected and covered with periodontal dressing&#xD;
      and post operative instructions will be given.&#xD;
&#xD;
      POST OPERATIVE CARE&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Suitable antibiotics and analgesics will be prescribed for 5 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Periodontal dressing and sutures will be removed after 1 week.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Instructions will be given for gentle brushing with soft brush and reinstructed for&#xD;
           proper oral hygiene postoperatively and will be examined weekly for up to 1 month after&#xD;
           surgery and again at 3 and 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 14, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PPD</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and half months</time_frame>
    <description>Probing pocket depth</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CAL</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and half months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical attachment loss</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodontal and Endodontic Lesion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Endodontic treatment using chlorhexidine metronidazole combination as an intracanal medicament along with open flap debridement (RCT with CHX-MTZ,OFD).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Positive Control Group :</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Endodontic treatment using chlorhexidine as an intracanal medicament along with surgical periodontal therapy in form of open flap debridement(RCT with CHX,OFD).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RCT with CHX-MTZ,OFD</intervention_name>
    <description>Endodontic treatment using chlorhexidine metronidazole combination as an intracanal medicament along with open flap debridement .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RCT with CHX,OFD</intervention_name>
    <description>Endodontic treatment using chlorhexidine as an intracanal medicament along with surgical periodontal therapy in form of open flap debridement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Positive Control Group :</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of age between 18-55 years with generalized chronic periodontitis will be&#xD;
             enrolled, having at least one tooth with concurrent endodontic periodontal lesion with&#xD;
             communication including following features:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a clinical and radiographic diagnosis of concurrent endodontic periodontal lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Wide base pocket, deep probing pocket depth&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non vital tooth on the basis of pulp sensibility tests along with periapical&#xD;
                  radiolucency&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiographic alveolar bone (marginal bone) destruction with apical communication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of generalized chronic periodontitis will be selected on the basis of&#xD;
             Armitage classification of periodontal diseases and conditions [≥30% sites involved&#xD;
             with clinical attachment level (CAL) 1-2mm (mild) or 3-4mm (moderate) or ≥5mm&#xD;
             (severe)]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should have more than 20 teeth in their oral cavity excluding third molars.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic illness known to affect the periodontium or outcome of periodontal therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient taking medications such as corticosteroids, calcium channel blockers and&#xD;
             anticoagulant therapy, which are known to interfere periodontal wound healing or&#xD;
             patient on long term NSAID therapy or bisphosphonates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients allergic to medication (chlorhexidine, local anaesthetic, antibiotics,&#xD;
             NSAID).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers (current and past) and tobacco chewers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 3 mobile teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unrestorable tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Root resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fractured/perforated roots.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Developing permanent tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abutments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously root canal filled tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with aggressive periodontitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of periodontal treatment within 6 months prior to study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 30, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 25, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 25, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 30, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

