<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02624466</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UGent_UToPaed_1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02624466</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Uraemic Toxins in Chronic Kidney Disease Paediatric Patients: Observational Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>UToPaed_1</acronym>
  <official_title>Part 1 of: 'Conceptualisation and Validation of a Paradigm Based on Uraemic Toxins for Management of Chronic Kidney Disease in Paediatric Patients (UToPaed)'</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Ghent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Ghent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Agentschap voor Innovatie door Wetenschap en Technologie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Ghent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Children with chronic kidney disease (CKD) suffer from one of the most devastating diseases&#xD;
      in childhood resulting in a lifelong need for health care, and a 3 times decreased life&#xD;
      expectancy. In addition, they have important comorbidities that negatively impact on their&#xD;
      quality of life and integration in society, jeopardizing their future even after a potential&#xD;
      transplantation. Retention of uraemic toxins is accepted to play a major role in the&#xD;
      pathogenesis of the comorbid conditions, but studies in children are lacking. Furthermore,&#xD;
      there are currently no good tools to evaluate severity and monitor adequacy of treatment,&#xD;
      resulting in suboptimal management.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall scientific objective of this four years UToPaed IWT-TBM project is to provide the&#xD;
      clinician with new diagnostic and therapeutic tools for the management of children with CKD,&#xD;
      based on the improved understanding of uraemic toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this first part of UToPaed, the investigators will associate concentrations of a wide&#xD;
      variety of uraemic toxins with different comorbidities in CKD children, i.e. growth,&#xD;
      protein-energy wasting, quality of life, cardiovascular risk factors, circadian rhythm, sleep&#xD;
      quality, and psychosocial and neurocognitive functioning (i.e. cross-sectional and&#xD;
      longitudinal). The toxins of which concentrations are best correlated with comorbidities&#xD;
      during the progress of CKD and eventually have representative kinetics (UToPaed - part 2:&#xD;
      Kinetic analysis) will be selected as markers. These markers will be, together with the&#xD;
      comorbidities, further tracked after interventions, i.e. starting on dialysis,&#xD;
      transplantation, changes in dialysis strategy (UToPaed - part 3 - intervention study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the validated kinetic models (UToPaed - part 2 and 3), an open access user-friendly&#xD;
      prediction simulator (PAEDSIM) based on patient characteristics and marker concentrations&#xD;
      will be developed to optimise and individualise the dialysis therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By providing clinicians with more advanced and appropriate tools to improve management of all&#xD;
      children with CKD, i.e. better assessment of the degree of renal dysfunction, better&#xD;
      determination of the ideal time to start renal replacement therapy, and more accurate&#xD;
      monitoring of dialysis adequacy, the investigators aim to improve neurocognitive and&#xD;
      psychosocial functioning (short term), growth, maturation into puberty, and social&#xD;
      integration (median term) and survival (long term).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective observational multicenter study in children (≤ 18 years) with chronic&#xD;
      kidney disease (CKD) stage 2 to 5D with or without renal replacement therapy. In this study,&#xD;
      60 children with CKD stage 2 - 5 (without renal replacement therapy)(GROUP 1), 30 children&#xD;
      with CKD stage 5D treated with peritoneal dialysis (GROUP 2) and 30 children with CKD stage&#xD;
      5D treated with haemodialysis (GROUP 3) will be followed for a total duration of 24 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study participants are evaluated on their standard visit at the outpatient clinic every 3&#xD;
      months. At this visit, a blood sample for uraemic toxin concentration is withdrawn and&#xD;
      several co-morbidities (growth, protein-energy wasting, cardiovascular disease, quality of&#xD;
      life, psychosocial functioning, sleep, attention and executive functions) are assessed.&#xD;
      Anthropometric parameters, dietary assessment, stool evaluation, nail evaluation, office and&#xD;
      24 hours ambulatory blood pressure monitoring, echocardiography and questionnaires are used&#xD;
      to map out the several co-morbidities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood analyses are performed to get the concentrations of a wide variety of uraemic toxins:&#xD;
      i.e. small water soluble solutes, middle molecules and protein-bound solutes. All blood&#xD;
      analyses within this project are performed in the Ghent University Hospital: i.e. urea,&#xD;
      creatinine, calcium, and phosphorus are determined in the routine laboratory of the Ghent&#xD;
      University Hospital using standard methods, while all other uraemic toxins are determined in&#xD;
      the laboratory of the Nephrology Section using ELISA and (in-house developed) HPLC/UPLC&#xD;
      techniques. For the protein-bound solutes two runs are needed to distinguish between total&#xD;
      and free fractions of the protein-bound solutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following actions are performed prior to enrolment:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Review medical history to determine eligibility based on inclusion/exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain document consent from participant (&gt;12 years) and parent/representative on study&#xD;
           consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Schedule study visits for individuals who are eligible and available for the duration of&#xD;
           the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Provide potential participants with instructions needed to prepare for first study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Verify inclusion/exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain and record general patient information: age, sex, medical history, underlying&#xD;
           kidney disease, medication history, current medication chart, dialysis settings and&#xD;
           demographic information&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of dietary assessment by a skilled dietician by means of 3-day diet diary or&#xD;
           three 24-hours recall&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform clinical assessment including anthropometric parameters and office blood&#xD;
           pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform a body composition monitoring (BCM) in children &gt; 10 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of blood sample (all groups; EDTA immediately on ice; serum 15-30 minutes&#xD;
           rest and subsequently on ice), 24 hours urine sample (group 2; 24 hours prior to visit),&#xD;
           intradialytic urine sample (group 3) and 24 hours dialysate collection (group 2; 24&#xD;
           hours prior to visit) for determination of uraemic toxin concentration&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intermediate visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain general patient information: medication chart, changes in medical situation and&#xD;
           dialysis settings&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of dietary intake by a skilled dietician by means of 3-day diet diary or&#xD;
           three 24-hours recall every 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform clinical assessment including anthropometric parameters and office blood&#xD;
           pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform BCM 3-monthly in children &gt; 10 kg with renal replacement therapy (group 2 and 3)&#xD;
           and 1-yearly in children &gt; 10 kg without renal replacement therapy (group 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of blood sample (group 1 to 3; EDTA immediately on ice; serum 15-30 minutes&#xD;
           rest and subsequently on ice), 24 hours urine sample (group 2 and 3; 24 hours prior to&#xD;
           visit) and 24 hours dialysate collection (group 2; 24 hours prior to visit) every 3&#xD;
           months for determination of uraemic toxin concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of stool sample for determination of microbiota and metabolome 1-yearly (only&#xD;
           participants of Ghent University Hospital)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of nails for determination of carbamylation process every 6 months (only&#xD;
           participants of Ghent University Hospital)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform echocardiography by a skilled paediatric cardiologist every year (visit 2, 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Withdraw questionnaires from the parent and/or child assessing quality of life,&#xD;
           attention, sleep, executive function and parental functioning every 6 months (visit 2,&#xD;
           4, 6, 8)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform 24 hours ambulatory blood pressure measurement in children &gt; 6 years once a year&#xD;
           (visit 2, 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Final Study Visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obtain general patient information: medication chart, changes in medical situation and&#xD;
           dialysis settings (detailed overview appendix 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of dietary assessment by a skilled dietician by means of 3-day diet diary or&#xD;
           three 24-hours recall&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform clinical assessment including anthropometric parameters and office blood&#xD;
           pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform a body composition monitoring (BCM) in children &gt; 10 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of blood sample (group 1 to 3; EDTA immediately on ice; serum 15-30 minutes&#xD;
           rest and subsequently on ice), 24 hours urine sample (group 2 and 3; 24 hours prior to&#xD;
           visit) and 24 hours dialysate collection (group 2; 24 hours prior to visit) for&#xD;
           determination of uraemic toxin concentration&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform echocardiography by a skilled paediatric cardiologist&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Perform 24 hours ambulatory blood pressure measurement in children &gt; 6 years&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following socio-demographic questionnaires are asked to be completed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Assessment of quality of life (QoL)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PedsQL for children (5-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PedsQL for children, disease specific (8-12 years, 13-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Parent Proxy Report by parents (2-4 years, 5-7 years, 8-12 years, 13-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Parent Proxy Report, disease specific by parents (8-12 years, 13-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Assessment of psychological wellbeing&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  YSR for children (&gt; 11 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CBCL/TRF by parent/teachers (1,5-5 years, 6-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CBSK for children (8-12 years), CBSA for children (13-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Assessment of attention &amp; executive functions&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  DBDRS by parents, teachers (6-16 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  BRIEF by parents/teachers (5-18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Assessment of sleep&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  ESS questionnaire by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CSHQ questionnaire by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Assessment of family functioning&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PIP by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HADS by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PSI-S by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PPS by parents&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CVS by parents&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Detect whether uraemic toxin concentrations are correlated with the different measured co-morbidities</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CKD - no dialysis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Follow-up of CKD progress by frequent assessment of: concentration of uraemic toxins in blood, anthropometry, cardio-vascular parameters, body composition monitoring, dietary assessment, psycho-social questionnaires, sleep disorders, stool, nails.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients on PD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Follow-up of CKD progress by frequent assessment of: concentration of uraemic toxins in blood, urine and PD fluid, anthropometry, cardio-vascular parameters, body composition monitoring, dietary assessment, psycho-social questionnaires, sleep disorders, stool, nails.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients on HD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Follow-up of CKD progress by frequent assessment of: concentration of uraemic toxins in blood, urine and spent dialysate, anthropometry, cardio-vascular parameters, body composition monitoring, dietary assessment, psycho-social questionnaires, sleep disorders, stool, nails.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CKD progress</intervention_name>
    <description>CKD progress</description>
    <arm_group_label>CKD - no dialysis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients on HD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients on PD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        CKD patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Subject Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide signed and dated informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to comply with all study procedures and be available for the duration of the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female, aged ≤ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with chronic kidney disease stage 2 to 5D, according to the K/DOQI&#xD;
             guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partially exclusion of children and/or parents who cannot fill in the questionnaires&#xD;
             due to language barriers. They will be excluded only from the questionnaires; the&#xD;
             other comorbidities will be followed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partially exclusion of children who cannot fill in the questionnaires due to mental&#xD;
             retardation. They will be excluded only from the questionnaires; the other&#xD;
             comorbidities will be followed.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sunny Eloot, Prof Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital - Nephrology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Johan Vande Walle, Prof Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital - Paediatric Nephrology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ann Raes, Prof Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital - Paediatric Nephrology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wim Van Biesen, Prof Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital - Nephrology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Evelien Snauwaert</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital - Paediatric Nephrology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ghent University Hospital - Nephrology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 8, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 12, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 12, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital, Ghent</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nefrologie</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Nephrology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
  <keyword>Nephrology</keyword>
  <keyword>Dialysis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

