<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02626156</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00043450</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02626156</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cooling Leg and Foot Ulcer Skin Post Healing to Prevent Ulcer Recurrence</brief_title>
  <acronym>MUSTCOOL</acronym>
  <official_title>Monitoring and Managing Newly Healed Chronic Leg and Foot Ulcer Skin Temperature: A Cooling Intervention (MUSTCOOL) to Prevent Ulcer Recurrence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of South Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of South Carolina</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to test MUSTCOOL, a home-based self-monitoring and self-management&#xD;
      ulcer prevention intervention for patients with newly healed chronic venous leg and diabetic&#xD;
      foot ulcers. Almost 90% of ulcers recur within 3 months of healing. During the six-month&#xD;
      randomized clinic trial, skin temperature will be monitored daily, a maintenance dose of&#xD;
      cooling gel pack or placebo will be applied three times weekly to the affected skin, and a&#xD;
      bolus dose of cooling will be applied for 5 consecutive days if skin temperature becomes&#xD;
      elevated. Outcomes on the incidence of leg ulcer recurrence, pain, physical activity and&#xD;
      quality of life will be measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this randomized control trial is to test a patient directed self-monitoring and&#xD;
      self-management intervention aimed at preventing the recurrence of chronic venous leg and&#xD;
      diabetic foot ulcers using skin temperature and cryotherapy (cooling). This MUSTCOOL study is&#xD;
      a novel ulcer prevention strategy for patients at highest risk for developing chronic ulcers;&#xD;
      those with a previous history. The aims are to compare a cooling treatment to a placebo to&#xD;
      determine the outcomes on ulcer recurrence, pain, physical activity and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individuals with newly healed chronic ulcers will be invited to participate in MUSTCOOL's two&#xD;
      component intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. self monitoring skin temperature over targeted &quot;hot spots&quot; daily with an infrared&#xD;
           thermometer; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. maintenance cooling with a cooling pack (or placebo pack) placed over the &quot;hot spot&quot;&#xD;
           three times each week for 30 minutes. If the temperature of the &quot;hot spot&quot; becomes&#xD;
           elevated 2°F above baseline (average of 30 days of daily temperature readings) for 2&#xD;
           days in a row, a bolus regimen of 5 consecutive daily, 30 minute applications of the&#xD;
           cooling or placebo pack will be implemented. The safety and side effects will be&#xD;
           monitored, however, there have been no reported adverse events reported in our previous&#xD;
           cryotherapy studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study was designed as a chronic ulcer prevention intervention that targets the&#xD;
      remodeling phase, the final repair process of healing after chronic ulcer closure. The skin&#xD;
      environment is particularly vulnerable to ulcer recurrence due to a persistent aberrant&#xD;
      inflammatory state. The previous research conducted by the study team has demonstrated that&#xD;
      cooling this skin reduces the abnormal metabolic activity, protecting it against ulcer&#xD;
      recurrence. Recent advancements in infrared technology allow us to take images of the affect&#xD;
      skin to identify the area that has the highest temperature or vulnerable &quot;hot spot&quot;. These&#xD;
      &quot;hot spots&quot; will be self monitored by patients with newly healed ulcers in the home with an&#xD;
      infrared thermometer that date and time stamps each reading. The study's outcomes on physical&#xD;
      activity will be evaluated with an accelerometer. It is hypothesized that by improving the&#xD;
      skin environment and reducing pain, patients will more likely be physically active and have&#xD;
      better quality of life, all measurable goals for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This prevention strategy will be evaluated over six months in 180 patients, 90 of whom will&#xD;
      be randomized to receive the cooling pack and 90 the placebo. The goal is to test this&#xD;
      non-pharmacological, non-invasive clinical intervention as a tailored self-management&#xD;
      strategy to prevent chronic ulcer recurrence. It will also determine alleviation of symptoms&#xD;
      such as pain, and the debilitating effects on physical activity and quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Ulcer Recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Number of recurrent ulcers that develop during the 6 month study period for in participants for 4 groups of patients with previously healed venous leg ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack and cooling cotton pack and those with previously healed diabetic foot ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack or cooling cotton pack.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Pain (Worst Pain, Least Pain, Pain Now)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Pain was measured with a visual analog scale and reported numerically (0 to 10 with 10 being the most severe pain) at baseline and at 6 months end of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in Step Counts</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in step counts reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Mean Scores on Quality of Life Measured With the VEINES QOL/Sym Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Venous Insufficiency Epidemiological and Economic Study-Quality of life/Symptoms (VEINES QOL/Sym) Questionnaire was used to evaluate quality of life. A sum score is provided as an overall quality of life score for both the QOL and Sym portions of the questionnaire. This instrument was used only for the VLU groups because it is a disease-specific measure. Of the 26 items in the questionnaire, 25 items are combined to create a summary score (VEINES-QOL). One item which asks about the time of day the leg problem is most intense, question 2, provides only descriptive information and is not scored. A subset (symptoms score) of ten of these items, questions 1a to 1i and 7, is used to create a symptom score (VEINES-Sym). For both the VEINES-QOL and VEINES-Sym scores, high values indicate better outcomes. VEINES-QOL scores can be compared only to other members of the same sample. Each set of VEINES-QOL scores will have a mean T-score = 50.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Severity and Intensity Pain Scores Measured With the Brief Pain Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) scale is reported as an average score. BPI rapidly assesses the severity of pain and its impact on functioning for intensity and Pain Intensity and Pain Interference. Pain Intensity is measured in four categories: worst, least, on average, and currently, while Pain Interference is measured in 7 categories: mood, work, general activity, walking, relationships, enjoyment of life, and sleep. The patient rates each of these on a scale from 0-10, 10 being excruciating pain intensity and a complete interference in their life. Subscores are determined by averaging over the 4 intensity items for the severity subscore and over the 7 interference items for the interference subscore; possible total scores range from 0 to 10. Higher scores indicate worse intensity and severity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in METS Minutes Engaging in Physical Activity Measured With The International Physical Activity Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in metabolic equivalent of task (METS) min per week for physical activity per The International Physical Activity Questionnaire reported for 4 groups from baseline to 6 months end of study. Scoring HIGH indicate physical activity levels equate to ~1hour of activity per day or more at least moderate intensity level or engage in vigorous intensity activity on at least 3 days achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 1500 MET min a week or 7 or more days of any combination of walking, moderate intensity or vigorous intensity activities achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 3000 MET min a week. MODERATE suggests engagement equivalent to 30 min of at least moderate intensity activity on most days; engage in 3 or more days of vigorous intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 min per day or 5 or more days of moderate intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 minutes per day. LOW level means that neither MODERATE or HIGH levels are met.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time Spent in Minutes Engaging in Physical Activities</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Mean time spent in minutes engaging in physical activities, reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant Adherence to the Study Protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>Daily measures starting at baseline for temperature and every other day cooling application during the 6-month study period.</time_frame>
    <description>Using study data logs, appropriate use of the thermometer and cooling pack was measured by the number of participants who adhered to the protocol for taking the temperature of the skin over the healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer. Adherence was defined as: the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to taking their temperatures with the infrared thermometer each morning and the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to performing the intervention every other day = 3 times times per week during the 6-month study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Indicating 'Yes' or 'Easy' on Study Instructions, Thermometer Use, Completing Logs, Performing Treatment, Helpfulness</measure>
    <time_frame>Survey conducted at end of the 6-month study period.</time_frame>
    <description>Patients satisfaction was measured by study personnel a during end of study phone survey with the following questions asked as follows (Yes/No): Were study instructions adequate, was thermometer easy to use, found cooling helpful, would cool skin area if it was proven that cooling prevented reulceration; (Easy/Not Easy): completing logs, performing the cooling treatment. Data are for (Yes/No) as number of participants who reported &quot;yes&quot; or if (Easy/Not Easy) the number of participants who reported &quot;easy.&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge Questionnaire of Study Instructions</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline after participant enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Participants were administered a 12-item (yes/no) questionnaire (test) during instruction at the start of the study, provided by the research personnel to determine comprehension of the protocol and to reinforce study procedures. Score of 12 or 100% was given for all items scoring correctly (1 point per item). Any items for which &quot;no&quot; was answered, remediation was conducted by study personnel at the time the questionnaire was conducted. Means scores are reported per VLU and DFU cooling pack intervention and VLU and DFU cotton cooling pack control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Venous Hypertension Ulcers</condition>
  <condition>Venous Stasis Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Venous Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Venous Insufficiency</condition>
  <condition>Leg Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Foot Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Varicose Ulcer</condition>
  <condition>Diabetic Foot</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cooling gel pack</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A cooling pack will be applied to affected leg or foot skin where an ulcer has recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients will self monitor skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and will cool the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature becomes elevated 2°F above the baseline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cooling cotton pack</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A cooling cotton pack will be applied to affected leg or foot skin where an ulcer has recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients will self monitor skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and will cool the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature becomes elevated 2°F above the baseline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cooling gel pack</intervention_name>
    <description>Individuals will self monitor skin temperature of skin over a recently health venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack will be applied to skin of recently healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increases and stays elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual will cool the skin 5 consecutive days and will continue to monitor skin temperature.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cooling gel pack</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cooling cotton pack</intervention_name>
    <description>Individuals will self monitor skin temperature of skin over a recently health venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack will be applied to skin of recently healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increases and stays elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual will cool the skin 5 consecutive days and will continue to monitor skin temperature.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cooling cotton pack</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newly healed leg or diabetic foot ulcer within past 7 - 14 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ankle brachial index 0.8- 1.3mmHg (rule out absence of arterial disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to wear compression stockings and appropriate footwear&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Working freezer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Open leg or foot ulcers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment: unable to recall 2 or more words or draw clock Mini-Cog™ for&#xD;
             cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic inflammatory or vascular conditions where blood flow of skin may be impaired&#xD;
             such as Lupus erythematosus, Raynaud's, scleroderma, end stage renal disease, chronic&#xD;
             regional pain syndrome, multiple sclerosis, hypersensitivity to cold, on chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to preform required protocol activities without assistance (return&#xD;
             demonstration to study staff)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Moby Madisetti, MS</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29412</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spartanburg Regional Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Spartanburg</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29303</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 1, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 10, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>post healed venous leg ulcer</keyword>
  <keyword>posted healed diabetic foot ulcer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venous Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leg Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methyl salicylate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 23, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/56/NCT02626156/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 28, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/56/NCT02626156/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Date recruitment period was January 2017 through December 2019 at wound clinics in the South and North Carolina areas including Charleston SC, Spartanburg SC and Greenville NC via clinicians practicing in those clinics and flyers were distributed in and around community settings such as senior centers, prior to approval from MUSC IRB.</recruitment_details>
      <pre_assignment_details>246 individuals approached, 211 prescreened eligible, 71 ineligible due to type of wound, could not make regular appointments for study visits, not interested in study, lost contact or developed infection or ulcer changed in size (healed or enlarged indicating deterioration prior to eligibility screening visit); 140 were enrolled - 58 in the DFU group (29 intervention and 29 control)and 82 in VLU group (42 intervention and 40 control)</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P3">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P4">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Baseline (Visit 1 to Visit 2)</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="29"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="29"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="42"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="40"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="23"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="22"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="37"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="35"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="6"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="7"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="5"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="5"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
        <period>
          <title>Study Visit 3</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="23"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="22"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="37"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="35"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="15"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="17"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="33"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="33"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="8"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="5"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="4"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
        <period>
          <title>Study Visit 4</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="15"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="17"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="33"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="33"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="12"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="15"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="24"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="28"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="3"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
                <participants group_id="P3" count="9"/>
                <participants group_id="P4" count="5"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B4">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B5">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="42"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="40"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="29"/>
            <count group_id="B4" value="29"/>
            <count group_id="B5" value="140"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="64.2" spread="14.7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="64.8" spread="12.2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="57.8" spread="11.7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="61.3" spread="11.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="62.4" spread="12.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="23"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="17"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="54"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="19"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="23"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="24"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="20"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="86"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="7"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="39"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="40"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="28"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="133"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="20"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="14"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="8"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="47"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="20"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="24"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="91"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="42"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="40"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="29"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B4" value="29"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B5" value="140"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants With Ulcer Recurrence</title>
        <description>Number of recurrent ulcers that develop during the 6 month study period for in participants for 4 groups of patients with previously healed venous leg ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack and cooling cotton pack and those with previously healed diabetic foot ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack or cooling cotton pack.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized to either the placebo control group (n=57; 34 VLU, 23 DFU) or the intervention (n=60; 35 VLU, 25 DFU), with a final completion of 117 individuals (84%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Cooling Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants With Ulcer Recurrence</title>
          <description>Number of recurrent ulcers that develop during the 6 month study period for in participants for 4 groups of patients with previously healed venous leg ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack and cooling cotton pack and those with previously healed diabetic foot ulcers receiving the cooling gel pack or cooling cotton pack.</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized to either the placebo control group (n=57; 34 VLU, 23 DFU) or the intervention (n=60; 35 VLU, 25 DFU), with a final completion of 117 individuals (84%)</population>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="35"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="34"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="25"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="23"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="5"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
              <group_id>O3</group_id>
              <group_id>O4</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Superiority</non_inferiority_type>
            <p_value>0.091</p_value>
            <method>Chi-squared</method>
            <param_type>Risk Difference (RD)</param_type>
            <param_value>0.13</param_value>
            <dispersion_type>Standard Error of the Mean</dispersion_type>
            <dispersion_value>0.07</dispersion_value>
            <ci_percent>95</ci_percent>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
            <ci_lower_limit>-0.02</ci_lower_limit>
            <ci_upper_limit>0.3</ci_upper_limit>
            <estimate_desc>Asymptotic standard error was used</estimate_desc>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Change in Pain (Worst Pain, Least Pain, Pain Now)</title>
        <description>Pain was measured with a visual analog scale and reported numerically (0 to 10 with 10 being the most severe pain) at baseline and at 6 months end of study</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 83 individuals (59%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Change in Pain (Worst Pain, Least Pain, Pain Now)</title>
          <description>Pain was measured with a visual analog scale and reported numerically (0 to 10 with 10 being the most severe pain) at baseline and at 6 months end of study</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 83 individuals (59%)</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="26"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="29"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="12"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="16"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Worst pain</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0.85" lower_limit="-0.1" upper_limit="1.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0.4" lower_limit="-0.6" upper_limit="1.3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="0" lower_limit="-1.6" upper_limit="1.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="-1.0" lower_limit="-2.3" upper_limit="0.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Least pain</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0.3" lower_limit="-0.2" upper_limit="0.8"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0" lower_limit="-0.6" upper_limit="0.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="-0.1" lower_limit="-0.8" upper_limit="0.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="0" lower_limit="0" upper_limit="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Pain now</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0.4" lower_limit="-0.06" upper_limit="0.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0.14" lower_limit="-0.3" upper_limit="0.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="0.1" lower_limit="-0.1" upper_limit="0.3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="-0.1" lower_limit="-0.4" upper_limit="0.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Differences in Step Counts</title>
        <description>Differences in step counts reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 75 individuals (56%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Cooling Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Differences in Step Counts</title>
          <description>Differences in step counts reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 75 individuals (56%)</population>
          <units>Steps</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="23"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="23"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="15"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="14"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="17295" lower_limit="9259" upper_limit="25332"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="14234" lower_limit="6874" upper_limit="21593"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="13232" lower_limit="2909" upper_limit="23555"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="15479" lower_limit="5614" upper_limit="25343"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Change in Mean Scores on Quality of Life Measured With the VEINES QOL/Sym Questionnaire</title>
        <description>The Venous Insufficiency Epidemiological and Economic Study-Quality of life/Symptoms (VEINES QOL/Sym) Questionnaire was used to evaluate quality of life. A sum score is provided as an overall quality of life score for both the QOL and Sym portions of the questionnaire. This instrument was used only for the VLU groups because it is a disease-specific measure. Of the 26 items in the questionnaire, 25 items are combined to create a summary score (VEINES-QOL). One item which asks about the time of day the leg problem is most intense, question 2, provides only descriptive information and is not scored. A subset (symptoms score) of ten of these items, questions 1a to 1i and 7, is used to create a symptom score (VEINES-Sym). For both the VEINES-QOL and VEINES-Sym scores, high values indicate better outcomes. VEINES-QOL scores can be compared only to other members of the same sample. Each set of VEINES-QOL scores will have a mean T-score = 50.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>Due to inadvertent scoring errors, there were data for 8 individuals.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg or foot skin where an ulcer has recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily 3 times per week to detect elevation and will cool the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature becomes elevated 2°F above the baseline.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg or foot skin where an ulcer has recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and will cool the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature becomes elevated 2°F above the baseline.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Change in Mean Scores on Quality of Life Measured With the VEINES QOL/Sym Questionnaire</title>
          <description>The Venous Insufficiency Epidemiological and Economic Study-Quality of life/Symptoms (VEINES QOL/Sym) Questionnaire was used to evaluate quality of life. A sum score is provided as an overall quality of life score for both the QOL and Sym portions of the questionnaire. This instrument was used only for the VLU groups because it is a disease-specific measure. Of the 26 items in the questionnaire, 25 items are combined to create a summary score (VEINES-QOL). One item which asks about the time of day the leg problem is most intense, question 2, provides only descriptive information and is not scored. A subset (symptoms score) of ten of these items, questions 1a to 1i and 7, is used to create a symptom score (VEINES-Sym). For both the VEINES-QOL and VEINES-Sym scores, high values indicate better outcomes. VEINES-QOL scores can be compared only to other members of the same sample. Each set of VEINES-QOL scores will have a mean T-score = 50.</description>
          <population>Due to inadvertent scoring errors, there were data for 8 individuals.</population>
          <units>t-scores</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="6"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="2"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Quality of life</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="13.8" lower_limit="4.0" upper_limit="23.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="-4.8" lower_limit="-121.6" upper_limit="111.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Symptoms</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="24.2" lower_limit="13.8" upper_limit="34.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="-4.3" lower_limit="-7.4" upper_limit="-1.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Changes in Severity and Intensity Pain Scores Measured With the Brief Pain Inventory</title>
        <description>The Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) scale is reported as an average score. BPI rapidly assesses the severity of pain and its impact on functioning for intensity and Pain Intensity and Pain Interference. Pain Intensity is measured in four categories: worst, least, on average, and currently, while Pain Interference is measured in 7 categories: mood, work, general activity, walking, relationships, enjoyment of life, and sleep. The patient rates each of these on a scale from 0-10, 10 being excruciating pain intensity and a complete interference in their life. Subscores are determined by averaging over the 4 intensity items for the severity subscore and over the 7 interference items for the interference subscore; possible total scores range from 0 to 10. Higher scores indicate worse intensity and severity.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 83 individuals (59%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Cooling Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Changes in Severity and Intensity Pain Scores Measured With the Brief Pain Inventory</title>
          <description>The Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) scale is reported as an average score. BPI rapidly assesses the severity of pain and its impact on functioning for intensity and Pain Intensity and Pain Interference. Pain Intensity is measured in four categories: worst, least, on average, and currently, while Pain Interference is measured in 7 categories: mood, work, general activity, walking, relationships, enjoyment of life, and sleep. The patient rates each of these on a scale from 0-10, 10 being excruciating pain intensity and a complete interference in their life. Subscores are determined by averaging over the 4 intensity items for the severity subscore and over the 7 interference items for the interference subscore; possible total scores range from 0 to 10. Higher scores indicate worse intensity and severity.</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 83 individuals (59%)</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="26"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="29"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="12"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="16"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Severity</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="-0.5" lower_limit="-1.0" upper_limit="0.01"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="-0.2" lower_limit="-0.8" upper_limit="0.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="0" lower_limit="-0.5" upper_limit="0.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="0.4" lower_limit="-0.1" upper_limit="0.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Interference</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="-0.4" lower_limit="-0.8" upper_limit="0.08"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="-0.5" lower_limit="-1.1" upper_limit="0.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="-0.1" lower_limit="-0.2" upper_limit="0.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="0.1" lower_limit="-0.2" upper_limit="0.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Change in METS Minutes Engaging in Physical Activity Measured With The International Physical Activity Questionnaire</title>
        <description>Change in metabolic equivalent of task (METS) min per week for physical activity per The International Physical Activity Questionnaire reported for 4 groups from baseline to 6 months end of study. Scoring HIGH indicate physical activity levels equate to ~1hour of activity per day or more at least moderate intensity level or engage in vigorous intensity activity on at least 3 days achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 1500 MET min a week or 7 or more days of any combination of walking, moderate intensity or vigorous intensity activities achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 3000 MET min a week. MODERATE suggests engagement equivalent to 30 min of at least moderate intensity activity on most days; engage in 3 or more days of vigorous intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 min per day or 5 or more days of moderate intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 minutes per day. LOW level means that neither MODERATE or HIGH levels are met.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 82 individuals (59%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Change in METS Minutes Engaging in Physical Activity Measured With The International Physical Activity Questionnaire</title>
          <description>Change in metabolic equivalent of task (METS) min per week for physical activity per The International Physical Activity Questionnaire reported for 4 groups from baseline to 6 months end of study. Scoring HIGH indicate physical activity levels equate to ~1hour of activity per day or more at least moderate intensity level or engage in vigorous intensity activity on at least 3 days achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 1500 MET min a week or 7 or more days of any combination of walking, moderate intensity or vigorous intensity activities achieving a minimum total physical activity of at least 3000 MET min a week. MODERATE suggests engagement equivalent to 30 min of at least moderate intensity activity on most days; engage in 3 or more days of vigorous intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 min per day or 5 or more days of moderate intensity activity and/or walking of at least 30 minutes per day. LOW level means that neither MODERATE or HIGH levels are met.</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 82 individuals (59%)</population>
          <units>minutes</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="25"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="29"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="12"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="16"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="73" lower_limit="-623" upper_limit="767"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="799" lower_limit="-507" upper_limit="2104"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="1921" lower_limit="1151" upper_limit="4993"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="225" lower_limit="-255" upper_limit="705"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Time Spent in Minutes Engaging in Physical Activities</title>
        <description>Mean time spent in minutes engaging in physical activities, reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
        <time_frame>Through study completion at 6 months from baseline</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 75 individuals (56%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Cooling Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Time Spent in Minutes Engaging in Physical Activities</title>
          <description>Mean time spent in minutes engaging in physical activities, reported via accelerometer data, from baseline to post treatment at 6 months end of intervention for the 4 groups.</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 75 individuals (56%)</population>
          <units>Minutes</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="23"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="23"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="15"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="14"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="1420" lower_limit="-2448" upper_limit="5288"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="2523" lower_limit="-765" upper_limit="5811"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="135" lower_limit="28" upper_limit="242"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="157" lower_limit="55" upper_limit="260"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Participant Adherence to the Study Protocol</title>
        <description>Using study data logs, appropriate use of the thermometer and cooling pack was measured by the number of participants who adhered to the protocol for taking the temperature of the skin over the healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer. Adherence was defined as: the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to taking their temperatures with the infrared thermometer each morning and the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to performing the intervention every other day = 3 times times per week during the 6-month study period.</description>
        <time_frame>Daily measures starting at baseline for temperature and every other day cooling application during the 6-month study period.</time_frame>
        <population>This outcome measured ALL participants in one group, rather than across arms, for adherence to temperature and use of cooling pack.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Adherence</title>
            <description>All participants were assessed for adherence to the temperature and cooling protocols.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Participant Adherence to the Study Protocol</title>
          <description>Using study data logs, appropriate use of the thermometer and cooling pack was measured by the number of participants who adhered to the protocol for taking the temperature of the skin over the healed venous leg or diabetic foot ulcer. Adherence was defined as: the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to taking their temperatures with the infrared thermometer each morning and the number of participants who were at least 80% adherent to performing the intervention every other day = 3 times times per week during the 6-month study period.</description>
          <population>This outcome measured ALL participants in one group, rather than across arms, for adherence to temperature and use of cooling pack.</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="121"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Temperature</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="106"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Cooling</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="82"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants Indicating 'Yes' or 'Easy' on Study Instructions, Thermometer Use, Completing Logs, Performing Treatment, Helpfulness</title>
        <description>Patients satisfaction was measured by study personnel a during end of study phone survey with the following questions asked as follows (Yes/No): Were study instructions adequate, was thermometer easy to use, found cooling helpful, would cool skin area if it was proven that cooling prevented reulceration; (Easy/Not Easy): completing logs, performing the cooling treatment. Data are for (Yes/No) as number of participants who reported &quot;yes&quot; or if (Easy/Not Easy) the number of participants who reported &quot;easy.&quot;</description>
        <time_frame>Survey conducted at end of the 6-month study period.</time_frame>
        <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 122 individuals (87%)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Cooling Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants Indicating 'Yes' or 'Easy' on Study Instructions, Thermometer Use, Completing Logs, Performing Treatment, Helpfulness</title>
          <description>Patients satisfaction was measured by study personnel a during end of study phone survey with the following questions asked as follows (Yes/No): Were study instructions adequate, was thermometer easy to use, found cooling helpful, would cool skin area if it was proven that cooling prevented reulceration; (Easy/Not Easy): completing logs, performing the cooling treatment. Data are for (Yes/No) as number of participants who reported &quot;yes&quot; or if (Easy/Not Easy) the number of participants who reported &quot;easy.&quot;</description>
          <population>A total of 140 participants were randomized, with a final completion for this outcome of 122 individuals (87%)</population>
          <units>count of participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="36"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="34"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="27"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="25"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Study Instructions Adequate - Yes</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="36"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="34"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="25"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Using Thermometer Easy - Yes</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="36"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="32"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="27"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="25"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Completing Logs - Easy</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="36"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="33"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="27"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="25"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Performing Cooling -Treatment - Easy</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="35"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="31"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="24"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Cooling Helpful - Yes</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="31"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="18"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Would Cool if Found to Prevent Re-Ulceration - Yes</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="34"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="33"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="24"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="25"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Knowledge Questionnaire of Study Instructions</title>
        <description>Participants were administered a 12-item (yes/no) questionnaire (test) during instruction at the start of the study, provided by the research personnel to determine comprehension of the protocol and to reinforce study procedures. Score of 12 or 100% was given for all items scoring correctly (1 point per item). Any items for which &quot;no&quot; was answered, remediation was conducted by study personnel at the time the questionnaire was conducted. Means scores are reported per VLU and DFU cooling pack intervention and VLU and DFU cotton cooling pack control.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline after participant enrollment</time_frame>
        <population>Of 140 participants, 140 (100%) completed the questionnaire.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venus Leg Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O4">
            <title>Cotton Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
            <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Knowledge Questionnaire of Study Instructions</title>
          <description>Participants were administered a 12-item (yes/no) questionnaire (test) during instruction at the start of the study, provided by the research personnel to determine comprehension of the protocol and to reinforce study procedures. Score of 12 or 100% was given for all items scoring correctly (1 point per item). Any items for which &quot;no&quot; was answered, remediation was conducted by study personnel at the time the questionnaire was conducted. Means scores are reported per VLU and DFU cooling pack intervention and VLU and DFU cotton cooling pack control.</description>
          <population>Of 140 participants, 140 (100%) completed the questionnaire.</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Full Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="42"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="40"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="29"/>
                <count group_id="O4" value="29"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="11.7" lower_limit="11" upper_limit="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="11.9" lower_limit="11" upper_limit="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="11.8" lower_limit="11" upper_limit="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O4" value="11.9" lower_limit="11" upper_limit="12"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Data were collected for each participant for 6 months during study enrollment period.</time_frame>
      <desc>ClinicalTrial.gov definitions were used and were consistent with reporting requirements for MUSC IRB</desc>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed venous leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Venous Leg Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected leg skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed leg ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed venous leg ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E3">
          <title>Cooling Gel Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Participants self monitored skin temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling gel pack: Individuals self monitored temperature of skin over a recently healed diabetic foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cooling gel pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E4">
          <title>Cooling Cotton Pack - Diabetic Foot Ulcer</title>
          <description>A cooling cotton pack was applied to affected foot skin where an ulcer was recently healed, for 30 minutes three times a week (preventive maintenance). Patients self monitored temperature of affected skin daily to detect elevation and cooled the affected skin daily for 5 consecutive days (bolus) if the skin temperature became elevated 2°F above the baseline.&#xD;
Cooling cotton pack: Individuals self monitored skin temperature of skin over a recently healed foot ulcer with a dermal thermometer. A cotton filled pack was applied to skin of recently healed diabetic foot ulcers for 30 minutes 3 times a week for six months. If the temperature of this skin site increased and stayed elevated 2°F above the usual temperature of that site, the individual cooled the skin 5 consecutive days and continued to monitor skin temperature.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Cardiac disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Heart attack or failure</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Ear and labyrinth disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Fainted</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Infection</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Neoplasms benign, malignant and unspecified (incl cysts and polyps)</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Renal cancer</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Respiratory, thoracic and mediastinal disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Shortness of breath</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Vascular disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Stroke</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Amputation</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="14" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="7" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" subjects_affected="15" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Infection</sub_title>
                <description>Knee infection after surgery</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Injury, poisoning and procedural complications</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Injury</sub_title>
                <description>Injuries from falls or other trauma</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Skin and subcutaneous tissue disorders</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>New ulcers</sub_title>
                <description>New ulcers that developed on the treatment and non-treatment leg not involving the study healed ulcer</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="10" subjects_affected="10" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="5" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="3" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="4" subjects_affected="4" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Recurrent ulcers</sub_title>
                <description>Recurrent ulcers of study wound</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="6" subjects_affected="6" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="3" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="11" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="5" subjects_affected="5" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Rash</sub_title>
                <description>Rash or redness of study leg or foot</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Surgical and medical procedures</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Surgery</sub_title>
                <description>Surgeries included cataracts, orthopedic</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="42"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E3" events="3" subjects_affected="3" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
                <counts group_id="E4" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="29"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Teresa J. Kelechi</name_or_title>
      <organization>Medical University of South Carolina</organization>
      <phone>843-792-4602</phone>
      <email>kelechtj@musc.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

