<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03207464</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016D007737</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03207464</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Molecular Imaging of Norepinephrine Transporter (NET) Using [C-11]Methylreboxetine PET in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Molecular Imaging of Norepinephrine Transporter (NET) Using [C-11]Methylreboxetine PET in Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to use [C-11]MRB PET (positron emission tomography) imaging to look at brain&#xD;
      injury in patients with Multiple Sclerosis (MS) and healthy individuals. The overarching&#xD;
      hypothesis is that there is decreased radioligand binding to the norepinephrine transporter&#xD;
      in multiple sclerosis, reflecting injury to the noradrenergic system and that it plays a role&#xD;
      in disease pathogenesis, its clinical manifestations and severity. This strategy is targeted&#xD;
      to address an unmet need because currently available MRI techniques lack sensitivity and&#xD;
      specificity for assessing such changes in the brains of people with MS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specific aims of the study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine norepinephrine transporter binding in the brains of MS patients using&#xD;
           [C-11]MRB PET and compare it with age, and sex matched healthy controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine correlation of norepinephrine transporter binding with clinical severity&#xD;
           and MRI parameters in MS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To determine correlation of norepinephrine transporter binding with fatigue and&#xD;
           cognitive impairment in MS patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Two groups of subjects will be recruited:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Individuals meeting the definition for Multiple Sclerosis by the International Panel&#xD;
           Criteria19, with an Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) less than 6.5&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Age- and sex-matched healthy controls&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal sample size is 12 subjects including 4 healthy controls and 8 subjects with Multiple&#xD;
      Sclerosis (MS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be recruited by the PI, one of the other co-investigators, or a staff member&#xD;
      listed on the protocol at the Partners MS Center and the Behavioral Neurology Clinic of&#xD;
      Brigham and Women's Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Side Effects Monitoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
      No side effects from the radiopharmaceutical are expected nor have they been reported with&#xD;
      C-11 MRB. As this study is conducted under MGH (Massachusetts General Hospital) RDRC&#xD;
      (Radioactive Drug Research Committee) oversight, the administered dose of C-11 MRB is well&#xD;
      below the known level to cause any pharmacologic effect. Subjects will also be exposed to a&#xD;
      small amount of radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject Safety:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject monitoring during MRI and PET scans will be performed using a 2-way intercom system&#xD;
      between the scanner operator and subject and by visual monitoring of the subject through the&#xD;
      window into the scan room (the subject is visible to the operator at all times).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will need to lie still in the PET camera for period of 120 min, and subjects may&#xD;
      find it uncomfortable to remain still over this time. Therefore, as mentioned above, subjects&#xD;
      will be given the opportunity to take a break for up to 20 minutes after 70 minutes of PET&#xD;
      scanning, following which the last 30 minutes of scanning will be completed. A standard&#xD;
      head-support device will be used to make the subjects comfortable during the scanning.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If subjects find an arterial line or duration of scanning too uncomfortable, they are free to&#xD;
      withdraw from the study at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MRI scans take place in a confined space that makes some people claustrophobic.&#xD;
      Claustrophobic individuals will be excluded from the study. Also during the scan the subject&#xD;
      will hear loud banging noises and will therefore wear ear plugs to reduce this noise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment Process:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physicians at the Partners MS Center and the Brigham and Women's Hospital (BWH) Behavioral&#xD;
      Neurology clinic may present the study to a subject during a regular scheduled clinic visit.&#xD;
      If the subject is interested in the study, a copy of the consent form will be given. At the&#xD;
      time of the subject's initial screening visit, a licensed physician investigator will answer&#xD;
      any questions the subject may have regarding the study and subsequently obtain informed&#xD;
      consent. In accordance with NIH guidelines, efforts will be made to attain a mix of study&#xD;
      participants, in terms of gender and racial/ethnic representation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent Process:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent will be obtained from the subjects by a licensed physician investigator on&#xD;
      the study protocol. If the investigator is a clinician from the MS Center clinic, they will&#xD;
      not be allowed to obtain consent from their own patients. Existing MS Center subjects may be&#xD;
      sent a letter describing the study and a copy of the consent document. Interested subjects&#xD;
      are directed to contact research staff via a telephone number provided in the letter inviting&#xD;
      participation in the study to set up a screening visit. They will have the opportunity to&#xD;
      discuss the study with research study staff prior to giving consent as outlined above.&#xD;
      Subjects approached for participation in the study during a routine clinical visit will have&#xD;
      the opportunity to participate in the study at that time or they may choose to return for&#xD;
      participation at another time in the future. All subjects will be informed that they are free&#xD;
      to withdraw consent from the study at any time without affecting the quality or type of care&#xD;
      that they receive at BWH or MGH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring and Quality Assurance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study period, subjects will be followed by their clinical neurologists for adverse&#xD;
      events and disease progression. If problems are reported to their physicians, they will&#xD;
      receive care as is normally performed. In addition, the Principal Investigator (PI) will&#xD;
      review all laboratory results of tests undergone by the subjects during the study period and&#xD;
      help co-ordinate any necessary care with patient's primary providers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tissue Volume of Distribution</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>PET Imaging measurement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple Sclerosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects meeting the definition for Multiple Sclerosis by the International Panel Criteria, with an Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) less than 6.5.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will serve as non disease population.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[C-11]Methylreboxetine</intervention_name>
    <description>8 individuals with Multiple Sclerosis and 4 healthy controls will undergo a [C-11]MRB PET scan and a MRI scan.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple Sclerosis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>[C-11]MRB</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals meeting the definition for Multiple Sclerosis by the International Panel&#xD;
             Criteria, with an Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) less than 7.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male and female subjects age 18 to 70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects willing to undergo PET and MRI imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects willing and able to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals with a comorbid severe psychiatric condition such as schizophrenia,&#xD;
             bipolar disorder, or post-traumatic stress disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals with a known alternate neurologic disorder, previous head injury, or&#xD;
             substance abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals taking tricyclic antidepressants, serotonin-norepinephrine reuptake&#xD;
             inhibitors, or norepinephrine-dopamine reuptake inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Concurrent medical conditions that contraindicate study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Women who are pregnant or nursing. Also, any woman who is seeking to become pregnant&#xD;
             or suspects she is pregnant will be excluded from enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Claustrophobia&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Non-MRI compatible implanted devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Corticosteroid treatment in the past four weeks&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tarun Singhal, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tarun Singhal, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>617-264-3043</phone>
    <email>tsinghal@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Partners MS Center, 60 Fenwood Road</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jack Ficke</last_name>
      <phone>617-264-3044</phone>
      <email>jficke@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Steven Cicero</last_name>
      <email>scicero@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 30, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>TARUN SINGHAL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>M.D.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

