<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02257892</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>140206</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>14-I-0206</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02257892</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Novel Genetic Disorders of the Immune System</brief_title>
  <official_title>Novel Genetic Disorders of the Immune System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - The immune system helps the body fight infection and disease. People with immune system&#xD;
      problems can get infections, blood disorders, and other health problems. Researchers want to&#xD;
      learn more about the immune system, like what causes it to not work properly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To evaluate people with certain types of immune system disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Adults and children with an immune disorder or symptoms of one, and their relatives. Some&#xD;
      disorders are not included in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Researchers will review participants medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants may mail in a blood or saliva sample, or be evaluated at the clinic. At the&#xD;
           clinic, they may have a medical history, physical exam, blood tests, and imaging scans&#xD;
           (with dye given through a needle in the arm). They may have genetic testing done on a&#xD;
           sample of blood, saliva, hair, or nail clipping.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants may choose to have a skin biopsy. Up to 2 skin samples will be taken from&#xD;
           their arm, back, or other area. A biopsy punch is inserted into the skin and rotated. A&#xD;
           small circle of skin is removed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants 10 and older may also choose to have leukapheresis. Blood is taken through&#xD;
           a needle in one arm. It passes through a machine that separates the white blood cells.&#xD;
           The rest of the blood is returned by needle in the other arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Researchers may recommend medicines, but no treatments are being studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants may be invited to return for visits over several years. At those visits,&#xD;
           they may repeat some or all of the above tests. Or they may mail in blood or other&#xD;
           samples. They may also send medical records.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to evaluate patients with suspected or identified novel immune&#xD;
      disorders, with a focus on abnormal immune homeostasis potentially due to defects in&#xD;
      activation or apoptosis. Blood relatives of enrolled patients will also be evaluated.&#xD;
      Affected individuals may have Mendelian gene defects involving mostly single or occasionally&#xD;
      multiple genes. These patients may have signs and symptoms suggestive of clinically&#xD;
      significant lymphocyte homeostasis disorders. However, some selected patients manifesting&#xD;
      autoimmunity, autoinflammatory conditions, end-organ dysfunction, Epstein-Barr virus (EBV)&#xD;
      and cytomegalovirus (CMV) viremia, frequent infections, allergies, or laboratory&#xD;
      abnormalities consistent with immune defects of research interest to the Laboratory of&#xD;
      Clinical Immunology and Microbiology may also be studied under this protocol at the&#xD;
      discretion of the Investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol will facilitate the discovery of the role of genetic pathways and modes of&#xD;
      inheritance associated with pathophysiological events leading to immune system dysregulation,&#xD;
      particularly disorders of immune cell homeostasis. A better understanding of the genetics as&#xD;
      well as biochemical and molecular basis of complex immune disorders could also lead to the&#xD;
      development of novel therapeutic targets and approaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo clinical evaluations that include history and physical examinations,&#xD;
      blood sampling, radiological exams, genetic testing, skin biopsy, and other medically&#xD;
      indicated procedures. Genetically related family members of patients may also be screened and&#xD;
      evaluated for clinical, in vitro, and genetic correlates of immune abnormalities. Patients&#xD;
      and blood relatives unable or too sick to travel to NIH Clinical Center (CC) may be evaluated&#xD;
      through mail-in blood samples. Patients and their relatives will remain enrolled on this&#xD;
      study to observe the natural history of the disorder and obtain blood, saliva, skin biopsy,&#xD;
      or other specimens at periodic intervals. This study aims to enroll up to a total of 500&#xD;
      patients and their family members.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 22, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Family-Based</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>discover novel genes in undiagnosed immune disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of a discrete genotype-phenotype association leading to a diagnosis and understanding of the natural history of the patient s immune disorder, an underlying trait, or both.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>study the natural history of newly identified genetic disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of a discrete genotype-phenotype association leading to a diagnosis and understanding of the natural history of the patient s immune disorder, an underlying trait, or both.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>PI3KCD</condition>
  <condition>CTLA4</condition>
  <condition>STAT3GOF</condition>
  <condition>MAGT1</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Affected patients, with symptoms or genetic mutation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unaffected/healthy relatives</arm_group_label>
    <description>Relatives without symptoms or genetic mutation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        No limitations. Generally patients are referring by physicians within the US and Canada&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following inclusion criteria apply to all subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient and relatives aged 0-99 years old to include women who are pregnant or&#xD;
             breastfeeding. Only patients &gt;2 years of age, in stable clinical status and meeting&#xD;
             the weight requirement of the NIH CC will be physically evaluated at the NIH CC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to allow storage of blood, saliva, and other tissue specimens for future&#xD;
             use in medical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate in genetic testing and allow sharing of genetic information&#xD;
             in secure databases like dbGAP. These tests may include, but are not limited to, whole&#xD;
             exome and whole genome sequencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Priority may be given to individuals with a family history (if readily available)&#xD;
             suggestive of multiple affected members with a constellation of signs and symptoms&#xD;
             suggestive of immune dysfunction among first- or second-degree relatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligibility of special populations&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A. NIH employees are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  B. Women who are pregnant or breast feeding are eligible to enroll as probands&#xD;
                  Pregnant relatives are also eligible for inclusion as&#xD;
&#xD;
        they can provide important controls, genetic reference and historic clinical information.&#xD;
        This protocol is not actively seeking women who are pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        --C. Pediatric populations are eligible, with restrictions, in order to learn about the&#xD;
        natural history of the immune disorders under investigation and to provide diagnostic work&#xD;
        up for their ongoing clinical care. Healthy pediatric relatives can provide important&#xD;
        diagnostic and genetic reference for affected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Pediatric populations are eligible, with restrictions, in order to learn about the natural&#xD;
        history of the immune disorders under investigation and to provide diagnostic work up for&#xD;
        their ongoing clinical care. Healthy pediatric relatives can provide important diagnostic&#xD;
        and genetic reference for affected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must have:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An identified genetic basis for an immune disorder or signs and symptoms suggestive of&#xD;
             clinically significant immune dysregulation and/or immunodeficiency manifesting with&#xD;
             features including but not limited to autoimmunity, autoinflammatory conditions,&#xD;
             lymphadenopathy, end-organ dysfunction, unusual infections, allergies, or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormalities consistent with immune dysregulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A primary physician outside of the NIH and will be required to submit a letter or&#xD;
             clinical summary from their referring physician that documents their relevant health&#xD;
             history.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will be excluded for any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known genetic disorders that are already well characterized, such as severe combined&#xD;
             immunodeficiency (SCID), chronic granulomatous disease (CGD), etc., and those in which&#xD;
             we do not have an enduring research interest in the LCIM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with unknown immune disorders will be excluded if they have received&#xD;
             chemotherapy within the last 6 months for a malignancy or have infections such as HIV&#xD;
             or mycobacterial infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe clinical illness requiring highly specialized teams and institutions. The NIH&#xD;
             may not be able to provide appropriate care for certain referred cases. The Principal&#xD;
             Investigator (PI) may determine that the patient is eligible for enrollment but&#xD;
             ineligible for admission to the Clinical Center. Patients and relatives with certain&#xD;
             obstetric issues may pose a safety risk for travel and evaluation here. Eligibility&#xD;
             for this group will be determined on a case by case basis by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with well-defined autoimmune conditions such as systemic lupus erythematosus&#xD;
             (SLE), Hashimoto s thyroiditis, Addison s disease, Graves disease, sarcoidosis and&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, among others.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Blood relatives will be excluded for the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Any condition which in the opinion of the investigator may interfere with evaluation of an&#xD;
        immune system abnormality that is the subject of study under this protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>V. Koneti Rao, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sharon F Webster</last_name>
    <phone>(202) 450-0696</phone>
    <email>sharon.webster@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>V. Koneti Rao, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-6502</phone>
    <email>kr191c@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2014-I-0206.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 17, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 4, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 7, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CTLA4</keyword>
  <keyword>PI3KCD</keyword>
  <keyword>MAG T1</keyword>
  <keyword>Rare Immune Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetic Testing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

