<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02256943</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>133/12</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02256943</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic Determinants of Amitriptyline Efficiency for Pain Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Amitriptyline on Central Pain Processing in Healthy Volunteers Depending on CYP Pharmacogenetics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Inselspital, Berne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ludwig-Maximilians - University of Munich</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aalborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Inselspital, Berne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Low dose tricyclic antidepressant drugs are routinely administered co-analgesics in pain&#xD;
      medicine. Amitriptyline is largely considered as a gold standard. Amitriptyline underlies&#xD;
      cytochrome CYP2D6 and CYP2D19 metabolism. CYP2D6 is highly polymorphic; numerous genetic&#xD;
      variants result in 4 major classes characterizing enzymatic activity: poor metabolizers,&#xD;
      intermediate metabolizers, extensive metabolizers and ultrarapid metabolizers. It is not&#xD;
      known to which extent metabolizer classes determine pain outcomes or side-effects. As only&#xD;
      one in three pain patients is considered to be a responder to amitriptyline's co-analgesic&#xD;
      effect, prediction of treatment efficacy with a fast and easy to perform bedside test may&#xD;
      contribute to the patients quality of life. The aim of this study is to determine the&#xD;
      influence of cytochrome variants on experimental pain, drug related side-effects and finally&#xD;
      identification of active metabolites.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain is defined as an ongoing unpleasant sensory experience, which can be classified&#xD;
      according to three major, although overlapping, etiologies: nociceptive, inflammatory and&#xD;
      neuropathic pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antidepressants are widely used as co-analgesics in the management of chronic pain. An&#xD;
      overview of different substances and their relation to their mechanism of action is presented&#xD;
      in the review of Dharmashaktu et al. Low-dose tricyclic antidepressants are well established&#xD;
      in the treatment of neuropathic pain. Amitriptyline and imipramine are two widely used&#xD;
      substances of this group. The hypoalgesic effect of amitriptyline is mainly mediated by&#xD;
      inhibiting serotoninergic and noradrenergic reuptake. When administered at night time,&#xD;
      amitriptyline's sedating effect enhances sleep quality, considered as an important&#xD;
      improvement in quality of life in chronic pain patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tricyclic antidepressants undergo biotransformation in the liver with CYP2D6 catalyzing&#xD;
      hydroxylation, whereas CYP2C19 mediates demethylation of the parent drug. The demethylated&#xD;
      metabolites are partially tricyclic drugs by themselves, such as nortriptyline and&#xD;
      desipramine, which are demethyl-metabolites of amitriptyline and imipramine. It is unknown&#xD;
      whether the analgesic effect of amitriptyline is mediated through its precursor or the&#xD;
      metabolites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The CYP2D6 gene is highly polymorphic and the numerous genetic variants result in 4 major&#xD;
      metabolizer classes characterizing enzyme activity: poor metabolizers (PM) with no enzyme&#xD;
      activity, intermediate metabolizers (IM) with reduced enzyme activity, (EM) extensive&#xD;
      metabolizers carrying two functionally active alleles and ultrarapid metabolizers (UM)&#xD;
      carrying a gene duplication or multi-duplication resulting in increased enzyme activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CYP2D6 PMs have higher plasma concentrations of the parent drug than EMs and are, therefore,&#xD;
      more likely to experience dose-dependent adverse drug reactions. In 50 psychiatric patients&#xD;
      receiving amitriptyline 150 mg/d, carriers of two functional CYP2D6 alleles (EMs) had a&#xD;
      significantly lower risk of side effects than IM (12.1% vs. 76.5%). The lowest risk was&#xD;
      observed for carriers of two functional CYP2D6 alleles combined with only one functional&#xD;
      CYP2C19 allele. The combination of normal (fast) CYP2C19 and slightly diminished CYP2D6&#xD;
      function leads to high concentrations of toxic intermediate metabolites and an increase of&#xD;
      adverse events. On the other hand, CYP2D6 UMs may be at risk for sub-therapeutic&#xD;
      concentrations resulting in poor therapeutic response. Thus, genetically determined&#xD;
      differences in blood concentrations of antidepressants make dose adjustments advisable.&#xD;
      However, these findings and dose recommendations have only been evaluated for psychiatric&#xD;
      patients and no investigation on antidepressants as low-dosed co-analgesics are available up&#xD;
      to now.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative sensory tests (QST) have been intensively used for more than three decades to&#xD;
      explore the central processing of painful stimuli in patients and healthy volunteers. QST&#xD;
      were developed to assess the responses to sensory stimuli, providing psychophysical methods&#xD;
      for the assessment of the nociceptive system. In addition, large cohorts of healthy&#xD;
      volunteers have been investigated using QST measures to produce reference values.&#xD;
&#xD;
      QST measures are based on a multimodal and multi-tissue approach, combining different pain&#xD;
      modalities applied to different tissues in order to gather sufficient and discriminative&#xD;
      information about the human nociceptive system. QST will be our tool to characterize&#xD;
      analgesic efficacy of amitriptyline. QST offers the unique opportunity of experimentally&#xD;
      induced pain being quantitatively measured by psychophysical, behavioural and&#xD;
      neurophysiological responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      We test the hypothesis that the extensive and ultrarapid CYP2D6 metabolizers are associated&#xD;
      with a higher analgesic effect of amitriptyline, compared to the poor and intermediate&#xD;
      metabolizers, as assessed by quantitative sensory tests. Plasma concentrations of&#xD;
      amitriptyline and its metabolites will be analysed as co-variates for drug efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two sub-studies, one peak-level, single-dose administration and one steady-state, repeated&#xD;
      dose administration, are needed to assess the pharmacokinetics of amitriptyline and its&#xD;
      active metabolites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics are provided by José A. Biurrun Manresa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two consecutive randomized placebo-controlled two-way crossover sub-studies on amitriptyline&#xD;
      will be conducted in consenting, healthy, male volunteers. Both sub-studies have the same&#xD;
      aim: to determine the association between CYP2D6 genotype, drug response measured by QST and&#xD;
      plasma concentrations of amitriptyline and its metabolites. The first sub-study will be&#xD;
      conducted with a single high dose of amitriptyline (100 mg). The second sub-study will be&#xD;
      conducted with repeated low doses of amitriptyline (25 mg) once a day for 10 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both sub-studies the same experimental procedures and statistical analyses will be&#xD;
      performed. The only difference between the sub-studies is the dose of amitriptyline and the&#xD;
      duration of drug intake.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nociceptive withdrawal reflex</measure>
    <time_frame>During measurement, expected to be ca. 2-3 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of involuntary electromyographic amplitude</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacogenetic information on CYP2D6 metabolism</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, i.e. on day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory measurement (genotyping)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in plasmatic metabolite level</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout study duration, expected to be ca. 20 days</time_frame>
    <description>Metabolite level in plasma</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Amitriptyline first, Placebo second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Amitriptyline first, Placebo second</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo first, Amitriptyline second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo first, Amitriptyline second</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Amitriptyline</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg single dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Amitriptyline first, Placebo second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo first, Amitriptyline second</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tryptizol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tolterodine</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo 1 mg single dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Amitriptyline first, Placebo second</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo first, Amitriptyline second</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;7 Metabolic Equivalents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic pain syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspicion of neurologic dysfunction at tested sites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing treatment with antidepressants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing treatment with analgesics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pretreatment with any CYP3A inducers or inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to tested drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elevated eye pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obstructive uropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illness&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ulrike Stamer, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Bern University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pascal H Vuilleumier, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bern University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dep. of Anesthesiology, Bern University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <zip>3010</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dharmshaktu P, Tayal V, Kalra BS. Efficacy of antidepressants as analgesics: a review. J Clin Pharmacol. 2012 Jan;52(1):6-17. doi: 10.1177/0091270010394852. Epub 2011 Mar 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21415285</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 1, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 6, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 23, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 23, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 24, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pharmacogenetics of Amitriptyline</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Amitriptyline</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amitriptyline, perphenazine drug combination</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tolterodine Tartrate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

