<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02257476</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00071307</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>WINSHIP2598-13</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02257476</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extended Infusion Carfilzomib on a Weekly Schedule in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of Extended Infusion Carfilzomib on a Weekly Schedule in Patients With Advanced Solid Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find the safest dose level of an approved drug, carfilzomib,&#xD;
      in solid tumors when given over a different period of time than normally used. The study will&#xD;
      also use markers in blood from routine blood draws to help check the levels of the drug.&#xD;
      Lastly, the study will check how well this drug works with regards to keeping cancer cells&#xD;
      from growing with the new time frame of delivery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The role of the proteasome in carcinogenesis and cell survival has been well established, and&#xD;
      its inhibition associated with an accumulation of pro-apoptotic proteins and cell death.&#xD;
      Proteasome inhibitors, such has bortezomib, have been extensively studied and are widely used&#xD;
      as effective therapy in the treatment for hematologic malignancies, such as multiple myeloma&#xD;
      where circulating proteasome levels have been correlated with survival. Carfilzomib, a novel&#xD;
      irreversible proteasome inhibitor which specifically targets the chymotryptic site of the&#xD;
      proteasome has shown more potency than bortezomib and may be able to overcome bortezomib&#xD;
      resistance. Response rates between 25-54% were seen in patients with previously treated&#xD;
      myeloma in the phase 2 setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the effectiveness of proteasome inhibition in multiple myeloma, the role of proteasome&#xD;
      in solid tumors is under active investigation. Previous trials of bortezomib in breast,&#xD;
      prostate, lung, and pancreatic cancer have shown little activity of this agent in these&#xD;
      diseases. Whether the lack of activity may be mechanistically related (bortezomib inhibits&#xD;
      chymotrypsin-like and peptidyl-glutamyl peptide-hydrolyzing (PGPH)-like activities of the&#xD;
      proteasome), or a lack of potency in target inhibition, is unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a phase Ib/II study of 14 patients (phase I) and 51 patients (phase II) with advanced&#xD;
      solid tumors, Rosen and colleagues noted single-agent activity with carfilzomib. Carfilzomib&#xD;
      was dosed on days 1, 2, 8, 9, 15, and 16 of a 28 day cycle to a maximum of 12 cycles, with&#xD;
      20-36 mg/m² noted as the recommended phase 2 dose based on DLT data. A PR in both renal and&#xD;
      small cell lung cancer, and stable disease &gt; 16 weeks in mesothelioma, ovarian, renal, and&#xD;
      non-small cell lung cancer was observed. The treatment was tolerable with the most common&#xD;
      adverse events (AEs) including fatigue, headache, diarrhea, nausea and constipation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the activity of carfilzomib seen in selected solid tumors, and unpublished data to&#xD;
      suggest weekly dosing may result in a similar pharmacokinetic profile including AUC, the&#xD;
      investigators propose to study the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and anti-tumor&#xD;
      activity of carfilzomib monotherapy given on a weekly dosing schedule. Weekly dosing has the&#xD;
      advantage of patient convenience, and if acceptable toxicity and pharmacokinetics, it allows&#xD;
      for easier integration of this schedule into subsequent combination therapy clinical trials.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of a weekly 4-hour carfilzomib infusion in patients with advanced solid malignancies</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate safety and tolerability of weekly dosed carfilzomib as assessed by using NCI Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Effects (CTCAE) v.4 criteria to determine DLTs, the MTD, and RP2D</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics (PK) of escalating doses of weekly intravenous carfilzomib</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 28 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic analysis (Tmax, Cmax, t1/2, AUC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in pharmacodynamic (PD) biomarkers before and during treatment with carfilzomib using peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) and paired tumor biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1, 2, 3, 8, 15, 21</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacodynamic (PD) evaluation of degree of 20S proteasomal inhibition in PBMC assays conducted at Emory University before treatment and at time of first restaging scan</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary anti-tumor efficacy (objective response rate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Objective Response Rate (CR + PR) by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1 criteria in patients who completed at least 2 cycles of protocol therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary anti-tumor efficacy (clinical benefit rate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Benefit Rate (CR + PR + SD) by RECIST 1.1 criteria in patients who completed at least 2 cycles of protocol therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary anti-tumor efficacy (progression free survival)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary anti-tumor efficacy (overall survival)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Malignancies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Carfilzomib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive single agent carfilzomib on a weekly dosing schedule (days 1, 8, 15) in a 21 day cycle. The initial dose will be 20 mg/m² for cycle 1, day 1. Dose escalation will proceed in a standard 3+3 fashion with the requirement that dose escalation to the next level can only proceed if 0 of 3 or ≤ 1 of 6 patients experience a dose limiting toxicity (DLT). Dexamethasone 8 mg PO/IV will be administered prior to all carfilzomib doses.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carfilzomib</intervention_name>
    <description>Carfilzomib will be given as an IV infusion over 4 hours. Subjects will remain at the clinic under observation for at least 1 hour following each dose of carfilzomib in Cycle 1 and following the dose on Cycle 2 Day 1. During these observation times, post dose IV hydration may be given at physician's discretion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carfilzomib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PR-171</other_name>
    <other_name>Kyprolis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexamethasone 8 mg PO/IV will be administered prior to all carfilzomib doses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carfilzomib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Decadron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient aged 18 years or older at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Advanced/metastatic solid tumor refractory to standard therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 - 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function as assessed by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bone marrow:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal to 1,500/mm³&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Platelet count greater than or equal to 100,000/mm³&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatic:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt; 3 x&#xD;
                       ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Prothrombin time (PT)-international normalized ratio (INR)/partial&#xD;
                       thromboplastin time (PTT) &lt; 1.5 x ULN except in patients receiving active&#xD;
                       anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) of 50 ml/minute or greater (if elevated&#xD;
                       serum creatinine level &gt; 1.5 x ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to sign informed consent by patient or patient's legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with known but adequately treated brain metastases and without central nervous&#xD;
             system (CNS) disease progression as determined by CT or MRI imaging within 4 weeks of&#xD;
             the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment related residual toxicity &gt; grade 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with a proteasome inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled systemic disease or intercurrent illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent history of myocardial infarction (MI) or symptomatic coronary artery disease&#xD;
             within the preceding 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of uncontrolled hypertension (systolic &gt; 150 mmHg or diastolic pressure &gt; 90&#xD;
             mmHG despite optimal medical management).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ejection fraction &lt; 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known and actively treated infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV),&#xD;
             hepatitis B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks of first study treatment&#xD;
             from which the subject has not fully recovered.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patient of child-bearing potential or male patient with partner of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential but unable or unwilling to use effective contraception (double&#xD;
             barrier such as condoms, contraceptive sponge, diaphragm or vaginal ring with&#xD;
             spermicidal jellies or cream; or hormonal method such as oral, parenteral or&#xD;
             transdermal hormonal agents for at least three months prior to study drug&#xD;
             administration).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corticosteroid doses greater than equivalent of prednisone 7.5 mg PO daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent therapy with any active anticancer agent within 4 weeks of the 1st dose of the&#xD;
             study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other current malignancy or previous malignancies within 3 years of enrollment&#xD;
             except: curatively treated in situ carcinoma of the cervix uteri; localized basal or&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, curatively treated in situ breast carcinoma, and&#xD;
             early stage prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of allergy to Captisol® (a cyclodextrin derivative used to solubilize&#xD;
             carfilzomib).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to any of the required concomitant drugs or supportive treatments,&#xD;
             including hypersensitivity to all anticoagulation and antiplatelet options, antiviral&#xD;
             drugs, or intolerance to hydration due to preexisting pulmonary or cardiac impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with pleural effusions requiring thoracentesis or ascites requiring&#xD;
             paracentesis within 14 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other clinically significant medical disease or condition that, in the&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion, may interfere with protocol adherence or a subject's ability&#xD;
             to give informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bradley C. Carthon, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University Winship Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 26, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 2, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 6, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 3, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 3, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 7, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bradley Carthon MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>carfilzomib</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced solid malignancies</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced solid cancers</keyword>
  <keyword>prostate</keyword>
  <keyword>bladder</keyword>
  <keyword>colon</keyword>
  <keyword>breast</keyword>
  <keyword>lung</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

