<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02415088</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15.26/anesth15.01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02415088</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ultrasound-guided Selective Shoulder Block Versus Ultrasound-guided Interscalene Brachial Plexus Block, an RCT</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Postoperative Pain After Shoulder Surgery. Ultrasound-guided Block of the Axillary and Suprascapular Nerves (Selective Shoulder Block) Versus Ultrasound-guided Interscalene Brachial Plexus Block: An Observer-blinded RCT</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stessel Björn</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jessa Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomised, observer-blinded trial to compare selective shoulder block with&#xD;
      interscalene block. Both blocks will be placed using an ultra-sound guided technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome measures will be postoperative pain scores and use of rescue opioids.&#xD;
      Secondary outcome measures will be pre- and postoperative occurence of motor deficit of the&#xD;
      arm and dyspnea, quality of sleep in the first night after surgery as measured by a numeric&#xD;
      rating scale and overall satisfaction with pain therapy as measured by the International Pain&#xD;
      Outcomes questionnaire and an NRS-score (0 = not satisfied at all and 10 = very satisfied).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary and secondary outcome measures will be assessed during the first 24hours after&#xD;
      surgery (assessment in the postanesthetic care unit (PACU) directly after admission and&#xD;
      before discharge and in the surgical ward at 4, 8 and 24 hours after surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall satisfaction with pain therapy will be assessed 48hours after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An interscalene block is a block of the plexus brachialis in the interscelene triangle (by&#xD;
      injecting a local anesthetic around the nerve plexus).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A selective shoulder block is a block of the suprascapular and axillary nerves (by injecting&#xD;
      a local anesthetic around these nerves).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomised, observer-blinded trial to compare selective shoulder block with&#xD;
      interscalene block.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this study is to compare ultrasound-guided selective shoulder block (regional&#xD;
      anesthesia of the suprascapular and axillary nerves) with ultrasound-guided interscalene&#xD;
      block after arthroscopic shoulder surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      More specific, this study is designed to compare postoperative pain scores, use of opioids,&#xD;
      pre- and postoperative occurence of motor deficit of the arm and dyspnea, quality of sleep in&#xD;
      the first night after surgery as measured by a numeric rating scale and overall satisfaction&#xD;
      as measured by the International Pain Outcomes questionnaire and an NRS-score (0 = not&#xD;
      satisfied at all and 10 = very satisfied).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary and secondary outcome measures will be assessed during the first 24hours after&#xD;
      surgery (assessment in the postanesthetic care unit (PACU) directly after admission and&#xD;
      before discharge and in the surgical ward at 4, 8 and 24 hours after surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall satisfaction with pain therapy will be assessed 48hours after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuous interscalene brachial plexus block is considered to be the standard treatment for&#xD;
      postoperative pain after shoulder surgery. With interscalene block a local anesthetic is&#xD;
      injected around the nerve plexus supplying motor and sensory innervation to the upper limb.&#xD;
      Disadvantages are an extensive motor and sensory block of the upper limb and paresis of the&#xD;
      diaphragm sometimes provoking dyspnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since 2007 newer techniques are described, for example selective block of the suprascapular&#xD;
      nerve and the axillary nerve. These two nerves supply most of the shoulder joint with motor&#xD;
      and sensory innervation, but have no function in the distal part of the upper limb. The risk&#xD;
      of loss of innervation to the diaphragm is avoided with this selective shoulder block. Hence,&#xD;
      possible breathing disorders are avoided. Previous studies have concluded that the selective&#xD;
      shoulder block is a safe technique and is effective to reduce postoperative pain after&#xD;
      arthroscopic shoulder surgery. Moreover, studies also suggest that selective shoulder block&#xD;
      has a longer duration, less fluctutations in pain score and less rebound pain after fading of&#xD;
      the regional anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With this study the investigators want to compare the effect of this newer technique with the&#xD;
      single shot interscalene plexus block. Therefore the investigators will allocate the patients&#xD;
      to two groups for comparison. One group will receive interscalene plexus block and the other&#xD;
      group will receive a selective shoulder block. The used local anesthetic will be the same in&#xD;
      both groups, that is ropivacaine 0,75% with a total volume of 20 ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both blocks will be placed using an ultra-sound guided technique. In previous studies a blind&#xD;
      technique, based on anatomical reference points or nerve stimulation, has been used to place&#xD;
      the selective shoulder block. As both blocks will be placed with an ultrasound-guided&#xD;
      technique, the anesthesiologist will have a direct view of the location of the needle. With&#xD;
      this technique there is less risk for accidental intravascular injection or nerve injury.&#xD;
      Also there is greater probability of success and faster implementation of the block.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indepent of the technique used, the pain that the patient may experience will be reduced to a&#xD;
      minimum. Therefore the patient wlll be supplied with a PCIA system (patient controlled&#xD;
      intravenous analgesia), next to the standard pain relievers (paracetamol, anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      medication). This PCIA system is a pump system with piritramide (Dipidolor®, an opioid)&#xD;
      connected with the infusion line. The system is set up in a way that, within certain limits,&#xD;
      the patient can decide for him/herself when pain treatment is provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a monocentric, prospective, randomised and observer-blinded study. Patients included&#xD;
      will be randomised in two groups. One group will receive the ultrasound-guided single shot&#xD;
      interscalene block, the other group will receive the ultrasound-guided selective shoulder&#xD;
      block (axillary nerve and suprascapular nerve). The patient is not strictly blinded as there&#xD;
      are two injections needed for the selective shoulder block, compared to only one injection&#xD;
      for the interscalene block. The data collector (per- and postoperative) will be blinded, as&#xD;
      he will not be informed about which block is performed. This in order to avoid bias.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Score as measured by Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>24hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of piritramide as documented by the PCIA (patient controlled intravenous analgesia) system</measure>
    <time_frame>24hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective feeling of dyspnea as measured by a numeric rating scale</measure>
    <time_frame>24hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Motor deficit after nerve block as measured by Medical Research Council scale</measure>
    <time_frame>24hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of sleep in the first night after surgery as measured by a numeric rating scale</measure>
    <time_frame>24hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall satisfaction as measured by the International Pain Outcomes questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain, Postoperative</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interscalene block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>block of the plexus brachialis in the interscalene region with local anaesthetics</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Selective shoulder block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>selective block of the suprascapular nerve and the axillary nerve with local anaesthetics</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interscalene block</intervention_name>
    <description>block of the plexus brachialis in the interscalene region with local anaesthetics</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interscalene block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Selective shoulder block</intervention_name>
    <description>selective block of the suprascapular nerve and the axillary nerve with local anaesthetics</description>
    <arm_group_label>Selective shoulder block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elective arthroscopic shoulder surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elective hospital admission for one night&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt; 18 years and &lt; 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status classification 1, 2 of 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe obesity ( BMI &gt; 35)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe COPD (Gold≥ 3) or restrictive (FEV1 &lt; 50%) lungdisease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  coagulation disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous injury or surgery of the involved shoulder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pre-existing neuropathy or myopathy of the involved arm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy or contra-indication for the medication used in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  preoperative use of opioids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  infection at the puncture site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to understand or speak Dutch&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to understand the PCIA system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to understand the NRS pain score system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  refusal to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dirk Schoorens, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Jessa Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jessaziekenhuis Hasselt</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hasselt</city>
        <state>Limburg</state>
        <zip>3500</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 8, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 14, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 5, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Jessa Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Stessel Björn</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nerve block</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

