<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00656110</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LID-RLS-RCT-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00656110</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neuroma Injections to Treat Restless Legs Syndrome - RCT</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial of Bilateral 3rd/4th Common Digital Foot Nerve Injections to Treat Restless Legs Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lowcountry Infectious Diseases</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lowcountry Infectious Diseases</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether, in a randomized, placebo-controlled trial,&#xD;
      restless legs syndrome (RLS) can be caused by pinched and damaged foot nerves called&#xD;
      neuromas.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Restless legs syndrome (RLS) is a medical condition in which there is an almost irresistible&#xD;
      urge to move the legs in response to uncomfortable, difficult-to-describe leg sensations that&#xD;
      are usually worse in the evening and especially noticeable when inactive such as sitting in a&#xD;
      chair watching TV or when resting in bed trying to go to sleep or back to sleep after&#xD;
      awakening. Most patients with RLS, while asleep, also have involuntary leg movements called&#xD;
      periodic limb movements of sleep (PLMS). During a sleep study, brain wave monitoring of&#xD;
      patients with RLS/PLMS often shows that the nighttime leg movements are associated with brain&#xD;
      stimulation and arousal to a lighter stage of sleep. When many such brain arousals happen&#xD;
      through the night, the natural pattern of deep sleep may be severely disrupted. Such&#xD;
      disturbed sleep is of poorer quality and is less refreshing. The combination of RLS-related&#xD;
      delay of initiation or resumption of sleep and PLMS-related poor quality of sleep may result&#xD;
      in a severe sleep disorder manifested by morning sluggishness and increased daytime fatigue.&#xD;
      The cause(s) of RLS and PLMS have not been determined. Neurologists believe that they&#xD;
      originate in the brain in areas that control movement and may be related to localized low&#xD;
      levels of dopamine (a chemical messenger between nerve cells) or related to disordered brain&#xD;
      iron metabolism, but these theories have never been proven.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RLS and PLMS generally are lifelong conditions for which there is no cure. RLS is treated&#xD;
      with medications targeting the brain and categories of drugs that have been used to treat&#xD;
      symptoms (with varying success) include mainly dopaminergic drugs but also sedatives,&#xD;
      anti-seizure drugs, and pain medications such as narcotics. Two dopaminergic drugs have been&#xD;
      approved by the FDA for the treatment of RLS: ropinirole (&quot;Requip&quot;) in 2005 and pramipexole&#xD;
      (&quot;Mirapex&quot;) in 2006. However such drugs are far from ideal because, in addition to the&#xD;
      problem of side effects, some patients may not respond to these drugs or symptoms may only&#xD;
      partially improve. Also, any improvement only occurs while continuing to take the drug, and&#xD;
      finally, symptoms may sometimes become much worse after an initial period of improvement, a&#xD;
      phenomenon called augmentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Foot neuromas are nerve entrapments (&quot;pinched nerves&quot;) which form at points where the common&#xD;
      interdigital nerves must stretch under ligaments between the metatarsal heads in the ball of&#xD;
      each foot. Repeated irritation and damage to the nerves at those stretch points eventually&#xD;
      results in fibrous thickening and enlargement of the nerve tissue into a lump called a&#xD;
      neuroma. This most commonly involves a nerve in the ball of the foot between the third and&#xD;
      fourth toes (&quot;Morton's Neuroma&quot;), but neuromas also often form at the entrapment/stretch&#xD;
      point of the nerves between the second/third and fourth/fifth toes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neuromas may be completely asymptomatic in the foot or may cause variable degrees of&#xD;
      unilateral or bilateral foot pain and numbness brought on or made worse by tight shoes, high&#xD;
      heels, or prolonged walking or standing. When neuromas become more severely symptomatic, they&#xD;
      may cause neuropathic symptoms such as burning, tingling, numbness, electric shock shooting&#xD;
      pains, and hypersensitivity. Neuromas are treated with a series of injections (local&#xD;
      anesthetic combined with either steroids and/or alcohol solution) given into the&#xD;
      neuroma-containing space in the ball of the foot. It is believed that these injections serve&#xD;
      to calm the nerve irritability which usually results in improvement or sometimes even&#xD;
      complete resolution of the neuropathic symptoms (burning pain, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies by our group determined that many patients with neuropathic foot symptoms&#xD;
      (burning, tingling, electric shocks, numbness, etc.) who had been previously diagnosed with&#xD;
      &quot;peripheral neuropathy,&quot; actually had neuromas in both feet as the cause of their symptoms.&#xD;
      The causative role of neuromas in these patients was demonstrated by the fact that their&#xD;
      chronic pain symptoms improved (in some cases markedly so) with standard neuroma injection&#xD;
      treatment. In addition to improvement in their neuropathic foot pains, many patients also&#xD;
      reported that they were sleeping much better. Such patients reported not only a decrease in&#xD;
      their RLS-type leg restlessness but also that their spouse had noted a decrease in their&#xD;
      PLMS-type nighttime leg movements, all as a direct result of their bilateral neuroma&#xD;
      injections. These reports prompted further study of patients who had RLS/PLMS both with and&#xD;
      without neuropathic foot pains.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most patients with RLS/PLMS do not have major foot complaints. However such patients have&#xD;
      been consistently found by us to have physical evidence of neuromas on examination of their&#xD;
      feet and standard treatment of their bilateral neuromas usually resulted in prompt&#xD;
      improvement of the symptoms related to RLS/PLMS along with the quality of their sleep. 15&#xD;
      such patients were studied intensively before and after neuroma treatment and 9 of these&#xD;
      patients had complete relief of RLS symptoms for an average of over 2 months after a series&#xD;
      of neuroma injections (Lettau LA, Gudas CJ. Bilateral Morton's neuromas as an etiology of&#xD;
      restless legs syndrome. J SC Med Assoc 2005; 101: e341-e347).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, the prevailing theory remains that RLS is of brain origin, so that a controlled&#xD;
      study is being done to further support a foot neuroma origin of RLS by comparing the&#xD;
      responses of two randomized groups of adults with RLS - one group to receive a series of 3&#xD;
      bilateral neuroma treatments (equal parts of 0.5% plain Marcaine and 2% lidocaine mixed with&#xD;
      0.8 mg Depo-medrol/4% absolute alcohol in a total injection volume of 1 ml injected weekly&#xD;
      over 3 weeks) and a second &quot;control&quot; group to receive only placebo (normal saline) injections&#xD;
      over a similar time period. Neither group will be told whether they are getting the actual&#xD;
      treatment solution or placebo over the 3 weeks. After the 3 weeks are up, the patients who&#xD;
      had received the placebo, will be told of their status and will be given the real injection&#xD;
      treatments over the next 3 weeks. One follow-up visit (4 weeks after the last treatment&#xD;
      injection) is planned to assess short term duration of treatment(s).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>April 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>International Restless Legs Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly during the study and three weeks after treatment completion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Restless Legs Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1-T</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment Group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2-P</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo comparator</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>equal parts of 0.5% plain Marcaine and 2% lidocaine mixed with 0.8 mg Depo-medrol/4% absolute alcohol in a total injection volume of 1 ml</intervention_name>
    <description>Bilateral 3rd/4th common digital nerve injections with neuroma treatment mixture given weekly for 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>1-T</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Normal saline - 1ml</intervention_name>
    <description>Bilateral 3rd/4th common digital nerve injections with normal saline given weekly for 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>2-P</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical symptoms (that fulfill the 4 essential clinical criteria for RLS) of at least&#xD;
             6 months duration with a current IRLS-rs score indicative of at least moderate&#xD;
             severity (15 or greater)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of bilateral 3rd/4th interspace neuromas by both physical examination and&#xD;
             ultrasound criteria at initial evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness and ability of patient to participate in initial weekly evaluation/neuroma&#xD;
             treatment visits and subsequent periodic follow-up visits over a period of&#xD;
             approximately 6-9 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Off dopaminergic drug treatment (ropinirole-&quot;Requip&quot; or pramipexole-&quot;Mirapex&quot;)&#xD;
             starting 2 weeks prior to the initial foot injections and for the duration of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major foot deformity, previous major foot surgery, or previous neuroma injections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected obstructive sleep apnea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to any of injection components (depo-medrol, lidocaine, marcaine, absolute&#xD;
             alcohol)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ludwig A Lettau, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lowcountry Infectious Diseases</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ludwig A Lettau, MD</last_name>
    <phone>843-402-0227</phone>
    <email>lettaul@comcast.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lisa A Lettau, RN, BSN</last_name>
    <phone>843-813-2940</phone>
    <email>lettaul@comcast.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southeastern Foot Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29414</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Charles J Gudas, DPM</last_name>
      <phone>843-852-9444</phone>
      <email>gudasturbo@bellsouth.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Charles J Gudas, DPM</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lettau LA, Gudas CJ. Bilateral Morton's neuromas as an etiology of restless legs syndrome. Journal of the South Carolina Medical Association 101: e341-e347, 2005</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 6, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 6, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 10, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 10, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Ludwig A. Lettau, M.D.</name_title>
    <organization>Lowcountry Infectious Diseases</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Restless legs syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Morton's neuroma</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Restless Legs Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

