<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04771793</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0420-20-MMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04771793</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Physical Restraint of Critically Ill Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Physical Restraint of Critically Ill Patients: Prevalence, Properties and Associated Delirium Score</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Meir Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Meir Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Physical restraint of patients in the intensive care unit (ICU) is a common&#xD;
      practice, with estimated prevalence of 50% of all ICU patients, with and without invasive&#xD;
      ventilation support(1). The prevalence of physical restraint varies between ICU's according&#xD;
      to patient population (surgical, cardiac, trauma, burns and general intensive care patients).&#xD;
      In mechanically ventilated patients, the physical restriction (tying the patient) is carried&#xD;
      out frequently in addition to pharmacological treatment with analgesic and sedative&#xD;
      medications, in order to prevent falling, self-inflicted injury or accidental removal of&#xD;
      essential medical devices (tracheobronchial tubes, central venous infusions, drains, etc.) by&#xD;
      the patient. In non-ventilated patients, physical restraint is often carried out in patients&#xD;
      with delirium or cognitive decline, in addition to pharmacological anti -delirium therapy&#xD;
      (1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, physical restraint has many drawbacks, including injuries to the skin and the soft&#xD;
      tissues, blood vessels, peripheral nerves, muscle and skeleton (2). In addition, physical&#xD;
      restraint may exacerbate symptoms of restlessness and delirium and even increase the risk of&#xD;
      developing post-traumatic stress disorder in these patients (3,4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the high prevalence of physical restraint of ICU patients, with its disadvantages and&#xD;
      advantages, currently there are no consensual criteria for physical restraint and the&#xD;
      decision when and how long to use it is at the discretion of the attending physician. It is&#xD;
      important to note that in recent years there has been a tendency to reduce the amount of&#xD;
      sedation that mechanically ventilated patients are given, which may lead to an increase in&#xD;
      the incidence of physical restraint of patients who are fully or partially conscious (5).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Physical restraint of patients in the intensive care unit (ICU) is a common&#xD;
      practice, with estimated prevalence of 50% of all ICU patients, with and without invasive&#xD;
      ventilation support(1). The prevalence of physical restraint varies between ICU's according&#xD;
      to patient population (surgical, cardiac, trauma, burns and general intensive care patients).&#xD;
      In mechanically ventilated patients, the physical restriction (tying the patient) is carried&#xD;
      out frequently in addition to pharmacological treatment with analgesic and sedative&#xD;
      medications, in order to prevent falling, self-inflicted injury or accidental removal of&#xD;
      essential medical devices (tracheobronchial tubes, central venous infusions, drains, etc.) by&#xD;
      the patient. In non-ventilated patients, physical restraint is often carried out in patients&#xD;
      with delirium or cognitive decline, in addition to pharmacological anti -delirium therapy&#xD;
      (1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, physical restraint has many drawbacks, including injuries to the skin and the soft&#xD;
      tissues, blood vessels, peripheral nerves, muscle and skeleton (2). In addition, physical&#xD;
      restraint may exacerbate symptoms of restlessness and delirium and even increase the risk of&#xD;
      developing post-traumatic stress disorder in these patients (3,4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the high prevalence of physical restraint of ICU patients, with its disadvantages and&#xD;
      advantages, currently there are no consensual criteria for physical restraint and the&#xD;
      decision when and how long to use it is at the discretion of the attending physician. It is&#xD;
      important to note that in recent years there has been a tendency to reduce the amount of&#xD;
      sedation that mechanically ventilated patients are given, which may lead to an increase in&#xD;
      the incidence of physical restraint of patients who are fully or partially conscious (5).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: In the first stage of our planned study (in this study) - we would like to assess&#xD;
      the prevalence of physical restraint in ICU patients, both with and without mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation support, their clinical characteristics and the rate of delirium among them. In&#xD;
      the second stage of the study (in a future study) - we plan to install specific protocols for&#xD;
      physical restraint, aiming to decrease the rate of physical restraint of patients in our ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data obtained from the first phase of the study can help us characterize the patients who&#xD;
      require physical restraint in the ICU, which from we will attempt to generate protocols that&#xD;
      will help us reduce the prevalence of physical restraint in the unit. For example, if the&#xD;
      group of patients who required physical restraint tended to experience delirium more often,&#xD;
      as measured by the RASS score, we could formulate a special protocol for the treatment of&#xD;
      delirium in these patients, which might reduce the need for physical restraint in some cases.&#xD;
      We can address factors that may alter the incidence of delirium, such as emphasizing the&#xD;
      importance of renewing as soon as possible all regular patients' pharmacological therapy with&#xD;
      antipsychotic drugs, if any, or to soon start treatment to prevent withdrawal syndrome (in&#xD;
      case of chronic ethanol abuse, or regular benzodiazepine treatment. Alternative measures can&#xD;
      also be used to decrease delirium prevalence, such as presence of the patient's family&#xD;
      member, music, television, maintaining the patient's room dark at night hours, etc.), as well&#xD;
      as other measures. The characterization of those patients is essential for the formulation of&#xD;
      such treatment protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods and materials:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study type: Retrospective study based on data collection. Data will be extracted from the&#xD;
      hospital computerized systems. The study will include all our ICU admitted patients from&#xD;
      1.1.2020 to 31.12.2020. About 1000 patients total.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria: All patients aged 18--99 admitted to the General Intensive Care Unit from&#xD;
      January 2020 to the end of December 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection: Retrospective observational data collection from hospital records and&#xD;
      computerized systems (Chameleon system and iMDsoft software).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collected data: Age, gender, hospital and ICU admission times, ventilation days, 28-day&#xD;
      mortality, past medical history including chronic medication therapy, APACHE-2 score,&#xD;
      admission lactate level, need for pressor or inotropic support, need for dialysis, need for&#xD;
      tracheostomy, type of ICU admission (Infectious, trauma etc.), delirium score measured by the&#xD;
      RASS score, need for physical restraint, duration of physical restraint, prevalence of self&#xD;
      extubation, prevalence of self-inflicted injuries including falls and inadvertent retrieval&#xD;
      of tubes or other medical devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study group size: 1000 patients. Statistical analysis: All demographic and intra-patient&#xD;
      parameters will be statistically examined by a qualified statistician depending on the type&#xD;
      of data. The current study group will be the control group (before intervention), and the&#xD;
      second group will be the treatment group (after intervention, i.e. after creating and&#xD;
      installing new physical restraint protocols in the ICU) .We will use the Chi square test to&#xD;
      analyze the discrete data and the Mann-Whitney test to analyze the continuous data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of physical restraint in ICU patients</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (January 2020 - December 2020.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the prevalence of physical restraint in ICU patients (%), both with and without mechanical ventilation support</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Delirium</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A- before implentation of physical restraint protocols</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B- after implentation of physical restraint protocols</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>new physical restraint protocols</intervention_name>
    <description>new physical restraint protocols</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A- before implentation of physical restraint protocols</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B- after implentation of physical restraint protocols</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients aged 18--99 admitted to the General Intensive Care Unit from January 2020 to&#xD;
        December 2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: All patients aged 18--99 admitted to the General Intensive Care Unit&#xD;
        from January 2020 to December 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: None.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sara Dichtwald, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>972-9-7472133</phone>
    <phone_ext>2</phone_ext>
    <email>sara.dichtwald@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Brian Fredman, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>972-9-7471545</phone>
    <phone_ext>2</phone_ext>
    <email>fredman.brian@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Meir medical center Kfar Saba</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kfar Saba</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>sara dichtwald, MD</last_name>
      <phone>972-9-7472133</phone>
      <email>sara.dichtwald@clalit.org.il</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Brian Fredman, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>972-9-7471545</phone>
      <email>fredman.brian@clalit.org.il</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Meir Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>sara dichtwald</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

