<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04777123</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MD-85-2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04777123</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prevention of Post-spinal Anesthesia Hypotension in Caesarean Delivery Using Delayed Supine Positioning</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevention of Post-spinal Anesthesia Hypotension in Caesarean Delivery Using Delayed Supine Positioning: a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Maternal hypotension is a common complication after spinal anaesthesia for caesarean&#xD;
      delivery. Prophylaxis against post-spinal hypotension (PSH) during caesarean delivery would&#xD;
      prevent serious maternal and fetal complications. Various methods had been investigated for&#xD;
      prophylaxis against maternal hypotension. The basic components of management of PSH are: 1.&#xD;
      Fluid loading. 2. Pharmacological agents. 3. Positioning protocols. Although Fluid loading is&#xD;
      superior to non-loading protocols during caesarean delivery, the incidence of Post-spinal&#xD;
      hypotension is high with all fluid loading protocols. Thus; the value of fluid loading in&#xD;
      caesarean delivery could not be used solely for prevention of PSH. Using vasopressors for&#xD;
      prophylaxis against PSH is nearly fundamental during caesarean delivery. However,&#xD;
      vasopressors are not devoid of side effects such as reflex bradycardia after phenylephrine&#xD;
      and fetal acidosis after ephedrine. Thus, combining vasopressor prophylaxis and&#xD;
      non-pharmacological protocols would help to decrease the dose of vasopressors, and&#xD;
      consequently decreasing their side effects. Ondansetron had been also reported as a useful&#xD;
      prophylactic drug from PSH with minimal side effects. Positioning protocols, such as&#xD;
      operating table tilting or flexing, the use of wedges or mechanical displacers, leg wrapping&#xD;
      or sequential compression devices, head down and head up positioning aim to reversing&#xD;
      aortocaval compression and/or increasing venous return. The sitting position for a short&#xD;
      period after spinal block in order to slow the onset of the spinal block. Keeping the patient&#xD;
      in the sitting position after spinal block would also prevent extension of local anaesthetic&#xD;
      solution to upper thoracic dermatomes which is an important factor in preventing maternal&#xD;
      hypotension.&#xD;
&#xD;
      no previous reports had evaluated the impact of sitting position within the context of a&#xD;
      multimodal protocol for prophylaxis against maternal hypotension. In this study, we aim to&#xD;
      evaluate the impact of 2-minute sitting position after spinal anesthesia on maternal&#xD;
      hemodynamics when combined with prophylactic norepinephrine infusion plus preoperative bolus&#xD;
      of ondansetron. We aim to reach the best possible maternal hemodynamic profile in addition to&#xD;
      maintenance of adequate block level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Upon arrival to operating room, Monitors will be applied (electrocardiography - pulse&#xD;
      oximetry - non-invasive blood pressure monitor). All measurements will be taken before IV&#xD;
      line insertion and premedications. Baseline systolic blood pressure will be obtained in the&#xD;
      supine position as the mean of three consecutive readings at 2-minute intervals with a&#xD;
      difference of less than 10%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After insertion of a peripheral 18-gauge line with a three way valve for fluids and&#xD;
      vasopressor infusion; Premedication's with ranitidine (50mg) and ondansetron (4 mg) will be&#xD;
      administered. Subarachnoid block (SAB) will be done in sitting position under complete&#xD;
      asepsis in L3-L4 or L4-L5 interspace using 25 g spinal needle. 11 mg of 0.5% intrathecal&#xD;
      hyperbaric Bupivacaine and 25um fentanyl will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Block success will be assessed using pinprick or sensation to cold besides adequate motor&#xD;
      block. Patients with failed SAB (Defined as sensory level below T4) will be excluded as well&#xD;
      as patients with high spinal block (defined as spinal anaesthesia in which spinal denervation&#xD;
      extends to second or third thoracic dermatome or sometimes up to cervical dermatomes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Co-hydration will be continued up to a maximum of 1.5 litres (patients with intraoperative&#xD;
      blood loss over 1000 ml will be excluded from the study). After delivery of the foetus,&#xD;
      oxytocin will be given as an initial bolus of 0.5 IU over five seconds followed by 40&#xD;
      mIU/minute infusion. Inspired air will be supplemented with oxygen 3 l/min via a nasal&#xD;
      catheter until delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuous norepinephrine fixed rate infusion will be given to both groups as 5 mcg&#xD;
      norepinephrine bolus at the same time cerebrospinal fluid obtained followed by norepinephrine&#xD;
      infusion in a starting dose of 0.05 mcg/Kg/min. Norepinephrine will be prepared as 8 mcg/mL&#xD;
      and will be delivered using a syringe pump. Post-spinal hypotension (defined as decreased SBP&#xD;
      less than 80% of the baseline reading during the period from intrathecal injection to&#xD;
      delivery of the foetus) will be managed by IV ephedrine 9 mg. Severe post-spinal hypotension&#xD;
      (defined as decreased SBP less than 60% of the baseline reading) will be managed by IV&#xD;
      ephedrine 15 mg. Additional vasopressor bolus was given if SBP did not respond to the first&#xD;
      dose within 2 minutes. Intraoperative hypertension (defined as SBP &gt;120% of the baseline&#xD;
      reading) will be managed by stopping norepinephrine infusion. The infusion will be resumed&#xD;
      when blood pressure returned to its normal value. Intraoperative bradycardia (defined as&#xD;
      heart rate less than 55 bpm without hypotension during the period from intrathecal injection&#xD;
      to delivery of the fetus) will be managed by stopping the vasopressor infusion. If&#xD;
      bradycardia was associated with hypotension, the patient was managed by IV ephedrine 9 mg. If&#xD;
      bradycardia persisted after the previous measures, an IV atropine bolus (0.5 mg) will be&#xD;
      given.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Norepinephrine total dose will be calculated in both groups for comparison purposes.&#xD;
      Measurements will be taken every 2 minutes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>average systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>mmHg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>post-spinal anaesthesia hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>frequency of patients with decreased systolic blood pressure less than 80% of the baseline reading</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>severe post-spinal anaesthesia hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>frequency of patients with decreased systolic blood pressure less than 60% of the baseline reading</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>reactive hypertension</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of patients with increased systolic blood pressure more than 120% of the baseline reading</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>nausea and vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>frequency</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>norepinephrine requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>mcg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ephedrine requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>mg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>atropine requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after SAB till delivery of fetus</time_frame>
    <description>mg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>umbilical cord blood gases</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minutes after delivery</time_frame>
    <description>pH</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apgar score</measure>
    <time_frame>at 1 minute and 5 minutes post-delivery.</time_frame>
    <description>assessing the appearance, pulse, grimace, activity, respiration on a scale from zero to two, then summing up the five values thus obtained. The resulting score ranges from zero to 10.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84</enrollment>
  <condition>Cesarean Section</condition>
  <condition>Hypotension</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Anaesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sitting position</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will be left in the sitting position</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>supine position</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will lie down immediately after injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sitting position</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will be left seated for 2 minutes after subarachnoid injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>sitting position</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full term (above 37 weeks gestation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Singleton.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant woman ASA II scheduled for elective caesarean section aged between 18 and 35&#xD;
             years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to spinal anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obese patients (body mass index &gt;35).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripartum bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cardiac contractility (Ejection fraction&lt;45%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac arrhythmias (I.e. any rhythm other than normal sinus rhythm and sinus&#xD;
             tachycardia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Valvular heart lesions (I.e. moderate to severe valve lesions).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing hypertension, pregnancy induced hypertensive disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fetal abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraoperative blood loss over 1000 ml and failed/ high subarachnoid block.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed Hasanin</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cairo University Kasr Alainy Faculty of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maha Mostafa, M.D</last_name>
    <phone>01000365115</phone>
    <email>maha.mostafa@cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cairo University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Hasanin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data are not publicly available. Data are available from the authors upon reasonable request and after permission of Cairo university</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

