<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04776876</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0083</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-00021</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-0083</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04776876</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retifanlimab (INCMGA00012) and Telotristat Ethyl for the Treatment of Advanced Neuroendocrine Tumors and Carcinoid Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Open-Label, Single-Arm Study of INCMGA00012 and Telotristat Ethyl in Patients With Advanced Neuroendocrine Tumors and Carcinoid Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies the effect of retifanlimab and telotristat ethyl in treating&#xD;
      patients with neuroendocrine tumors that have spread to other places in the body (advanced)&#xD;
      and carcinoid syndrome. Retifanlimab is a monoclonal antibody that may interfere with the&#xD;
      ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Telotristat ethyl is a drug used to reduce side&#xD;
      effects of carcinoid syndrome. Giving retifanlimab and telotristat ethyl may help to control&#xD;
      neuroendocrine tumors in patients who also have carcinoid syndrome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the efficacy of retifanlimab (A12) + telotristat ethyl (TE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the efficacy of A12 + TE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SAFETY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the safety of A12 + TE. II. To evaluate the safety of withholding concurrent&#xD;
      somatostatin analogue in patients receiving A12 + TE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY BIOMARKER OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To identify biomarkers that are predictive of response to A12 + TE (i.e., predictive&#xD;
      biomarkers), are associated with progression to a more severe disease state (i.e., prognostic&#xD;
      biomarkers), are associated with resistance to A12 + TE, are associated with susceptibility&#xD;
      to developing adverse events, can provide evidence of study treatment activity, or can&#xD;
      increase the knowledge and understanding of disease biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive retifanlimab intravenously (IV) over 30-60 minutes on day 1 and telotristat&#xD;
      ethyl orally (PO) 3 times daily (TID) on days 1-28. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 2&#xD;
      years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 2 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The study will not be opening. Support was withdrawn.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall best response rate (partial response or complete response)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will estimate the best response rate and its 95% exact confidence interval using the Clopper and Pearson method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by an independent radiologist according to immune-modified RECIST.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from enrollment to the first occurrence of disease progression or death from any cause, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by an independent radiologist according to RECIST v1.1. Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The log-rank test will be performed to test the difference in time-to-event distributions between patient groups. Cox proportional hazards model may be utilized to include multiple covariates in the time-to-event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from the first occurrence of a documented objective response to disease progression or death from any cause, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by an independent radiologist according to RECIST v1.1. Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The log-rank test will be performed to test the difference in time-to-event distributions between patient groups. Cox proportional hazards model may be utilized to include multiple covariates in the time-to-event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined by an independent radiologist according to RECIST v1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from enrollment to death from any cause, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The log-rank test will be performed to test the difference in time-to-event distributions between patient groups. Cox proportional hazards model may be utilized to include multiple covariates in the time-to-event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence and severity of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Will be determined according to National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events, version 5.0. Toxicity data will be summarized by frequency tables.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Neuroendocrine Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoid Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (retifanlimab, telotristat ethyl)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive retifanlimab IV over 30-60 minutes on day 1 and telotristat ethyl PO TID on days 1-28. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Retifanlimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (retifanlimab, telotristat ethyl)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>INCMGA 0012</other_name>
    <other_name>INCMGA-0012</other_name>
    <other_name>INCMGA00012</other_name>
    <other_name>INCMGA0012</other_name>
    <other_name>MGA 012</other_name>
    <other_name>MGA-012</other_name>
    <other_name>MGA012</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telotristat Ethyl</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (retifanlimab, telotristat ethyl)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 1, 2, or 3 (or described as low grade, intermediate grade, well differentiated,&#xD;
             or moderately differentiated) neuroendocrine tumor, according to reviewing pathologist&#xD;
             or documented interpretation of report by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive disease over the preceding 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy with any number of anticancer therapies, but a somatostatin analogue&#xD;
             (such as octreotide, lanreotide, or pasireotide) must be one of the prior therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Carcinoid syndrome, as documented by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients using a somatostatin analogue for symptom control must be on stable doses for&#xD;
             56 days prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to comply with the study protocol, in the investigator's judgment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST)&#xD;
             version (v)1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previously irradiated lesions can be considered as measurable disease only if&#xD;
                  progressive disease has been unequivocally documented at that site since&#xD;
                  radiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mm^3 without granulocyte colony-stimulating factor&#xD;
             support (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lymphocyte count &gt;= 500/mm^3 (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 without transfusion (obtained within 28 days prior to&#xD;
             initiation of study treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cell count &gt;= 2,500/mm^3 (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may be transfused to meet this criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate transaminase (AST), alanine transaminase (ALT), and alkaline phosphatase =&lt;&#xD;
             2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment), with the following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with documented liver metastases: AST and ALT =&lt; 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with documented liver or bone metastases: alkaline phosphatase =&lt; 5 x&#xD;
                  ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment) with the following exception:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with known Gilbert disease: serum bilirubin level =&lt; 3 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum albumin &gt;= 2.5 g/dL (obtained within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients not receiving therapeutic anticoagulation: international normalized ratio&#xD;
             (INR) or activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (obtained within 28&#xD;
             days prior to initiation of study treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients receiving therapeutic anticoagulation: stable anticoagulant regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For men: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from heterosexual intercourse) or use&#xD;
             a barrier contraceptive method with a failure rate of &lt; 1% per year during the&#xD;
             treatment period and for 6 months after the last dose of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of childbearing potential: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from&#xD;
             heterosexual intercourse) or use a contraceptive method with a failure rate of &lt; 1%&#xD;
             per year during the treatment period and for 6 months after the last dose of study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A woman is considered to be of childbearing potential if she is postmenarcheal,&#xD;
                  has not reached a postmenopausal state (&gt;= 12 continuous months of amenorrhea&#xD;
                  with no identified cause other than menopause), and has not undergone surgical&#xD;
                  sterilization (removal of ovaries and/or uterus)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Examples of contraceptive methods with a failure rate of &lt; 1% per year include&#xD;
                  bilateral tubal ligation, male sterilization, hormonal contraceptives that&#xD;
                  inhibit ovulation, hormone-releasing intrauterine devices, and copper&#xD;
                  intrauterine devices&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The reliability of sexual abstinence should be evaluated in relation to the&#xD;
                  duration of the clinical trial and the preferred and usual lifestyle of the&#xD;
                  patient. Periodic abstinence (e.g., calendar, ovulation, symptothermal, or&#xD;
                  postovulation methods) and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 3, poorly differentiated neuroendocrine carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Large cell or small cell histology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment for the studied cancer within 28 days prior to initiation of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with investigational therapy within 28 days prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Palliative radiation therapy administered within 1 week of first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment or radiation therapy in the thoracic region that is &gt; 30 Gy within 6 months&#xD;
             of the first dose of study treatment. Note: Participants must have recovered from all&#xD;
             radiation-related toxicities, not require corticosteroids for this purpose, and not&#xD;
             have had radiation pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Toxicity of prior therapy that has not recovered to =&lt; grade 1 or baseline (with the&#xD;
             exception of any grade of alopecia and anemia not requiring transfusion support)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to another monoclonal antibody that cannot be controlled with&#xD;
             standard measures (e.g., antihistamines and corticosteroids)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any component of the INCMGA00012 formulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any component of the telotristat formulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic immunosuppression in excess of&#xD;
             physiologic maintenance doses of corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg/day of prednisone or&#xD;
             equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy at doses &gt; 10 mg/day of prednisone&#xD;
                  or equivalent for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency and in the absence of active&#xD;
                  autoimmune disease is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with asthma that requires intermittent use of bronchodilators,&#xD;
                  inhaled steroids, or local steroid injections may participate&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Brief courses of corticosteroids for prophylaxis (e.g., contrast dye allergy) or&#xD;
                  study treatment-related standard premedication are permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants using topical, ocular, intra-articular, or intranasal steroids (with&#xD;
                  minimal systemic absorption) may participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior allogeneic stem cell or solid organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of interstitial lung disease, history of interstitial lung disease, or&#xD;
             active, noninfectious pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) test at screening with CD4+ T-cell count &lt;&#xD;
             350 cells/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known HIV infection and opportunistic infection within the past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection (chronic or acute), defined as having a&#xD;
             positive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) test at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with a past or resolved HBV infection, defined as having a negative&#xD;
                  HBsAg test and a positive total hepatitis B core antibody (HBcAb) test and&#xD;
                  negative HBV deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) test at screening, are eligible for the&#xD;
                  study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection, defined as having a positive HCV antibody&#xD;
             test followed by a positive HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA) test at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The HCV RNA test will be performed only for patients who have a positive HCV&#xD;
                  antibody test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known diagnosis of active tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with therapeutic oral or IV antibiotics within 7 days prior to initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients receiving prophylactic antibiotics (e.g., to prevent a urinary tract&#xD;
                  infection or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation) are eligible for&#xD;
                  the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with a live, attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks prior to initiation of study&#xD;
             treatment, or anticipation of need for such a vaccine during the course of the study,&#xD;
             or up to 5 months following the anticipated last dose of INCMGA00012&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancies other than the disease under study within 3 years prior to cycle 1, day&#xD;
             1, with the exception of those with a negligible risk of metastasis or death and with&#xD;
             expected curative outcome (such as adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix,&#xD;
             basal or squamous cell skin cancer, or ductal carcinoma in situ treated surgically&#xD;
             with curative intent) or undergoing active surveillance per standard-of-care&#xD;
             management (e.g., chronic lymphocytic leukemia Rai stage 0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical&#xD;
             laboratory finding that contraindicates the use of an investigational drug, may affect&#xD;
             the interpretation of the results, or may render the patient at high risk from&#xD;
             treatment complications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with CD137 agonists or immune checkpoint blockade therapies, including&#xD;
             anti-CTLA-4, anti-PD-1, and anti-PD-L1 therapeutic antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with systemic immunostimulatory agents (including, but not limited to,&#xD;
             interferon and interleukin 2) within 4 weeks or five half-lives of the drug (whichever&#xD;
             is longer) prior to initiation of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medication (including, but not limited to,&#xD;
             corticosteroids, cyclophosphamide, azathioprine, methotrexate, thalidomide, and&#xD;
             anti-TNF-alpha agents) within 2 weeks prior to initiation of study treatment, or&#xD;
             anticipation of need for systemic immunosuppressive medication during the course of&#xD;
             the study, with the following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who received low-dose immunosuppressant medication are eligible for the&#xD;
                  study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who received mineralocorticoids (e.g., fludrocortisone), corticosteroids&#xD;
                  for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or asthma, or low-dose corticosteroids&#xD;
                  for orthostatic hypotension or adrenal insufficiency are eligible for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding, or intending to become pregnant during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test result&#xD;
                  within 14 days prior to initiation of study treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel M Halperin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoid Tumor</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malignant Carcinoid Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Serotonin Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

