<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04772300</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZKSJ0132</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04772300</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of Sirolimus-Coated Balloon vs. Uncoated Standard Angioplasty for the Treatment of Below-the-knee Peripheral Arterial Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>LIMES</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Multi-Center Randomized Controlled Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of SiroLIMus Drug Coated Balloon Versus Non-coated Standard Angioplasty for the Treatment of Infrapopliteal Occlusions in Patients With PEripheral Arterial DiSease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jena University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Concept Medical Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>VascuScience GmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>CoreLab Black Forest</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Center for Clinical Studies, University Hospital Jena</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jena University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective, interventional, multicenter 1:1 randomized trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial evaluates the safety and efficacy of the Magic Touch PTA sirolimus drug-coated&#xD;
      balloon in comparison to the treatment with POBA (control device) in patients with&#xD;
      infrapopliteal artery disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to assess whether efficacy of the MagicTouch Sirolimus&#xD;
      Coated PTA Balloon Catheter (SRL-DCB) is superior and whether safety is noninferior to Plain&#xD;
      Old Balloon Angioplasty (POBA) regarding treatment of occlusions in the infrapopliteal&#xD;
      arteries (located below the P3 segment of the popliteal artery to the tibiotalar joint) in&#xD;
      patients pre-senting with chronic limb-threatening ischemia (CLTI) (Rutherford 4-6).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>1:1-randomization, parallel design, stratified by center.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>composite of limb salvage and primary patency at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after study procedure (PTA with medical product under investigation or comparator)</time_frame>
    <description>composite of limb salvage and primary patency at 6 months. Patency is defined as the absence of target lesion occlusion (no flow) as determined by duplex ultrasound and/or absence of clinically-driven TLR revascularization (CD-TLR), where clinically-driven is defined as a restenosis of ≥ 70 % in the target lesion with&#xD;
Wound persistence and/or&#xD;
Increase in size of pre-existing wounds and/or&#xD;
Occurrence of new wounds and/or&#xD;
Deterioration of Rutherford Class</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MALE-POD</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Major Adverse Limb Events (MALE) with perioperative death (POD) after 1 month. Major Adverse Limb Events (MALE) are defined as above-ankle amputation or major reintervention (i.e., new bypass graft, interposition graft revision, or thrombectomy/thrombolysis) of the treated limb involving a BTK artery.&#xD;
Perioperative death (POD) is defined as death within 30 days after index procedure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of clinically-driven TVR</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>occurrence of clinically-driven TVR at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TVR rate in treated target vessel and non-target vessels</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of all TVR including treated non-target vessel at 1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TVR rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of all TVR at 1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Patency rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Patency rate at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Patency of target and treat non-target vessel</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Patency rate of target and treat non-target vessel at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary Patency rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary Patency rate at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary Patency of target and treat non-target vessel</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary Patency rate of target and treat non-target vessel at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Re-occlusion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of re-occlusion at certain time points, defined as the absence of flow in the target vessel as determined by duplex ultrasound</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of treated Non-target vessels</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months after study procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Number of treated Non-target vessels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Walking Capacity Assessment 1</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>patient-self-assessment of walking distance at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Walking Capacity Assessment 2</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>VascuQoL questionnaire (Vascular Quality of Life Questionnaire) at certain time points; 25 questions (scale 1 to 7); best score 175, worst score 25.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Target Limb Major Amputations</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of target limb major amputations at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>all-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of all-cause death at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Amputation free survival (AFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Amputation free survival (AFS) at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Amputation free survival and resolved CLTI</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Amputation free survival and resolved CLTI at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ankle-Brachial-Index (ABI)</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in ankle-brachial index (ABI) from pre-procedure to certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toe-Brachial-Index (TBI)</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in toe-brachial index (TBI) from pre-procedure to certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rutherford classification</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Rutherford category from pre-procedure to certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary sustained clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>improvement shift in the Rutherford Category of one class or more in amputation free surviving patients without the need for clinically driven TVR at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary sustained clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>improvement shift in the Rutherford classification of one class or more in amputation free surviving patients including those with clinically driven TVR at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-3L</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in EQ-5D-3L (Quality of Life questionnaire) from pre-procedure to certain time points; 5 questions (scale 1 to 3), best score 5, worst score 15.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Wound healing</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of wound healing from pre-procedure to certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New or recurrent wound of the target limb</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>New or recurrent wound of the target limb from pre-procedure to certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in VascuQoL</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Walking capacity assessment by VascuQoL from pre-procedure to certain time points. 25 questions (scale 1 to 7); best score 175, worst score 25.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of in-hospital-stay</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Days of hospitalization at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major Adverse Limb Events (MALE)</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>MALE at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device Success</measure>
    <time_frame>at index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Device Success defined as exact deployment of the device according to the instructions for use</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical Success</measure>
    <time_frame>at index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Technical Success defined as successful vascular access and completion of the endovascular procedure and immediate morphological success with ≤ 50 % residual diameter reduction of the treated lesion on completion angiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedural success</measure>
    <time_frame>at index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Procedural success, defined as combination of technical success, device success and absence of procedural complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>composite endpoint: patency, rate of overall-cause death and amputation-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>composite endpoint consisting of patency, rate of overall-cause death and amputation-free survival at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>composite endpoint: rate of all-cause death, target limb major amputation and clinically-driven TLR</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after study procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>composite endpoint consisting of rate of all-cause death, target limb major amputation and clinically-driven Target Lesion Revascularization at certain time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">230</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sirolimus DCB group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention with Sirolimus-coated balloon catheter</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>POBA group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention with non-coated balloon catheter (POBA)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Percutaneous Transluminal Angioplasty (PTA) MagicTouch Sirolimus Coated PTA Balloon Catheter</intervention_name>
    <description>PTA with an sirolimus drug-coated balloon catheter (SRL-DCB) in the infrapopliteal artery</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sirolimus DCB group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Percutaneous Transluminal Angioplasty (PTA) with non-coated balloon catheter (POBA)</intervention_name>
    <description>PTA with an non-coated balloon catheter (POBA) in the infrapopliteal artery</description>
    <arm_group_label>POBA group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has been informed of the nature of the study, is willing to comply with all&#xD;
             required follow-up evaluations within the defined follow-up visit windows and has&#xD;
             signed an Ethics Committee (EC) approved consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Female subjects of childbearing potential have a negative pregnancy test ≤ 7 days&#xD;
             before the procedure and are willing to use a reliable method of birth control for the&#xD;
             duration of study participation. Female subjects will be exempted from this&#xD;
             requirement in case they are sterile, infertile, or have been post-menopausal for at&#xD;
             least 12 months (no menses).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Life expectancy &gt; 1 year in the investigator's opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject presenting with documented chronic limb-threatening ischemia (CLTI) in the&#xD;
             target limb defined as Rutherford category 4, 5 or 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. In case of Rutherford category 5 or 6: Subjects with documented infection grade 0-2&#xD;
             and/or ischemia grade 2-3 according to the wound ischemia foot infection (WIfI)&#xD;
             classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Reference Vessel Diameter (RVD) ≥ 2 and ≤ 4.0 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Total occlusion (100 % stenosis) of the target vessel; no minimal lesion length&#xD;
             required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The target lesion may consist of multiple target vessel lesions, if they are ≤ 5 cm&#xD;
             away from each other and if at least one of them is occluded and all lesions are&#xD;
             located in only one of the infrapopliteal arteries or directly within the transition&#xD;
             area.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Non-target vessels (e.g. inflow lesions or contralateral extremity) can be treated&#xD;
             during the study index procedure but according to the patient's randomization result&#xD;
             (interventional group: Sirolimus-coated balloon or POBA; control group: only POBA).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. No lesion length limitation, no limitation in number of used devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The lesion must be located in the infrapopliteal arteries and above the ankle joint.&#xD;
             Lesions may not extend above the tibioperoneal trunk (P3 segment of the popliteal&#xD;
             artery) or below the tibiotalar joint (arteries of the foot), nor can the treatment&#xD;
             (investigational device or standard PTA, including pre-dilatation) extend beyond these&#xD;
             indicated regions for more than 1 cm. Note: A target lesion can extend into the P3&#xD;
             segment in case it involves a straight uninterrupted lesion extending from the target&#xD;
             vessel. Non-significant stenosis below the ankle joint can be allowed in case this is&#xD;
             not part of the target lesion and does not require treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Presence of documented run-off to the foot (clearly visible at least one of the&#xD;
             following run-off vessels: dorsalis pedis or pedal arch or plantar arteries by&#xD;
             angiography). The target vessel should give direct or indirect run-off to the foot.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Inflow free from flow-limiting lesion confirmed by angiography. Patients with&#xD;
             flow-limiting inflow lesions (≥ 50 % stenosis) can be included if the lesion(s) have&#xD;
             been treated successfully before enrollment, with a maximum residual stenosis of ≤ 30&#xD;
             % per visual assessment. If an inflow lesion must be treated within or above the P3&#xD;
             segment of the popliteal artery, there must be a minimum of 3 cm healthy tissue&#xD;
             between this (treated) lesion and the infrapopliteal target lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Successful pre-dilatation of the (entire) target lesion. Success being documented by&#xD;
             angiographic visual estimate of ≤ 50 % residual diameter stenosis of the target lesion&#xD;
             and no flow limiting dissection (&lt; Grade D dissection). TL is not considered&#xD;
             non-dilatable by the operator due to concentric, circumferential calcium and TL can be&#xD;
             treated successfully by balloon angioplasty without the need for bail-out stenting.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects with amputation of the target leg above the metatarsal level.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Planned index limb amputation above the metatarsal level, or any other planned major&#xD;
             surgery within 30 days pre- or post-procedure. A planned amputation including and&#xD;
             below the metatarsal level (1 or multiple rays) is accepted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Recent MI or stroke &lt; 30 days prior to the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known or suspected active infection at the time of the index procedure (abnormal white&#xD;
             blood cell count, fever, sepsis or positive blood culture), excluding an infection of&#xD;
             a lower extremity wound on the target limb (only WIfI infection grade 0-2 allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with infection grade 3 and ischemia grade 0 and/or 1 according to WIfI&#xD;
             classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with neurotrophic ulcers, heel pressure ulcers or calcaneal ulcers with a&#xD;
             risk for major amputation; Subjects with uncomplicated ulcers can be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with documented active osteomyelitis, excluding the phalanges, that is beyond&#xD;
             cortical involvement of the bone per clinical judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with vasculitis, systemic Lupus Erythematosus or polymyalgia rheumatica on&#xD;
             active treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects receiving systemic corticosteroid therapy (expected dosage &gt; 5 mg of&#xD;
             prednisolone or equivalent, per day, during the initial 9 months after procedure).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known allergies or sensitivities to heparin, aspirin (ASA), other&#xD;
             anticoagulant/anti-platelet therapies which could not be substituted, and/or sirolimus&#xD;
             or an allergy to contrast media that cannot be adequately pre-treated prior to the&#xD;
             index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The subject is currently enrolled in another investigational device, drug or&#xD;
             biological trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Female subjects who are breast feeding at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Significant gastrointestinal bleeding or any coagulopathy that would contraindicate&#xD;
             the use of anti-platelet therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prior stent(s) or bypass surgery within the target vessel (including stents placed&#xD;
             within target vessels during the index procedure prior to randomization).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Previous procedure with drug-coated balloons in the target vessel within 6 months&#xD;
             prior to index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Occlusions located or extending in the popliteal artery or below the ankle joint&#xD;
             space. Note: A target lesion can extend into the P3 segment in case it involves a&#xD;
             straight lesion extending from the target vessel. Non-significant stenosis below the&#xD;
             ankle joint can be allowed in case this is not part of the target lesion and does not&#xD;
             require treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Untreated significant (≥ 50 % residual stenosis measured by Duplex Sonography) inflow&#xD;
             lesion or occlusion in the ipsilateral iliac, SFA and popliteal arteries.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Failure to obtain a ≤ 30 % residual stenosis in pre-existing, hemodynamically&#xD;
             significant (≥ 50 % measured by Duplex Sonography) inflow lesions in the ipsilateral&#xD;
             iliac, SFA and popliteal artery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Aneurysm in the target vessel.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Angiographic evidence of thrombus within target vessel.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Pre-dilatation resulted in a major (≥ Grade D) flow-limiting dissection (observed on 2&#xD;
             orthogonal views) or residual stenosis &gt; 50 %.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Use of alternative therapy, e.g. atherectomy, scoring balloon, laser, radiation&#xD;
             therapy, stents as part of target vessel treatment. Note: Use of stents is only&#xD;
             allowed for bailout stenting.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ulf Teichgraeber, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital Jena, Institute of Radiology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ulf Teichgrarber, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+49 3641</phone>
    <phone_ext>9 324806</phone_ext>
    <email>ulf.teichgraeber@med.uni-jena.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laura Graziani, M.A.</last_name>
    <phone>+49 3641</phone>
    <phone_ext>9 324910</phone_ext>
    <email>laura.graziani@med.uni-jena.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AKH Wien, Universitätsklinik für Innere Medizin II, Klinische Abteilung für Angiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Schlager, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+43 1 40400</phone>
      <phone_ext>46700</phone_ext>
      <email>oliver.schlager@meduniwien.ac.at</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Allgemeines Krankenhaus der Stadt Wien (Wien AKH), Department of Radiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Floria Wolf, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+43 1 40 400</phone>
      <phone_ext>58020</phone_ext>
      <email>florian.wolf@meduniwien.ac.at</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hanusch-Krankenhaus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>1140</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Werner, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+43 1 91021</phone>
      <phone_ext>57812</phone_ext>
      <email>martin.werner@oegk.at</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitäts-Herzzentrum Freiburg-Bad Krozingen; Clinic for Cardiology and Angiology II</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Krozingen</city>
        <zip>79189</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thomas Zeller, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 7633 402</phone>
      <phone_ext>4973</phone_ext>
      <email>Thomas.Zeller@universitaets-herzzentrum.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charité Universitätsmedizin, Klinik für Radiologie, Campus Benjamin Franklin (CBF)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>12203</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maximilian de Bucourt, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 30 450 527</phone>
      <phone_ext>855</phone_ext>
      <email>maximilian.de-bucourt@charite.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fürst-Stirum-Klinik Bruchsal, Klinik für Kardiologie, Angiologie, Diabetologie, Neurologie und Intensivmedizin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bruchsal</city>
        <zip>76646</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Andrassy, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 7251 708</phone>
      <phone_ext>57791</phone_ext>
      <email>martin.andrassy@rkh-kliniken.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>DIAKO gGmbH, Institut für Diagnostische und Interventionelle Radiologie und Neuroradiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Flensburg</city>
        <zip>24939</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stefan Müller-Hülsbeck, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 461 812</phone>
      <phone_ext>1800</phone_ext>
      <email>muehue@diako.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Heidelberg, Medizinische Klinik III, Kardiologie, Angiologie und Pneumologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christian Erbel, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 6221 56</phone>
      <phone_ext>8612</phone_ext>
      <email>christian.erbel@med.uni-heidelberg.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Jena</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jena</city>
        <zip>07747</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ulf Teichgraeber, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 3641 9</phone>
      <phone_ext>324806</phone_ext>
      <email>ulf.teichgraeber@med.uni-jena.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Leipzig</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <zip>04103</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dierk Scheinert, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 341 97</phone>
      <phone_ext>18770</phone_ext>
      <email>Dierk.Scheinert@medizin.uni-leipzig.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Katholisches Klinikum Mainz, Klinik für Diagnostische und Interventionelle Radiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mainz</city>
        <zip>55131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jörn-Oliver Balzer, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 6131 57583</phone>
      <phone_ext>1700</phone_ext>
      <email>joern.balzer@marienhaus.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gefäßpraxis im Tal</name>
      <address>
        <city>München</city>
        <zip>80331</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Britta Heilmeier, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 89 24215</phone>
      <phone_ext>86</phone_ext>
      <email>BrittaH@angiopraxis.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Franziskus-Hospital GmbH, Klinik für Gefäßchirurgie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <zip>48145</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michel Bosiers, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 251 935</phone>
      <phone_ext>5829</phone_ext>
      <email>Michel.Bosiers@sfh-muenster.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Münster, Klinik für Kardiologie I, Koronare Herzkrankheit, Herzinsuffizienz und Angiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <zip>48149</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nasser Malyar, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 251 83</phone>
      <phone_ext>47688</phone_ext>
      <email>Nasser.Malyar@ukmuenster.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Elblandklinikum Radebeul, Gefäßzentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Radebeul</city>
        <zip>01445</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Torsten Fuss, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+49 351 833</phone>
      <phone_ext>4542</phone_ext>
      <email>torsten.fuss@elblandkliniken.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Krankenhaus Barmherzige Brüder Regensburg, Institut für Radiologie, Neuroradiologie und Nuklearmedizi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Regensburg</city>
        <zip>93049</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Niels Zorger, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 941 369</phone>
      <phone_ext>2500</phone_ext>
      <email>Niels.Zorger@barmherzige-regensburg.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imland Klinik Rendsburg, Institut für Diagnostische und Interventionelle Radiologie/Neuroradiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rendsburg</city>
        <zip>24768</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christian Wissgott, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 4331 200</phone>
      <phone_ext>6001</phone_ext>
      <email>christian.wissgott@imland.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Elblandklinikum Riesa, Gefäßzentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Riesa</city>
        <zip>01589</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Torsten Fuss, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 351 833</phone>
      <phone_ext>4542</phone_ext>
      <email>torsten.fuss@elblandkliniken.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>RoMed Klinikum Rosenheim, Diagnostische und Interventionelle Radiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rosenheim</city>
        <zip>83022</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gunnar Tepe, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 8031 365</phone>
      <phone_ext>3551</phone_ext>
      <email>gunnar.tepe@ro-med.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MEDINOS-Kliniken Sonneberg, Gefäßzentrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sonneberg</city>
        <zip>96515</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marcus Thieme, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+49 3675 821</phone>
      <phone_ext>2012</phone_ext>
      <email>marcus.thieme@regiomed-kliniken.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Jena University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ulf Teichgräber</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Coordinating Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Peripheral Artery Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Sirolimus</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-Coated Balloon</keyword>
  <keyword>Percuteanous Transluminal Angioplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>MagicTouch</keyword>
  <keyword>Below-the-knee</keyword>
  <keyword>BTK</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-Coated Ballon</keyword>
  <keyword>plain old angioplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>POBA</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized-Controlled Trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

