<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04778787</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10773100889666</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04778787</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sodium-glucose Cotransporter Type 2 Inhibitors for Acute Cardiorenal Syndrome Prevention</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Sodium-glucose Cotransporter Type 2 Inhibitors on the Course of Cardiorenal Syndrome in Acute Decompensation of Chronic Heart Failure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>I.M. Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>I.M. Sechenov First Moscow State Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The effect of sodium-glucose cotransporter type 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) on the parameters of&#xD;
      renal function in acute decompensation of chronic heart failure (CHF) compared to standard&#xD;
      therapy will be analyzed. Based on the dynamics of the clinical condition, the duration of&#xD;
      hospitalization, and blood biochemical parameters (creatinine, urea, uric acid, potassium,&#xD;
      sodium, N-terminal pro-brain natriuretic peptide NT-proBNP) conclusions will be drawn about&#xD;
      the possibility of using SGLT2i in this group of patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized multicenter prospective clinical trial involving patients over 18 years&#xD;
      of age who were hospitalized due to decompensation of chronic heart failure (CHF).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of SGLT2i on renal function in the treatment&#xD;
      of decompensation of chronic heart failure compared to standard therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is planned to include 100 patients with decompensated chronic heart failure. The&#xD;
      study will be conducted in Сity clinical hospital number 7, University clinical hospital&#xD;
      number 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be screened in the first 24-48 hours from the moment of hospitalization,&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria will be applied. The diagnosis of decompensation of chronic&#xD;
      heart failure will be made based on the collection of anamnesis, assessment of cardiovascular&#xD;
      symptoms and potential risk factors, as well as assessment of symptoms of stagnation or&#xD;
      hypoperfusion by physical examination, and confirmed by appropriate additional studies, such&#xD;
      as electrocardiogram (ECG) (twelve-channel electrocardiograph MAC 600, №72244-18), chest&#xD;
      X-ray in straight and side projections with radiation load 0,1 mSv (СombiDiagnost R90,&#xD;
      №2017/6644), laboratory tests (specific biomarkers -N-terminal brain natriuretic propeptide&#xD;
      (NT-proBNP) and transthoracic echocardiography (Ge Logic F6; №9451\61287) on the first day&#xD;
      after admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravenous administration of 40 mg of furosemide (lasix; 10 mg / ml; N014865/02) is allowed&#xD;
      no later than in the first 24 hours from the moment of admission (provided that the patient&#xD;
      has not previously received regular loop diuretics). If prior to this hospitalization,&#xD;
      regular therapy with loop diuretics was carried out, the daily dose should be increased by&#xD;
      more than 2 times with the transition to intravenous administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the first visit, patients who meet the inclusion criteria will be randomized by the&#xD;
      random number table method. Participants will be divided into two groups, the main group will&#xD;
      include patients receiving dapagliflozin (Forxiga; MP-002596) at a dose of 10 mg / day per os&#xD;
      in addition to the current therapy. The comparison group will be patients receiving standard&#xD;
      therapy (loop diuretics, vasodilators, digoxin, inotropic agents, vasopressors).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the second visit (on 3-4 days of hospitalization), the researcher will assess the&#xD;
      clinical condition (blood pressure, heart rate, respiratory rate, auscultation, edema&#xD;
      dynamics), biochemical and general blood analysis, 24-hour diuresis calculation, and patient&#xD;
      weighing in both groups of patients. Accounting for how the patient excretes fluid will be&#xD;
      made by the research doctor by weighing in the morning on an empty stomach and calculating&#xD;
      the volume of diuresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the third visit (on the day of discharge ), the researcher will assess the clinical&#xD;
      condition (blood pressure, heart rate, respiratory rate, auscultation, edema dynamics),&#xD;
      biochemical and general blood analysis, 24-hour diuresis calculation, and patient weighing in&#xD;
      both groups of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The criterion for acute renal injury will be an increase in serum creatinine by 0.3 mg / dl&#xD;
      or more for 48 hours (Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) criteria). The&#xD;
      criteria for refractoriness to diuretic therapy will be the need to increase the daily dose&#xD;
      of loop diuretics by more than 2 times compared to the initial one, or the need to add&#xD;
      another class of diuretic drugs to the therapy. (Muthiah Vaduganathan et al. Unsolved&#xD;
      challenges in diuretic therapy for acute heart failure: a focus on diuretic response.Expert&#xD;
      Review of Cardiovascular Therapy/ Volume 13, 2015 -Issue 10. Pages&#xD;
&#xD;
      1075-1078). The initial dose will be the daily dose of loop diuretics used on the first day&#xD;
      of hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to find out whether there were repeated hospitalizations or deaths of patients&#xD;
      within 30 days, the study participants will be called on the 30th day after discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reliability of the differences in the groups will be determined by the Man-Whitney&#xD;
      criterion, the differences will be considered statistically significant at p&lt;0.05.&#xD;
      Statistical processing of the obtained data will be carried out using the Statistical Package&#xD;
      for the Social Sciences program version 9.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study can be classified as a study of average accuracy. The significance level of 0.05&#xD;
      will be used as the limit of the statistical significance of the results, then according to&#xD;
      the method of K. A. Otdelnova, the sample size of the dissertation research should be 100&#xD;
      observation units. The research capacity will be 80%.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>admission to the intensive care unit due to worsening heart failure during the current hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>admission to an intensive care unit (because of hemodynamic instability, systolic blood pressure less than 90 millimeters of mercury (mm Hg.St.), severe (progressive) shortness of breath with use of additional respiratory muscles, breathing frequency more than 25\min, need for intubation, lung ventilation, the presence of symptoms of hypoperfusion, oxygen saturation less than 90% (despite oxygen therapy), brady - and tachyarrhythmias with heart rate &lt;40 or &gt;130 beats/min, respectively, high-&#xD;
grade atrioventricular block, life-threatening condition: acute coronary syndrome, mechanical complications of acute insufficiency of the heart valves, chest trauma, pulmonary thromboembolism, aorta dissection)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>death due to heart failure</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Death during hospitalization or 30days post-discharge</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>deterioration of renal function (increase in blood creatinine by 0.3 mg / dl within 48 hours)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>By deterioration of kidney function is meant an increase in blood creatinine by 0.3 mg / dl within 48 hours. The maximum creatinine at hospitalization, the maximum uric acid at hospitalization, an episode of hyponatremia (sodium less than 136), an episode of oligoanuria (diuresis less than 300 ml per day) will also be taken into account. Renal function will be determined at the date of inclusion and randomisation, 3-4 days of hospitalization (second visit) and the date of discharge (third visit).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>development of resistance to diuretics</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>The need to increase the daily dose of loop diuretics by more than 2 times compared to the initial one, or the need to add another class of diuretic drugs to the therapy. (Muthiah Vaduganathan et al. Unsolved challenges in diuretic therapy for acute heart&#xD;
failure: a focus on diuretic response.Expert Review of Cardiovascular Therapy/ Volume 13, 2015 -Issue 10. Pages 1075-1078).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>re-hospitalization about decompensation of chronic heart failure within 30 days after discharge from the hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days</time_frame>
    <description>30 days after discharge, patients will be called to find out whether there are repeated hospitalizations for heart failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Congestive Heart Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention group includes patients with decompensated chronic heart failure. The diagnosis will be made according to the criteria described above</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will be identical to the main group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard list of drugs used for acute decompensation of CHF (loop diuretics, vasodilators, digoxin, inotropic agents, vasopressors), plus dapagliflozin (Forxiga; MP-002596)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive dapagliflozin at a dose of 10 mg daily during hospitalization in addition to ongoing therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>the control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>the intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically diagnosed acute decompensation of chronic heart failure. The diagnosis will&#xD;
             be made based on the collection of anamnesis and potential risk factors (hypertension,&#xD;
             previous myocardial infarction, myocarditis, cardiomyopathies, cardiotoxic drugs),&#xD;
             assessment of cardiovascular symptoms (dyspnea, orthopnea, paroxysmal nocturnal&#xD;
             dyspnea, decreased exercise tolerance, weakness, fatigue, weight gain of more than 2&#xD;
             kilograms per week, third tone (gallop rhythm), hepatomegaly, ascites), and the need&#xD;
             for intravenous administration of loop diuretics on the first day of hospitalization.&#xD;
             The diagnosis will be confirmed by appropriate additional studies, such as ECG&#xD;
             (scarring of the myocardium, blockage of the right or left legs of the bundle of Gis,&#xD;
             signs of myocardial hypertrophy), chest x-ray (the identification of cardiomegaly,&#xD;
             effusion in the sinuses, pulmonary edema), laboratory&#xD;
&#xD;
             tests (specific biomarkers - NT-proBNP more than 400 pg / ml) and echocardiography&#xD;
             (evaluation of systolic and diastolic function)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Written consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A history of type 1 diabetes mellitus, episodes of diabetic ketoacidosis or&#xD;
             hypoglycemia that required urgent medical intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Significant valvular defects (aortic regurgitation of the 3rd degree, aortic stenosis&#xD;
             with a valve opening area of less than 1 cm2), except for mitral and tricuspid&#xD;
             regurgitation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Rhythm of pacemaker more than 20% per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Therapy with any drug from the sodium-glucose cotransporter type 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i)&#xD;
             group, carried out before the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Potentially reversible causes of heart failure, such as inflammatory myocardial&#xD;
             diseases, heart defects (congenital and acquired), pericarditis (constrictive and&#xD;
             exudative), cardiac arrhythmias (brady - and tachyarrhythmias), arterial hypertension,&#xD;
             myxoma of the heart, anemia, hyper - and hypothyroidism, ischemic heart disease (in&#xD;
             the case of angioplasty, coronary artery bypass grafting, aneurysmectomy), myocardial&#xD;
             insufficiency as a component of multiple organ failure in decompensation of liver and&#xD;
             kidney diseases, as well as peripartal cardiomyopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Mental illness (if patients are not capable of understanding the nature, significance&#xD;
             and implications of the clinical trial)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of hypersensitivity to any SGLT2 inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Cardiogenic shock (decrease in systolic pressure &lt;90 mmHg for more than 30 minutes,&#xD;
             average blood pressure less than 65 mmHg for more than 30 minutes, or the need for&#xD;
             vasopressors to maintain systolic pressure ≥90 mmHg; signs of stagnation in the lungs&#xD;
             or increased left ventricular filling pressure; signs of organ hypoperfusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The presence of an acute infectious process, including the urinary tract (fever,&#xD;
             leukocytosis with a shift leukocyte formula to the left, increased erythrocyte&#xD;
             sedimentation rate (ESR), increased C-reactive protein blood, leukocyturia )&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) below 30 ml/min/1.73 m2 (Chronic Kidney Disease&#xD;
             Epidemiology Collaboration Formula - CKD-EPI)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Individual intolerance to the components of the drug&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dmitri Schekochikhin</last_name>
    <phone>4992487818</phone>
    <email>agishm@list.ru</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kristina Charaya</last_name>
    <phone>89152012944</phone>
    <email>chichachar@mail.ru</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Clinical Hospital number 1</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Сity Сlinical Нospital n 7</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Сity Сlinical Нospital number 7</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://medstatistic.ru/calculators/calcsize.html</url>
    <description>The significance level of 0.05 will be used as the limit of the statistical significance of the results, then the sample size of the research should be 100 observation units.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vaduganathan M, Kumar V, Voors AA, Butler J. Unsolved challenges in diuretic therapy for acute heart failure: a focus on diuretic response. Expert Rev Cardiovasc Ther. 2015 Oct;13(10):1075-8. doi: 10.1586/14779072.2015.1087313. Epub 2015 Sep 10.</citation>
    <PMID>26357970</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>heart failure</keyword>
  <keyword>decompensation</keyword>
  <keyword>gliflozins</keyword>
  <keyword>kidneys</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardio-Renal Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dapagliflozin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Digoxin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vasoconstrictor Agents</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vasodilator Agents</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diuretics</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sodium Potassium Chloride Symporter Inhibitors</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>since this is prohibited by the local ethics committee</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

