<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04772287</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LungMate-008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04772287</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adjuvant Toripalimab Plus Chemotherapy for EGFR/ALK Mutation Negative Stage II-IIIB(N2) NSCLC (LungMate-008)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Adjuvant Toripalimab Versus Placebo Combined With Chemotherapy for EGFR/ALK Mutation Negative Stage II-IIIB(N2) Non-small-cell Lung Cancer (LungMate-008): a Randomised, Double-blind, Controlled, Phase 3 Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai Pulmonary Hospital, Shanghai, China</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai Pulmonary Hospital, Shanghai, China</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, controlled, double-blind, single-center Phase III clinical study in&#xD;
      patients with EGFR/ALK mutation negative stage II-IIIB (N2) non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
      (NSCLC) after complete tumor resection. To evaluate the effectiveness and safety of&#xD;
      toripalimab compared with placebo combined with platinum-containing dual-drug chemotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease-free survival (DFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 40 months</time_frame>
    <description>It refers to the time from radical surgery to relapse or death of a participant due to disease progression. In the case of a patient who still survives at the time of analysis, the latest evaluation date will be used for interpolation (censoring).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>It is defined as the time from enrollment to death of participant due to any cause. In the case of a patient who still survives at the time of analysis, the date of last contact will be taken as the censoring date.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: frequency of severe adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of severe adverse events from the participants enrolling to 90 days after the last drug administration or 30 days after surgery or new anti-cancer therapy, which comes first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health related quality of life (HRQol)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The assessment is made according to the Quality of Life Scale for Lung Cancer Patients (EORTC-QLQ-C30 &amp; LC13, Version 3). EORTC's QLQ-C30 &amp; LC13 (V3.0) is a core scale for lung cancer patients, with a total of 43 items. Among them, Item 29 and 30 are divided into seven grades, which are assigned with 1 to 7 scores according to the answer options. The other items are divided into 4 grades: Not at All, A Little, Quite a Bit, and Very Much, assigned with 1 to 4 scores respectively. The higher score, the worse quality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5-year overall survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From the completion of the intervention to 5 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Five-year survival rate measures survival at 5 years after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">341</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toripalimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Toripalimab: 240mg, IV, q3w, 4 cycles in total; Platinum-containing dual-drug chemotherapy: The specific dose is based on the standard of the selected protocol, IV, q3w, a total of 4 cycles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cisplatin/Carboplatin</other_name>
    <other_name>Pemetrexed (non-squamous cell carcinoma)/ Docetaxel/ Gemcitabine/ Vinorelbine/ Paclitaxel</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toripalimab mimetic (placebo)</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo: 240mg, IV, q3w, 4 cycles in total; Platinum-containing dual-drug chemotherapy: The specific dose is based on the standard of the selected protocol, IV, q3w, a total of 4 cycles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cisplatin/Carboplatin</other_name>
    <other_name>Pemetrexed (non-squamous cell carcinoma)/ Docetaxel/ Gemcitabine/ Vinorelbine/ Paclitaxel</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Volunteer to participate in this clinical study, understand the research procedures&#xD;
             and be able to sign written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age ≥18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histological diagnosis of primary non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. An MRI or CT scan of the brain must be performed before lung cancer resection, and it&#xD;
             is confirmed that there is no brain metastasis. For patients who have not been&#xD;
             examined before surgery, if they have a brain MRI or CT scan before randomization and&#xD;
             it is confirmed that there is no brain metastasis, they can still be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Total resection of primary lung cancer (R0) and systemic lymph node dissection must be&#xD;
             performed: complete resection includes lobectomy, sleeve resection, and bilobectomy;&#xD;
             systemic lymph node dissection includes hilar and mediastinal lymph node dissection Or&#xD;
             sampling, including at least 6 groups of lymph nodes, of which 3 groups are from&#xD;
             intrapulmonary (lobar, interlobar or segment) and hilar lymph nodes, and 3 groups are&#xD;
             from mediastinal lymph nodes including subcarinal lymph nodes; all surgical margins&#xD;
             must be tumor-negative; respectively; The removed mediastinal lymph nodes or the&#xD;
             marginal lymph nodes of the removed lung lobes cannot have extranodal invasion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Postoperative pathologically confirmed NSCLC patients with stage II, IIIA and IIIB&#xD;
             (N2), the disease is staged according to the American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC)&#xD;
             8th edition lung cancer staging standard.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Confirmed as negative for EGFR/ALK mutation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Complete recovery from surgery during randomization, and complete postoperative wound&#xD;
             healing must be achieved after any surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) physical status (PS) score is 0 or 1 and&#xD;
             has not deteriorated 2 weeks before the first administration of the study drug, and&#xD;
             the minimum expected survival is greater than 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Other major organs (liver, kidney, blood system, etc.) function well:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5×10^9/L, platelet ≥100×10^9/L, hemoglobin ≥90&#xD;
                  g/L. Note: Patients shall not receive blood transfusion or growth factor support&#xD;
                  within 14 days before blood collection during the screening period;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  International normalized ratio (INR) or prothrombin time (PT)≤1.5×upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal (ULN);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT)≤1.5×ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin≤1.5×ULN (total bilirubin in patients with Gilbert syndrome&#xD;
                  must be &lt;3×ULN);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartic acid and alanine aminotransferase (AST and ALT) ≤2.5×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Female patients of childbearing age are willing to take appropriate contraceptive&#xD;
             measures (Appendix K) and should not breastfeed from signing informed consent to the&#xD;
             end of the study medication within 6 months (whichever occurs later); male patients&#xD;
             are effective from signing informed consent Willingness to use barrier contraception&#xD;
             (i.e. condoms) within 6 months of the end of sexual evaluation/study medication&#xD;
             (whichever occurs later).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Female patients have a negative blood pregnancy test result within 7 days before&#xD;
             randomization, or meet one of the following criteria to prove that there is no risk of&#xD;
             pregnancy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Postmenopausal is defined as amenorrhea at least 12 months after the age is&#xD;
                  greater than or equal to 50 years and all exogenous hormone replacement therapy&#xD;
                  is stopped;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Women younger than 50 years old, if you stop all exogenous hormone treatments and&#xD;
                  have amenorrhea for 12 months or more, and the levels of luteinizing hormone (LH)&#xD;
                  and follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) are within the reference range of&#xD;
                  postmenopausal laboratory Can be considered post-menopausal;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Have received irreversible sterilization, including hysterectomy, bilateral&#xD;
                  ovarian removal, or bilateral fallopian tube resection, except for bilateral&#xD;
                  tubal ligation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unresectable or metastatic disease, pathology report showing positive surgical margins&#xD;
             or extranodal invasion under the microscope, or leftover lesions during surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with lung adenocarcinoma with clear EGFR mutation or ALK rearrangement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Upper sulcus lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Only patients undergoing segmental resection or wedge resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Because NSCLC has previously received any anti-cancer treatment other than surgery,&#xD;
             including preoperative and postoperative chemotherapy, radiotherapy, targeted therapy&#xD;
             (such as small molecule tyrosine kinase inhibitors targeting EGFR, VEGFR and other&#xD;
             pathways, monoclonal Antibodies, etc.), immunotherapy, research therapy, etc.; within&#xD;
             14 days before the first administration of the research drug, Chinese medicines and&#xD;
             Chinese medicine preparations with anti-tumor therapy indications or tumor adjuvant&#xD;
             therapy effects have been used;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Suffered from other malignant tumors before the start of the trial, except for the&#xD;
             following medical history:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Malignant tumors that have been cured, have been inactive for more than 5 years&#xD;
                  and have a very low risk of recurrence before being selected for the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer or malignant lentigines with no&#xD;
                  evidence of disease recurrence;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Carcinoma in situ with adequate treatment and no evidence of disease recurrence;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Localized prostate cancer after radical surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Complicated with unstable systemic diseases, including active infections, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥140 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥90 mmHg),&#xD;
             unstable angina pectoris, attacks that have started within the last 3 months Angina&#xD;
             pectoris, congestive heart failure (≥ New York Heart Association [NYHA] level II),&#xD;
             myocardial infarction (6 months before enrollment), severe arrhythmia requiring&#xD;
             medication, liver, kidney or metabolic diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active, known or suspected autoimmune diseases, or autoimmune paraneoplastic syndromes&#xD;
             that require systemic treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who have used corticosteroids (&gt;10 mg/day of prednisone or other equivalent&#xD;
             hormones) or other immunosuppressive agents for systemic treatment within 2 weeks&#xD;
             before the first administration. In the absence of active autoimmune diseases, inhaled&#xD;
             or topical corticosteroids are allowed, and adrenal hormone replacement therapy with a&#xD;
             dose of ≤10 mg/day prednisone is allowed;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Have significant clinically significant bleeding symptoms or obvious bleeding tendency&#xD;
             within 1 month before the first administration, such as gastrointestinal bleeding,&#xD;
             gastric ulcer bleeding, active hemoptysis or vasculitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Arteriovenous thrombosis, such as deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, etc.&#xD;
             occurred within 3 months before the first administration (except for implantable&#xD;
             venous port, catheter-derived thrombosis or superficial venous thrombosis, these cases&#xD;
             Not considered as &quot;severe&quot; thromboembolism).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Diabetic ketoacidosis or hyperglycemia and hyperosmotic state occurred within 6 months&#xD;
             before the first administration; fasting blood glucose during the screening period&#xD;
             Diabetic patients with ≥7.8 mmol/L or glycosylated hemoglobin test value ≥7.5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. It has been known that there are active infectious diseases, such as active hepatitis&#xD;
             B (the virus surface antigen [HBsAg] test result in the screening period is positive&#xD;
             and the HBV-DNA test value is ≥2×103 IU/mL) or hepatitis C (defined as the screening&#xD;
             period) Hepatitis C virus antibody [HCV-Ab] test result is positive, and HCV-RNA is&#xD;
             positive), tuberculosis (there is evidence of active tuberculosis infection within 1&#xD;
             year), syphilis (positive Treponema pallidum specific antibodies and non-specific&#xD;
             antibodies), or human immunodeficiency Viral HIV infection (anti-HIV antibody&#xD;
             positive), etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Allergic to test drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Previously or currently suffering from interstitial lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. People with neurological diseases or mental illnesses who cannot cooperate.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. At the same time participate in another therapeutic clinical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Other situations considered unsuitable by researchers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Shanghai Pulmonary Hospital, Shanghai, China</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Peng Zhang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of thoracic department</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

