<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04779086</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-282</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04779086</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigation of E-health Literacy Levels of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Department Students</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation of E-health Literacy Levels of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Department Students</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ankara Yildirim Beyazıt University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ankara Yildirim Beyazıt University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will be carried out in order to determine the e-health literacy levels of the&#xD;
      students of the Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation and to reveal whether the&#xD;
      level of their education has an effect on e-health literacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is aimed to contribute to the literature with the objective, evidence-based results to be&#xD;
      obtained from the study and to contribute to undergraduate education as a result of the&#xD;
      differences between class levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Health literacy is generally affected by many factors, from demographic, cultural and&#xD;
      psychosocial factors, general literacy level, individual characteristics, experiences related&#xD;
      to the disease, and factors related to the healthcare system. It is stated that the evidence&#xD;
      supporting the negative effects on the health of individuals is increasing due to the lack of&#xD;
      health literacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These effects; Low use of preventive healthcare services are shown as delay in seeking health&#xD;
      care in the symptomatic period, inability to understand the medical condition of the&#xD;
      individual, inability to adhere to medical advice / instructions, insufficient self-care,&#xD;
      increase in health care costs and increase in mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In terms of health, health literacy is a stronger determinant than income, employment status,&#xD;
      education level, race or ethnic group . The strong place of the concept of health literacy&#xD;
      among the main determinants of health appears to be an important factor in the struggle for&#xD;
      inequality in health. It is stated that adoption of lifelong learning policies to increase&#xD;
      health literacy has important effects .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since health literacy is directly related to general literacy, studies to be carried out in&#xD;
      the field of education can contribute to health literacy and to the improvement of health,&#xD;
      thereby reducing health inequalities. It has been determined that the e-health literacy&#xD;
      levels of the students studying at Kırıkkale University Faculty of Health Sciences in&#xD;
      2016-2017 differ according to the departments, they are at medium and high levels (average&#xD;
      29.48).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies have been suggested to improve the e-health literacy levels of Faculty of Health&#xD;
      Sciences students. These recommendations are in line with this study is to determine the&#xD;
      students of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Department e-health literacy levels in Turkey&#xD;
      and will be conducted to determine whether there is effective on the e-health literacy&#xD;
      attended class. In case of a difference, secondary goal is to improve the level of health&#xD;
      literacy by contributing to undergraduate education.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>E-health Literacy Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>E-health Literacy E-health Literacy scale score,The scale score is a minimum of 8 and a maximum of 40 points. The higher the score, the higher the health literacy level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">220</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Health Attitude</condition>
  <condition>Health Knowledge</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1. group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scale score results of first year physiotherapy and rehabilitation department students</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2. group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scale score results of 2nd year physiotherapy and rehabilitation department students</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3. group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scale score results of 3rd year physiotherapy and rehabilitation department students</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>4. group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scale score results of 4th year physiotherapy and rehabilitation department students</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        1st, 2nd, 3rd and 4th year students studying in the Department of Physiotherapy and&#xD;
        Rehabilitation of the Faculty of Health Sciences in 2020-2021 and; The data will be&#xD;
        obtained from the students who agree to participate in the study by using a questionnaire&#xD;
        method.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1st, 2nd, 3rd and 4th year students studying in the Department of Physiotherapy and&#xD;
             Rehabilitation of the Faculty of Health Sciences in 2020-2021&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteer to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who do not study at the Faculty of Health Sciences, Physiotherapy and&#xD;
             Rehabilitation Department of universities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not volunteering to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rabia Tugba Kilic</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ankara Yildirim Beyazıt University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rabia Tugba Kilic</last_name>
    <phone>+905303642866</phone>
    <email>rtugbakilic@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ankara Yildirim Beyazit University,Faculty of Health Sciences, Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <zip>06760</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sørensen K, Van den Broucke S, Fullam J, Doyle G, Pelikan J, Slonska Z, Brand H; (HLS-EU) Consortium Health Literacy Project European. Health literacy and public health: a systematic review and integration of definitions and models. BMC Public Health. 2012 Jan 25;12:80. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-12-80. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22276600</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Whitehead M, Dahlgren G. What can be done about inequalities in health? Lancet. 1991 Oct 26;338(8774):1059-63.</citation>
    <PMID>1681366</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kickbusch IS. Health literacy: addressing the health and education divide. Health Promot Int. 2001 Sep;16(3):289-97.</citation>
    <PMID>11509466</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bilir LK. Patent laws, product life-cycle lengths, and multinational activity. American Economic Review. 2014;104(7):1979-2013.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yılmaz A, Saygılı M, Kaya M. Sağlık Bilimleri Fakültesi Öğrencilerinin E-Sağlık Okuryazarlığı Düzeylerinin Belirlenmesi. Mehmet Akif Ersoy Üniversitesi Sosyal Bilimler Enstitüsü Dergisi. 2020 (May) : 31.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Norman CD, Skinner HA. eHEALS: The eHealth Literacy Scale. J Med Internet Res. 2006 Nov 14;8(4):e27.</citation>
    <PMID>17213046</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Coşkun S, Bebiş H. Psychometric evaluation of a Turkısh version of the e-health literacy scale (e-heals) in adolescent. Gülhane Tip Dergisi. 2015;57(4):378.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ankara Yildirim Beyazıt University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rabia Tugba Kilic</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>e-health literacy, physiotherapy and rehabilitation</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

