<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04777877</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021P000203</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04777877</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PNE Delivered With a VR Headset in Outpatient LBP Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring the Feasibility and Acceptability of Pain Neuroscience Education Delivered With a Virtual Reality Headset to Outpatient Physical Therapy Patients Treated for Low Back Pain: a Pilot Multi-site Implementation Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to explore the feasibility and acceptability of the&#xD;
      delivery of educational content using a virtual reality headset in the setting of an&#xD;
      outpatient physical therapy (PT) course of care for chronic low back pain. We aim to collect&#xD;
      both qualitative and quantitative data regarding: 1) specifics of device use in the course of&#xD;
      PT care 2) acceptability of both the content and delivery method from the therapist and&#xD;
      subject perspective 3) subject attributes to characterize the study population and explore&#xD;
      possible associations with content responses and 4) changes in pain knowledge from pre to&#xD;
      post intervention. Information learned in this pilot study will assist us in 1) improving the&#xD;
      content and delivery method of a chronic pain education program 2) implementing the program&#xD;
      across the Spaulding rehabilitation network and 3) designing a more rigorous effectiveness&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study staff physical therapists will identify potential subjects upon completion of a&#xD;
      standard physical therapy evaluation on patients referred for low back pain. Spaulding&#xD;
      Outpatient sites in Malden, Quincy YMCA and Charlestown will participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inclusion criteria: 1) pain lasting &gt; 3 months and 2) &gt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exclusion criteria: 1) inability to understand and communicate in English 2) inability&#xD;
           to provide informed consent Individuals who meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria will&#xD;
           receive an information study sheet, the full consent form for reference, and hear a&#xD;
           brief explanation of the study from the treating study staff physical therapist. It will&#xD;
           be emphasized that study participation is completely voluntary and refusal to&#xD;
           participate will in no way impact their care at that clinic site or other MGB facilities&#xD;
           either now or in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SUBJECT ENROLLMENT&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once an eligible subject is identified, the evaluating study staff physical therapist will&#xD;
      briefly introduce the study and provide the study information sheet and full consent form for&#xD;
      review. Interested individuals will be contacted by phone by study staff. Study staff&#xD;
      obtaining consent will discuss the details of the study with the individual using the full&#xD;
      consent form and study information sheet as a guide and will cover all of the required&#xD;
      elements of informed consent, including the purpose of the research, the study procedures,&#xD;
      risks and benefits associated with participation, and answer study-related questions.&#xD;
      Subjects will be advised that their clinical care will not be affected in any way if they&#xD;
      decide to participate or decline participation, and that participation can be discontinued at&#xD;
      any time. The principal investigator's and consenting study staff's contact information will&#xD;
      be provided on the information sheet and consent form, and other study staff will provide&#xD;
      their contact information as appropriate. The study will be explained in detail and the&#xD;
      individual will be given the chance to ask any questions. Informed consent will be obtained&#xD;
      verbally over the phone due to the minimal study risk, low study burden, and the necessity of&#xD;
      limiting in-person contact. Study staff will document verbal consent by electronically&#xD;
      signing a copy of the IRB approved telephone information consent document which will be&#xD;
      electronically stored in a protected Dropbox file that only study staff will have access to.&#xD;
      Paper consent forms will not be stored. A copy will be securely emailed via Outlook to the&#xD;
      treating study staff physical therapist. This copy will be printed and provided to the&#xD;
      subject in-person by the treating study staff physical therapist at the subject's next&#xD;
      scheduled physical therapy visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the minimal risk involved, informed consent may be given with less than 12 hours of&#xD;
      notice, or they may be given additional time to consider.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY PROCEDURES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study staff physical therapists will be informed of enrollment. Once enrolled, subjects will&#xD;
      complete the Keele STarT back questionnaire and a pain knowledge check. The pain education&#xD;
      content will be delivered via the Oculus Go virtual reality (VR) headset at the beginning or&#xD;
      end of the subjects scheduled PT appointments. There will be no added costs for content&#xD;
      delivery and no additional study visits will be required outside of the regularly scheduled&#xD;
      PT visits. Upon completing the pain education series, subjects will complete a feedback&#xD;
      survey and a post-pain knowledge check. Study staff physical therapists will complete a&#xD;
      survey for each enrolled subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, demographic information will be collected from the Epic electronic health&#xD;
      record (EHR) such as: age, gender, educational level, relevant past medical history, results&#xD;
      of relevant images, and pertinent physical therapy evaluation and treatment information that&#xD;
      is standard of care for this patient population. This information will be used to&#xD;
      characterize the study sample and begin to identify important attributes that may have more&#xD;
      relevance regarding the response to the content.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain knowledge and beliefs questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion; an average of 4 clinical sessions delivered over 2 to 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>assesses change in subject's knowledge and beliefs about pain</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pain Neuroscience Education delivered via a Virtual Reality Headset</intervention_name>
    <description>Pain educational videos (5) and guided imagery 360 degree nature videos (5)</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        chronic low back pain patients referred for outpatient physical therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pain lasting &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to understand and communicate in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to give informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Binder, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lorna Brown, DPT</last_name>
    <phone>617 952 6813</phone>
    <email>lbrown26@partners.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02129</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lorna Brown, DPT</last_name>
      <phone>617-952-6813</phone>
      <email>lbrown26@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David Saul Binder</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

