<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04773470</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DYSSMA1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04773470</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Quantitative Assessment of Dysphagia in Spinal Muscle Atrophy</brief_title>
  <acronym>DYS-SMA</acronym>
  <official_title>Quantitative Assessment of Dysphagia in Spinal Muscle Atrophy (SMA) - DYS-SMA Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Giessen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Giessen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The major aim of this project is to assess comprehensively frequency and extent of dysphagia&#xD;
      and bulbar dysfunction in SMA1, 2, and 3 patients by applying FEES and validated dysphagia&#xD;
      scores. Further aims are to follow changes of dysphagia over time in newly diagnosed&#xD;
      patients, and in subjects starting treatment with one of the new therapeutic SMA drugs.&#xD;
      Special attention will be paid to subjects treated with Risdiplam. If applicable, the data&#xD;
      will be compared between groups receiving different drugs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) is a progressive autosomal recessive neuromuscular disease&#xD;
      characterized by premature degeneration of the 2nd motor neuron and a broad phenotype. SMA&#xD;
      results from biallelic mutations in the SMN1 gene at 5q13. SMN1 encodes the SMN protein that&#xD;
      is essential for proper function of the anterior horn cells. The estimated incidence is 1 per&#xD;
      6000-11 000 births. The classification of SMA is based on age at symptom onset and maximum&#xD;
      motor function achieved. SMA1 patients develop symptoms within the first 6 months of life and&#xD;
      do not achieve sitting without support. SMA2 patients typically show first symptoms from 6 to&#xD;
      18 months and never learn to walk. SMA3 patients display first clinical signs after the age&#xD;
      of 18 months and achieve walking. Rarely, patients develop first symptoms in adulthood&#xD;
      (SMA4). While defects in SMN1 are the cause of SMA, the severity of disease is related to the&#xD;
      copy number of SMN2, a paralogous gene located next to SMN1 that differs from SMN1 by 5&#xD;
      nucleotides only. This results in a splicing defect reducing the amount of SMN protein&#xD;
      produced by one copy of SMN2 to about 10%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical hallmarks of SMA are progressive muscle weakness and muscular atrophy. Scoliotic&#xD;
      deformities, contractures, reduced head control, limited jaw closure, coughing difficulties,&#xD;
      and impaired clearance of tracheal secretions are common problems. In many patients, bulbar&#xD;
      muscle weakness including dysphagia represents a great diagnostic and therapeutic challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment of SMA remained purely symptomatic for many decades, but this has changed&#xD;
      fundamentally within the last years, since several therapeutic agents have been developed&#xD;
      targeting to correct causal disease mechanisms. Nusinersen, an antisense oligonucleotide&#xD;
      modifying SMN2 splicing, has been approved in the US and in Europe. Onasemnogene abeparvovec,&#xD;
      an AAV9-mediated gene therapy, provides patients with intact SMN1 copies and has also been&#xD;
      licensed in the US and in Europe. Finally, Risdiplam, an oral splicing modifier acting on&#xD;
      SMN2, has been approved in the US and is currently available in Germany for SMA1 and 2&#xD;
      patients via a compassionate use program. Data from two recent studies, FIREFISH (SMA1) and&#xD;
      SUNFISH (SMA2/3) have shown significant improvements in motor and bulbar functions in&#xD;
      Risdiplam treated individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although these new therapies will substantially modify the course of disease and improve the&#xD;
      prognosis of SMA, the treatment of clinical symptoms and their diagnosis will remain&#xD;
      challenging. Dysphagia of variable degree often necessitating artificial feeding to prevent&#xD;
      malnutrition and low body weight occurs in all types of SMA. Poor sucking, swallowing&#xD;
      difficulties, and inadequate mobilization of mucous with increased risk of aspiration and&#xD;
      pneumonia are frequent in SMA1, while restricted jaw mobility and opening as well as weakness&#xD;
      of the jaw muscles are common in SMA2 and 3. Altogether, dysphagia represents an important&#xD;
      factor of morbidity in SMA, and adequate diagnosis and care of this symptom are essential to&#xD;
      maintain quality of life. To achieve this, the application of validated diagnostic methods&#xD;
      and scales are necessary. But until now, only a few retrospective studies with small numbers&#xD;
      of patients or case reports dealing with dysphagia in SMA are on record, and no standardized&#xD;
      assessments using validated tests have been applied. Moreover, no larger study has&#xD;
      systematically analyzed which percentages of SMA1, 2, and 3 patients suffer from dysphagia,&#xD;
      and no data are available about severity of dysphagia in the single types. Furthermore, it is&#xD;
      not known, which effects on swallowing the new therapeutic agents have.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Flexible Endoscopic Evaluation of Swallowing (FEES) is the gold standard of swallowing&#xD;
      imaging, but has not yet been comprehensively and prospectively used for analysis of the&#xD;
      swallowing process in SMA. In patients with neurogenic dysphagia, validated dysphagia&#xD;
      severity scores in tandem with FEES are used since many years, and allow early detection and&#xD;
      improved management of swallowing disorders.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Secretion severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in presence and severity of dysphagia examined via FEES and scored by Murray´s Secretions Severity Rating Scale Minimum value: 0 Maximum value: 3 Higher scores mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dysphagia severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in presence and severity of dysphagia examined via FEES and scored by Rosenbek´s Penetration-Aspiration-Scale Minimum value: 1 Maximum value: 8 Higher scores mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharyngeal residue severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in presence and severity of dysphagia examined via FEES and scored by Yale Pharyngeal Residue Severity Rating Scale Minimum value: 1 Maximum value: 5 Higher scores mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Oral Intake Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of functional oral intake over time. Scored via Functional Oral Intake Scale (FOIS-G, German version): Minimum value 1, maximum value 7; lower scores mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of Dysphagia in Neuromuscular Diseases</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of dysphagia in neuromuscular diseases paired with necessity of oropharyngeal and endotracheal suction as measuered via Neuromuscular Disease Swallowing Status Scale; Minimum value 1, maximum value 8; lower scores mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper limb function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment specifically designed for upper limb function in SMA patients: RULM-Test (Revised Upper Limb Module); minimum value 1, maximum value 37; lower values mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional motor abilites</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Functional motor abilities as measured by HFSME-Test (Hammersmith Functional Motor Scale). Minimum value 0, maximum value 2; lower values mean worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">79</enrollment>
  <condition>Spinal Muscular Atrophy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Spinal Muscle Atrophy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients with Spinal Muscle Atrophy type 1 to 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Flexible Endoscopic Evaluation of Swallowing</intervention_name>
    <description>Endoscopical swallowing study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Spinal Muscle Atrophy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients with genetically determined 5q-linked SMA followed at the neuromuscular center&#xD;
        Gießen&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Informed and written consent signed by the patient or a legal guardian&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical illness that, according to its type and severity, could interfere with the&#xD;
             planned assessments, could have an influence on the parameters to be investigated or&#xD;
             could endanger the patient or test person during the course of the investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation and a positive pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute suicidal tendency or external danger&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor general condition&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samra Hamzic, MA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Giessen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Giessen and Marburg, Campus Giessen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Giessen</city>
        <state>Hesse</state>
        <zip>35392</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscular Atrophy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Muscular Atrophy, Spinal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

