<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04774770</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NKFRC/2018/01/02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04774770</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HED-Start: Evaluating a Positive Skills Intervention for Patients New on Haemodialysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>HED-Start: A Randomised Controlled Trial to Evaluate a Positive Skills Intervention for Patients New on Haemodialysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nanyang Technological University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Kidney Foundation, Singapore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nanyang Technological University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hemodialysis patients often experience barriers and misperceptions that hinder adjustment to&#xD;
      life on dialysis. This study seeks to explore a group-based intervention (titled HED-Start)&#xD;
      developed to improve self-care and emotional wellbeing among incident hemodialysis patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There are potentially modifiable psychosocial barriers and misperceptions about life on&#xD;
      dialysis that hinder adjustment outcomes. It is hypothesized that these may include: poor&#xD;
      understanding on what is needed or 'how to implement treatment principles', misperceptions&#xD;
      related to disease and treatment, catastrophizing beliefs about impact of dialysis and low&#xD;
      level of confidence on ability to manage treatment regime and renegotiate life roles as a&#xD;
      &quot;dialysis patient&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study seeks to explore the feasibility and acceptability of implementing a two-arm&#xD;
      parallel randomized controlled trial of a group-based intervention (titled HED-Start).&#xD;
      HED-Start is specifically developed to reduce psychological distress and support self-care&#xD;
      and self-management outcomes in incident hemodialysis patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drawing on self-management and motivational interviewing principles paradigm, the HED-Start&#xD;
      program aims to facilitate acquisition of skills and knowledge to support and improve&#xD;
      self-care and emotional adjustment outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Care providers (dialysis nurses) and outcomes assessors (research staff conducting the baseline and follow-up questionnaires) will be blinded to participant allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Anxiety and Depression (HADS) scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). The HADS comprises two subscales (anxiety; depression) and can be totaled to produce an overall scale score. Scores range from 0 to 21 for each subscale, and from 0 to 42 for the overall score. Higher scores are indicative of worse anxiety and depression symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Quality of life (WHOQOL-BREF) scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>World Health Organization Quality of Life instrument (WHOQOL-BREF). Two global items (overall quality of life; general health) and two subscales (psychological health; social relationships) from the WHOQOL-BREF are used. Global scores range from 1 to 5, while subscale scores range from 4 to 20. Higher scores indicate better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in kidney disease-related quality of life (KDQOL-SF) scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Kidney Disease Quality of Life instrument (KDQOL-SF). The Burden of Kidney Disease subscale from the KDQOL-SF will be administered. Scores range from 0 to 100, with a higher score reflecting better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Illness Perception scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Brief Illness Perception Questionnaire (BIPQ). The BIPQ consists of 8 subscales (i.e., Consequence, Timeline, Identity, Personal Control, Treatment Control, Concern, Coherence, and Emotional Representation). Subscale scores range from 0 to 10, with higher scores reflective of more negative illness perceptions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Positive and Negative Affect scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Scale of Positive and Negative Experience (SPANE). The SPANE comprises 6 items assessing positive affect and 6 items assessing negative affect. Subscale scores range from 6 to 30. Higher scores in the Positive and Negative affect subscale indicate greater positive and negative affect respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Self-Efficacy for Managing Chronic Disease 6-item Scale scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Self-Efficacy for Managing Chronic Disease 6-item Scale. The overall scale score ranges from 1 to 10. Higher scores reflect greater self-efficacy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Benefit finding in hemodialysis (BFS) scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Benefit Finding Scale (BFS). Two subscales (personal growth; acceptance) and an overall score can be computed. All scores range from 1 to 4, with a higher score reflecting a greater extent of benefit finding.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Resilience scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>2-item Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC-2). The CD-RISC-2 score ranges from 0 to 8. Higher scores indicate greater resilience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Health Education Impact Questionnaire scores from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will be assessed at two time points: [T1] Baseline and [T2] 3 months post-randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Health Education Impact Questionnaire (heiQ). Six subscales from the heiQ (Positive and Active Engagement in Life, Skill and Technique Acquisition, Constructive Attitudes and Approaches, Self-Monitoring and Insight, Health Services Navigation, and Social Integration and Support) will be used to assess other self-management skills. Scores range from 1 to 4. Higher scores indicate greater proficiency with the relevant skill domain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">148</enrollment>
  <condition>End Stage Renal Disease on Dialysis</condition>
  <condition>End Stage Renal Failure on Dialysis</condition>
  <condition>End Stage Renal Disease</condition>
  <condition>End Stage Kidney Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HED-Start Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants assigned to the intervention arm will undergo 4 sessions of the HED-Start program. Each session is 2 hours long and will be conducted fortnightly.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants assigned to the standard care arm will proceed with routine standard care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HED-Start</intervention_name>
    <description>The HED-Start Program is a cognitive-behavioral intervention based on self-management and motivational interviewing principles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>HED-Start Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with end-stage kidney disease (ESKD) and established on&#xD;
             hemodialysis with the National Kidney Foundation Singapore (NKF) for fewer than 90&#xD;
             days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 21 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proficient in spoken and written English or Mandarin&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to give informed consent or refuse to be randomized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have cognitive impairments or psychiatric conditions that preclude consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are currently involved in other intervention trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are failing on dialysis and approaching end of life (supportive/palliative care&#xD;
             pathway)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Konstadina Griva, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nanyang Technological University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Konstadina Griva, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+6569047348</phone>
    <email>konstadina.griva@ntu.edu.sg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Kidney Foundation Singapore</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nanyang Technological University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Konstadina Griva</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Health Psychology and Behavioural Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All deidentified IPD that underlie results in a publication will be available upon reasonable request.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

