<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04775953</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-0002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5UM1AI104681-09</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04775953</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DOTS: Dalbavancin as an Option for Treatment of Staphylococcus Aureus Bacteremia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dalbavancin as an Option for Treatment of S. Aureus Bacteremia (DOTS): A Phase 2b, Multicenter, Randomized, Open-Label, Assessor-Blinded Superiority Study to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Dalbavancin to Standard of Care Antibiotic Therapy for the Completion of Treatment of Patients With Complicated S. Aureus Bacteremia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2b clinical study, multicenter, randomized, open-label, assessor-blinded,&#xD;
      superiority study. The study will compare dalbavancin to standard of care antibiotic therapy&#xD;
      for the completion of therapy in patients with complicated bacteremia or right-sided native&#xD;
      valve Infective Endocarditis (IE) caused by S. aureus who have cleared their baseline&#xD;
      bacteremia. Approximately 200 subjects will be randomized 1:1 to receive either dalbavancin&#xD;
      or a standard of care antibiotic regimen that is based upon the identification and antibiotic&#xD;
      susceptibility pattern of the baseline organism. Subjects randomized to the dalbavancin&#xD;
      treatment group will receive 2 doses of dalbavancin intravenously (IV) 1 week apart (1500 mg&#xD;
      on Day 1 and Day 8 after randomization, with renal dose adjustment if appropriate). Subjects&#xD;
      randomized to the standard of care antibiotic therapy treatment group will receive an&#xD;
      antibiotic regimen considered to be standard of care based on the methicillin susceptibility&#xD;
      pattern of the pathogen isolated at baseline for a duration of 4 to 6 weeks and up to 8 weeks&#xD;
      for patients with vertebral osteomyelitis/discitis. The primary objective is to compare the&#xD;
      Desirability of Outcome Ranking (DOOR) at Day 70 of dalbavancin to that of standard of care&#xD;
      antibiotic therapy used to consolidate therapy for the treatment of subjects with complicated&#xD;
      S. aureus bacteremia in the intent-to-treat population (ITT).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2b clinical study, multicenter, randomized, open-label, assessor-blinded,&#xD;
      superiority study. The study will compare dalbavancin to standard of care antibiotic therapy&#xD;
      for the completion of therapy in patients with complicated bacteremia or right-sided native&#xD;
      valve Infective Endocarditis (IE) caused by S. aureus who have cleared their baseline&#xD;
      bacteremia. Approximately 200 subjects will be randomized 1:1 to receive either dalbavancin&#xD;
      or a standard of care antibiotic regimen that is based upon the identification and antibiotic&#xD;
      susceptibility pattern of the baseline organism. Subjects randomized to the dalbavancin&#xD;
      treatment group will receive 2 doses of dalbavancin intravenously (IV) 1 week apart (1500 mg&#xD;
      on Day 1 and Day 8 after randomization, with renal dose adjustment if appropriate). Subjects&#xD;
      randomized to the standard of care antibiotic therapy treatment group will receive an&#xD;
      antibiotic regimen considered to be standard of care based on the methicillin susceptibility&#xD;
      pattern of the pathogen isolated at baseline for a duration of 4 to 6 weeks and up to 8 weeks&#xD;
      for patients with vertebral osteomyelitis/discitis. The primary objective is to compare the&#xD;
      Desirability of Outcome Ranking (DOOR) at Day 70 of dalbavancin to that of standard of care&#xD;
      antibiotic therapy used to consolidate therapy for the treatment of subjects with complicated&#xD;
      S. aureus bacteremia in the intent-to-treat population (ITT). The secondary objectives are 1)&#xD;
      to compare the clinical outcomes of dalbavancin with the standard of care antibiotic therapy&#xD;
      at day 70 in the modified intent-to-treat population (mITT). 2) to compare the safety of&#xD;
      dalbavancin with that of the standard of care treatment in the modified intent-to-treat&#xD;
      population (mITT). 3) to compare each individual component of the Desirability of Outcome&#xD;
      Ranking (DOOR) outcome by treatment arm, in the intent-to-treat population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Desirability of Outcome Ranking (DOOR) for the treatment of subjects with complicated Staphylococcus aureus bacteremia</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 70</time_frame>
    <description>Desirability of Outcome Ranking (DOOR) will be assessed by: 1.Clinical Success: Resolution of clinical signs and symptoms of S. aureus bacteremia such that no additional antibiotic therapy is required or anticipated for its treatment. 2. Clinical Failure: Absence of clinical success. 3. Infectious Complications such as: Endocarditis, New evidence of metastatic foci of infection (osteomyelitis, visceral abscess, septic joint), relapse - isolation of baseline S. aureus pathogen from a blood culture drawn after randomization, readmission for subsequent care of indication under study, need for additional unplanned source control procedures (abscess debridement or drainage, cardiac valve replacement), change in antibiotic therapy due to inadequate clinical response.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of all-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who experienced a clinical efficacy of antibiotic therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical efficacy, defined as none of 1) Clinical failure; 2) Infectious complications; 3) All-cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who experienced any adverse event (AE) leading to study drug discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who experienced any serious adverse event (SAE) leading to study drug discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who experienced clinical success of antibiotic therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Success: Resolution of clinical signs and symptoms of S. aureus bacteremia such that no additional antibiotic therapy is required or anticipated for its treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants with infectious complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through Day 180</time_frame>
    <description>Infectious Complications such as: Endocarditis, New evidence of metastatic foci of infection (osteomyelitis, visceral abscess, septic joint), relapse - isolation of baseline S. aureus pathogen from a blood culture drawn after randomization, readmission for subsequent care of indication under study, need for additional unplanned source control procedures (abscess debridement or drainage, cardiac valve replacement), change in antibiotic therapy due to inadequate clinical response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Staphylococcal Bacteraemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1 (Dalbavancin)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dalbavancin 1500 mg will be administrated intravenously (IV) over 30 (-/+10) minutes on Day 1 and 1500 mg IV over 30 (-/+10) minutes on Day 8, renally dose-adjusted to 1125 mg for subjects with Creatinine Clearance (CrCl) &lt;30 and not on dialysis. N=100</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>For Methicillin-sensitive Staphylococcus aureus (MSSA): nafcillin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 4 hours for 4-6 weeks) OR oxacillin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 4 hours for 4-6 weeks OR cefazolin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 8 hours for 4-6 weeks) For Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA): vancomycin (dose per local standard of care × 4-6 weeks) OR daptomycin (6-10 mg/kg will be administrated intravenously (IV) daily for 4-6 weeks). N=100</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cefazolin</intervention_name>
    <description>Cefazolin is a semisynthetic cephalosporin analog with broad-spectrum antibiotic action due to inhibition of bacterial cell wall synthesis. Cefazolin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 8 hours for 4-6 weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dalbavancin</intervention_name>
    <description>A second-generation lipoglycopeptide antibiotic synthesized from a fermentation product of Nonomuraea species</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1 (Dalbavancin)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daptomycin</intervention_name>
    <description>Daptomycin (USA) or Cubicin (Spain) is a cyclic lipopeptide antibiotic that inhibits gram-positive bacteria. Daptomycin (6-10 mg/kg will be administrated intravenously (IV) daily for 4-6 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nafcillin</intervention_name>
    <description>Nafcillin is a semi-synthetic antibiotic related to penicillin. Nafcillin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 4 hours for 4-6 weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oxacillin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oxacillin is an antibiotic used in resistant staphylococci infections. Oxacillin (2 g will be administrated intravenously (IV) every 4 hours for 4-6 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vancomycin</intervention_name>
    <description>Vancomycin is a glycopeptide antibiotic product of the organism Amycolatopsis orientalis. Vancomycin (dose per local standard of care × 4-6 weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 (Standard of Care)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Written informed consent obtained from the patient or legally authorized&#xD;
             representative before the initiation of any study-specific procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients &gt; / = to 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A diagnosis of complicated Staphylococcus aureus (either Methicillin-sensitive&#xD;
             Staphylococcus aureus or Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus) bloodstream&#xD;
             infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treated with effective antibiotic therapy for at least 72 hours (maximum 10 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subsequent defervescence for at least 24 hours and clearance of bacteremia from the&#xD;
             qualifying pathogen (at Screening), with negative blood culture incubated for at least&#xD;
             48 hours.*&#xD;
&#xD;
             *Two negative blood cultures incubated for 48 hours are preferred. However, if only a&#xD;
             single blood culture set is drawn, no growth at 48 hours will be considered adequate&#xD;
             to demonstrate clearance. If more than one culture set is drawn, all must show no&#xD;
             growth at 48 hours to be considered evidence of clearance (e.g., 1 of 2 positive&#xD;
             cultures would still be considered as ongoing bacteremia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Provider willing to treat with either dalbavancin for two doses, or standard of care&#xD;
             intravenous monotherapy for at least 4 and no more than 8 weeks from randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients must be willing and able, if discharged, to return to the hospital or&#xD;
             designated clinic for scheduled treatment, laboratory tests, or other procedures as&#xD;
             required by the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. According to the site Principal Investigator or sub-investigator assessment, patients&#xD;
             must be expected to survive with appropriate antibiotic therapy and appropriate&#xD;
             supportive care throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Uncomplicated bacteremia.*&#xD;
&#xD;
             *Uncomplicated Staphylococcus aureus bacteremia is defined as all of the following:&#xD;
             exclusion of endocarditis by echocardiography; catheter-associated bacteremia and&#xD;
             removal of catheter; no implanted prostheses; follow-up blood cultures drawn within 48&#xD;
             hours after initial set that do not grow screening pathogen and all follow-up blood&#xD;
             cultures thereafter do not grow the screening pathogen; defervescence within 72 hours&#xD;
             of initiating effective therapy; and no evidence of metastatic sites of infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Infectious Central Nervous System events, including septic emboli, ischemic or&#xD;
             hemorrhagic stroke, epidural abscess, or meningitis (prior/unrelated Central Nervous&#xD;
             System events are not exclusion criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known or suspected left-sided endocarditis or presence of a perivalvular abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Planned right-sided valve replacement surgery in the first 3 days following&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Presence of prosthetic heart valve, cardiac device** UNLESS removal is planned within&#xD;
             4 days post-randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
             **Implantable cardioverter defibrillator (ICD), permanent pacemaker, valve support&#xD;
             ring, ventricular assist device (VAD).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of intravascular graft or intravascular material (excluding cardiac stents)&#xD;
             UNLESS removal is planned within 4 days post-randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Infected prosthetic joint or extravascular hardware UNLESS removal is planned within 4&#xD;
             days post-randomization OR hardware was placed &gt;60 days before bacteremia and&#xD;
             clinically appears uninfected.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Polymicrobial bacteremia unless the non-Staphylococcus aureus organism is a&#xD;
             contaminant.***&#xD;
&#xD;
             ***Note: If a gram-negative bacteremia or fungemia develops after the qualifying S.&#xD;
             aureus blood culture, AND the patient does not have right-sided endocarditis, AND the&#xD;
             infection can be treated with an antibiotic without efficacy against the patient's S.&#xD;
             aureus isolate (e.g. aztreonam), then the patient may remain eligible. Discussion with&#xD;
             the DMID Medical Officer is strongly encouraged.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Significant hepatic insufficiency (Child-Pugh class C or aspartate transaminase&#xD;
             (AST)/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) values &gt;5x Upper Limit Normal at the time of&#xD;
             randomization).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Immunosuppression****&#xD;
&#xD;
             ****On chemotherapy or immunotherapy for active hematologic malignancy expected to&#xD;
             cause absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 500 cells/mm3 lasting &gt; 7 days during the&#xD;
             study period, recent bone marrow transplant (in the past 90 days), solid organ&#xD;
             transplantation within prior 3 months or receipt of augmented immunosuppression for&#xD;
             rejection within 3 months, chronic high dose oral steroids (equivalent of &gt; / = 20 mg&#xD;
             prednisolone per day for or equivalent, for &gt;2 weeks within the last month), chronic&#xD;
             granulomatous disease, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection with a cluster of&#xD;
             differentiation 4 (CD4) cell count &lt; 100 cells/mm3 based on last known measurement or&#xD;
             patient-reported value.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of hypersensitivity reaction to dalbavancin or other drugs of the glycopeptide&#xD;
             class of antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Treatment with either dalbavancin or oritavancin in the 60 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Infection with Staphylococcus aureus not susceptible to dalbavancin (dalbavancin mean&#xD;
             inhibitory concentration Minimum Inhibitory Concentration (MIC) &gt; 0.25 µg/mL) or&#xD;
             vancomycin (vancomycin Minimum Inhibitory Concentration (MIC) &gt; 2 µg/mL).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Planned treatment with concomitant systemic antibacterial therapy with potential&#xD;
             efficacy against the patient's qualifying Staphylococcus aureus isolate, other than&#xD;
             that allowed in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Pregnant/ nursing females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test***** within 48h&#xD;
             of randomization and use effective contraception for trial duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
             *****If the serum pregnancy test results cannot be obtained before randomization, a&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test may be used for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Other medical or psychiatric condition that may, in the judgment of the investigator,&#xD;
             increase the risk of study participation or interfere with interpretation of study&#xD;
             results.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Unwilling or unable to follow study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Treatment with an investigational drug within 30 days preceding the first dose of&#xD;
             study medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas L. Holland</last_name>
    <phone>19196134268</phone>
    <email>thomas.holland@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama Hospital - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35233</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Medical Center - Internal Medicine - Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817-1460</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harbor UCLA Medical Center - Medicine - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torrance</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90502-2006</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Torrance Memorial Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torrance</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90505</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida Health - Shands Hospital - Division of Infectious Diseases and Global Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ochsner Health - Ochsner Medical Center - Department of Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Orleans</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70121</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center - Medicine - Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Health System - Henry Ford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202-2608</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>William Beaumont Hospital - Royal Oak Campus - Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Royal Oak</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48073-6757</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68198-5400</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Jersey Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Somers Point</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08244</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Presbyterian Hospital - Weill Cornell Medical Center - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065-4870</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Rochester Medical Center - Strong Memorial Hospital - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642-0001</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SUNY Upstate Medical University - Infectious Disease Division</name>
      <address>
        <city>Syracuse</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Atrium Health ID Consultants &amp; Infusion Care Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center - Duke Clinical Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27705-3824</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center - Pediatric Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27705-3941</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Hospital - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East Carolina University - Infectious Diseases and Tropical/Travel Medicine Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27834-9997</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Health and Science University - Adult Infectious Diseases Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239-3098</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh - Medicine - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prisma Health - Greenville Health System - Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29605</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas - MD Anderson Cancer Center - Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030-4000</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carilion Roanoke Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roanoke</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>24014</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 1, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bacteremia</keyword>
  <keyword>Dalbavancin</keyword>
  <keyword>DOTS</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Staphylococcus aureus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bacteremia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vancomycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cefazolin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Daptomycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dalbavancin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oxacillin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nafcillin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

