<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04779710</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>222255</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04779710</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>How Does Dysphagia Assessment in Acute Stroke Affect Pneumonia?</brief_title>
  <official_title>How Does Variation in Assessment and Clinical Management of Dysphagia in Acute Stroke Affect Development of Stroke-associated Pneumonia (SAP)?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Manchester Metropolitan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Stroke Association, United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Manchester Metropolitan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Stroke-associated pneumonia (SAP) is common in acute stroke. A significant risk factor is&#xD;
      dysphagia. To identify dysphagia, patients are screened using a bedside tool and those&#xD;
      suspected of dysphagia then have a specialist Speech and Language Therapy (SLT) assessment.&#xD;
      Currently there is a wide range of screening protocols used. The aim of this research is to&#xD;
      investigate the variation in dysphagia assessment and management to identify what factors&#xD;
      affect the risk of SAP. The type of screen and other variations in management and practice&#xD;
      (such as time from hospital admission to when the screen is done) will be investigated to&#xD;
      identify any associations with higher risk of SAP. A mixed methods study will include a&#xD;
      systematic review of the literature, interviews with patients, carers and staff and a review&#xD;
      of medical records to investigate the patient journey during the first 72 hours from&#xD;
      admission. Findings will be triangulated to inform a national survey of dysphagia screening&#xD;
      and management in hospitals registered with the Sentinel Stroke National Audit Programme&#xD;
      (SSNAP). Data from the survey will be cross-referenced with the SSNAP register and analysed&#xD;
      to identify relationships. Results will inform development of an intervention to reduce SAP&#xD;
      for subsequent feasibility testing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research Questions: 1. How do methods of dysphagia assessment and clinical management during&#xD;
      the first 72 hours of admission affect the risk of stroke patients developing&#xD;
      Stroke-Associated Pneumonia (SAP)? 2. During the first 72 hours of admission, what&#xD;
      organisational factors (for example; oral hygiene routine, adherence of the speech and&#xD;
      language therapy recommendations) affect the risk of stroke patients developing SAP? Aims and&#xD;
      objectives: 1. To explore how variations in dysphagia assessment and management within the&#xD;
      first 72 hours post stroke, impacts on developing SAP? 2. What and how do other&#xD;
      organisational factors affect the development of SAP? Background to the project: Dysphagia&#xD;
      (swallowing problems) occurs in 37-55% of acute stroke patients and is associated with&#xD;
      difficulty swallowing foods, liquids and saliva. Inhalation of oral or gastric contents into&#xD;
      the lungs (aspiration) can lead to pneumonia which increases the risk of mortality and is one&#xD;
      of the main causes of death in the first few days and weeks after stroke. Aspiration&#xD;
      pneumonia is also independently associated with worse rehabilitation outcomes, increased&#xD;
      length of hospitalisation and associated healthcare costs. Aspiration pneumonia develops most&#xD;
      frequently in the first few days of stroke, therefore timely detection and management of&#xD;
      dysphagia is essential. In England and Wales, patients with acute stroke are recommended to&#xD;
      have their swallow screened using a validated multi item screening tool within four hours of&#xD;
      admission and a comprehensive speech and language therapy (SLT) assessment within 72 hours of&#xD;
      admission. However, the Royal College of Physicians (RCP) National Clinical Guideline for&#xD;
      Stroke does not specify the exact screening tool to be used (2016).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Sentinel Stroke National Audit Programme (SSNAP) is the national register of stroke in&#xD;
      England and Wales and collects data for stroke patients in the majority of acute hospitals.&#xD;
      Using this national dataset, Bray et al. (2016) found an association between a delay in&#xD;
      screening and specialist SLT assessment with an increased risk of stroke-associated pneumonia&#xD;
      (SAP) and that reducing the risk of SAP might also reduce mortality after stroke. There are&#xD;
      several possible mechanisms for why delays in dysphagia assessment might lead to an increased&#xD;
      risk of SAP, including variation in who, when and how the screening is carried out. Anecdotal&#xD;
      evidence from the clinical team has found that a number of patients who pass the screen, are&#xD;
      subsequently referred to SLT because of ongoing concerns about risk of aspiration. This&#xD;
      raises the question of whether the timing of the screen is too early for some patients whose&#xD;
      neurological symptoms may still be evolving. Other possible reasons might be that the screen&#xD;
      is not sufficiently sensitive to detect aspiration or the competencies of the staff&#xD;
      undertaking the screen are inadequate. Further studies are required to test these&#xD;
      uncertainties and confirm or refute a causal relationship not only between dysphagia&#xD;
      assessment and management and development of SAP but other potential outcomes, including&#xD;
      death, alternative nutrition and return to normal diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: Ethical approval will be sought from the Yorkshire and the Humber Sheffield Research&#xD;
      Ethics Committee and the Research Ethics Committee at Sheffield Hallam University. Most&#xD;
      hospital (aggregate) level SSNAP data are publicly accessible. A data request will be&#xD;
      submitted for non-publicly available aggregate data, if necessary. Accessing anonymised&#xD;
      patient level data from SSNAP involves applying for data access from Healthcare Quality&#xD;
      Improvement Programme (HQIP) who commission SSNAP and are the data controller. Phase 1 (6&#xD;
      months) Systematic search and review of the literature: A systematic search and review of the&#xD;
      literature will be undertaken on the nature and evidence for early assessment and management&#xD;
      of dysphagia in acute stroke and the risk of developing stroke aspiration pneumonia, using&#xD;
      the Centre for Reviews and Dissemination guidance on systematic reviews . The search&#xD;
      strategies adopted RCP clinical guideline for Stroke will be utilised and developed,&#xD;
      following a building-block approach which will identify search terms for the different&#xD;
      concepts of the search question and culminating in a search of electronic databases. Manual&#xD;
      search methods will also be carried out. The findings from the literature will be synthesised&#xD;
      and used as one of the methods to inform the development of a national survey. A&#xD;
      peer-reviewed, open-access paper will be submitted for publication based on the findings of&#xD;
      the literature. Alongside this, a review of the evidence on questionnaire design to inform&#xD;
      the development of the national survey will be carried out. During this phase, participant&#xD;
      information sheets and consent forms and data collection tools for Phase 2 will be developed.&#xD;
      Service users feedback on the study protocol and design, information accessibility of&#xD;
      participant materials and research outcomes will be sought from stroke survivors and carers.&#xD;
      Phase 2 (18 months) Mixed Methods Study: This phase will further inform the development of&#xD;
      the national survey across the 199 hospitals registered with the SSNAP. The survey will be to&#xD;
      find out about the dysphagia screening protocols used and details of the comprehensive SLT&#xD;
      assessments so as to understand the variations in patient management during the 72 hours from&#xD;
      admission. In addition, the questionnaire will investigate other organisational factors (e.g.&#xD;
      training protocols) or care processes (e.g. policies on positioning, oral hygiene, early&#xD;
      mobilisation) which may affect the development of SAP. To inform this development phase, data&#xD;
      will be collected using two methods; a medical note review and interviews. Patient&#xD;
      information will be collected from the medical notes of 30 consecutive patients admitted to&#xD;
      the Hyper Acute Stroke Unit (HASU) in Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.&#xD;
      Information will be collected on time/day of admission and dysphagia screen, outcome of&#xD;
      screen, other investigations and assessments during 4 hours from admission, outcome of SLT&#xD;
      assessment if indicated and whether SAP is recorded within the first 7 days post stroke. The&#xD;
      data collected from this 72-hour timeline will be descriptively analysed to identify key&#xD;
      events which occur on the patient pathway during the 72-hours. Staff and patient interviews&#xD;
      will explore the views of different groups about what happens during these first 72 hours and&#xD;
      how different factors may impact on patients developing SAP. Patients will be asked if they&#xD;
      would like a carer to attend the interview. The role of the carer would be to support the&#xD;
      patient during the interview recognising that some patients may appreciate a carer being&#xD;
      present. All participants will be provided information about the study and a consent form and&#xD;
      asked to indicate their consent to be involved. Possible areas for investigation include: Are&#xD;
      the SLT dysphagia management plans put in place? Are patients put nil by mouth (NBM)? Who is&#xD;
      responsible for providing oral hygiene for patients and how frequently is it carried out? Are&#xD;
      patients positioned appropriately at mealtimes? Fifteen local and regional interviews will be&#xD;
      undertaken with different staff groups e.g. Stroke Nurse Specialists, staff trained in&#xD;
      dysphagia screening, SLT Stroke Team Leaders, Ward Sisters, Dysphagia Trained&#xD;
      Practitioners/SLTs working in HASUs in Sheffield Teaching Hospitals and other regional NHS&#xD;
      Trust HASUs. User perspectives will be gathered from five interviews with stroke patients and&#xD;
      carers of patients who have received the dysphagia screen and/or had a comprehensive SLT&#xD;
      swallow assessment. Patient participants will be those who have been admitted via the&#xD;
      Neurological Assessment Unit where I work as part of their care team and routinely have&#xD;
      access to their records. All the interviews will be recorded and transcribed. A framework&#xD;
      approach will be used to analyse the interview transcripts and textual data from the&#xD;
      interviews will be managed and coded using QSR NIVO software. The findings from the 72 hour&#xD;
      time line and interviews will be triangulated to gain a more complete picture and to inform&#xD;
      the content of the survey for the follow-on cross-sectional study of national practice. Phase&#xD;
      3 (12 months) National Survey: This phase will involve the development of the survey, in the&#xD;
      form of a questionnaire. Service users will be involved in reviewing the format and&#xD;
      accessibility of the language used. The electronic questionnaire will be piloted across a&#xD;
      target group of SLTs from the Trent Dysphagia Clinical Excellence Network (CEN) who will&#xD;
      access the pilot questionnaire and provide feedback via their virtual Basecamp network. The&#xD;
      questionnaire will be adapted following their feedback before being distributed nationally to&#xD;
      the SLT Clinical Lead for Stroke working in each Hyper/Acute Stroke Unit (H/ASU) in hospitals&#xD;
      in England and Wales registered on the Sentinel Stroke National Audit Programme (SSNAP)&#xD;
      register. The SLT Clinical Lead for Stroke will be identified from the researcher and&#xD;
      research team existing professional networks, wider research networks, for example, the&#xD;
      Council for Allied Health Professions Research (CAPHR), social media networks such as&#xD;
      Twitter, and information that is publicly available. In instances where there is no&#xD;
      pre-existing professional relationship or the information about the appropriate person is not&#xD;
      publicly available the researcher would contact a third party, with the request that they&#xD;
      circulate information about the study with the researcher's contact details, with a further&#xD;
      request that the most appropriate person contact the researcher about the survey if they are&#xD;
      interested in receiving more information. Phase 4 (12 months) Data Analysis: The survey data&#xD;
      will be analysed and data extracted from the SSNAP register. Cross-referencing information&#xD;
      from the questionnaire with centre-level SSNAP data will explore associations between date,&#xD;
      time and type of screen, SLT assessment and the risk of developing SAP. The adjusted odds of&#xD;
      developing SAP will be estimated by fitting multivariable logistic regression models. The&#xD;
      data sets from the seminal research by Bray et al. (2016) will be used for consistency and&#xD;
      comparison of data. The findings of this analysis will be published in an open-access, peer&#xD;
      reviewed journal. Phase 5: (1 year) Write up and development of future research projects: The&#xD;
      programme of work will be written up and the next stages developed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 20, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between incidence of stroke-associated pneumonia and hospital teams using dysphagia screening protocols which use water only compared to water and other consistencies</measure>
    <time_frame>SSNAP 2019 Patient Centred Post 72 hour cohort data will be used for stroke-associated pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Stroke-associated pneumonia was defined as the administration of antibiotics for a new clinical diagnosis of pneumonia in the first 7 days of admission as recorded on the SSNAP register</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between incidence of stroke-associated pneumonia and hospital teams using written guidelines for the first specialist swallow assessment compared to hospital teams that do not use written guidelines for the first specialist assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>SSNAP 2019 Patient Centred Post 72 hour cohort data will be used for stroke-associated pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Stroke-associated pneumonia was defined as the administration of antibiotics for a new clinical diagnosis of pneumonia in the first 7 days of admission as recorded on the SSNAP register</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between incidence of stroke-associated pneumonia and hospital teams that insert nasogastric tubes overnight compared to hospital teams that do not insert nasogastric tubes overnight</measure>
    <time_frame>SSNAP 2019 Patient Centred Post 72 hour cohort data will be used for stroke-associated pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Stroke-associated pneumonia was defined as the administration of antibiotics for a new clinical diagnosis of pneumonia in the first 7 days of admission as recorded on the SSNAP register</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between incidence of stroke-associated pneumonia and hospital teams with a written oral care protocol compared to hospital teams that do not have a written oral care protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>SSNAP 2019 Patient Centred Post 72 hour cohort data will be used for stroke-associated pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Stroke-associated pneumonia was defined as the administration of antibiotics for a new clinical diagnosis of pneumonia in the first 7 days of admission as recorded on the SSNAP register</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">113</enrollment>
  <condition>Dysphagia</condition>
  <condition>Pneumonia</condition>
  <condition>Acute Stroke</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Staff Survey</intervention_name>
    <description>A mixed mode survey design comprising of a self-administered electronic survey with a secondary option of a postal survey. The survey population was Speech and Language Therapy (SLT) Clinical Leads for Acute Stroke in Hyper/Acute Hospital Stroke Units in England and Wales. The sample frame was Routinely Admitting, and Non-Routinely Admitting Acute Stroke Hospital Teams registered on the Sentinel Stroke National Audit Programme (SSNAP) register. One hundred and sixty-six hospital teams were included after exclusions. Survey participants were asked to respond about assessment and management of dysphagia and other clinical processes during the first seven days of a person's admission to hospital following a stroke. Respondents were asked to respond about practice on behalf of the Stroke Unit rather than as an individual practitioner.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Speech and Language Therapy Clinical Leads in Hyper/Acute Stroke Units in hospitals in&#xD;
        England and Wales&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speech and Language Therapist working in a National Health Service (NHS) Hospital&#xD;
             Stroke Unit in England and Wales&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non speech and language therapists&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speech and Language Therapists not working in a NHS Hospital Stroke Unit in England&#xD;
             and Wales&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sabrina Eltringham</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Manchester Metropolitan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sheffield</city>
        <zip>S10 2JF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.strokeaudit.org/Home</url>
    <description>Sentinel Stroke National Audit Programme</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.york.ac.uk/media/crd/Systematic_Reviews.pdf</url>
    <description>Centre for Reviews and Dissemination</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martino R, Foley N, Bhogal S, Diamant N, Speechley M, Teasell R. Dysphagia after stroke: incidence, diagnosis, and pulmonary complications. Stroke. 2005 Dec;36(12):2756-63. Epub 2005 Nov 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16269630</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vernino S, Brown RD Jr, Sejvar JJ, Sicks JD, Petty GW, O'Fallon WM. Cause-specific mortality after first cerebral infarction: a population-based study. Stroke. 2003 Aug;34(8):1828-32. Epub 2003 Jul 10.</citation>
    <PMID>12855836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ingeman A, Andersen G, Hundborg HH, Svendsen ML, Johnsen SP. In-hospital medical complications, length of stay, and mortality among stroke unit patients. Stroke. 2011 Nov;42(11):3214-8. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.110.610881. Epub 2011 Aug 25.</citation>
    <PMID>21868737</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Katzan IL, Dawson NV, Thomas CL, Votruba ME, Cebul RD. The cost of pneumonia after acute stroke. Neurology. 2007 May 29;68(22):1938-43.</citation>
    <PMID>17536051</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Westendorp WF, Nederkoorn PJ, Vermeij JD, Dijkgraaf MG, van de Beek D. Post-stroke infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2011 Sep 20;11:110. doi: 10.1186/1471-2377-11-110. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21933425</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bray BD, Smith CJ, Cloud GC, Enderby P, James M, Paley L, Tyrrell PJ, Wolfe CD, Rudd AG; SSNAP Collaboration. The association between delays in screening for and assessing dysphagia after acute stroke, and the risk of stroke-associated pneumonia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017 Jan;88(1):25-30. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2016-313356. Epub 2016 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>27298147</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eltringham SA, Kilner K, Gee M, Sage K, Bray BD, Pownall S, Smith CJ. Impact of Dysphagia Assessment and Management on Risk of Stroke-Associated Pneumonia: A Systematic Review. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018;46(3-4):99-107. doi: 10.1159/000492730. Epub 2018 Sep 10.</citation>
    <PMID>30199856</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eltringham SA, Kilner K, Gee M, Sage K, Bray BD, Smith CJ, Pownall S. Factors Associated with Risk of Stroke-Associated Pneumonia in Patients with Dysphagia: A Systematic Review. Dysphagia. 2020 Oct;35(5):735-744. doi: 10.1007/s00455-019-10061-6. Epub 2019 Sep 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31493069</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eltringham SA, Smith CJ, Pownall S, Sage K, Bray B. Variation in Dysphagia Assessment and Management in Acute Stroke: An Interview Study. Geriatrics (Basel). 2019 Oct 25;4(4). pii: E60. doi: 10.3390/geriatrics4040060.</citation>
    <PMID>31731452</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eltringham SA, Pownall S, Bray B, Smith CJ, Piercy L, Sage K. Experiences of Dysphagia after Stroke: An Interview Study of Stroke Survivors and Their Informal Caregivers. Geriatrics (Basel). 2019 Dec 7;4(4). pii: E67. doi: 10.3390/geriatrics4040067.</citation>
    <PMID>31817883</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Manchester Metropolitan University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sabrina Eltringham</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>assessment</keyword>
  <keyword>acute stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>dysphagia</keyword>
  <keyword>aspiration pneumonia</keyword>
  <keyword>screening</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 20, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/10/NCT04779710/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

