<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03328416</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017P001456</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03328416</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Augmented Reality Headset as Adjunct Display Monitor in AMIGO</brief_title>
  <official_title>Augmented Reality Headset as Adjunct Display Monitor in AMIGO</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators' overarching goal is to investigate whether use of an augmented reality&#xD;
      display system (utilized in addition to, not as a replacement to, conventional CT and MRI&#xD;
      displays currently available in the procedure suite) streamlines the process of a procedure&#xD;
      and/or provides ease of access to helpful pre-procedure and intra-procedure imaging&#xD;
      information that would be more difficult and time-consuming to obtain with the conventional&#xD;
      imaging display systems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Augmented reality is a computer display technology that represents an incremental improvement&#xD;
      over current computer monitors. Currently, a patient has a pre-procedure or intra-procedure&#xD;
      CT or MRI scan and the scan images are displayed for the proceduralist on computer monitors&#xD;
      in the procedure suite. Typically, only a single, or several selected, cross-sectional images&#xD;
      can be viewed at a given time. With an augmented reality display headset, the pre-procedure&#xD;
      and intra-procedure CT or MR images, including 3D reconstructions, can be displayed on&#xD;
      transparent eyeglasses worn by the proceduralist. Moreover, the images are registered to the&#xD;
      patient's location on the operating table and the images can be continuously updated to&#xD;
      correspond with the body part in the proceduralist's field of view. Augmented reality display&#xD;
      systems could thus decreased perceived work load of a procedure by allowing natural posture&#xD;
      throughout the procedure, streamline and improve the clinical workflow, and provide the&#xD;
      proceduralist with information in a manner that more readily facilitates three-dimensional&#xD;
      understanding of the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators' overarching goal is to investigate whether use of an augmented reality&#xD;
      display system (utilized in addition to, not as a replacement to, conventional CT and MRI&#xD;
      displays currently available in the procedure suite) streamlines the process of a procedure&#xD;
      and/or provides ease of access to helpful pre-procedure and intra-procedure imaging&#xD;
      information that would be more difficult and time-consuming to obtain with the conventional&#xD;
      imaging display systems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The three aims are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine if the augmented reality display system streamlines workflow.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine if the augmented reality display system decreases perceived work load.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine if the augmented reality display system facilitates access to helpful&#xD;
           pre-procedure and intra-procedure imaging information as compared to traditional display&#xD;
           systems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the augmented reality display system will streamline&#xD;
      workflow by reducing time required to stop the procedure to look away from the operative&#xD;
      field to the conventional hanging monitor and then look back to the operative field and&#xD;
      reorient to the operative field space.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the augmented reality display system will decrease&#xD;
      perceived work load by reducing intra-procedure postural strain by projecting the images on a&#xD;
      headset in addition to on traditional monitors hanging from the procedure-suite ceiling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the augmented reality display system will facilitate&#xD;
      access to helpful pre-procedure and intra-procedure imaging information because it will allow&#xD;
      real-time projection of three-dimensional reconstructed images over the operative site with&#xD;
      the images reflecting the point-of-view and field-of-view of the proceduralist. While this&#xD;
      information can be generated and projected on traditional display systems, the positioning of&#xD;
      the imaging is likely inferior as it can only mimic the point of view and field of view of&#xD;
      the proceduralist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All procedures will be performed in accordance with normal standard of care for the condition&#xD;
      being treated. The only difference in care will be that the proceduralist will have imaging&#xD;
      information projected on a headset in addition to on the conventional monitors that hang from&#xD;
      the procedure suite ceiling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A single REDCap survey will be sent to the performing co-investigator proceduralist&#xD;
      (interventional radiologist or surgeon) following each procedure. The survey will include the&#xD;
      NASA Task Load Index (TLX) to assess the work load associated with the procedure as well as&#xD;
      several questions designed to determine if the NASA TLX score would likely have been higher&#xD;
      or lower if the augmented reality system was not used and several questions designed to&#xD;
      determine if the augmented reality system allowed visualization of imaging information in a&#xD;
      way that was helpful in procedure planning or intraprocedural approach. The NASA TLX method&#xD;
      assesses work load on five 7-point scales and the additional questions assess procedural&#xD;
      strain on 7-point scales.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measures are the TLX scores. If these scores achieve statistical&#xD;
      significance in one sample statistical tests then use of the augmented reality display will&#xD;
      be considered successful. Although co-investigators will be subjects, the co-investigators&#xD;
      have no relationship with the device maker and have no invested interest in using this device&#xD;
      unless the device improves procedure efficiency and success; as such, it is unlikely that&#xD;
      co-investigators as subjects will bias the results as the co-investigators will not want to&#xD;
      utilize the device if it has a negative impact on workflow or if it increases perceived work&#xD;
      load.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Expected technology was not available.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Scores from NASA Task Load Index (TLX) with supplemental questions to assess procedure strain</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The NASA TLX method assesses work load on five 7-point scales and the additional questions assess procedural strain on 7-point scales. Each 7-point scale item will be assessed independently. Total scores will also be summed and assessed. Higher scores translate to a higher work load (worse outcome).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignancy</condition>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Augmented Reality</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The neurointerventional radiologist will have imaging information projected on a headset in addition to on the conventional monitors that hang from the procedure suite ceiling.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Augmented Reality</intervention_name>
    <description>The neurointerventional radiologist will have imaging information projected on a headset in addition to on the conventional monitors that hang from the procedure suite ceiling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Augmented Reality</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient referred to one of the study co-investigators for a procedure that&#xD;
             requires either: Pre-procedure planning that utilizes either CT or MR images;&#xD;
             Intra-procedure imaging for the purpose of needle placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 18 at time of procedure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas C Lee, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham &amp; Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas C. Lee</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Radiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Image-Guided Biopsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Multidetector Computed Tomography</keyword>
  <keyword>Diagnostic Imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Cryosurgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Ablation Techniques</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

