<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03323944</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>827644 (UPCC 14217)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03323944</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CAR T Cell Immunotherapy for Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Study of Human Chimeric Antigen Receptor Modified T Cells (CAR T Cells) in Patients With Pancreatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stand Up To Cancer</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lustgarten</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Phase I study to establish the safety and feasibility of both intravenous administration and&#xD;
      local delivery of lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells in patients with histologically&#xD;
      confirmed unresectable or metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase I study evaluating the safety and feasibility of lentiviral transduced&#xD;
      huCART-meso cells in up to 4 cohorts. Lymphodepleting chemotherapy will not be utilized as&#xD;
      part of the planned dosing strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Cohort 1 (N=3-6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x107/m2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
      huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intravenous infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Enrollment into Cohort 1 will be paused after the 3rd subject is infused to allow for a&#xD;
           formal DLT assessment (performed by the Clinical PI and Medical Director) and DSMB&#xD;
           review. If 1 DLT/3 subjects occurs in Cohort 1, the Sponsor (with guidance from the&#xD;
           DSMB), will determine whether the study will enroll an additional 3 subjects at this&#xD;
           dose level to further establish safety via intravenous infusion, or advance to Cohorts 2&#xD;
           and 3 to explore local delivery of huCART-meso cells at the same dose level. If 0 DLT/3&#xD;
           subjects or 1 DLT/6 subjects occurs at any time, the study may advance to Cohorts 2 and&#xD;
           3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If 2 DLTs occur at this dose level at any time, enrollment in Cohort 1 will be stopped&#xD;
           and the dose will be de-escalated by 10-fold to 1-3x106 cells/m2 (Cohort -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The infusions in Cohort 1 will be staggered by at least 28 days to allow for the&#xD;
           assessment of DLTs for cohort progression, expansion, or dose de-escalation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the event that 2 DLTs occur among subjects enrolled in Cohort 1, then enrollment in Cohort&#xD;
      1 will be stopped and the dose will be de-escalated by 10-fold to 1-3x106 cells/m2. This&#xD;
      de-escalated cohort will be designated Cohort -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Cohort -1 (N=3-6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x106 cells/m2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
      huCART-meso cells on day 0. Up to 6 subjects will be infused in Cohort -1 if ≤ 1 DLT occurs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If 0 DLT/3 subjects or 1 DLT/6 subjects occurs in Cohort 1, the study may advance to Cohorts&#xD;
      2 and 3. Enrollment into Cohort 2 and Cohort 3 may occur in parallel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 2 (N= up to 6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x107/m2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intraperitoneal (i.p.) administration. The initial i.p.&#xD;
           infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of huCART-meso cells via&#xD;
           intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given between 21-42 days apart.&#xD;
           The subject must meet eligibility to receive additional infusions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           o Infusion #1 for the first three subjects in Cohort 2 will be staggered by at least 21&#xD;
           days to allow for the assessment of DLTs. A DLT assessment will be performed after the&#xD;
           2nd subject reaches the Day 21 safety follow-up visit. If no DLTs are identified in the&#xD;
           1st two subjects, subsequent infusions may occur consecutively, however no more than two&#xD;
           new subjects may be infused concurrently.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 3 (N= up to 6): will receive a single dose of 1-3x107/m2 lentiviral transduced&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intrahepatic delivery (Hepatic Arterial Infusion). The&#xD;
           initial intrahepatic infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of&#xD;
           huCART-meso cells via intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given&#xD;
           between 21-42 days apart. The subject must meet eligibility to receive additional&#xD;
           infusions.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Infusion #1 for the first three subjects in Cohort 3 will be staggered by at least&#xD;
                21 days to allow for the assessment of DLTs. A DLT assessment will be performed&#xD;
                after the 2nd subject reaches the Day 21 safety follow-up visit. If no DLTs are&#xD;
                identified in the 1st two subjects, subsequent infusions may occur consecutively,&#xD;
                however no more than two new subjects may be infused concurrently.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse events will be collected and evaluated during the protocol specified adverse event&#xD;
      reporting period. Subjects will be continually evaluated for dose-limiting toxicities (DLT).&#xD;
      In the event of 2 DLTs in a specific cohort, additional enrollment and treatment activity&#xD;
      will be paused to allow for further investigation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of study subjects with treatment-related adverse events using NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor response rates measured according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST 1.1) criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28, Month 3, Month 6</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">8</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Cancer of the Pancreas</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: huCART-meso cells via intravenous infusion (IV).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^7/m^2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intravenous infusion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort -1: low dose huCART-meso cells via intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the event that 2 DLTs occur among subjects enrolled in Cohort 1, then enrollment in Cohort 1 will be stopped and the dose will be de-escalated by 10-fold to 1-3x10^6 cells/m2. Subjects will receive a single dose of 1-3x10^6 cells/m^2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells on day 0.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2 - huCART meso cells via intraperitoneal infusion (IP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Eligible subjects will receive a single dose of 1-3x107/m2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intraperitoneal (i.p.) administration. The initial i.p. infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of huCART-meso cells via intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given between 21-42 days apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3 - huCART meso cells via intrahepatic infusion (hepatic arterial infusion)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Eligible subjects will receive a single dose of 1-3x107/m2 lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells on day 0 via intrahepatic delivery (Hepatic Arterial Infusion). The initial intrahepatic infusion may be followed by up to two additional infusions of huCART-meso cells via intravenous (IV) administration at the same dose level, given between 21-42 days apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>huCART-meso cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous administration or local delivery of lentiviral transduced huCART-meso cells.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort -1: low dose huCART-meso cells via intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: huCART-meso cells via intravenous infusion (IV).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2 - huCART meso cells via intraperitoneal infusion (IP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3 - huCART meso cells via intrahepatic infusion (hepatic arterial infusion)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with the following diagnoses:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Cohorts 1 and -1: Histologically confirmed unresectable or metastatic&#xD;
                       pancreatic adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Cohort 2: Histologically confirmed unresectable or metastatic pancreatic&#xD;
                       adenocarcinoma; and either cytologically-proven ascites or known peritoneal&#xD;
                       disease on radiologic imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Cohort 3: Histologically confirmed unresectable or metastatic pancreatic&#xD;
                       adenocarcinoma with liver metastases as confirmed by pathology or&#xD;
                       radiographic imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. INCLUSION CRITERIA HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Failure of at least one prior standard of care chemotherapy for advanced stage&#xD;
                  disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Subjects must have measurable disease as defined by RECIST 1.1 criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Satisfactory organ and bone marrow function as defined by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                  i. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000/μl ii. Platelets ≥75,000/μl iii. Hemoglobin&#xD;
                  ≥ 8 g/dL iv. Bilirubin ≤ 2.0x the institutional normal upper limit v. Creatinine&#xD;
                  ≤ 1.5x the institutional normal upper limit vi. Albumin ≥ 2 vii. Serum alanine&#xD;
                  aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤5x the institutional&#xD;
                  normal upper limit viii. Cardiac ejection fraction of ≥40% as measured by resting&#xD;
                  echocardiogram, with no clinically significant pericardial effusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Blood coagulation parameters: PT such that international normalized ratio (INR)&#xD;
                  is ≤ 1.5 and a PTT ≤ 1.2 time the upper limit of normal unless the patient is&#xD;
                  therapeutically anti-coagulated for history of cancer-related thrombosis and has&#xD;
                  stable coagulation parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Provides written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Subjects of reproductive potential must agree to use acceptable birth control&#xD;
                  methods&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. EXCLUSION CRITERIA HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Active invasive cancer other than pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Patients with active&#xD;
                  non-invasive cancers (such as non-melanoma skin cancer, superficial cervical and&#xD;
                  bladder cancer, or prostate cancer with PSA level &lt; 1.0) are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Active hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Active autoimmune disease (including but not limited to: systemic lupus&#xD;
                  erythematosus, Sjogren's syndrome, rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis, multiple&#xD;
                  sclerosis, inflammatory bowel disease, etc.) requiring immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
                  within 4 weeks prior to eligibility confirmation by physician-investigator, with&#xD;
                  the exception of thyroid replacement.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Patients with ongoing or active infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Planned concurrent treatment with systemic high dose corticosteroids. Patients&#xD;
                  may be on a stable low dose of steroids (&lt;10mg equivalent of prednisone) for&#xD;
                  chronic respiratory conditions or adrenal insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Patients requiring supplemental oxygen therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Prior therapy with lentiviral gene modified cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to study product excipients (human serum&#xD;
                  albumin, DMSO, and Dextran 40)&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Any clinically significant pericardial effusion, Class II-IV cardiovascular&#xD;
                  disability according to the New York Heart Association Classification (see&#xD;
                  Appendix 3) or other cardiovascular condition that would preclude assessment of&#xD;
                  mesothelin induced pericarditis or that may worsen as a result of toxicities&#xD;
                  expected for this study. This determination will be made by a cardiologist if&#xD;
                  cardiac issues are suspected.&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Any clinically significant pleural or peritoneal effusion that cannot be drained&#xD;
                  with standard approaches. An indwelling drainage device placed prior to&#xD;
                  eligibility confirmation by physician-investigator is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. EXCLUSION CRITERIA HAS BEEN RETIRED&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Treatment with a PD-1 or PD-L1 inhibitor, including but not limited to nivolumab,&#xD;
                  pembrolizumab, atezolizumab, and/or durvalumab, within 2 months prior to&#xD;
                  eligibility confirmation by investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Patients with significant lung disease as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with radiographic evidence of greater than lobar lymphangitic pulmonary&#xD;
                  involvement, greater than lobar bronchial wall thickening suggestive of&#xD;
                  peribronchial lymphatic disease extension, and/or evidence of extensive bilateral&#xD;
                  parenchymal metastatic burden.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with radiographic and/or clinical evidence of active radiation&#xD;
                  pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with radiographic evidence of underlying interstitial lung disease,&#xD;
                  including evidence of unresolved drug toxicity from any agent (e.g. chemotherapy,&#xD;
                  targeted agents, amiodarone, nitrofurantoin, etc) 17. Cohort 3 Subjects Only:&#xD;
                  Patients with a contraindication to IV contrast.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark O'Hara, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistant Professor of Medicine, Penn Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>metastatic adenocarcinoma, pancreas</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

