<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04406584</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-55353</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04406584</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intranasal Injection of PRP Versus Saline for Treatment of Olfactory Dysfunction</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intranasal Injection of Platelet-rich Plasma Versus Saline for Treatment of Olfactory Dysfunction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This randomized clinical trial will evaluate the benefit of platelet-rich plasma (PrP) in the&#xD;
      treatment of olfactory dysfunction. PrP can be isolated from a patient's own blood and has&#xD;
      been found in previous studies to have anti-inflammatory and pro-regenerative properties. It&#xD;
      has been used across multiple specialties, such as Orthopedics, Facial Plastics, Dermatology,&#xD;
      Neurology in injected form to treat a wide variety of tissues to encourage the body's&#xD;
      inherent regenerative capacity. The investigators have completed a pilot study here&#xD;
      evaluating it's use in olfactory loss which demonstrated safety and also suggested efficacy.&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators aim to assess the ability of PrP to improve olfactory function&#xD;
      in patients with decreased sense of smell.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Olfactory dysfunction constitutes a common impairment in the general population, affecting&#xD;
      nearly 20 million in the USA and severely impairing quality of life. Unfortunately, this&#xD;
      problem is often permanent, and no effective treatment is available at this time. Although&#xD;
      many etiologies exist for olfactory loss, the underlying pathology is thought to be permanent&#xD;
      damage to the olfactory bulb, nerves or basal cells of the olfactory system. Platelet-rich&#xD;
      plasma (PRP) is an autologous treatment derived from a patient's own blood and has been found&#xD;
      to have pro-nerve regenerative properties in animal and human studies. A small pilot study at&#xD;
      the principal investigator's institution demonstrated improved olfactory thresholds in&#xD;
      patients with partial olfactory loss who received PrP injections. In this randomized clinical&#xD;
      trial, the investigators aim to further evaluate the ability of PRP injections to restore&#xD;
      olfactory function in human subjects. Given the lack of effective current treatments, a&#xD;
      therapeutic benefit of PrP would represent a crucial advancement in research and treatment of&#xD;
      olfactory loss, which affects a large swath of the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be seen at the Stanford Sinus center, or at the newly added collaborating&#xD;
      institution UCSD, and those with smell loss will be identified by the clinically validated&#xD;
      patient directed survey: The UPSIT (University of Pennsylvania Smell Identification Test).&#xD;
      They will undergo nasal endoscopy to exclude structural causes of smell loss including mass&#xD;
      or tumor. Nasal endoscopy will be performed to exclude structural causes of olfactory, using&#xD;
      topical anesthesia (1% phenylephrine &amp; 4% lidocaine topical spray). THESE ABOVE STEPS&#xD;
      CONSTITUTE STANDARD OF CARE FOR EVALUATION OF OLFACTORY LOSS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The timing of the initial research visit will depend on the evolution of the current covid-19&#xD;
      pandemic and adhere to Stanford guidelines regarding research visits. At the initial research&#xD;
      visit, patients meeting inclusion criteria will be evaluated in a procedure room at the&#xD;
      Stanford Sinus center. A baseline Sniffin' sticks smell test will be performed (see below). A&#xD;
      small vial of blood will be drawn from the patient at the Blake Wilbur first floor&#xD;
      laboratory. The research coordinator will walk the patient back to clinic along with the&#xD;
      patient's blood smple. PRP will be isolated from the blood by the study investigator,&#xD;
      following manufacturer instructions from the PurePRP preparation kit (Emcyte corporation),&#xD;
      which will involve use of a centrifuge located in the clinic for this purpose. 0.5 mL of the&#xD;
      PRP solution will be set aside for platelet quantification. From the remaining PRP solution,&#xD;
      patients will then receive 1ml of autologous PrP or sterile saline (0.9% Sodium Chloride),&#xD;
      which will be injected into the superior septum mucosa near the olfactory groove bilaterally.&#xD;
      Patients will be blindfolded during injection to prevent identification of the injected&#xD;
      specimen, and will previously be randomized in a 1:1 ratio via a random number generator.&#xD;
      Patients will be monitored for side effects for 15 minutes. (We routinely perform nasal&#xD;
      endoscopy with injection and associated procedures in our clinic, which patients tolerate&#xD;
      very well.) Injections will then be performed twice more at 2-weeks and 4-weeks after the&#xD;
      initial injection, for a total of 3 biweekly injections. ALL OF THE ABOVE STEPS ARE FOR&#xD;
      RESEARCH PURPOSES.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Sniffin' Sticks test is a validated, non-invasive assessment of olfactory function via&#xD;
      presentation of scented felt pens to blindfolded patients. The output is the TDI score&#xD;
      (threshold, discrimination, identification). The TDI score will be recorded at baseline&#xD;
      (initial research visit), and then at 1-month and 3-months after the initial test, for a&#xD;
      total of 3 tests. The first test will occur before the first injection, and the second test&#xD;
      will be performed before the third injection. There will be no injection at the last (third)&#xD;
      test. THE ABOVE VISITS ARE FOR RESEARCH PURPOSES.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study time-line is summarized as follows Visit 1: 1st Sniffin' Sticks test, 1st injection&#xD;
      Visit 2: 2 weeks after Visit 1, second injection Visit 3: 4 weeks after Visit 1, second test,&#xD;
      third injection Visit 4: 3 months after Visit 1, third test&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Comparison of two randomized groups</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Blindfold during injection and during portions of the smell test</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Smelling ability</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Using Sniffin' Sticks olfactory testing pens to test smell</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Olfactory Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Olfaction Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Olfactory Nerve Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Olfactory Nerve Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Olfactory Nerve Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Post-Viral Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Injection of 1cc saline into olfactory cleft x4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Platelet Rich Plasma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Injection of 1cc patient's own platelet rich plasma (PRP) into olfactory cleft x4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Injection into olfactory cleft</intervention_name>
    <description>Already stated above.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Platelet Rich Plasma</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &gt;= 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have olfactory loss (based off of UPSIT score &lt;= 33 out of 40)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who also have an age-adjusted TDI Sniffin' Sticks score that demonstrates&#xD;
             hyposmia (TDI&gt;16 and &lt;30)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Etiology of olfactory loss is due to URI or idiopathic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 6 months of olfactory loss but less than 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients can have been previously treated with oral and topical steroids but this is&#xD;
             not a requirement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will receive concurrent olfactory training - the practice of smelling strong&#xD;
             odors (standard of care)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to read and understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able and willing to provide Informed Consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &lt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who have any structural abnormalities on nasal endoscopy or radiographic&#xD;
             imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Olfactory loss due to trauma, chronic sinusitis / inflammation / polyps, neoplasms, or&#xD;
             neurodegenerative diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had olfactory loss &gt; 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with bleeding disorders or on blood thinners such as coumadin and plavix&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zara M. Patel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zara M Patel, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6507235651</phone>
    <email>zmpatel@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California - San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92093</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carol Yan, MD</last_name>
      <email>c1yan@health.ucsd.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zara M Patel, MD</last_name>
      <phone>650-723-5651</phone>
      <email>zmpatel@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://profiles.stanford.edu/zara-patel</url>
    <description>Dr. Patel's Stanford University School of Medicine Profile and Link to Donate to Research</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yan CH, Mundy DC, Patel ZM. The use of platelet-rich plasma in treatment of olfactory dysfunction: A pilot study. Laryngoscope Investig Otolaryngol. 2020 Feb 21;5(2):187-193. doi: 10.1002/lio2.357. eCollection 2020 Apr.</citation>
    <PMID>32337347</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Stanford University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zara M. Patel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor and Director of Endoscopic Skull Base Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>olfactory</keyword>
  <keyword>olfactory loss</keyword>
  <keyword>anosmia</keyword>
  <keyword>hyposmia</keyword>
  <keyword>olfactory dysfunction</keyword>
  <keyword>prp</keyword>
  <keyword>platelet enriched plasma</keyword>
  <keyword>platelet rich plasma</keyword>
  <keyword>endoscopic</keyword>
  <keyword>covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>post-viral disorder</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olfaction Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olfactory Nerve Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olfactory Nerve Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

