<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03694600</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LAM-2018-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03694600</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Multi-analyte Blood Test</brief_title>
  <acronym>CLiMB</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Clinical Trial to Detect Liver Cancer Through Quantification of cfDNA Methylation in Blood Samples: A LAM Insight Trial Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laboratory for Advanced Medicine, Indiana</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laboratory for Advanced Medicine, Indiana</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a clinical trial designed to evaluate the performance of a multi-analyte blood test&#xD;
      alone, ultrasound alone and the combination of both the multi-analyte blood test and&#xD;
      ultrasound for the detection of HCC within a population that is at high risk for HCC due to&#xD;
      liver cirrhosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This multi-site, prospective study is designed to compare the sensitivity and specificity of&#xD;
      a multi-analyte blood test alone, ultrasound alone and the combination of the multi-analyte&#xD;
      blood test and ultrasound for the detection of HCC within a population at high risk of HCC&#xD;
      due to liver cirrhosis. Subjects will be enrolled until the pre-determined number of subjects&#xD;
      are enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects at high risk for developing HCC due to liver cirrhosis and who are eligible for&#xD;
      liver cancer surveillance as determined by the patient's physician and who meet all inclusion&#xD;
      and exclusion eligibility criteria as described in this protocol, will be invited to&#xD;
      participate in this study. Subjects will then read, understand and sign the Informed Consent&#xD;
      Form and the HIPAA Authorization Agreement for Medical Records Form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each subject upon enrollment, the following blood analytes will also be determined:&#xD;
      creatinine, prothrombin time, bilirubin, blood platelet count, ALT, AST and ALP. The results&#xD;
      of all clinical laboratory tests will be recorded by use of the subject's Case Report Form.&#xD;
      Whole blood samples drawn for the multi-analyte blood test will be collected (according to&#xD;
      the instructions provided with each sample collection kit) by using the multi-analyte Sample&#xD;
      Collection, Stabilization and Shipping Kit, and shipped to a central LAM laboratory for&#xD;
      testing. Samples will be assayed by laboratory technicians blinded to the results of any&#xD;
      other testing. Within the same clinical visit as the blood draws (when possible), subjects&#xD;
      will undergo conventional ultrasound to examine the liver. Every subject will then go on to&#xD;
      diagnostic imaging by multiphasic MRI. The results of diagnostic imaging will primarily be&#xD;
      scored by LI-RADS score and the number and size of any malignant lesions identified will be&#xD;
      recorded. The images of all MRI, CT, or ultrasound will be saved and uploaded for evaluation&#xD;
      by a blinded, centralized team of radiologists to confirm diagnosis. Any biopsy results or&#xD;
      surgical pathology results that are generated for study subjects as part of current clinical&#xD;
      practice will also be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study procedures will consist of conventional ultrasound to examine the liver, providing&#xD;
      blood samples for testing with the multi-analyte blood test and other conventional blood&#xD;
      analytes, and diagnostic imaging by multiphasic MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon enrolling in the study, subjects will commence the Initial Surveillance Visit (t=0&#xD;
      months). During the Initial Surveillance Visit, all enrolled subjects will undergo ultrasound&#xD;
      to examine the liver and provide blood samples for the multi-analyte blood test and for&#xD;
      determining conventional blood analytes. Every subject will then go on to diagnostic imaging&#xD;
      by multiphasic MRI. The results of diagnostic imaging will primarily be scored by a Liver&#xD;
      Reporting and Data System (LI-RADS) score. The data of all diagnostic imaging by MRI will be&#xD;
      saved and uploaded for evaluation by a blinded, centralized team of radiologists, which will&#xD;
      be used as the basis of the clinical truth for all subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the Initial Surveillance Visit (t=0 months), subjects with an indeterminant HCC finding&#xD;
      by MRI (LI-RADS 3) will be recommended to up to three Follow-Up Visits (t=6 months, t=12&#xD;
      months, and t=18 months) to attempt to resolve the clinical truth for these subjects. Each&#xD;
      Follow-Up Visit will consist of an ultrasound to examine the liver, providing blood samples&#xD;
      for the multi-analyte blood test , as well as diagnostic imaging by multiphasic MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although not required by this clinical protocol, any biopsy or surgical pathology results, or&#xD;
      any additional imaging (such as multiphasic CT) that are generated for study subjects as part&#xD;
      of current clinical practice will also be recorded for each subject and the results shall be&#xD;
      made available to the Sponsor if performed within 6 months of a scheduled Visit. Biopsy and&#xD;
      surgical pathology results that indicate a malignancy will be used in place of diagnostic&#xD;
      imaging as the clinical truth for each subject if performed within 6 months of a scheduled&#xD;
      visit and prior to database lock.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All study-related procedures will occur during the Study Duration Period, which consists of&#xD;
      the Initial Surveillance Visit for all subjects and up to three Follow-Up Visits for subjects&#xD;
      with an initial indeterminant HCC finding (LI-RADS 3) by diagnostic imaging. After this Study&#xD;
      Duration Period, no study related blood draws, imaging or procedures will occur for these&#xD;
      subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 4, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Independent performance measure of sensitivity and specificity of a multi-analyte blood test vs Ultrasound</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the combination of both ultrasound and the multi-analyte blood Test for the detection of liver cancers within a high-risk population.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the multi-analyte blood Test alone for the detection of liver cancers.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of the multi-analyte blood Test alone to ultrasound alone for the detection of liver cancer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the combination of both ultrasound and the multi-analyte blood Test for the detection of liver cancer lesions that are ≤ 2cm in diameter.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the combination of both ultrasound and the multi-analyte blood Test for the detection of liver cancer lesions that are ≤ 2cm in diameter.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the multi-analyte Test alone for the detection of liver cancer lesions that are ≤ 2cm in diameter.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the performance (sensitivity and specificity) of ultrasound alone to the multi-analyte blood Test alone for the detection of liver cancer lesions that are ≤ 2cm in diameter.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1600</enrollment>
  <condition>Liver Cirrhosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>men or women between 21-84</arm_group_label>
    <description>Multi-analyte blood test screening alone and as combination with multi-analyte Test and Ultrasound in subjects diagnosed with liver cirrhosis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Multi-analyte blood Test</intervention_name>
    <description>intended for the qualitative detection of DNA methylation profiles associated with hepatocellular carcinoma in cell-free DNA derived from patient whole blood specimens.</description>
    <arm_group_label>men or women between 21-84</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The maximum study duration for any given subject participating in the trial will be&#xD;
        approximately 21 months (includes Initial Surveillance Visit and Follow-Up Visits at 6&#xD;
        months, 12 months and 18 months). No study-related lab assessments, imaging or procedures&#xD;
        shall be required for any subject after the Study Duration Period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject Eligibility Screening Period: 14 days Study Duration Period: Up to 21 months&#xD;
        (includes Initial Surveillance Visit for all subjects and up to three Follow-Up Visits ONLY&#xD;
        for subjects with indeterminant findings by diagnostic imaging) The maximum observational&#xD;
        window for any subject enrolled in the study is expected to be approximately 21 months (for&#xD;
        subjects with indeterminant findings by diagnostic imaging).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is age 21 to 84 (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is able to read, comprehend and sign the Informed Consent Document&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing and able to undergo liver cancer surveillance by ultrasound and the&#xD;
             multi-analyte blood Test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is able and willing to undergo diagnostic imaging by multiphasic MRI with&#xD;
             contrast according to the Study Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has been diagnosed with liver cirrhosis by one or more of the following&#xD;
             methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Clinical diagnosis by blood analytes (APRI ≥ 1.5 or Bonacini cirrhosis&#xD;
                  discriminant score ≥ 8 or Lok index &gt; 0.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Ultrasound and Elastography &gt; 12.5 kPa (Vibration-controlled transient&#xD;
                  elastography, Point shear wave elastography, Two-dimensional shear wave&#xD;
                  ultrasound and transient elastography or Magnetic Resonance Elastography)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Diagnostic imaging by CT or MRI (liver cirrhosis indicated on radiology report)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Liver biopsy (liver cirrhosis indicated on pathology report)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study investigator deems the subject's participation to be unsafe due to an&#xD;
             underlying medical condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has previously been diagnosed with a primary liver cancer or a non-liver&#xD;
             cancer that has metastasized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has previously submitted a blood sample to Helio Health (HELIO) through a&#xD;
             separate clinical protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is unable or unwilling to submit blood samples for testing, undergo ultrasound&#xD;
             or undergo diagnostic imaging by multiphasic MRI with contrast as required for the&#xD;
             Study Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has any internal metallic device or fragment, including but not limited to: A&#xD;
             pacemaker, artificial joint or valve, surgical clips, pins, plates, screws, wire mesh&#xD;
             or shrapnel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  It is unsafe for the subject to receive an MRI contrast dye due to pregnancy or severe&#xD;
             kidney disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject would not routinely be recommended for HCC surveillance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject received an abdominal ultrasound or diagnostic imaging by MRI or CT to image&#xD;
             the liver within the past 5 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alamdar Rizvi, MS</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Laboratory for Advanced Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alamdar Rizvi, MS</last_name>
    <phone>6308578049</phone>
    <phone_ext>6308578049</phone_ext>
    <email>alamdar.rizvi@lamoncogroup.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>David Taggart, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6308578049</phone>
    <phone_ext>6308578049</phone_ext>
    <email>david.taggart@lamoncogroup.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alliance Research Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irvine</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicole Skvarna</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kenneth Deck, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gastroenterology Group of Naples</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naples</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paula Allain</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Raymond Phillips, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kansas City Research Institute (KCRI)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64131</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christy Altman</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bradley Freilich, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Quality Medical</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christy Swope</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Herring, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Liver Center of Texas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75234</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Abdullah Mubarak, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Khadija Shoaib, PhD</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Abdullah Mubarak, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Liver Institute - American Research Corp.</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rodney Ray</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Lawitz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Digestive &amp; Liver Disease Specialists (DLDS) - Norfolk</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aricka Fayton</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John Smith, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 28, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 1, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 3, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

