<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00023153</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>010239</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>01-I-0239</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00023153</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00044850</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lamivudine and Adefovir to Treat Chronic Hepatitis B Infection in People With and Without HIV Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Studies of the Addition of Adefovir Dipivoxil to Lamivudine for the Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo Controlled Study in HIV-Infected Patients and an Open-Label Study in HIV-Negative Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the safety and effectiveness of adefovir plus lamivudine for chronic&#xD;
      hepatitis B infection in people with and without HIV infection. Lamuvidine, an FDA-approved&#xD;
      treatment for hepatitis B infection, also works against HIV. In some patients, the hepatitis&#xD;
      B virus (HBV) continues to reproduce despite lamivudine treatment. Adefovir is an&#xD;
      experimental drug that inhibits HBV replication and may work against some strains of the&#xD;
      virus that have become resistant to lamivudine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 21 years of age or older with active hepatitis B infection despite treatment with&#xD;
      lamivudine for at least 1 year may be eligible for this 48-week study. Patients both with or&#xD;
      without HIV infection may participate. Candidates will be screened with a medical history,&#xD;
      blood and urine tests, liver ultrasound exam, electrocardiogram (EKG) and chest X-ray.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a physical examination, review of their medical history, blood tests,&#xD;
      and a 24-hour urine collection. They will be admitted to the hospital for a liver biopsy to&#xD;
      determine if they can receive the study drug. For this procedure, the patient is given a&#xD;
      sedative for relaxation. The skin over the biopsy is numbed with an anesthetic and the biopsy&#xD;
      needle is passed rapidly into and out of the liver to collect a tissue specimen. Patients are&#xD;
      monitored in the hospital overnight for possible complications. After discharge, they return&#xD;
      home and begin taking the study medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomized to two treatment groups. One group will take 10 milligrams/day of&#xD;
      adefovir by mouth, and the other will take a placebo-a lookalike pill with no active&#xD;
      ingredient. Both groups will also take 150 mg lamivudine by mouth and L-carnitine pills or&#xD;
      liquid. Patients with HIV infection will continue to take antiretroviral therapy as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed in the clinic at study weeks 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, 28, 32, 36,&#xD;
      40 and 44 for blood and urine tests to determine the safety of the drug and to evaluate the&#xD;
      response to treatment. On week 48, a repeat 24-hour urine test and repeat liver biopsy will&#xD;
      be done. At the end of the 48 weeks, patients may continue to receive adefovir for another 48&#xD;
      weeks and possibly longer. All those who participate in this extension phase will receive&#xD;
      active adefovir, regardless of whether they had previously taken adefovir or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will have the option to enroll in a separate study to examine the levels of HBV&#xD;
      (and levels of HIV in HIV-infected patients) in the blood immediately after starting&#xD;
      treatment and to determine if these initial levels can predict later outcome. This involves&#xD;
      seven additional visits, for which participants will be compensated. At these visits, blood&#xD;
      will be drawn on study days 0 (before starting drug treatment), 1, 3, 5, 7, 10 and 21 for HIV&#xD;
      and HBV viral loads and specialized immunology tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial examines the addition of adefovir dipivoxil to a lamivudine regimen for&#xD;
      treating chronic hepatitis B infection. Two patient populations will be separately recruited:&#xD;
      HIV-infected (40 subjects) and HIV-uninfected (20 subjects). HIV-infected patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled in a randomized, placebo controlled study of the safety and efficacy of the addition&#xD;
      of adefovir to lamivudine for the treatment of chronic hepatitis B in subjects with a&#xD;
      hepatitis B virus (HBV) viral load of at least one million copies/mL despite at least one&#xD;
      year of lamivudine therapy. A similar population of HIV-uninfected subjects will be treated&#xD;
      with open-label adefovir 10 mg daily for one year. These HIV-negative subjects will serve as&#xD;
      a control group for immunological comparisons to the HIV-positive group treated with&#xD;
      adefovir. HIV-infected subjects will be randomly allocated to receive adefovir 10 mg daily&#xD;
      for one year or matching placebo. At the end of one year, HIV-infected patients may choose to&#xD;
      receive open-label adefovir, and HIV-uninfected patients will have the option of continuing&#xD;
      open-label drug if they are responding to treatment. Patients may not have decompensated&#xD;
      cirrhosis or other causes of liver disease such as hepatitis C. Liver biopsies are performed&#xD;
      prior to study and at the end of one year. HIV-positive subjects whose liver biopsy&#xD;
      demonstrates cirrhosis will not be randomized but will be treated with open-label adefovir 10&#xD;
      mg daily. The purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of lamivudine plus&#xD;
      adefovir as compared with continued lamivudine in HIV-infected patients, to compare responses&#xD;
      between HIV-uninfected and HIV-infected subjects, and to obtain specimens for studies of&#xD;
      immune responses to HBV. HIV-infected patients will receive lamivudine 150 mg bid plus&#xD;
      adefovir 10 mg qd (or placebo) and HIV-uninfected subjects will receive lamivudine 100 mg qd&#xD;
      plus adefovir 10 mg qd. L-carnitine supplementation will be used only if low serum carnitine&#xD;
      levels are documented. Additionally, patients will have the option of enrolling in a&#xD;
      sub-study assessing the kinetics of viral load response to study drug. Specimens will be&#xD;
      stored for possible future determination of adefovir levels and use in evaluating HBV and HIV&#xD;
      resistance to adefovir. Patients discontinuing study drug and not initiating a commerically&#xD;
      available anti-HBV medication (including adefovir) will be monitored for safety for at least&#xD;
      an additional 24 weeks. The primary study endpoint will be a comparison of the absolute HBV&#xD;
      viral load at Week 48 between the placebo and adefovir HIV-positive patient groups, and for&#xD;
      the HIV-negative population, the comparison of absolute HBV viral at Week 48 versus baseline.&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints include safety, liver pathology, and transaminase level. Adefovir will be&#xD;
      discontinued for toxicity; there will be no dose reduction. A DSMB will oversee the trial for&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date>October 2004</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>100</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis B</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adefovir Dipivoxil</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age greater than or equal to 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Infection with HBV with HBV viral load greater than 1.0 x 10 (6) copies/mL by Roche assay&#xD;
        at screen&#xD;
&#xD;
        HIV infected or uninfected&#xD;
&#xD;
        If HIV infected: CD4 greater than or equal to 100 and VL less than or equal to 10,000 at&#xD;
        screen; No antiretroviral changes 12 weeks prior to entry and no anticipated changes 12&#xD;
        weeks into study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Have a physician(s) outside of NIH who will provide routine, as well as HIV (if applicable)&#xD;
        and liver specific, care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Able to return to NIH for study visits&#xD;
&#xD;
        Receiving lamivudine at a dose of at least 100 mg qd for greater than or equal to one year&#xD;
        prior to enrollment (with no dosing interruptions of greater than 1 month total in the&#xD;
        previous year and no interruption in the 3 months prior to study entry)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serum creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        1.2 less than or equal to ALT (SGPT) less than or equal to 7 X ULN (current NIH lab values&#xD;
        49-287 U/L inclusive) at screen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Direct bilirubin less than or equal to 1.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serum phosphorus greater than or equal to 2.2 mg/dL (normal range NIH 2.3-4.3 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Neutrophil count greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Platelets greater than or equal to 70,000/mm(3)&#xD;
&#xD;
        INR less than or equal to 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        If capable of pregnancy: use of effective contraception during study: effective&#xD;
        contraception methods include abstinence, surgical sterilization of either partner, barrier&#xD;
        methods such as diaphragm, condom, cap or sponge, or use of hormonal contraception. If HIV&#xD;
        infected using hormonal contraception, must be receiving an anti-HIV regimen that will not&#xD;
        alter the metabolism of hormonal contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willing and able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willing to undergo hepatic biopsy at the start and end of study. The initial protocol&#xD;
        biopsy will not be required if the subject can provide pathologic slides from a biopsy&#xD;
        performed within six months of the History and Physical visit that are found by the Liver&#xD;
        Disease Section and the NIH's pathologist to be adequate for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prior use of ADV, tenofovir, or cidofovir&#xD;
&#xD;
        Decompensated cirrhosis:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Child-Pugh Class B or C cirrhosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Class A Score = 5 acceptable; Class A Score = 6 acceptable as long as not secondary to&#xD;
        encephalopathy or ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
        Active serious systemic infections other than HIV or HBV&#xD;
&#xD;
        Liver disease caused by reasons other than hepatitis B e.g., HCV, HDV, Wilson's,&#xD;
        hemochromatosis, autoimmune hepatitis (ANA greater than or equal to 3 EU) except history of&#xD;
        drug-associated hepatitis with discontinuation of causative agent&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of encephalopathy, varices, heart failure, or ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current history of clinical pancreatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
        New AIDS-defining event other than esophageal candidiasis diagnosed within 1 month prior to&#xD;
        baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treatment with immunomodulator drugs (interleukins, corticosteriods for indications other&#xD;
        than the treatment of adrenal insufficiency) in the 4 weeks prior to baseline. G-CSF and&#xD;
        epoetin use are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Anti-HBV therapy other than lamivudine (such as emtricitabine, lobucavir, entecavir, HBIG,&#xD;
        clevudine, MCC-478) with the exception of interferon alpha, famciclovir or foscarnet that&#xD;
        ended more than 12 weeks prior to screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hepatic mass suggestive of hepatocellular carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        Alpha fetoprotein greater than 200 ng/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
        Evidence of gastrointestinal malabsorption or chronic nausea or vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current alcohol or substance abuse that potentially could interfere with patient compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Malignancy other than cutaneous Kaposi's sarcoma, skin cancer treated by resection or&#xD;
        HPV-associated carcinoma in situ or Bowen's disease in the 5 years prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of clinically significant renal dysfunction within the previous 12 months prior to&#xD;
        baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
        Concomitant therapy with aminoglycosides, amphotericin B, cisplatinum, IV pentamidine,&#xD;
        vancomycin, systemic chemotherapeutic agents, probenecid or other nephrotoxic agents&#xD;
&#xD;
        Proteinuria (greater than or equal to 3+)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Positive PCR test for hepatitis C&#xD;
&#xD;
        Antibodies to hepatitis D (delta hepatitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnancy or breast-feeding. Pregnancy test must be negative within two weeks prior to&#xD;
        dosing with adefovir or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        History of organ or bone marrow transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any systemic illness that will make it unlikely that the subject will be able to return to&#xD;
        NIH for the required study visits&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benhamou Y, Katlama C, Lunel F, Coutellier A, Dohin E, Hamm N, Tubiana R, Herson S, Poynard T, Opolon P. Effects of lamivudine on replication of hepatitis B virus in HIV-infected men. Ann Intern Med. 1996 Nov 1;125(9):705-12.</citation>
    <PMID>8929003</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dienstag JL, Schiff ER, Wright TL, Perrillo RP, Hann HW, Goodman Z, Crowther L, Condreay LD, Woessner M, Rubin M, Brown NA. Lamivudine as initial treatment for chronic hepatitis B in the United States. N Engl J Med. 1999 Oct 21;341(17):1256-63.</citation>
    <PMID>10528035</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lau DT, Khokhar MF, Doo E, Ghany MG, Herion D, Park Y, Kleiner DE, Schmid P, Condreay LD, Gauthier J, Kuhns MC, Liang TJ, Hoofnagle JH. Long-term therapy of chronic hepatitis B with lamivudine. Hepatology. 2000 Oct;32(4 Pt 1):828-34.</citation>
    <PMID>11003630</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2004</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2001</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 24, 2001</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 27, 2001</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Drug Resistance</keyword>
  <keyword>Viral Load</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunology</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver Histology</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
  <keyword>HBV</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adefovir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adefovir dipivoxil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

