<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00021762</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A5120</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10938</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>ACTG A5120</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>AACTG A5120</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00021762</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Immunization With HIV-1 Immunogen Plus Anti-HIV Treatment Interruption on the Levels of HIV</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Phase II Evaluation of the Effects on HIV Replication of Immunization With a gp120-Depleted, Inactivated Whole Virus Vaccine Combined With Exposures to Replicating Autologous HIV by Scheduled Treatment Interruptions, a Rollover Study of A5057</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to see whether or not an HIV vaccination will help the body&#xD;
      control the amount of HIV virus in blood (viral load) in patients who are not taking anti-HIV&#xD;
      medicines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Doctors are not sure why the body fails to control HIV viral load in most people infected&#xD;
      with HIV. The vaccine Remune has been shown to boost part of the body's immune response to&#xD;
      HIV in patients whose viral load has been lowered with anti-HIV drugs. This study will test&#xD;
      the ability of Remune to improve the body's immune response and to lower HIV viral load in&#xD;
      patients who stop taking anti-HIV drugs for short periods of time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Investigators of the pathogenesis of HIV infection agree that one of the most critical&#xD;
      questions in HIV disease is why immune responses do not control HIV replication in the vast&#xD;
      majority of infected individuals. More specifically, the absence of large lymphocyte&#xD;
      proliferation response (LPR) to HIV antigens in these individuals, and their presence in&#xD;
      long-term nonprogressors (LTNPs) with a low viral load, requires an investigation of whether&#xD;
      a causal relationship exists between LPR to HIV and control of HIV replication. Immunization&#xD;
      with Remune has been shown to induce large LPR to HIV antigens when administered to patients&#xD;
      in whom HIV replication has been suppressed with antiretroviral therapy (ART). A5120 will&#xD;
      evaluate the abilities of immunization with HIV-1 Immunogen and of STIs to enhance immune&#xD;
      responses that may control HIV replication in the absence of antiretroviral drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients remain in the treatment arm (vaccine versus adjuvant placebo) to which they were&#xD;
      randomized on entry to protocol A5057, and both the participant and investigator remain&#xD;
      blinded as to the assignment. Patients may receive up to 3 injections of vaccine/adjuvant&#xD;
      control in 1 of the following 2 groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm A: HIV-1 immunogen at study entry and at Week 9 in Step 3 and Step 5. Arm B: HIV-1&#xD;
      immunogen placebo at study entry and at Week 9 in Step 3 and Step 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ART is required during Steps 1, 3, 5, and 8 but is not provided by this study. The study is&#xD;
      organized into the following series of steps.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 1 (ART and injection): receive injection of vaccine/adjuvant control. Patients remain on&#xD;
      ART for 6 to 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 2 (first STI): all ART is stopped for up to 8 weeks with careful monitoring of viral&#xD;
      load and CD4 T cells. Patients whose viral load is controlled may remain on Step 2 for an&#xD;
      additional 6 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 3 (resumption of ART): restart ART for 14 weeks. Eligible patients receive an&#xD;
      immunization with vaccine/adjuvant control at Week 9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 4 (second STI): identical to Step 2. Step 5 (resumption of ART): identical to Step 3.&#xD;
      Step 6 (analytical treatment interruption [ATI]): analytical &quot;read-out&quot; discontinuation of&#xD;
      ART for up to 14 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 7 (long-term follow-up without ART): open only to patients with control of viral load&#xD;
      who agree to participate in continued treatment withdrawal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 8 (final resumption of ART): patients are followed for 8 weeks on ART to document the&#xD;
      effect of restarting ART on suppression of viral load. Patients advance through steps as&#xD;
      criteria for HIV RNA level, CD4 count, and treatment are met.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients have regular clinic visits for medical/medication histories, physical examinations,&#xD;
      and laboratory tests for viral load and immunological parameters.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HIV-1 Immunogen</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Structured Treatment Interruption</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients may be eligible for this study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have been enrolled in A5057, which includes the 6-month extension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have participated in A5057 for at least 44 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received at least 4 treatments on A5057.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are between 8 and 22 weeks from the last study injection on A5057.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a viral load (amount of HIV in the blood) of 400 or less copies/ml at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a stable anti-HIV drug combination (no changes in anti-HIV drugs) for 8 or more&#xD;
             weeks prior to entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a CD4 count of 300 or more cells/ml at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to use at least 1 approved method of birth control, if women able to have&#xD;
             children. Birth control is not required if a male partner is infertile and provides&#xD;
             evidence of that fact.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a negative pregnancy test within 14 days of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will not be eligible for this study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are allergic to the study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have had an acute infection requiring an antibiotic, an outbreak of herpes simplex&#xD;
             virus or herpes zoster, or other acute medical illness or surgery within 30 days prior&#xD;
             to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received within 30 days of study entry GM-CSF, G-CSF, M-CSF, IFN, IL-2, or other&#xD;
             cytokines; drugs affecting the immune system including cyclosporine, methotrexate,&#xD;
             azathioprine, anti-CD25 antibody, or other agents; systemic oral or IV corticosteroids&#xD;
             for 21 or more days; and HIV vaccine other than the one provided in this study;&#xD;
             hydroxyurea; systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy; or medications that should not be taken&#xD;
             with any HIV drugs being received.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have been assigned randomly to A5058s.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fred Valentine</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
  </overall_official>
  <link>
    <url>http://aidsinfo.nih.gov/clinicaltrials/htmltrials_sp.asp?an=1407</url>
    <description>Haga clic aquí para ver información sobre este ensayo clínico en español.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2001</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 30, 2001</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 31, 2001</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Virus Replication</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug Administration Schedule</keyword>
  <keyword>AIDS Vaccines</keyword>
  <keyword>RNA, Viral</keyword>
  <keyword>Viral Load</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV-1 immunogen, incomplete Freund's adjuvant</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Interruption</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV Therapeutic Vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

