<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00026052</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>020034</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>02-M-0034</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00026052</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Riluzole to Treat Major Depression</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Investigation of the Antidepressant Efficacy of an Antiglutamatergic Agent With Neurotrophic Properties in Major Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine the safety and effectiveness of the drug riluzole (Rilutek®&#xD;
      (Registered Trademark)) for short-term treatment of depression symptoms, such as depressed&#xD;
      mood, psychomotor retardation, and excessive sleeping. Despite the availability of a wide&#xD;
      range of antidepressant drugs, studies indicate that 30 to 40 percent of patients with major&#xD;
      depression do not respond to first-line antidepressant treatment with drugs such as&#xD;
      fluoxetine, upropion, venlafaxine and others. Riluzole, which is approved by the Food and&#xD;
      Drug Administration (FDA) for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), causes chemical changes in&#xD;
      the brain that may also have antidepressant properties.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients between 18 and 70 years of age with major depressive disorder without psychotic&#xD;
      features may be eligible for this 2-stage 7-week study. Candidates will be screened with a&#xD;
      medical history and physical examination, including an electrocardiogram (EKG), blood and&#xD;
      urine tests, and a psychiatric evaluation. A&#xD;
&#xD;
      blood or urine sample will be tested for illegal drugs.Women of childbearing potential will&#xD;
      have a pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete stage 1 of the study, which lasts 1 week, and may then continue&#xD;
      with stage 2 for an additional 6 weeks. At the start of the study, patients will be tapered&#xD;
      off all psychiatric medicines and will begin treatment with a placebo (a sugar pill&#xD;
      formulated to look like the active drug). At some point, they will be switched from placebo&#xD;
      to riluzole. In addition, participants will undergo the following procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical examination and electrocardiograms (EKG) at the beginning and end of the study,&#xD;
           with vital signs (temperature, blood pressure and heart rate) checked daily&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weekly 1-hour interviews consisting of psychiatric and psychomotor rating scales to&#xD;
           assess treatment response&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weekly blood tests to measure blood levels of riluzole and evaluate drug side effects&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study, participants' psychiatric status will be reassessed and appropriate&#xD;
      long-term psychiatric treatment arranged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients, ages 18 to 70 with a diagnosis of major depression without psychotic features, will&#xD;
      in this pilot study (single arm, single blind) receive riluzole (50-200 mg/day) for a period&#xD;
      of 6 weeks. Acute efficacy will be determined by demonstrating a greater response rate using&#xD;
      specified criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 25 patients will enter the study to obtain 22 subjects who complete the 6 weeks&#xD;
      of acute riluzole treatment. Therefore, if 7/22 patients or greater have greater than 50%&#xD;
      improvement on the primary efficacy measure, then based on statistically guidelines from the&#xD;
      Optimal Two Stage Design for Clinical Trials, a controlled trial would be indicated to&#xD;
      scientifically confirm the signal observed in the single arm trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Major affective disorders are common, severe, chronic and often life-threatening illnesses.&#xD;
      Major depression contributes to significant morbidity and mortality. Impairment in physical&#xD;
      and social functioning resulting from depression can be just as severe as other chronic&#xD;
      medical illnesses. Suicide is the cause of death in 10-20% of individuals with either bipolar&#xD;
      or recurrent depressive disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the availability of a wide range of antidepressant drugs, clinical trials indicate&#xD;
      that 30% to 40% of patients with major depression fail to respond to first-line&#xD;
      antidepressant treatment, despite adequate dosage, duration, and compliance. Thus, there is a&#xD;
      clear need to develop novel and improved therapeutics for unipolar and bipolar depression.&#xD;
      Recent preclinical studies suggest that antidepressants may exert delayed indirect effects on&#xD;
      the glutamatergic system. Furthermore, a growing body of data suggests that mood disorders&#xD;
      are associated with regional volumetric reductions, and cell loss and atrophy. It is thus&#xD;
      noteworthy that lamotrigine, which, among other effects reduces glutamate release, has&#xD;
      antidepressant effects, and a pilot study has suggested that NMDA antagonists may have&#xD;
      antidepressant effects. Together, this data suggests that the glutamatergic system may play a&#xD;
      role in the pathophysiology and treatment of depression, and that agents, which more directly&#xD;
      reduce glutamatergic neurotransmission, may represent a novel class of antidepressants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Riluzole, an agent that is Food and Drug Administration-approved for Amyotrophic Lateral&#xD;
      Sclerosis has significant antiglutamatergic and neuroprotective properties, may prove to have&#xD;
      antidepressant properties in depressed patients. In this study, we propose to investigate the&#xD;
      potential antidepressant efficacy of riluzole, an agent which reduces glutamatergic&#xD;
      throughput via inhibition of its release, which also exerts robus neurotrophic effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a 6-week single-arm, single-blind study that will examine the efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      riluzole in patients with major depression without psychotic features.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study has two Study Periods. Study Period I is the washout phase that will last 7 days.&#xD;
      Study Period II is a monotherapy 6-week acute treatment phase in which the efficacy and&#xD;
      tolerability of riluzole is compared to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients, ages 18 to 60 with a diagnosis of major depression without psychotic features, will&#xD;
      in this pilot study (single arm, single-blind) receive riluzole (50-200 mg/day) for a period&#xD;
      of 6 weeks. Acute efficacy will be determined by demonstrating a greater response rate using&#xD;
      specified criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 25 patients will enter the study to obtain 22 subjects who complete the 6 weeks&#xD;
      of acute riluzole treatment. Therefore if 7/22 patients or greater have greater than 50%&#xD;
      improvement on the primary efficacy measure, then based on statistically guidelines from the&#xD;
      Optimal Two Stage Design for Clinical Trials, a controlled trial would be indicated to&#xD;
      scientifically confirm the signal observed in the single arm trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 2003</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>31</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>riluzole</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Male or female subjects, 18 to 70 years of age will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female subjects of childbearing potential must be using a medically accepted means of&#xD;
        contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Each subject must have a level of understanding sufficient to agree to all required tests&#xD;
        and examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Each subject must understand the nature of the study and must sign an informed consent&#xD;
        document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must fulfill the criteria for major depression, recurrent without psychotic&#xD;
        features as defined in DSM-IV (296.32, 296.33) based on clinical assessment and confirmed&#xD;
        by structured diagnostic interview SCID-P.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must have an initial score at Visit 1 and Visit 2 of at least 20 on the MADRS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must not have a decrease in the total score of MADRS of greater than or equal 20%&#xD;
        during washout (between Visits 1 and 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must have experienced, in the opinion of the investigator, at least one prior&#xD;
        major depressive episode as defined in DSM-IV (not including the current major depressive&#xD;
        episode).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must have had at least one adequate antidepressant trial (SSRI, bupropion, or&#xD;
        venlafaxine) during an episode of major depression (Thase and Rush, 1995; Thase et al.,&#xD;
        2000).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with current major depressive episode of no more than 24 months will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presence of psychotic features.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participate in a clinical trial of another investigational drug within 1 month (30 days)&#xD;
        prior to study entry (Visit 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female subjects who are either pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serious, unstable illnesses including hepatic, renal, gastroenterologic, respiratory,&#xD;
        cardiovascular (including ischemic heart disease), endocrinologic, neurologic, immunologic,&#xD;
        or hematologic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with uncorrected hypothyroidism or hyperthyroidism.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Abnormal levels of serum transaminases (ALT/SGPT; AST/SGOT), current or past blood&#xD;
        dyscrasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Documented history of hypersensitivity or intolerance to riluzole.&#xD;
&#xD;
        DSM-IV substance abuse or dependence within the past 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treatment with an injectable depot neuroleptic within less than one dosing interval between&#xD;
        depot neuroleptic injections prior to Visit 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treatment with a reversible MAOI, guanethidine, or guanadrel within 1 week or with&#xD;
        fluoxetine within 3 weeks prior to Visit 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treatment with any other concomitant medication with primarily CNS activity, other than&#xD;
        specified in Appendix A.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treatment with clozapine or ECT within 12 weeks prior to Visit 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current diagnosis of schizophrenia or other psychotic disorder as defined in the DSM-IV&#xD;
        will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Judged clinically to be at serious suicidal risk, with a score of 3 or more on item 3 of&#xD;
        the HAMD will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will not be allowed to receive structured psychotherapy during the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aronowski J, Strong R, Grotta JC. Combined neuroprotection and reperfusion therapy for stroke. Effect of lubeluzole and diaspirin cross-linked hemoglobin in experimental focal ischemia. Stroke. 1996 Sep;27(9):1571-6; discussion 1576-7.</citation>
    <PMID>8784132</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Altamura CA, Mauri MC, Ferrara A, Moro AR, D'Andrea G, Zamberlan F. Plasma and platelet excitatory amino acids in psychiatric disorders. Am J Psychiatry. 1993 Nov;150(11):1731-3.</citation>
    <PMID>8214185</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abe K, Aoki M, Kawagoe J, Yoshida T, Hattori A, Kogure K, Itoyama Y. Ischemic delayed neuronal death. A mitochondrial hypothesis. Stroke. 1995 Aug;26(8):1478-89. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>7631357</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2003</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2001</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2001</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 9, 2001</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Riluzole</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroprotective</keyword>
  <keyword>Open-Label Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Glutamate Dysfunction</keyword>
  <keyword>Unipolar Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Antidepressant</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Depression</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Riluzole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

