<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04151862</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0145-19 SOR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04151862</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Two Most Common Ways Post-operative Eye Patch Are Therapeutic Contact Lenses (TCL) and Overnight Bandaging With Tight Bandage Patch: This Study is Designed to Determine the Most Effective Post-operative Care to Relief the Patient's Discomfort After Pterygium Excision Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Therapeutic Contact Lenses vs. Tight Bandage Patching and Pain Following Pterygium Excision: a Prospective Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Soroka University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Soroka University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to determine the most effective post-operative care to relief the&#xD;
      patient's discomfort after pterygium excision surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized controlled trial. 50 patients with primary pterygium in&#xD;
      both eyes for whom surgery was advised, will be recruited to the study. Criteria for&#xD;
      pterygium excision surgery is mostly cosmetic, local eye symptoms, or visual impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following data will be collected and analyzed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Demographic data such as: age, gender&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Clinical data: best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) full biomacroscopy examination,&#xD;
           before surgery and at post-operative day (POD) 1 and 3&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Symptoms and discomfort: Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) score and pain killer use. The&#xD;
           differences in these variables values preoperatively and on the first and 3rd&#xD;
           postoperative day will compared between the two treated eyes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical technique and postoperative care&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be operated for the same pterygium excision under local anesthesia in the&#xD;
      formal accepted surgical method. All patients will be treated with ofloxacin drops +&#xD;
      dexamethasone drops four times daily during the first postoperative week. The only difference&#xD;
      is that one group will be bandaged with tight bandage patching and the other with therapeutic&#xD;
      contact lenses (TCL) only for the first 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient-centered outcome&#xD;
&#xD;
      Discomfort and pain will be evaluated on the follow-up meeting on the first and 3rd&#xD;
      postoperative day. The patient will be asked to rate pain and discomfort for each operated&#xD;
      eye on pain scale of VAS ranking the pain on a line from No pain at 0 cm to worst possible&#xD;
      pain at 10 cm and the estimated pain given by the patient's translation of pain into spot on&#xD;
      a line.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will also be queried about the number of hours during which they feel pain, and the&#xD;
      number of pain killers used ( every patient will be given prescription for 3 tabs of&#xD;
      Paracetamol 500 mg (giving no drugs sensitivity for paracetamol) on POD 1 &amp; 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Their sleep quality will rated according to whether they reported having a full night's sleep&#xD;
      and the number of times they were awoken due to pain/discomfort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      The t test was used to calculate differences in numerical variables (VA, hours of pain,&#xD;
      number of pain killers, etc.). Non-parametric Wilcoxon Mann-Whitney was used to calculate&#xD;
      differences in non-numerical variables such as pain level (VAS scale). Chi-square analyses&#xD;
      were used to calculate proportional group differences (e.g., use of pain killers and sleep&#xD;
      pattern). The overall significance level was set to a value of 0.05. The statistical analysis&#xD;
      was carried out using Microsoft Excel 2013.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurment of pain and discomfort for patients post pterygium excision: Visual Analog Scale by questionnaire on marking straight horizontal line of fixed length from 0-100 mm where 0 mm is no pain and 100 mm is maximal pain.</measure>
    <time_frame>1st Post Operative Day and 3rd Post Operative Day</time_frame>
    <description>Assessing pain and discomfort comparing the two groups ( one with tight bandage and the other with contact lens).post pterygium excision by the change in pain scores on Visual Analog Scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Pterygium of Both Eyes</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Postoperative</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>tight eye bandage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Both eyes will be operated at two separate sessions. In the first session the first 25 patients will be bandaged postoperatively with tight eye bandage patching.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>therapeutic contact lenses (TCL)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Both eyes will be operated at two separate sessions. In the second session the 25 patients will be bandaged postoperatively with therapeutic contact lenses (TCL).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>tight eye bandage</intervention_name>
    <description>sterile eye pad made of 100% cotton</description>
    <arm_group_label>tight eye bandage</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nissan LTD</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Soflex Soft Contact Lens</intervention_name>
    <description>Therapeutic contact lenses (TCL)</description>
    <arm_group_label>therapeutic contact lenses (TCL)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SOFLEX LTD (TH78)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  healthy patients with no significant ocular diseases, older than 18 year old with both&#xD;
             eyes pterygia, referred for surgery and which are interested of their own will for&#xD;
             pterygium excision surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients younger than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with chronic diseases of the immune system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic diseases of eyelid or ocular surface, history of previous ocular surgery or&#xD;
             trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  collagen vascular disease or diabetes mellitus chronic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ingestion of pain killers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erez Tzumi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Head of ophthalmology department</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tal Koren, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972523606310</phone>
    <email>tuli_pi@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 6, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 6, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Soroka University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Erez Tsumi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Ophthalmology Department</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pterygium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

