<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04159805</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-079-1005</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-003383-47</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04159805</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of TAK-079 in People With Generalized Myasthenia Gravis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Study to Evaluate Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of TAK-079 in Patients With Generalized Myasthenia Gravis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Myasthenia gravis is an autoimmune condition that causes muscle weakness. Autoimmune means&#xD;
      the body makes antibodies that attack its own cells and tissues. These types of antibodies&#xD;
      are also known as autoantibodies. People with generalized myasthenia gravis have a weakness&#xD;
      in many muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TAK-079 is a medicine to help people with generalized myasthenia gravis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main aim of this study is to check if people with generalized myasthenia gravis have side&#xD;
      effects from 2 doses of TAK-079. Other aims are to learn if TAK-079 improves their clinical&#xD;
      condition and lowers their autoantibody levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the first visit, the study doctor will check if each person can take part. For those who&#xD;
      can take part, participants will continue with their standard medicines for this condition&#xD;
      during the study. Each participant will have a check-up by the study doctor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then, the participants will have 1 of 3 treatments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A low dose of TAK-079.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A high dose of TAK-079.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A placebo. In this study, a placebo looks like TAK-079 but does not have any medicine in&#xD;
           it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will not know which treatment they received, nor will their study doctors. This&#xD;
      is to help make sure the results are more reliable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each treatment, participants will receive injections just under the skin, once a week for&#xD;
      8 weeks. The study doctors will check for side effects from the study treatments. The study&#xD;
      doctors can stop or delay the injections in each participant if needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then, the study doctors will continue to check for side effects for up to 24 weeks after&#xD;
      treatment. They will also check the clinical condition of the participants, including their&#xD;
      autoantibody levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Myasthenia gravis (MG) is an autoimmune disorder in which autoantibodies, such as those&#xD;
      targeting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptor (AChR) or muscle specific kinase (MuSK),&#xD;
      interfere with neuromuscular transmission, resulting in fatigue and weakness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The drug being tested in this study is called TAK-079. TAK-079 is being tested to treat&#xD;
      people who have generalized myasthenia gravis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 25, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 13, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs), Grade 3 or Higher TEAEs, AEs Leading to TAK-079 Discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>An Adverse Event (AE) is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation participant administered a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (example, a clinically significant abnormal laboratory finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a drug, whether or not it is considered related to the drug. A TEAE is defined as an AE with an onset that occurs after receiving study drug and will be graded as per national cancer institute common terminology criteria for adverse events (NCI CTCAE), version 4.03.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Myasthenia Gravis (MG) Activities of Daily Living (MG-ADL) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-reported scale to assess MG symptoms to evaluate capacity to perform activities of daily living. Each question is graded on a 4-point scale from 0=normal to 3=severe with a total score of 0 to 24; the higher score indicates greater functional impairment and disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Quantitative Myasthenia Gravis (QMG) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>Physician-reported scale to assess MG disease severity by quantifying several body functions by physical exam. Each question is graded on a 4-point scale from 0=normal to 3=severe with a total score of 0 to 39; the higher score indicates greater disease burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Myasthenia Gravis Composite (MGC) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment scale of MG disease activity based on a combination of patient- and physician-reported items. Each question is graded on 4 levels of impact from normal to severe with a total score of 0 to 50; the higher score indicates worse MG disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Revised 15-item Myasthenia Gravis Quality of Life Scale (MG-QoL15r) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>A patient-reported score that assesses the patient's perception of impairment and disability and the degree to which the patient tolerates disease manifestations. Each question is graded on a 3-point scale from 0=normal to 2=severe with a total score of 0 to 30; the higher score indicates worse MG disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Anti-acetylcholine receptor (AChR) or Anti- Muscle-specific Tyrosine Kinase (MuSK) Antibody Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical laboratory evaluations (anti-AChR and anti-MuSK antibodies) will be tested to monitor disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Meeting Minimal Clinically Important Difference Criteria in MG-ADL Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-reported scale to assess MG symptoms to evaluate capacity to perform activities of daily living. Each question is graded on a 4-point scale from 0=normal to 3=severe with a total score of 0 to 24; the higher score indicates greater functional impairment and disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Patients Meeting Minimal Clinically Important Difference Criteria in Quantitative Myasthenia Gravis (QMG) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>Physician-reported scale to assess MG disease severity by quantifying several body functions by physical exam. Each question is graded on a 4-point scale from 0=normal to 3=severe with a total score of 0 to 39; the higher score indicates greater disease burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Meeting Minimal Clinically Important Difference Criteria in Myasthenia Gravis Composite (MGC) Scale Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 32</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment scale of MG disease activity based on a combination of patient- and physician-reported items. Each question is graded on 4 levels of impact from normal to severe with a total score of 0 to 50; the higher score indicates worse MG disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Myasthenia Gravis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-079 dose 1 injection, subcutaneously, once weekly for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Dose 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-079 dose 2 injection, subcutaneously, once weekly for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Placebo-matching</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-079 placebo-matching injection, subcutaneously, once weekly for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAK-079</intervention_name>
    <description>TAK-079 subcutaneous injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Dose 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAK-079 Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>TAK-079 placebo-matching subcutaneous injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-079 Placebo-matching</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Main Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosis of Myasthenia Gravis (MG) supported by a positive serologic test for&#xD;
             anti-AChR or anti-MuSK antibodies at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Myasthenia Gravis Foundation of America (MGFA) clinical classification II to IV at&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Myasthenia Gravis Activities of Daily Living (MG-ADL) total score of 6 or greater at&#xD;
             screening, with at least 4 points attributed to nonocular items.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If receiving immunosuppressive drugs (ie, mycophenolate mofetil, methotrexate,&#xD;
             cyclosporine, tacrolimus, cyclophosphamide), therapy must be ongoing for at least 6&#xD;
             months, with stable dosing ongoing for at least 3 months before screening.&#xD;
             Participants receiving azathioprine must be on a stable dose for at least 6 months&#xD;
             before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. If receiving oral corticosteroids, therapy must be ongoing for at least 3 months, with&#xD;
             a stable dose at least 1 month before screening. Corticosteroids, including&#xD;
             dexamethasone, must be given as oral, daily or every-other-day therapy, as opposed to&#xD;
             pulse therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If receiving cholinesterase inhibitors, therapy with a stable dose is required at&#xD;
             least 2 weeks before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The doses of concomitant standard background therapy must be expected to remain stable&#xD;
             throughout the study unless dose reduction is required due to toxicities. Allowed&#xD;
             background therapy is defined as no more than a cholinesterase inhibitor ±&#xD;
             corticosteroid ± 1 steroid-sparing immunosuppressive drug (limited to azathioprine,&#xD;
             mycophenolate mofetil, methotrexate, cyclosporine, tacrolimus, or cyclophosphamide).&#xD;
             Participants must be on at least one allowed background medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Main Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of a thymoma (previous history of a fully encapsulated thymoma removed ≥ 12&#xD;
             months before screening is allowed) or history of invasive thymic malignancy unless&#xD;
             deemed cured by adequate treatment with no evidence of recurrence for ≥ 5 years before&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of thymectomy within 12 months before screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. MGFA class I or V.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Received intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIg), subcutaneous immunoglobulin (SCIg), or&#xD;
             plasmapheresis/plasma exchange within 4 weeks before screening, or an expectation that&#xD;
             any therapy besides the participants standard background therapies may be used for&#xD;
             treatment of MG (eg, a rescue therapy) between screening and dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) or asthma with a pre-bronchodilatory&#xD;
             forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) &lt;50% of predicted normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: FEV1 testing is required for participants suspected of having COPD or asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Received rituximab, belimumab, eculizumab, or any monoclonal antibody for&#xD;
             immunomodulation within 6 months before first dosing. Participants with prior exposure&#xD;
             to rituximab must have CD19 counts within the normal range at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Known autoimmune disease other than MG that could interfere with the course and&#xD;
             conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Received a live vaccine within 4 weeks before screening or has any live vaccination&#xD;
             planned during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Opportunistic infection ≤12 weeks before initial study dosing or currently receiving&#xD;
             treatment for a chronic opportunistic infection, such as tuberculosis (TB),&#xD;
             pneumocystis pneumonia, cytomegalovirus, herpes simplex virus, herpes zoster, or&#xD;
             atypical mycobacteria. A mild, localized herpes simplex infection within 12 weeks of&#xD;
             study dosing is allowed, as long as the lesion has resolved without systemic therapy&#xD;
             prior to Day 1.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Study Registration Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+1 877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medinfoUS@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Arizona Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85713</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford Neuroscience Health Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95816-5266</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>George Washington University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SFM Clinical Research, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boca Raton</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33487</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neurology Associates PA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maitland</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32751</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medsol Clinical Research Center Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Port Charlotte</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33952</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Augusta University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Augusta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30912-3125</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Consultants In Neurology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Northbrook</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60062</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wayne State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Michigan State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>East Lansing</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48824</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neurology and Sleep Disorders Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbia</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>65212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital For Special Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carolinas HealthCare System Neurosciences Institute-Neurology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Cincinnati</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45267-0525</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Austin Neuromuscular Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas South Western Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Central Texas Neurology Consultants PA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Round Rock</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78681</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for Neurological Disorders</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milwaukee</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milwaukee</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53226</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Governors of the University of Calgary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T3M 1M4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vancouver General Hospital (VGH)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6E2E3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toronto General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2C4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A Gemelli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <state>Lazio</state>
        <zip>00168</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Careggi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Firenze</city>
        <zip>50139</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS AOU San Martino</name>
      <address>
        <city>Genova</city>
        <zip>16132</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione IRCCS Di Rilievo Nazionale Istituto Nazionale Neurologico Carlo Besta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Sant'andrea</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rome</city>
        <zip>00189</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neurocentrum Bydgoszcz sp. z o.o.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bydgoszcz</city>
        <state>Kujawsko-pomorskie</state>
        <zip>85-796</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centrum Neurologii Klinicznej Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Krakow</city>
        <state>Malopolskie</state>
        <zip>31-505</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centrum Medyczne NeuroProtect</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warsaw</city>
        <zip>01-684</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centrum Medyczne Warszawa - PRATIA - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>01-868</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Center of Serbia - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belgrade</city>
        <zip>11000</zip>
        <country>Serbia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Military Medical Academy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belgrade</city>
        <zip>11000</zip>
        <country>Serbia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Center Nis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nis</city>
        <zip>18000</zip>
        <country>Serbia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario de Alicante</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alicante</city>
        <zip>03010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Vall d'Hebron - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de La Santa Creu i Sant Pau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Maranon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28007</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinico San Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario La Paz - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28046</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen Macarena</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari i Politecnic La Fe de Valencia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46026</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Serbia</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/study-detail/5f6b603c4db2bf003ab4a369</url>
    <description>To obtain more information on the study, click here/on this link</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myasthenia Gravis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Takeda provides access to the de-identified individual participant data (IPD) for eligible studies to aid qualified researchers in addressing legitimate scientific objectives (Takeda's data sharing commitment is available on https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/takedas-commitment?commitment=5). These IPDs will be provided in a secure research environment following approval of a data sharing request, and under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_access_criteria>IPD from eligible studies will be shared with qualified researchers according to the criteria and process described on https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/. For approved requests, the researchers will be provided access to anonymized data (to respect patient privacy in line with applicable laws and regulations) and with information necessary to address the research objectives under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

