<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03563573</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-01A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03563573</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single-dose Potassium Supplementation in Patients With ADHD for Whom the Anesthetic Lidocaine is Ineffective</brief_title>
  <official_title>Single-dose Potassium Supplementation in ADHD Patients With Lidocaine Ineffectiveness</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AlkaliDx, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AlkaliDx, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Randomized, controlled, double-blind trial of the effect of a single dose of potassium on&#xD;
      ADHD symptoms as measured by changes in measures of symptoms of ADHD correlated with the&#xD;
      results of their Lidocaine Effectiveness Test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subjects with a confirmed diagnosis of Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD), who&#xD;
      are either untreated or poorly controlled with existing ADHD therapy, will be recruited for a&#xD;
      single, four-hour session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will be tested for lidocaine effectiveness using the application of lidocaine&#xD;
      gel to the tongue and assessment by taste.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects will then be assigned to two arms, (1) lidocaine sensitive (effective) or (2)&#xD;
      lidocaine insensitive (ineffective), and then randomized as to an intervention of potassium&#xD;
      supplementation or a placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Complete questionnaires about their history of certain symptoms and a food diary.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Get an ECG to exclude those with arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have their baseline serum potassium tested&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have measures of ADHD symptoms performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then each subject will receive the intervention of a single dose of the potassium or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the wait of one hour, a repeat serum potassium and measurement of symptoms will be&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note; The FDA also requires a Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (C-SSRS) for all ADHD&#xD;
      trials&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Enrolling by invitation</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 4, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The trial will have 2 arms, lidocaine sensitive (effective) and lidocaine insensitive (ineffective). The sample will be enriched to have 50% in each arm. Within each arm, subjects will be randomized on a 1-to-1 allocation to the treatment or control groups.&#xD;
The investigators will adopt an iterative approach of testing of batches of subjects because (1) the frequency of lidocaine-insensitivity is only known approximately, (2) the frequency may be unevenly distributed across ethnic groups, and (3) the exact effect size of the potassium is not known, though reported to be high in off-label use in clinical settings with more chronic administration.&#xD;
At the end of testing 40 patients, the results will be analyzed for statistical significance. (1) If the results are statistically significant with a 95% confidence, the testing may stop with the first batch of 40 subjects. (2) If not, sequential, iterative batches of 20 subjects will be tested, and the results reanalyzed.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The scoring of the lidocaine test is masked, using the coded identity of the tastes. The scoring will be done during the visit by the Scoring and Randomization Specialist so that the patient can be assigned to an intervention or control group to maintain equal numbers in treatment versus control groups. To prevent bias, the Scoring and Randomization Specialist will not be involved in any of the ADHD assessment steps and the patients will not be told about their lidocaine status until after all study testing is done. The subjects and other study personnel such as those doing the ADHD testing will be told not to discuss what they could or couldn't taste. Having scored the lidocaine test, the Scoring and Randomization Specialist will assign subjects to Intervention versus Control using a 1-to-1 allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of lidocaine ineffectiveness in those with ADHD</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator assesses identification and intensity of tastes (such as sweet) before and after application of oral lidocaine gel to the tongue.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator documentation of adverse reactions to either lidocaine or potassium</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Other discomforts</measure>
    <time_frame>1-2 hours after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator documentation of complaints or minor discomforts</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ADHD-RS questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and ~1-2 hours later, 1 hour after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire is a standard assessment tool for measuring the level of ADHD symptoms. The ADHD-RS-IV is for adults and the ADHD-RSM-5 is for teenagers. This test has been validated for measuring the impact of drugs in ADHD, typically multi-dose, multi-week changes.&#xD;
Since this study is a single-dose, several-hour study, the Investigators will complete only the portions designed to done with the patient and by the clinician; sections designed to be completed by parents and teachers. The results will establish expectations for future multi-dose studies.&#xD;
All scores on a range of None, Mild, Moderate, Severe.&#xD;
Carelessness&#xD;
Difficulty sustaining attention in activities&#xD;
No follow through&#xD;
Can't organize&#xD;
Avoids/dislikes tasks requiring sustained mental effort&#xD;
Loses Important items&#xD;
Easily distractible&#xD;
Forgetful in daily activities</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Clinical Global Impression Physician Completed Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and ~1-2 hours later, 1 hour after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician-assessed improvement in overall symptoms, using CGI S (severity) as baseline and CGI I (improvement) to track any change.&#xD;
Investigator assesses &quot;Compared to his or her condition at baseline, how much has he or she changed?&quot;&#xD;
Very much improved Much improved Minimally improved No change Minimally worse Much worse Very much worse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in scores using Quotient ADHD System</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and ~1 hour after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Quotient device (http://www.quotient-adhd.com) tracks scores on 6 factors of motion analysis; 6 factors of attention response; and 8 factors of attention state. The subject plays a diagnostic &quot;video game&quot; and the machine tracks movement of the head, and speed and accuracy of the mouse clicks.&#xD;
The first assessment will serve as a baseline and the assessment post-intervention will measure any changes. (all scores from 0-100)&#xD;
Motion Analysis (including Immobility Duration, Number of movements, displacement, area, spacial complexity, temporal scaling)&#xD;
Attention Response Analysis (including adjusted Accuracy, Omission Errors, Commission Errors, Latency, Variability, Coefficient of Variation for response latency)&#xD;
Attention State Analysis (including number of shifts, Attentive, Impulsive, Distracted, Disengaged, Random, Minimal, Contrary, Overall Results)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>ADHD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-effective ADHD: Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-dose potassium gluconate oral capsule intervention for ADHD subjects for whom lidocaine is effective</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-effective ADHD: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-dose placebo oral capsule intervention for ADHD subjects for whom lidocaine is effective</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-ineffective ADHD: Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-dose potassium gluconate oral capsule intervention for ADHD subjects for whom lidocaine is ineffective</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-ineffective ADHD: placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-dose placebo oral capsule intervention for ADHD subjects for whom lidocaine is ineffective</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Potassium Gluconate Oral Capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>Each subject will receive a dose of ~8 mg/kg of potassium. We will be giving a maximum of 14 mEq in a single dose.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-effective ADHD: Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-ineffective ADHD: Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo oral capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>Each subject will receive a dose of ~8 mg/kg of a placebo capsule</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-effective ADHD: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lidocaine-ineffective ADHD: placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previously documented ADHD diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Untreated or taking existing ADHD drugs, but symptoms poorly controlled (e.g.,&#xD;
             symptoms not well managed by amphetamines, including ongoing inattention and&#xD;
             impulsivity)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Well treated with existing ADHD medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. IQ less than 80&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Severe head trauma that led to loss of consciousness for more than an hour or required&#xD;
             surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Birth weight below 5 pounds or 2270 grams&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Severe autism (milder conditions described as Asperger syndrome or &quot;high-functioning&#xD;
             autism&quot; are not excluded)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Comorbid psychiatric disorders, such as generalized anxiety disorder, major depressive&#xD;
             disorder, schizophrenia and schizoaffective disorder, bipolar disorder, and any&#xD;
             co-morbid condition at the discretion of the PI that would interfere with a patient's&#xD;
             ability to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Mouth lesions, known to temporarily interfere with lidocaine effectiveness&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Renal disease or abnormal kidney function or receiving dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. An individual has a factor likely to reduce penetrance, including excessive salt loss,&#xD;
             such as caked salt on the body after exercise and Cystic fibrosis in a relative&#xD;
             suggestive of the individual being a carrier.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Heart arrhythmia, known or evident on ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known intolerance or allergy to lidocaine&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Already taking supplemental potassium or renin angiotensin aldosterone inhibitors or&#xD;
             other potassium elevating agents (see list below)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Angiotensin Converting Enzyme Inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Alacepril (not available in US)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Benazepril (Lotensin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Captopril (trade name Capoten)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Cilazapril (Inhibace)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Delapril (not available in US)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Enalapril (Vasotec/Renitec)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Fosinopril (Fositen/Monopril)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Imidapril (Tanatril)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Lisinopril (Listril/Lopril/Novatec/Prinivil/Zestril)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Moexipril (Univasc)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Perindopril (Coversyl/Aceon/Perindo)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Quinapril (Accupril)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Ramipril (Altace/Prilace/Ramace/Ramiwin/Triatec/Tritace)&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Spirapril (Renormax)&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Temocapril (not available in US)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Teprotide (but not active by oral administration and not used in US)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Trandolapril (Mavik/Odrik/Gopten)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Zofenopril&#xD;
&#xD;
        Angiotensin receptor blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Azilsartan (Edarbi)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Candesartan (Atacand)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Eprosartan (Teveten)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Fimasartan (Kanarb)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Irbesartan (Avapro)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Losartan (Cozaar)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Olmesartan (Benicar/Olmetec)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Telmisartan (Micardis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Valsartan (Diovan)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Aldosterone antagonists&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Spironolactone (Aldactone)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Eplerenone (Inspra)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Renin inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
        a. Aliskiren (Tekturna, Rasilez)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other potassium elevating agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Antibiotics, including penicillin G and trimethoprim&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Azole antifungals&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Beta-blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Herbal supplements, including milkweed, lily of the valley, Siberian ginseng, Hawthorn&#xD;
             berries&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Heparin&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory medications (NSAIDs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Oral contraceptives containing drospirenone&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael M Segal, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>PhenoSolve, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Mintz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CNNH &amp; CRCNJ</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Research Center of New Jersey (CRCNJ)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Voorhees</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08043</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/1778/f693dc7dd257ab98a96b5bf03408d9cef3eb.pdf</url>
    <description>Rozanski RJ, Primosch RE, Courts FJ (1988). Clinical efficacy of 1 and 2% solutions of lidocaine. Pediatr Dent.10:287-90</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.amazon.com/ADHD-Does-Not-Exist-Hyperactivity/dp/006226673X</url>
    <description>Saul R (2014) &quot;ADHD Does Not Exist&quot;. HarperCollins.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://simulconsult.com/resources/hypopp.html</url>
    <description>Segal MM, Jurkat-Rott K, Levitt J, Lehmann-Horn F (2014) Hypokalemic periodic paralysis - an owner's manual</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://patents.google.com/patent/WO2017035470A1/en</url>
    <description>Segal MM (2015) Devices, Kits, and Methods for Determining Sensitivity to Anesthetics. US Patent Filing 62/210,747, Filed 09/14/2015</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Infante MA, Moore EM, Nguyen TT, Fourligas N, Mattson SN, Riley EP. Objective assessment of ADHD core symptoms in children with heavy prenatal alcohol exposure. Physiol Behav. 2015 Sep 1;148:45-50. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2014.10.014. Epub 2014 Oct 23.</citation>
    <PMID>25447751</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Levitt JO. Practical aspects in the management of hypokalemic periodic paralysis. J Transl Med. 2008 Apr 21;6:18. doi: 10.1186/1479-5876-6-18. Erratum in: J Transl Med. 2014;12:198. Dosage error in article text.</citation>
    <PMID>18426576</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nakai Y, Milgrom P, Mancl L, Coldwell SE, Domoto PK, Ramsay DS. Effectiveness of local anesthesia in pediatric dental practice. J Am Dent Assoc. 2000 Dec;131(12):1699-705.</citation>
    <PMID>11143733</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Segal MM. We cannot say whether attention deficit hyperactivity disorder exists, but we can find its molecular mechanisms. Pediatr Neurol. 2014 Jul;51(1):15-6. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2014.04.014. Epub 2014 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>24938135</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Segal MM, Rogers GF, Needleman HL, Chapman CA. Hypokalemic sensory overstimulation. J Child Neurol. 2007 Dec;22(12):1408-10. doi: 10.1177/0883073807307095.</citation>
    <PMID>18174562</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Segal MM, Douglas AF. Late sodium channel openings underlying epileptiform activity are preferentially diminished by the anticonvulsant phenytoin. J Neurophysiol. 1997 Jun;77(6):3021-34.</citation>
    <PMID>9212254</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Teicher MH, Polcari A, Fourligas N, Vitaliano G, Navalta CP. Hyperactivity persists in male and female adults with ADHD and remains a highly discriminative feature of the disorder: a case-control study. BMC Psychiatry. 2012 Nov 7;12:190. doi: 10.1186/1471-244X-12-190.</citation>
    <PMID>23134619</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 15, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 14, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 14, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 20, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Conditions in which lidocaine is ineffective</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We plan to submit for publication descriptions of what was accomplished, and the evaluations as described in the study, including the incidence of lidocaine ineffectiveness in those with ADHD.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>When the study is complete</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>open</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

