<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03568760</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016-01275</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03568760</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Finding the Right Words in Neurogenic Communication Disorders</brief_title>
  <official_title>Finding the Right Words in Neurogenic Communication Disorders: Naming of Objects and Actions, Communicative Strategies in Conversation and Effects of Training</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Göteborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Swedish Research Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Swedish Council for Working Life and Social Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Göteborg University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Every year thousands of persons suffer from brain damage resulting in anomia, that is, word&#xD;
      finding difficulties affecting their ability to talk to other people. Anomia may be a result&#xD;
      of stroke or of progressive neurological diseases such as Parkinson's disease or multiple&#xD;
      sclerosis (MS). Word retrieval is dependent on a complex system of different neural networks&#xD;
      and to name objects and activities can be affected to different degrees. The present project&#xD;
      explores different aspects of naming ability in altogether 90 persons that has anomia related&#xD;
      to stroke or to Parkinson's disease or MS. Furthermore, the communicative strategies and&#xD;
      resources used by conversation partners in everyday conversational interaction and in care&#xD;
      situations, affected by anomia are studied. Finally, the project includes a study of the&#xD;
      effectiveness of a word finding training program based on stimulation of semantic and&#xD;
      phonological networks in the brain, involved in the production of words. There is a lack of&#xD;
      research on effects on communication from anomia in Parkinson's disease and MS and there is&#xD;
      no research on anomia that investigates both object and action naming using a material&#xD;
      adapted to the Swedish language. In the project quantitative and qualitative methods are used&#xD;
      to explore and describe how persons with different neurogenic communication disorders can use&#xD;
      different resources and communicative strategies to express themselves.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Project out line&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main project consists of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A descriptive study of the occurrence and type of naming difficulties in people with&#xD;
           stroke, Parkinson's disease or Multiple sclerosis (MS) where quantitative data is&#xD;
           compared at group level, (study 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A descriptive study in which word search strategies are investigated with both&#xD;
           quantitative and qualitative methods (study 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A series of three intervention studies examining the effect of treatment of anomia&#xD;
           (studies 3-5).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 1: The relation between type of injury and ability to name objects and actions and&#xD;
      complex semantic-pragmatic word fluency&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants The project includes a total of 90 people with anomia: 50 subjects with anomia&#xD;
      after stroke, 20 individuals with Parkinson's disease and 20 individuals with MS are&#xD;
      recruited are recruited through patient associations and health care facilities in Västra&#xD;
      Götaland and included consecutively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the study confrontation naming ability, and word fluency is explored. In addition, the&#xD;
      type of naming difficulties and consequences of anomia in everyday communication are examined&#xD;
      with a questionnaire and communication analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) Confrontation naming ability is examined with a material consisting of 42 images&#xD;
      representing 21 nouns and 21 verbs. The selection of images comes from The Object &amp; Action&#xD;
      Naming Battery and is adapted to Swedish linguistic and cultural conditions. The images&#xD;
      consist of simple black and white drawings. There is a 20-second time limit for response for&#xD;
      each image. In addition to scoring, an analysis and categorization of the response according&#xD;
      to the coding scheme is performed; 2) Word fluency is examined with semantic (animals and&#xD;
      activities) and phonological (F, A and S) word fluency tests where the participant will&#xD;
      produce as many words as possible for each category during one minute. The results are&#xD;
      compared with reference data for healthy participants and the use of strategies is analyzed&#xD;
      by calculating cluster size and number of switches between different categories; a more&#xD;
      complex semantic-pragmatic word fluency task is also administrated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants' experience of their communication skills in everyday life and quality of life&#xD;
      is gathered in a questionnaire with image support: The Communication Outcome After Stroke&#xD;
      (COAST) scale. COAST consists of 20 questions where participants estimate themselves on a&#xD;
      5-degree likert scale. Stroke and Aphasia Quality of Life Scale (SAQOL-39) and Communicative&#xD;
      Participation Item Bank (CPIB) are also administrated as well as a formalized interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 2: Word search strategies in naming difficulties in people with different types of&#xD;
      neurogenic communication disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants In this descriptive study fifteen participants with Parkinson's disease and&#xD;
      fifteen participants with MS are included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods Word search strategies in ten-twenty minutes of naturally occurring&#xD;
      conversations are assessed through communication analysis. Sequences where participants are&#xD;
      involved in repair due to difficulties to express themselves are analyzed with the&#xD;
      qualitative method Conversation Analysis in combination med Aktivity based communication&#xD;
      analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies 3-4: Training with semantic feature analysis to improve naming&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants Six participants with MS and six participants with Parkinson's disease and 40&#xD;
      participants with anomia due to stroke will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention Participants receive training in semantic feature analysis (SFA) for naming of&#xD;
      objects and activities. The training is administered by presenting an image representing&#xD;
      either an object or an activity are presented to the participant. The participant is&#xD;
      encouraged to try to produce the target word as well as a number of words semantically&#xD;
      related to the target word. The related words are listed in a certain order and describe&#xD;
      different semantic aspects of the target word. The participants get to choose a number of&#xD;
      words which they want to practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants receive training at 20 occasions, three times a week. The training is&#xD;
      delivered during one hour each session in individual training for the participants with MS&#xD;
      and in a group setting for two hours, including 30 minutes pause for participants with stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 3-4 - training anomia due to Parkinson's disease and MS Since semantic feature analysis&#xD;
      has not previously been used as treatment for people with Parkinson's disease or MS, the&#xD;
      effect is evaluated in using time series design with multiple baselines. Three-five baseline&#xD;
      measures of the dependent variable is collected before start of training and then every&#xD;
      fourth training session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 5 - training anomia due to stroke In study 5 the effect of intervention for&#xD;
      participants with anomia due to stroke is assessed in a randomized group study with a control&#xD;
      group. The control group receives training in comprehension. The groups are matched in terms&#xD;
      of age, severity of anomia time since onset and level of education. Before and after the&#xD;
      intervention, as well as at a twelve week follow up, the effects are assessed in both groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The results are assessed by independent assessors blinded to when the data is obtained and from which group.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Naming ability in the Object &amp; Action Naming Battery</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to name forty pictures consisting of simple black and white drawings. There is a 20-second time limit for response for each picture. Number of correct objects and activities will be calculated separately (range 0-20) as well as summarized (range 0-40)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in naming ability in the Object &amp; Action Naming Battery</measure>
    <time_frame>At a twelve week follow up after the completion of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to name forty pictures consisting of simple black and white drawings. There is a 20-second time limit for response for each picture. Number of correct objects and activities will be calculated separately (range 0-20) as well as summarized (range 0-40)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Naming of 20 individually chosen training words</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to name objects and action words participants have chosen to practice</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in naming of 20 individually chosen training words</measure>
    <time_frame>At a twelve week follow up after the completion of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to name objects and action words participants have chosen to practice</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Communication Outcome After Stroke (COAST) scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in participants perception of the communicative ability from baseline to after intervention. COAST comprises 20 items where participants rates themselves on a 5-graded likert scale. The scale is running from 1) &quot;couldn't do it at all, through 2) &quot;with a lot of difficulty&quot;, 3) &quot;with some difficulty&quot;, 4) &quot;quite well&quot; to 5) &quot;very well&quot;. The scoring of each item will be summarized and averaged (total range 0-5) and a higher score indicates perceptions of better communicative ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in the Communication Outcome After Stroke (COAST) scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At a twelve week follow up after the completion of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in participants perception of the communicative ability twelve weeks after intervention is completed. COAST comprises 20 items where participants rates themselves on a 5-graded likert scale. The scale is running from The scale is running from 1) &quot;couldn't do it at all, through 2) &quot;with a lot of difficulty&quot;, 3) &quot;with some difficulty&quot;, 4) &quot;quite well&quot; to 5) &quot;very well&quot;. The scoring of each item will be summarized and averaged (total range 0-5) and a higher score indicates perceptions of better communicative ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Stroke Aphasia Quality of Life (SAQOL-39)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change after intervention in participant reported health related quality of life in a questionnaire with 39 items where participants evaluate of their everyday functioning in three domains: physical, psychosocial and communication. Scores range from 1 to 5 in each sub domain and are averaged; higher scores indicate better quality of life. Scoring in each domain will be summarized and averaged and presented separately as well as in a compound averaged score (range 1-5).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in the Stroke Aphasia Quality of Life (SAQOL-39)</measure>
    <time_frame>At a follow up twelve weeks after completion of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change 12 weeks after intervention is completed in participant reported health related quality of life in a questionnaire with 39 items where participants evaluate of their everyday functioning in three domains: physical, psychosocial and communication. Scores range from 1 to 5 in each sub domain and are averaged; higher scores indicate better quality of life. Scoring in each domain will be summarized and averaged and presented separately as well as in a compound averaged score (range 1-5).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change from baseline to after intervention in participants' perceptions of their communicative participation in everyday life activities. A short form of the item bank with ten items are used - participants rates their perception of degree of participation on a four-graded scale where higher scores indicate higher degree of participation. The scale runs from 0) &quot;very much&quot;, through 1) &quot;quite a bit&quot;, 2) &quot;a little&quot;, to 3) &quot;not at all&quot;. The scoring of each item will be summarized into a total score (range 0-30).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in the Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB)</measure>
    <time_frame>At a 12 week follow up after the completion of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change 12 weeks after the completion of the intervention in participants' perceptions of their communicative participation in everyday life activities. A short form of the item bank with ten items are used - participants rates their perception of degree of participation on a four-graded scale where higher scores indicate higher degree of participation. The scale runs from 0) &quot;very much&quot;, through 1) &quot;quite a bit&quot;, 2) &quot;a little&quot;, to 3) &quot;not at all&quot;. The scoring of each item will be summarized into a total score (range 0-30).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retelling of events in video clips</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before start of intervention and after 21 days, at completion the intervention program</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to retell and describe events from baseline to after intervention is completed.The participants view short video clips with a character involved with different activities including objects and are asked to retell what happened every tenth second.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained change in retelling of events in video clips</measure>
    <time_frame>At a 12 week follow up after the completion of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of change in ability to retell and describe events from after the completion of intervention to a 12 weeks follow up. The participants view short video clips with a character involved with different activities including objects and are asked to retell what happened every tenth second.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Anomia</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Aphasia</condition>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SFA treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Semantic feature analysis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comprehension training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Comprehension training</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Semantic feature analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Confrontation naming training and training in doing circumlocutions</description>
    <arm_group_label>SFA treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Comprehension training</intervention_name>
    <description>Reading and hearing comprehension</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comprehension training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjective experience of word finding difficulties&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed left hemisphere stroke or Parkinson's disease or MS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With correction, sufficient hearing and vision to be able to participate in the&#xD;
             assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with stroke at least six months post-onset and documented location of&#xD;
             injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mother tongue other than Swedish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderately or severely impaired comprehension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other neurological injury or disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate-severe apraxia of speech or dysarthria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fatigue or impaired attention deficit which prevents participating in intensive&#xD;
             training&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charlotta Saldert</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Inst of Neurosci &amp; Physiology, Speech &amp; Language Pathology Unit University of Gothenburg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Gothenburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gothenburg</city>
        <state>Västra Göraland</state>
        <zip>405 30</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tallberg IM, Ivachova E, Jones Tinghag K, Ostberg P. Swedish norms for word fluency tests: FAS, animals and verbs. Scand J Psychol. 2008 Oct;49(5):479-85. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-9450.2008.00653.x. Epub 2008 Apr 29.</citation>
    <PMID>18452499</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Long A, Hesketh A, Paszek G, Booth M, Bowen A. Development of a reliable self-report outcome measure for pragmatic trials of communication therapy following stroke: the Communication Outcome after Stroke (COAST) scale. Clin Rehabil. 2008 Dec;22(12):1083-94. doi: 10.1177/0269215508090091.</citation>
    <PMID>19052247</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baylor C, Yorkston K, Eadie T, Kim J, Chung H, Amtmann D. The Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB): item bank calibration and development of a disorder-generic short form. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2013 Aug;56(4):1190-208. doi: 10.1044/1092-4388(2012/12-0140). Epub 2013 Jul 1.</citation>
    <PMID>23816661</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hilari K, Lamping DL, Smith SC, Northcott S, Lamb A, Marshall J. Psychometric properties of the Stroke and Aphasia Quality of Life Scale (SAQOL-39) in a generic stroke population. Clin Rehabil. 2009 Jun;23(6):544-57. doi: 10.1177/0269215508101729. Epub 2009 May 15.</citation>
    <PMID>19447841</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 21, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anomia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aphasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anomia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communication Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

