<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03568058</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>180410</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03568058</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personalized Immunotherapy in Adults With Advanced Cancers Immunotherapy in Adults With Advanced Cancers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b Safety and Feasibility Study of Personalized Immunotherapy in Adults With Advanced Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ezra Cohen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if it is possible to make and administer safely a&#xD;
      'personalized' vaccine to treat patients that have been diagnosed with advanced cancer and&#xD;
      are not candidates for curative therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if it is possible to make and administer safely a&#xD;
      'personalized' vaccine to treat patients that have been diagnosed with advanced cancer and&#xD;
      are not candidates for curative therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This 'personalized' vaccine will use information gained from specific characteristics of your&#xD;
      own cancer. It is known that cancer has mutations (changes in genetic material) that are&#xD;
      specific to an individual and tumor. These mutations can cause the tumor cells to produce&#xD;
      proteins that appear very different from the body's own cells. It is possible that these&#xD;
      proteins used in a vaccine may induce strong immune (protective) responses, which may help&#xD;
      your body fight any tumor cells that could cause your cancer to come back in the future. The&#xD;
      study will examine the safety of the vaccine when given at several time points and will&#xD;
      examine your blood cells for signs that the vaccine induced an immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The personalized vaccine will be given in combination with an anti-PD1 antibody,&#xD;
      pembrolizumab, which is used with the intention to increase anti-cancer immunity&#xD;
      (protection). Pembrolizumab is a type of drug that blocks certain proteins made by some types&#xD;
      of immune system cells, such as T cells, and some cancer cells. These proteins help keep&#xD;
      immune responses in check and can keep T cells from killing cancer cells. When these proteins&#xD;
      are blocked, the &quot;brakes&quot; on the immune system are released and T cells are able to kill&#xD;
      cancer cells better.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This personalized vaccine is considered experimental because this is not an FDA approved&#xD;
      therapy for cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pembrolizumab is FDA approved for the treatment of melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
      (NSCLC), head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC), classical Hodgkin lymphoma (cHL),&#xD;
      urothelial carcinoma, microsatellite instability-high cancer (MSI-H), gastric cancer,&#xD;
      cervical cancer, and hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). Pembrolizumab is considered experimental&#xD;
      (investigational) for the treatment of all other cancer types.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 26, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantitative frequency of TCR</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Treatment-related Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>RECIST 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of time from start of study treatment until objective tumor progression or death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Progression</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of time from start of study treatment until objective tumor progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of time from start of study treatment to death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>vaccine and anti-PD-1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>personalized vaccine and anti-PD-1 administered concurrently at the start of study therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 before vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>anti-PD-1 antibody for 6 weeks followed by personalized vaccine therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 and vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>anti-PD-1 antibody followed by personalized vaccine therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>personalized vaccine therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>personalized vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Vaccine will be constructed for each subject that express multiple candidate tumor-derived neoantigens.</description>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 and vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 before vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>vaccine and anti-PD-1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg pembrolizumab will be administered intravenous (IV) infusion every 3 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 and vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>anti-PD1 before vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>vaccine and anti-PD-1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>keytruda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically documented incurable solid tumor [excluding lymphoma].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease as defined by RECIST 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressed on or be intolerant to therapies that are known to provide clinical&#xD;
             benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-measurable disease by RECIST 1.1 and high-risk (&gt;50% over 5 years) of mortality&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one tumor site accessible for biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men with partners of child-bearing potential must&#xD;
             agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control;&#xD;
             abstinence) prior to study entry, for the duration of study participation, and for 90&#xD;
             days following completion of therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving or has received another anti-cancer therapy within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to first dose of vaccine study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving or has received PD1/PDL1 inhibitor immunotherapy within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving or has received anti-PD1 or anti-CTLA4 treatment during the&#xD;
             vaccine preparation period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving TNF pathway inhibitors, PI3 kinase inhibitors, systemic steroid therapy or&#xD;
             any other form of immunosuppressive therapy within 14 days prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received an investigational agent within 28 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated brain metastases; individuals with treated and stable metastases are&#xD;
             eligible. Eligible subjects should have recovered from the acute effects of radiation&#xD;
             therapy or surgery prior to study entry, have discontinued corticosteroid treatment&#xD;
             for brain metastases for at least 4 weeks and are neurologically stable for 8 weeks&#xD;
             (confirmed by MRI) prior to administration of experimental therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received a diagnosis of hepatitis B or hepatitis C for which there is no clear&#xD;
             evidence of natural immunity, immunity subsequent to vaccination, or successful&#xD;
             eradication of the virus following antiviral therapy (individuals who are hepatitis C&#xD;
             antibody positive may be enrolled if negative viral load confirmed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autoimmune disease including: inflammatory bowel disease (including&#xD;
             ulcerative colitis and Crohn's Disease), rheumatoid arthritis, systemic progressive&#xD;
             sclerosis (scleroderma), systemic lupus erythematosus, autoimmune vasculitis (e.g.&#xD;
             Wegener's granulomatosis); central nervous system or motor neuropathy considered of&#xD;
             autoimmune origin (e.g. Guillain-Barré syndrome, myasthenia gravis, multiple&#xD;
             sclerosis). Individuals with vitiligo, Sjogren's Syndrome, interstitial cystitis,&#xD;
             Graves' or Hashimoto's Disease, celiac disease, DM1, or hypothyroidism stable on&#xD;
             hormone replacement will be allowed with Study Medical Monitor's approval.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current&#xD;
             pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of receiving a solid organ transplant or allogeneic bone marrow transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedure within 28 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female, pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erza Cohen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Diego</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSD Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 13, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 13, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ezra Cohen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>personalized cancer vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>personalized immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>pembrolizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Keytruda</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>neoantigen</keyword>
  <keyword>solid tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

