<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04861038</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SOM-029</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04861038</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study Using Negative Pressure to Reduce Apnea</brief_title>
  <acronym>SUPRA</acronym>
  <official_title>Study Using Negative Pressure to Reduce Apnea (SUPRA)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sommetrics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sommetrics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to determine the safety and effectiveness of the aerSleep® II&#xD;
      device for treatment of moderate to severe Obstructive Sleep Apnea (OSA) over 24 weeks of&#xD;
      home use in spontaneously breathing adult subjects who are intolerant of Continuous Positive&#xD;
      Airway Pressure (CPAP) therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center, single-arm, prospective, observational intervention study to&#xD;
      determine the safety and effectiveness of the aerSleep II System. Up to 200 subjects will be&#xD;
      enrolled at up to ten study sites in the United States to ensure that approximately 79&#xD;
      subjects who are termed initial responders can be evaluated after 24 weeks of home use with&#xD;
      the aerSleep II device. As part of screening and prior to intervention, home sleep testing&#xD;
      will be performed to establish baseline apnea-hypopnea index (AHI). Subjects meeting study&#xD;
      criteria will wear the aerSleep II device at home. After a 1-week period of acclimation,&#xD;
      subjects will have a second HST (HST #2). Initial responders with a ≥50% reduction in AHI&#xD;
      from baseline with an AHI &lt;20/hour will be continued on home treatment. Non-responders will&#xD;
      be discontinued from the study. After 12 weeks, subjects will have an interim home sleep&#xD;
      study. After 24 weeks of home use, subjects will have HST #4 to determine the primary&#xD;
      effectiveness endpoint.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained response to aerSleep II therapy at 24 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The primary effectiveness endpoint is to demonstrate that a majority of adult subjects who are initial responders to aerSleep II therapy experience a change of at least 50% of their baseline AHI with an AHI rate less than 20 per hour at the final home sleep test at 24 weeks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Device Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The primary safety endpoint is to characterize the adverse device effects experienced throughout the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ODI change</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Demonstrate a change in Oxygen Desaturation Index (ODI) at HST #4 compared to baseline HST for initial responders</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AHI change from baseline for all subjects that acclimate to the aerSleep II device</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the proportion of subjects that acclimate to the device that exhibit a change in AHI after 24 weeks of home use with the aerSleep II device</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep disturbance from baseline as measured by Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Sleep Disturbance questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the change in sleep disturbance at the end of the study compared to baseline using the validated PROMIS Short Form Sleep Disturbance 8b questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep impairment from baseline as measured by PROMIS Sleep Sleep-Related Impairment questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the change in sleep impairment at the end of the study from baseline as measured by the validated PROMIS Short Form Sleep-Related Impairment 8a questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep from baseline as measured by Patient Global Impression Scale questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determine any change in sleep at the end of the study from baseline as measured by the Patient Global Impression Scale questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</condition>
  <condition>Apnea, Sleep</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>aerSleep II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of aerSleep II device to provide continuous external negative pressure to treat moderate to severe OSA in spontaneously breathing subjects who are intolerant of CPAP</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>aerSleep II</intervention_name>
    <description>Continuous negative external pressure (cNEP) system that maintains an open airway by applying negative pressure to the anterior neck via a soft silicone collar</description>
    <arm_group_label>aerSleep II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index &lt;38 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior documented diagnosis of OSA by means of a polysomnography (PSG) test or home&#xD;
             sleep test (HST)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documented evidence from a screening HST following consent to demonstrate:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. AHI 15 - 50/hour&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. &gt;80% of the apneas and hypopneas are obstructive&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous treatment attempt with CPAP resulting in failure to treat or discontinuation&#xD;
             due to intolerance, subject choice, or struggle to use CPAP&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have not used CPAP or oral appliances within 1 week of the screening home sleep test&#xD;
             and agree not to use CPAP or oral appliances throughout the study duration&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Access to and ability to use a smart device such as a smartphone or tablet&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to speak, read, and write English&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. In the opinion of the investigator, the subject will be able to understand and comply&#xD;
             with all study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known sleep disorder other than OSA, such as narcolepsy, restless leg syndrome,&#xD;
             idiopathic hypersomnolence or chronic insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Craniofacial abnormalities that may be contributing to OSA&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous surgery, injury, or radiation to the neck which, in the Investigator's&#xD;
             judgment, could interfere with collar fit or comfort&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Excessive hair or beard in the area of the neck where the collar will be placed,&#xD;
             and/or unwillingness to shave that area for the duration of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Inflammatory skin condition, such as acne or eczema in the area where the collar will&#xD;
             be affixed to the skin, which, in the Investigator's judgment, could interfere with&#xD;
             collar fit or comfort&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known silicone allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Night shift work because of irregular sleep-wake cycles&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Excessive alcohol intake, defined as that leading to interference with work, home&#xD;
             life, or the ability to optimally perform normal everyday duties and tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Use of illicit drugs (including marijuana) currently or within the past 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Serious pulmonary disease (e.g., cor pulmonale, CO2 retention, or poorly controlled&#xD;
             asthma)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Use of home oxygen or baseline oxygen saturation &lt;94%&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Cancer that has been in remission for less than one year&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Psychiatric illness that, in the opinion of the Investigator, is not reasonably&#xD;
             well-controlled with treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Serious cardiac disease (e.g., congestive heart failure, unstable coronary artery&#xD;
             disease, or poorly controlled rhythm disturbance)&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Prior carotid endarterectomy, prior percutaneous coronary angiography (including any&#xD;
             placement of carotid stents), or known stenosis of either internal carotid artery &gt;&#xD;
             70% from prior carotid imaging (e.g., carotid duplex ultrasound, angiography, computed&#xD;
             tomography angiography, or magnetic resonance angiography)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Previous surgery for peripheral arterial disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Presence of possible or definite carotid artery disease, defined as any of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. history of cerebrovascular accident (CVA) or transient ischemic attack (TIA) with&#xD;
                  uncertain etiology that is compatible with carotid artery disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. diminished carotid pulse on screening physical examination*&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. &gt; 70% stenosis in either extra-cranial internal carotid artery as determined by&#xD;
                  duplex ultrasound* (only performed on those who do not exhibit 17 a. or b.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Tonsil size 3 or 4 (Appendix C)*&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Currently pregnant* or planning to become pregnant during participation in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Unable to obtain adequate collar fit*&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Any condition or circumstance that, in the opinion of the investigator, may preclude&#xD;
             study completion, interfere with accurate data collection, or bias the results&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. The investigator believes that the subject's participation may not be in his or her&#xD;
             best interest&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kingman P. Strohl, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eric Koehler</last_name>
    <phone>760.295.5620</phone>
    <email>ekoehler@sommetrics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Richard Rose, M.D.</last_name>
    <email>rrose@sommetrics.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baptist Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33176</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yudmilla Barbon</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Harneet Walia, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alicia Gonzalez Zacarias</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ulysses Magalang, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UPMC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shirley Longinotti</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sanjay Patel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bogan Sleep Consultants</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbia</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Heather Byrd</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard Bogan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BioSerenity</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbia</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alisha Henderson</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alyssa Cairns, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

