<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04865549</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HCB/2016/0296</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04865549</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sentinel Node After Neoadjuvancy In Node-Positive Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>SANA</acronym>
  <official_title>Sentinel Node After Neoadjuvancy In Node-Positive Breast Cancer: SANA Multicentric Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Clinic of Barcelona</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Clinic of Barcelona</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The status of the axillary lymph nodes is one of the main prognostic factors in breast cancer&#xD;
      (BC). SLNB is currently the standard staging method for patients with clinically&#xD;
      node-negative (cN0) breast cancer. In patients with a positive SLN and in those with affected&#xD;
      lymph nodes at the beginning (cN+), LND is the standard of treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Breast cancer (BC) is the most common malignant tumor and the one that causes the highest&#xD;
      number of deaths among women around the world. In Spain some 25,000 new cases are diagnosed&#xD;
      per year, which represents almost 30% of all female tumors. In Catalonia, the incidence is&#xD;
      83.9 cases / 100,000 inhabitants, while the national average is 50.9 cases / 100,000&#xD;
      inhabitants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thanks to screening programs and the awareness of patients and professionals, the majority of&#xD;
      diagnosed cases are found in an early stage of the disease. In early stages, the prognosis is&#xD;
      excellent with a 5-year survival greater than 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lymph node staging: selective sentinel node biopsy (SLNB) vs axillary lymphadenectomy The&#xD;
      status of the axillary lymph nodes is one of the main prognostic factors. Knowing the lymph&#xD;
      node status allows the disease to be staged and modulates locoregional and systemic&#xD;
      treatment. Lymph node staging and management of axillary disease have changed dramatically in&#xD;
      recent decades.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SLNB is currently the standard staging method for patients with clinically node-negative&#xD;
      (cN0) breast cancer. When SLN is negative, axillary lymph node dissection (LND) can be&#xD;
      omitted without prejudice to patient survival or locoregional control of the disease. In&#xD;
      patients with a positive SLN and in those with affected lymph nodes at the beginning (cN+),&#xD;
      LND is the standard of treatment. Morbidity associated with this technique affects up to 80%&#xD;
      of patients and includes: chronic lymphedema of the upper limb (20-30%), seromas (50-60%)&#xD;
      that in many cases require repeated punctures for drainage, infection of the wound (5-15%)&#xD;
      that requires antibiotic treatment and sometimes drainage, decreased mobility of the arm or&#xD;
      &quot;frozen shoulder&quot; (up to 10%) that requires rehabilitation treatment, neuropathic pain due to&#xD;
      injury to the intercostobrachial nerve (5- 20%) and other less frequent ones such as hematoma&#xD;
      or section of the long thoracic nerves (which produces a scapula alata) or the latissimus&#xD;
      dorsi. It is obvious that all these complications affect the quality of life of patients and&#xD;
      their emotional state. LND lengthens the days of hospitalization and this, together with the&#xD;
      treatment of associated complications, substantially increases healthcare costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current focus on the initial treatment of breast cancer: primary systemic treatment Advances&#xD;
      in biological knowledge of the disease and in systemic treatments have led to an increasing&#xD;
      number of patients with BC starting with systemic therapy, relegating surgery to a second&#xD;
      stage. This approach evaluates the tumor response in vivo to systemic treatment and provides&#xD;
      critical prognostic information. In addition, the decrease and even disappearance of the&#xD;
      tumor increases the chances of offering a conservative surgery in the breast. Response rates&#xD;
      vary according to the biological type of tumor and the treatment used, being higher for Her2+&#xD;
      tumors treated with chemotherapy combined with anti-Her2 antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In cN0 patients receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NCT), SLNB can be performed before or&#xD;
      after. Performing it later, together with breast surgery, has the advantage of saving the&#xD;
      patient a surgical procedure. This strategy is supported by numerous studies that show&#xD;
      detection and false negative (FN) rates comparable to those of patients who undergo SLNB&#xD;
      before neoadjuvant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In those patients who present clinically positive lymph nodes (cN +) before initiating&#xD;
      neoadjuvancy, the standard strategy in relation to the axilla is to perform LND. However, in&#xD;
      40-50% of patients, lymph node disease disappears with treatment. Nodal response is greater&#xD;
      in tumors with estrogen receptor negative, high histologic grade, and Her2 overexpression. It&#xD;
      follows that up to 40-50% of unnecessary lymphadenectomies are currently being carried out.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Application of the SLNB in cN + patients undergoing neoadjuvant chemotherapy Due to the&#xD;
      benefits that SLNB represents in cN0 patients and the complete response rates in the axilla&#xD;
      after neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) in initial cN+ patients, the question arises as to&#xD;
      whether SLNB can be valid in these patients. Previous studies in which SLNB was performed in&#xD;
      clinically node-positive patients who received NAC have shown FN rates of up to 25%. The&#xD;
      Spanish Society of Senology and Breast Pathology (SESPM) recommends for the validation of the&#xD;
      SLN technique to obtain a detection rate equal to or greater than 95% and a FN rate equal to&#xD;
      or less than 5%. International literature accepts FN rates equal to or less than 10%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The success of SLNB after NAC may be affected by altered lymphatic drainage of the breast&#xD;
      during chemotherapy. On the other hand, it is possible that the regression of the axillary&#xD;
      disease does not follow an orderly and uniform pattern, reducing the reliability of the&#xD;
      technique. Finally, the impact that a FN of the technique may have on the prognosis of these&#xD;
      patients is unknown, and it is probably not the same as in a cN0 patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The American College of Surgeons Oncology Group (ACOSOG) conducted a phase II trial that&#xD;
      included patients with BC T1-4, N1-2, M0. The patients received primary chemotherapy and&#xD;
      subsequently SLNB plus LND. The detection rate was 92.9%. There was a complete pathological&#xD;
      response in the axilla in 41% of the patients. The FN rate was 12.6% (higher than the&#xD;
      accepted 10%). The conclusion was that SLN biopsy cannot be recommended for these patients at&#xD;
      this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The multicenter study SENTINA (SENTinel NeoAdjuvant), carried out in Germany and Austria,&#xD;
      evaluated in one of its arms the performance of SLNB in cN + patients who converted to cN0&#xD;
      with NAC. The SLN detection rate and the FN rate were 80.1% and 14.2%, respectively. None of&#xD;
      these studies evaluate the results of the technique based on the biological profile of the&#xD;
      tumor or the response of the disease to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is imperative to correctly select patients and apply new strategies to optimize the&#xD;
      results of SLNB in order to identify regression of axillary disease and to avoid radicality&#xD;
      of LA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      New strategies: placement of a marker in the metastatic lymph node. Assessment of the&#xD;
      response according to the biological profile of the tumor and its impact on the rate of FN&#xD;
      Axillary ultrasound prior to neoadjuvancy is performed to detect possible lymph node&#xD;
      involvement and, together with biopsy of the suspicious node, offers a sensitivity and&#xD;
      specificity of 25% -95% and 97% -100%, respectively. Its application could be useful to&#xD;
      assess axillary lymph node response. Patients with normal-appearing axillary nodes on&#xD;
      ultrasound are likely to be less likely to have residual disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The placement of a marker in the biopsied pathological node that allows its identification&#xD;
      during the surgical act and to check whether or not it correlates with the SLN can be useful&#xD;
      strategies to reduce the rate of FN of the SLNB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The response of the disease in the breast and in the lymph nodes to NAC is different&#xD;
      depending on the biological profile of the tumor. The axillary response to treatment may have&#xD;
      an impact on the rate of FN of SLNB. Studying the results of the technique according to the&#xD;
      biological profile of the tumor can help us to better select the candidate patients for the&#xD;
      application of the technique.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Targetted axilary dissection detection rate in cN+ after neoadjuvant therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Targetted axilary dissection detection rate in cN+ after neoadjuvant therapy (Sentinel lymph node plus cliped node)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>False negative Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To know the detection rate and the false negative rate of the SLN biopsy in cN + patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Concordance</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Know the concordance rate between the SLN and the pathological node marked with an echo-visible marker</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ultrasound before-after NAC</measure>
    <time_frame>before the start of systemic therapy - after finishing systemic therapy just before surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To study the usefulness of axillary ultrasound before and after NAC to assess lymph node involvement and response to treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response Rate by biological profile</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention/procedure/surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the axillary lymph node response rate based on the biological profile of the tumor</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response Rate by treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention/procedure/surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the axillary lymph node response rate based on the primary systemic treatment received.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk factors description</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention/procedure/surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Study factors that influence detection rates and FN: marker placement in the pathological node of origin, method of SN identification; number of GC obtained; systemic treatment received; clinical and radiological response to treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>False Negative Rate by biological profile</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the intervention/procedure/surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To study specifically the influence of the biological profile of the tumor on the FN rate of the technique</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAD arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sentinel Node Biopsy + Targetted Axillary Dissection (Clipped cN1 node) extraction + lymphadenectomy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SNB + TAD + Lymphadenectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Sentinel Node Biopsy + Targetted Axillary Dissection (Previously to surgery marked cN1 node) + Lymphadenectomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAD arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age equal to or greater than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a diagnosis of T1-T3 primary infiltrating breast carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Axillary clinical involvement (cN +)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmation by FNAC or BAG of lymph node involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Candidates for neoadjuvant chemotherapy including anthracyclines and taxanes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T4 tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supra / infraclavicular lymph node or internal mammary chain (cN3) involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous ipsilateral breast or axillary surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Distant metastasis at diagnosis (M1)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Immaculada Alonso Vargas, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Clinic of Barcelona</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínic de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

