<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04868591</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-2261</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04868591</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Session Compared to Multiple Sessions of Education and Exercise for Older Adults With Spinal Pain in an Advanced Practice Physiotherapy Model of Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical and Economic Effectiveness of a Single Session Compared to Multiple Sessions of Education and Exercise for Older Adults With Spinal Pain in an Advanced Practice Physiotherapy Model of Care: Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ciusss de L'Est de l'Île de Montréal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ciusss de L'Est de l'Île de Montréal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: To assess the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a single session compared&#xD;
      to multiple sessions of education and exercise for older adults with spinal pain treated&#xD;
      conservatively in an advanced practice physiotherapy (APP) model of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods and Analysis: In this pragmatic randomized controlled trial, 152 older adults (≥ 65&#xD;
      years old) with neck or back pain initially referred for a consultation in neurosurgery, but&#xD;
      treated conservatively, will be recruited through the APP neurosurgery CareAxis program in&#xD;
      the Montreal region (Quebec, Canada). In the CareAxis program, older patients with spinal&#xD;
      pain are triaged by an advance practice physiotherapist and are offered conservative care and&#xD;
      only potential surgical candidates are referred to a neurosurgeon. Participants will be&#xD;
      randomized into one of two arms: 1- a single session or 2- multiple sessions (6 sessions over&#xD;
      12 weeks) of education and exercise with the advance practice physiotherapist. The primary&#xD;
      outcome measure will be the Brief Pain Inventory (pain severity and interference subscales).&#xD;
      Secondary measures will include self-reported disability (the Neck Disability Index or&#xD;
      Oswestry Disability Index), The Pain Catastrophizing Scale, satisfaction with care (VSQ-9 and&#xD;
      MedRisk questionnaires), and health-related quality of life (EQ-5D-5L). Participants&#xD;
      healthcare resources use, and related costs will be measured. Outcomes will be collected at&#xD;
      baseline and at 6, 12 and 26 weeks after enrollment. Intention-to-treat analyses will be&#xD;
      performed, and repeated mixed-model ANOVA will assess differences between treatment arms.&#xD;
      Cost-utility analyses will be conducted from the perspective of the health care system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics and dissemination: Ethics approval has been obtained from the Comité d'éthique de la&#xD;
      recherche du CIUSS de l'Est-de-l'Île-de-Montréal (FWA00001935 and IRB00002087). Results of&#xD;
      this study will be presented to different stakeholders, published in peer-reviewed journals&#xD;
      and presented at international conferences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this pragmatic randomized controlled trial is to evaluate at 6, 12 and 24 weeks,&#xD;
      the clinical effectiveness in terms of patient-centered outcomes and the cost-effectiveness&#xD;
      of a single session compared to multiple sessions of education and exercise for older adults&#xD;
      with spinal pain treated conservatively in an APP neurosurgery model of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design This study is a pragmatic randomized controlled trial with cost-effectiveness&#xD;
      analyses. This trial will use a pragmatic approach within an existing APP model of care in&#xD;
      neurosurgery. Therefore, the rehabilitation intervention in both treatment arms will be&#xD;
      offered as they are provided in their current clinical reality (see Figure 1 for flowchart).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting and Participants This pragmatic randomized controlled trial will be performed within&#xD;
      the CareAxis neurosurgery APP model of care. In 2019, CareAxis, a non-profit organization,&#xD;
      developed and implemented an APP model of care for older patients (65 years and older) with&#xD;
      spinal pain referred to neurosurgery in the province of Quebec (Canada). The model was&#xD;
      developed in partnership with the Montreal Neurological Institute and Hospital, Montreal,&#xD;
      Quebec, Canada. The aim of this model is to reduce wait time to consult a neurosurgeon, more&#xD;
      efficiently triage surgical candidates, and improve conservative and rehabilitation care for&#xD;
      patients referred to the program. The current model of care involves a group of trained&#xD;
      APPTs, who assess and triage potential surgical candidates, recommend medical care&#xD;
      (medication or injection), provide education, and prescribe a self-management exercise&#xD;
      program. This is systematically offered to all patients in a one-hour session. Only patients&#xD;
      deemed surgical candidates are then referred to see the neurosurgeon. The program is funded&#xD;
      through health charities and is offered at no costs to older adults with a referral from a&#xD;
      family physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will take place in physiotherapy clinics (n=9) associated with the CareAxis group&#xD;
      in Quebec, Canada. Eligible participants will be recruited when referred to the CareAxis&#xD;
      model of care, either directly through family physicians or from the Centre de répartition&#xD;
      des demandes de service de Montréal - the centralized intake system for specialist referrals&#xD;
      (including neurosurgery) from primary care in Montreal, Quebec. The eligibility criteria in&#xD;
      the current trial are based on the intended clientele to be cared by the APPT within this&#xD;
      model of care, representing our pragmatic approach to the definition of our sample.&#xD;
      Eligibility criteria: 1) adults consulting for a neck or back condition; 2) aged 65 years old&#xD;
      or older; 3) referred for a consultation in neurosurgery to the CareAxis group, either&#xD;
      directly by family physicians or from the Centre de répartition des demandes de service de&#xD;
      Montréal and 4) not considered as a potential surgical candidate based on the initial APPT&#xD;
      assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients who decline participation in the project, demographic data, such as age, gender&#xD;
      and duration of symptoms will be collected to calculate participation proportions and&#xD;
      establish comparison between participants and non-participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization All eligible and consenting patients will be randomly assigned to either the&#xD;
      single session APP arm or the multiple sessions APP arm. A randomization list will be&#xD;
      generated prior to the initiation of the study using an online random number generator. A&#xD;
      blocked randomization will be performed with block sizes of 4, 6 or 8. Randomization will be&#xD;
      stratified for the affected body region (neck or back) and with respect to gender. Allocation&#xD;
      will be concealed in opaque and sealed envelopes that will be sequentially numbered. The&#xD;
      randomization procedure will be performed by an independent research assistant not involved&#xD;
      in other aspects of the current trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions Participants will initially consult an APPT of the CareAxis group. In a&#xD;
      one-hour consultation, the APPT will assess and triage surgical candidates, recommend medical&#xD;
      care (medication or injection), as well as provide education and prescribe a self-management&#xD;
      exercise program aimed at impairments and functional limitations identified during the&#xD;
      initial assessment. Participants randomized to the single session arm will not receive&#xD;
      additional care by the APPT while those randomized to the multiple sessions arm will receive&#xD;
      five additional consultations with the APPT within a 12-week period. During the follow-up&#xD;
      visits, the APPT will reassess the participants, provide further education and&#xD;
      recommendations, review and modify the home exercise program and may provide other&#xD;
      rehabilitation interventions. Since this is a pragmatic trial, the interventions in both&#xD;
      treatment arms will be offered as they are provided in their current clinical reality and&#xD;
      will not be standardized. Information regarding care will be systematically recorded.&#xD;
      Patients will be allowed to take their usual medication and this data will be systematically&#xD;
      collected through a diary. Information on other co-interventions during follow-up will also&#xD;
      be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Data collection will take place at baseline and at 6, 12 and 26 weeks after&#xD;
      the initial evaluation. Prior to being randomized and seen by the APP, eligible participants&#xD;
      will answer a questionnaire regarding socio-demographic characteristics, such as age, sex,&#xD;
      gender, education level, household income, and living status. Information on clinical&#xD;
      variables such as anthropometric data, affected body area (neck or low back), reason for&#xD;
      consultation, duration of symptoms and presence of any comorbidities such as arthritis, high&#xD;
      blood pressure and diabetes will also be documented. The STart Back Screening Tool and a&#xD;
      modified version for neck pain will be used to evaluate prognosis. All data collection will&#xD;
      be done through the CareAxis web data collection portal already in use for clinical follow-up&#xD;
      of patients and with the Centre de Recherche de l'Hôpital Maisonneuve-Rosemont (CRHMR) REDCap&#xD;
      data collection portal. Both web platforms use Transport Layer Security (SLL/TLS) encryption&#xD;
      to secure data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures The primary outcome measure will be the Brief Pain Inventory (BPI), short&#xD;
      form, pain severity scale and pain interference scale. The BPI is a self-reported&#xD;
      questionnaire. The pain severity scale includes four numerical pain rating questions (0-10)&#xD;
      related to worst, least, average and current pain intensity, while the pain interference&#xD;
      scale includes seven numerical rating questions (0-10) related to the impact of pain on&#xD;
      various functional activities. The BPI is valid, reliable and responsive to change in MSKDs&#xD;
      populations, including spinal pain patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary outcome measures will include other validated, reliable and responsive to&#xD;
      change self-reported questionnaires. Depending on the affected body region, participants will&#xD;
      complete the Neck Disability Index (NDI) for neck-related disorder or the Oswestry Disability&#xD;
      Index (ODI), for back-related disorder. Pain catastrophizing will be assessed through the&#xD;
      Pain Catastrophizing Scale. To assess satisfaction with received care, patients will be asked&#xD;
      to complete a modified validated version of the 9-item visit-specific satisfaction&#xD;
      questionnaire (VSQ-9) after the initial assessment. To assess satisfaction following the&#xD;
      interventions and follow-up, participants will be asked to complete the MedRisk which was&#xD;
      developed to measure patient satisfaction with rehabilitation care. EQ-5D-5L will be used to&#xD;
      measured health-related quality of life. The investigators will also collect health care&#xD;
      resource use, including medical consultations, diagnostic tests, medication, injections,&#xD;
      rehabilitation and surgery using a self-reported questionnaire. Occurrence of any adverse&#xD;
      events will be questioned at each time point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on their initial assessment, the APPTs will complete a standardized form, indicating&#xD;
      their diagnosis, suggestion for additional medical imaging or laboratory tests (if relevant),&#xD;
      treatment plan (e.g., conservative treatment options, medication, injections, or&#xD;
      physiotherapy care) and referral to other specialists, if relevant. For the multiple session&#xD;
      arm, APPTs will document patients' progress, change in the exercise plan and all treatments&#xD;
      provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analyses Descriptive statistics will be used to present the participants'&#xD;
      characteristics. Participants withdrawing from the study and reasons for withdrawal will be&#xD;
      analyzed. Characteristics of participants and non-participants will be compared. Baseline&#xD;
      demographic data will be compared across groups to establish the comparability across&#xD;
      intervention arms (unpaired t-tests and Chi-square tests). If differences are observed,&#xD;
      statistical models will be adjusted. Descriptive statistics will be computed for all outcome&#xD;
      measures at the different measurement times. Intention-to-treat analyses will be performed.&#xD;
      As secondary analyses, per-protocol analyses will also be performed. Missing data will be&#xD;
      handled with multiple data imputation. A repeated mixed-model ANOVA will be used to determine&#xD;
      whether outcomes differ between treatment arms across time points. Separate analyses will be&#xD;
      conducted on each of the primary and secondary outcomes. In particular, if a difference&#xD;
      (interaction) between groups is detected (p&lt; 0.05), individual effects will be examined.&#xD;
      Sphericity will be tested with Mauchly's test. If sphericity is rejected (variances of the&#xD;
      difference are not equal), correction will be used to determine if repeated measures ANOVA&#xD;
      test is statistically significant. If Epsilon &gt; 0.75, the Huynh-Feldt correction will be used&#xD;
      and if Epsilon ≤ 0.75, the Greenhouse-Geisser correction will be used. Differences in&#xD;
      proportions of adverse events, co-interventions (medication, injections or any other&#xD;
      treatment), satisfaction scores (VSQ-9 at initial assessment and MedRisk at 12 weeks) between&#xD;
      treatment arms will be calculated using Chi-Square tests or Student's t-tests. Alpha level&#xD;
      will be set at 0.05. All analyses will be carried out using the SPSS software (IBM Corp.&#xD;
      Released 2019. IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 26.0) and the Excel software&#xD;
      (Microsoft Corporation. 2018. Microsoft Excel for Windows).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Economic Evaluation A cost-utility analysis comparing both arms will be conducted. The&#xD;
      analysis will be from the perspective of the publicly funded health care system. Secondary&#xD;
      analyses including publicly and privately health care system costs will also be performed.&#xD;
      Costs and outcomes will be assessed within the follow up period of the trial. Data on&#xD;
      services used and the efficacy of each approach will be obtained from the concurrent trial.&#xD;
      Health utility value will be derived from the EQ-5D-5L using the Canadian validated&#xD;
      algorithm. Quality-adjusted life years (QALYs) will be estimated using the total area under&#xD;
      the curve method. Unit costs for each health care resource will be obtained from Canadian&#xD;
      sources. Costs will be expressed in 2021 Canadian Dollars.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results of the cost-utility analysis will be presented as incremental cost per QALY gained.&#xD;
      The statistical analysis will be conducted in accordance with current guidelines for a&#xD;
      cost-effectiveness analysis alongside randomized control trials. The incremental cost and&#xD;
      incremental outcome will be estimated using generalized estimating equations (GEEs) with&#xD;
      appropriate links and distributions to account for repeated nature of the trial data. The&#xD;
      incremental cost-effectiveness ratio will be obtained through the difference in the mean&#xD;
      costs of the two approaches divided by the difference in the mean value of QALYs for the two&#xD;
      arms as denoted by the coefficient of the intervention indicator variables. Uncertainty in&#xD;
      the analysis will be addressed by estimating 95% confidence intervals using a non-parametric&#xD;
      bootstrapping method. For this study, 10,000 estimates of costs and outcomes will be obtained&#xD;
      for both arms. Results from the bootstrapping exercise will also be used to show&#xD;
      cost-effectiveness acceptability curves, which represent the probability of each APP approach&#xD;
      being cost-effective over a range of willingness to pay values that the health system may be&#xD;
      willing to pay for an additional unit of QALY. A series of sensitivity analyses will be&#xD;
      undertaken to examine the robustness of the trial findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size Calculation The sample size required is based on the primary outcome measure, the&#xD;
      BPI short form. The BPI interference scale and the severity scale have estimated minimum&#xD;
      clinically important difference of 1 point.The estimated standard deviation is 2.03 for&#xD;
      spinal pain. The considered parameters are 0.05 for a type I error (α) with a power of 0.80&#xD;
      (1-β). For an analysis of variance (ANOVA), the sample size required is 76 participants per&#xD;
      group. This sample also accounts for a potential 15% loss to follow up at 6 months. The total&#xD;
      sample will be 152 participants and will provide adequate power.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain interference scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain interference scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 7 items where the patient is asked to rate their perceived impact of pain on various functional activities. The finale score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=pain does not interfere; 10=pain completely interferes).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain interference scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain interference scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 7 items where the patient is asked to rate their perceived impact of pain on various functional activities. The final score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=pain does not interfere; 10=pain completely interferes).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain interference scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain interference scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 7 items where the patient is asked to rate their perceived impact of pain on various functional activities. The final score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=pain does not interfere; 10=pain completely interferes).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain severity scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain severity scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 4 items where the patient is asked to rate their pain intensity (wort, least, general and current). The final score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=no pain; 10=pain as bad as you can imagine).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain severity scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain severity scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 4 items where the patient is asked to rate their pain intensity (wort, least, general and current). The final score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=no pain; 10=pain as bad as you can imagine).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) Short form, Pain severity scale (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BPI pain severity scale is a self-administered questionnaire which includes 4 items where the patient is asked to rate their pain intensity (wort, least, general and current). The final score ranges from 0 to 10 (0=no pain; 10=pain as bad as you can imagine).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neck Disability Index (NDI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The NDI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for neck-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neck Disability Index (NDI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The NDI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for neck-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neck Disability Index (NDI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The NDI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for neck-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ODI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for back-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ODI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for back-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ODI is a self-reported disability questionnaire for back-related disorders. The final score ranges from 0 to 100 (0=better condition; 100=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PCS is a self-reported questionnaire to assess pain catastrophizing. The final score ranges from 0 to 50 (0=better condition; 50=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PCS is a self-reported questionnaire to assess pain catastrophizing. The final score ranges from 0 to 50 (0=better condition; 50=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Catastrophizing Scale (PCS) (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PCS is a self-reported questionnaire to assess pain catastrophizing. The final score ranges from 0 to 50 (0=better condition; 50=worst condition).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified 9-item visit-specific satisfaction questionnaire (VSQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The modified and validated VSQ-9 is questionnaire to assess patient satisfaction with care after a consultation. The final score ranges from 9 to 45 (9=excellent satisfaction; 45=poor satisfaction).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MedRisk</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The MedRisk is questionnaire to assess patient satisfaction with care. The final score ranges from 12 to 60 (12=poor satisfaction; 60=excellent satisfaction).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-5L (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L will be the outcome measure for the economic analysis outcomes. The EQ-5D-5L is a generic health-related quality of life questionnaire. The final score ranges from 5 to 25 (5=full health; 25=worst health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-5L (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L will be the outcome measure for the economic analysis outcomes. The EQ-5D-5L is a generic health-related quality of life questionnaire. The final score ranges from 5 to 25 (5=full health; 25=worst health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-5L (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L will be the outcome measure for the economic analysis outcomes. The EQ-5D-5L is a generic health-related quality of life questionnaire. The final score ranges from 5 to 25 (5=full health; 25=worst health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-VAS (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-VAS is a vertical visual analogue scale on global health. The final score ranges from 0 to100 (0=worst health; 100=full health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-VAS (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-VAS is a vertical visual analogue scale on global health. The final score ranges from 0 to100 (0=worst health; 100=full health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-VAS (change from baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-VAS is a vertical visual analogue scale on global health. The final score ranges from 0 to100 (0=worst health; 100=full health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health care resources</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Health care resources uses will be measured to estimate cost.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of any adverse events related to the interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">152</enrollment>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single session APP arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will received one session with the advanced practice physiotherapist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple sessions APP arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will received 6 sessions (in 12 weeks) with the advanced practice physiotherapist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Single session of education and exercise provided by an advanced practice physiotherapist.</intervention_name>
    <description>In a one-hour consultation, the APPT will assess and triage surgical candidates, recommend medical care (medication or injection), as well as provide education and prescribe a self-management exercise program aimed at impairments and functional limitations identified during the initial assessment. Participant will not receive additional care by the APPT.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single session APP arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Multiple session of education and exercise provided by an advanced practice physiotherapist.</intervention_name>
    <description>In a one-hour consultation, the APPT will assess and triage surgical candidates, recommend medical care (medication or injection), as well as provide education and prescribe a self-management exercise program aimed at impairments and functional limitations identified during the initial assessment. Participants will receive five additional consultations with the APPT within a 12-week period. During the follow-up visits, the APPT will reassess the participants, provide further education and recommendations, review and modify the home exercise program and may provide other rehabilitation interventions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple sessions APP arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. adults consulting for a neck or back condition;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. aged 65 years old or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. referred for a consultation in neurosurgery to the CareAxis group, either directly by&#xD;
             family physicians or from the Centre de répartition des demandes de service de&#xD;
             Montréal and&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. not considered as a potential surgical candidate based on the initial APPT assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Considered as a potential surgical candidate based on the initial advanced practice&#xD;
        physiotherapist assessment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CareAxis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3H2L3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paul Santaguida</last_name>
      <phone>18446752947</phone>
      <phone_ext>701</phone_ext>
      <email>paul.s@careaxis.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Simon Lafrance, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>François Desmeules, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Health care organization</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced practice</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Spine</keyword>
  <keyword>Musculoskeletal Pain Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Economic evaluation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Somatoform Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the primary study manuscript after deidentification.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

