<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04863573</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B21/07</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04863573</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Antibody Responses In Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAR-CF</acronym>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Antibody Responses In Cystic Fibrosis: CAR-CF</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Queen's University, Belfast</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cystic Fibrosis Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Queen's University, Belfast</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) which is caused by the virus SARS-CoV-2 has resulted in&#xD;
      an ongoing global pandemic. It is unclear whether the relatively low number of reported cases&#xD;
      of COVID-19 in people with CF (pwCF) is due to enhanced infection prevention practices or&#xD;
      whether pwCF have protective genetic/immune factors. This study aims to prospectively assess&#xD;
      the proportion of pwCF, including both adults and children with CF who have evidence of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 antibodies over a two-year period. This study will also examine whether pwCF who&#xD;
      have antibodies for SARS-CoV-2 have a different clinical presentation and what impact this&#xD;
      has on their CF disease. The proposed study will recruit pwCF from paediatric and adult CF&#xD;
      centres throughout the United Kingdom. Serological testing to detect antibodies will be&#xD;
      performed on blood samples taken at month 0, 6, 12, 18 and 24 with additional time-points if&#xD;
      bloodwork is available via normal clinical care. Clinical data on, lung function, CF-related&#xD;
      medical history, pulmonary exacerbations, antibiotic use, and microbiology and vaccination&#xD;
      receipt, will be collected during routine clinical assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Associations will be examined between socio-demographic and clinical variables and serologic&#xD;
      testing. The effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection on clinical outcomes and analyse end-points will&#xD;
      be examined to explore any age-related or gender-based differences, as well as subgroup&#xD;
      analysis of outcomes in lung-transplant recipients and pwCF receiving CFTR modulator&#xD;
      therapies. As pwCF receive COVID-19 vaccination a comparison of the development and&#xD;
      progression of anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in pwCF following natural infection and vaccination&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 over time will be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, longitudinal cohort study in people with Cystic Fibrosis (pwCF) that&#xD;
      involves repeated serial sampling of participants. This study design was chosen to provide&#xD;
      comprehensive information on SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence changes over time and the subsequent&#xD;
      clinical impact on pwCF. The study will be conducted at participating CF centres over a&#xD;
      3-year period. Study participants will include paediatric and adult pwCF. For the UK section&#xD;
      of the study, UK investigators in the European Cystic Fibrosis Society-Clinical Trials&#xD;
      Network (ECFS-CTN) will be invited to participate. Participating investigators can enrol all&#xD;
      eligible pwCF over a 12-month period. Participants are then followed up for 24 months.&#xD;
      Participants will donate blood samples at their routine clinic visits. Blood samples will be&#xD;
      collected at Day 0 (baseline), at Months 6, 12, 18 and 24 (to coincide with routine clinical&#xD;
      reviews). Additional blood samples will be taken opportunistically every time the participant&#xD;
      visits the clinic for blood draws. These blood samples could be related to, routine care,&#xD;
      annual review visits, pulmonary exacerbations (PEx), CF complications or when initiating new&#xD;
      treatments (e.g. CFTR modulators).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serum from blood samples will be shipped to a central laboratory (Queen's University Belfast)&#xD;
      for standardized measurement of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alongside the blood samples the investigators will also collect clinical data from the&#xD;
      patient's health records and will input this data into the case report form (CRF). Clinical&#xD;
      data will be collected in conjunction with routine care visits, according to local clinical&#xD;
      practice. Investigators will collect data elements from information routinely recorded in the&#xD;
      patients' medical records. Data will be collected at baseline, month 6, 12, 18 and 24 as per&#xD;
      the study schedule, and at additional blood sampling timepoints as previously explained&#xD;
      above. Data collection will include routine data available from CF clinic follow-ups&#xD;
      including background demographic information, CF medical history, medications, exacerbation&#xD;
      information, sputum microbiology and clinical and lung function parameters. Information on&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection history and vaccine receipt will also be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The maximum follow-up duration of participation in the study for each patient will be 24&#xD;
      months. This study duration (24-month follow-up) is justified as it provides sufficient time&#xD;
      to observe changes in antibody prevalence over the course of the COVID-19 pandemic as well as&#xD;
      sufficient time to determine long term clinical outcomes for pwCF who are SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      seropositive. Furthermore, we anticipate the 2-year study follow-up period will provide&#xD;
      sufficient time to observe the impact of vaccination on antibody levels given that a number&#xD;
      of vaccines are now commercially available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will compare the level of antibody responses between natural COVID-19&#xD;
      infection and vaccination in pwCF and how this varies over time. This will be achieved by&#xD;
      analyzing seroprevalence and antibody levels according to natural infection and vaccination&#xD;
      status and according to time of sample post infection or post vaccination, if known.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Optional Study sample collection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For participants who consent, a second blood sample will also be drawn into EDTA tubes&#xD;
      (plasma). Consent to this optional study sample would allow this sample and any remaining&#xD;
      serum (following antibody testing) to be stored for future analysis and allow further&#xD;
      research to be carried out on related studies to COVID-19 and CF.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-COV-2 seroprevalence</measure>
    <time_frame>3-year period (comprising a 1-year enrollment period and a 2-year follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of pwCF with at least 1 seropositive result over the study period and the difference in this proportion by age, geographical area and over time.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity, clinical symptoms and clinical outcomes in pwCF</measure>
    <time_frame>3-year period (comprising a 1-year enrollment period and a 2-year follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>incidence of symptomatic COVID-19 over the study period and severity; proportion of seropositive pwCF with subsequent CF exacerbation compared to pwCF who are seronegative; death rate in pwCF with at least one seropositive result compared to pwCF who are seronegative.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Longitudinal comparison of the detection, including level and duration, of anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in pwCF following natural infection and SARS-CoV-2 vaccination.</measure>
    <time_frame>3-year period (comprising a 1-year enrollment period and a 2-year follow-up)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum proteomic and genomic responses of pwCF who are SARS-CoV-2 seropositive and seronegative.</measure>
    <time_frame>anticipated 5-10 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Cystic Fibrosis</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood serum samples will be collected for analysis of COVID-19 antibody levels. For&#xD;
      participants who consent to the optional study, a second blood sample will also be drawn into&#xD;
      EDTA tubes (plasma)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consenting people with cystic fibrosis of any age, genotype, transplant status and disease&#xD;
        severity will be eligible to participate in the study. The study population is expected to&#xD;
        be representative of the general CF population.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Consenting people with cystic fibrosis of any age, genotype, transplant status and&#xD;
        disease severity&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to venepuncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants already enrolled in a clinical trial are eligible for enrollment in this&#xD;
        study. Inclusion in CAR-CF should not preclude enrollment in other observational clinical&#xD;
        trial studies or clinical trials of an investigational medicinal product (CTIMP).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Damian Downey</last_name>
    <phone>02895041135</phone>
    <email>d.downey@qub.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helen Groves</last_name>
    <phone>02895041135</phone>
    <email>h.groves@qub.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Southampton Nhs Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <state>Engladn</state>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shobonna Akhter</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals Birmingham Nhs Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>B15 2GW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Birmingham Women'S and Children'S Nhs Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>B4 6NH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maya Desai</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leeds Teaching Hospitals Nhs Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leeds</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>LS9 7TF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Peckham</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King'S College Hospital Nhs Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael Waller</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Brompton &amp; Harefield Nhs Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>SW3 6NP</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicholas Simmonds</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nottingham University Hospitals Nhs Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>NG7 2UH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Helen Barr</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queens University Belfast</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belfast</city>
        <state>Northern Ireland</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Damian Downey</last_name>
      <email>d.downey@qub.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Damian Downey</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <state>Scotland</state>
        <zip>G12 0XH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gordon MacGregor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiff &amp; Vale University Lhb</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cardiff</city>
        <state>Wales</state>
        <zip>CF14 4HH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thia Lena</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiff &amp; Vale University Lhb</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cardiff</city>
        <state>Wales</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Queen's University, Belfast</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Damian Downey</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Senior Lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

