<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04862598</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H20-03663</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04862598</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Virtual Reality to Improve Satisfaction in Hysteroscopy Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>VIP</acronym>
  <official_title>Virtual Reality to Improve Satisfaction in Patients Undergoing Hysteroscopy: A Single-centre Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to investigate whether viewing an immersive virtual reality (VR) image&#xD;
      through a VR headset during elective hysteroscopy under Registered Nurse (RN) led sedation&#xD;
      with fentanyl and midazolam plus local anesthesia (monitored anesthetic care) will improve&#xD;
      patient satisfaction with their anesthesia. Patients will be randomized to either receive&#xD;
      usual care or usual care plus VR. Satisfaction will be measured by asking patients to&#xD;
      complete a post-procedure survey consisting of 11 questions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: To determine whether viewing an immersive VR image (viewed over an Oculus Quest VR&#xD;
      headset) during hysteroscopy can improve patient satisfaction with their anesthesia (sedation&#xD;
      plus local anesthesia). The VR image used in the study is Cosmic Flow: A Relaxing VR&#xD;
      experience, which is freely available from Oculus. The patient will also wear headphones&#xD;
      during the study which will play relaxing meditation music.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The use of immersive VR during elective hysteroscopy under sedation will improve&#xD;
      patient satisfaction with their anesthesia by at least 20%, measured using the Iowa&#xD;
      Satisfaction with Anesthesia Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Justification: Ambulatory hysteroscopy is conducted under general anesthesia or in the&#xD;
      established Procedural Sedation Program. The latter involves Registered Nurse (RN) led&#xD;
      sedation, consisting of the administration of sedation (midazolam) and analgesia (fentanyl)&#xD;
      to reduce discomfort and anxiety. However, these medications have unwanted side-effects such&#xD;
      as over-sedation and nausea, which can delay discharge and reduce patient satisfaction with&#xD;
      their procedure. To minimize these complications, non-pharmacological therapy is of interest,&#xD;
      as it aims to reduce the need and dosage of these medications. Virtual reality is one such&#xD;
      non-pharmacological intervention which has been trialled in several settings, and has been&#xD;
      shown to have beneficial effects on pain and anxiety during procedures such as wound dressing&#xD;
      changes, upper GI endoscopies and dental procedures. Virtual reality use in the healthcare&#xD;
      setting is currently in an early phase of research, and more study is needed on effects of VR&#xD;
      on precise outcomes such as patient satisfaction, which is an important marker for quality in&#xD;
      healthcare.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: The objective is to study patient reported satisfaction with their anesthesia&#xD;
      (sedation plus local anesthesia) when they receive standard care to when they receive&#xD;
      standard care plus viewing an immersive VR image during their hysteroscopy procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Design: This is a randomized controlled trial involving data collection before,&#xD;
      during and after the hysteroscopy procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis: The primary outcome in change in patient satisfaction scores will be&#xD;
      compared using paired t-test. For secondary outcomes, all continuous data will be compared&#xD;
      using t-test or Mann-Whitney U test as appropriate. Incidence and proportion outcomes will be&#xD;
      analyzed using Fisher exact test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Change in post-procedure patient satisfaction score (Iowa Satisfaction Scale) of at least 0.6 between the Virtual Reality group and the control group. High scores are better than low scores which are worse. Scores range from -3 (completely unsatisfied) to 3 (completely satisfied)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient anxiety scores before and after the procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes before operation (one anxiety score). 15 minutes after operation (one anxiety score). On a 10 point Likert anxiety scale (0-10) high scores are more anxious and low scores are less anxious.</time_frame>
    <description>10-point Likert Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Fentanyl dose</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes throughout the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Total IV Fentanyl dose in mcgs during the procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Midazolam dose</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes throughout the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Total IV Midazolam dose in mgs during the procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of intraoperative hemodynamic changes</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes throughout the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Increase/decrease of 30 percent of SBP or HR compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of desaturation</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes throughout the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse oxygen saturation &lt;90 percent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of early termination of VR experience</measure>
    <time_frame>Noted during the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Noting whether the patient decides to terminate the VR experience before the end of their procedure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients wishing to use the technology again</measure>
    <time_frame>Noted 15 minutes after the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Yes/No response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immersion perception score of the VR system</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes after the operation.</time_frame>
    <description>10 point Likert scale. On a 10 point Likert immersion scale (0-10) high scores are more immersed and low scores are less immersed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Reason for early termination of VR experience</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes throughout the operation</time_frame>
    <description>Reasons may include: Patient desire/Medical decision/Nausea/Vomiting/Dizziness/ Headache/Device failure/ other</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">192</enrollment>
  <condition>Patient Satisfaction</condition>
  <condition>Virtual Reality</condition>
  <condition>Hysteroscopy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient will be positioned on the operating table and have routine monitoring attached (ECG, blood pressure, O2 saturations, end tidal carbon dioxide monitoring (ETCO2). A surgical safety time out will be performed. The patient will receive routine operative and nursing care. The study team member will record highest and lowest heart rate and blood pressure as well as lowest O2 saturation and the total intra-operative dose of fentanyl and midazolam administered to the patient. At the end of the procedure, the patient is assisted into a wheelchair and will return to the recovery area. After 15 minutes of recovery, a member of the study team will give them the post-operative questionnaires which will consist of answering how anxious they felt during the procedure and the 11 question Iowa Satisfaction with Anesthesia scale (ISAS). The patient will then be free to leave once they have met the standard discharge criteria.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>VR Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient wears the VR headset after being positioned on the table and the surgical time out has been completed. The VR scene and accompanying music will continue until the end of the procedure or until the patient wishes for it to be removed. The patient will receive standard operative and nursing care. The study team member will record the intra-operative vitals as detailed in the control group procedure. At the end of the procedure, the patient will be moved to recovery and will receive standard care. At 15 minutes, they will be provided with the anxiety questionnaire and the ISAS. Additional questions will be asked; their level of VR immersion and if they would like to receive the VR technology again if they were to undergo another procedure in the future. They will then be free to leave once they have met the standard discharge criteria.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oculus Virtual Reality</intervention_name>
    <description>The patient will receive standard care, augmented with virtual reality. Their post-operative satisfaction score will be recorded.</description>
    <arm_group_label>VR Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indications for hysteroscopy under RN-provided sedation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide informed consent to participate in the study (e.g. significant&#xD;
             language barrier)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic benzodiazepine use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic opioid use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of psychotic psychiatric disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of seizure disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual acuity &lt;1 with correction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hearing impairment requiring correction&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anton Chau, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Helen K Parker, FRCA</last_name>
    <phone>6048752158</phone>
    <phone_ext>6076</phone_ext>
    <email>helenkparker22@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cyrus Bhiladvala, B.Sc</last_name>
    <phone>6048752158</phone>
    <phone_ext>6076</phone_ext>
    <email>cyrus.bhiladvala@cw.bc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BC Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6H4J4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anton Chau, MD</last_name>
      <phone>6048752158</phone>
      <phone_ext>6111</phone_ext>
      <email>anton.chau@ubc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Cyrus Bhiladvala, B.Sc</last_name>
      <phone>6048752158</phone>
      <phone_ext>6076</phone_ext>
      <email>cyrus.bhiladvala@cw.bc.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anthony Chau</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Virtual Reality</keyword>
  <keyword>Hysteroscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Iowa Satisfaction Scale</keyword>
  <keyword>Sedation</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

