<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04860180</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RF-2013-02356606</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04860180</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Surgical or Conservative Approach in Patients With Adrenal Incidentalomas</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Surgical or Conservative Approach in Patients With Adrenal Incidentalomas on Cardiovascular, Metabolic, Neuropsychological and Bone Manifestations: Respective Roles of Cortisol Secretion and Glucocorticoid Sensitivity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Casa Sollievo della Sofferenza IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Istituto Ortopedico Galeazzi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Health, Italy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Subclinical hypercortisolism (SH) is a status of asymptomatic hypercortisolism, frequently&#xD;
      found in patients with adrenal adenomas (estimated prevalence: 0.8-2% after 60 years of age).&#xD;
      Although SH may lead to diabetes, hypertension and osteoporosis, the diagnostic SH criteria&#xD;
      and those suggesting the need of adrenalectomy are debated. Indeed, beside the cortisol&#xD;
      secretion, the individual cortisol sensitivity may play a role in determining the SH&#xD;
      consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with possible SH due to adrenal adenoma will be randomized to surgery/conservative&#xD;
      follow up. The effects of surgery on the cardiovascular, bone, metabolic complications of SH&#xD;
      and on neuropsychological aspects and quality of life (QoL) and the possibility to predict&#xD;
      them by using cortisol sensitivity and secretion markers will be studied. The study may&#xD;
      clarify how to individuate patients who can benefit from surgery. These results will help&#xD;
      reducing the costs of both useless surgical operations and SH consequences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subclinical hypercortisolism (SH) is a status of asymptomatic hypercortisolism, which is&#xD;
      present in up to the 30% of patients with incidentally discovered adrenal adenomas (adrenal&#xD;
      incidentalomas, AI). Since AI are present in 7-10% of individuals after 60 years of age, the&#xD;
      estimated SH prevalence in this population is 0.8-2%. In patients with SH due to an adrenal&#xD;
      adenoma the risk of diabetes, hypertension, cardiovascular events, osteoporosis and mortality&#xD;
      seems to be increased, and monolateral adrenalectomy beneficial. However, no randomized&#xD;
      studies evaluated the effects of surgery on SH consequences and established the criteria&#xD;
      indicating the need of surgery itself. Thus, in many patients the SH diagnosis is uncertain&#xD;
      and the best approach (surgical or conservative) unknown. These uncertainties are also due to&#xD;
      the influence of the individual glucocorticoid (GC) sensitivity. Indeed, in the single&#xD;
      individual the various polymorphisms of GC receptor (GR) and the different&#xD;
      11ß-hydroxysteroid-dehydrogenase type 2 enzyme (11HSD2) activity, regulating the tissue&#xD;
      exposure to the active GC, may differently predispose to the consequences of GC excess.&#xD;
      Therefore, in AI patients, beside the evaluation of the degree of the cortisol&#xD;
      hypersecretion, the assessment of the cortisol sensitivity may be useful in establishing the&#xD;
      individual risk of SH consequences and the possible usefulness of a surgical approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In AI subjects with uncertain SH the combined evaluation of the clinical features together&#xD;
      with the parameters of cortisol secretion and sensitivity will consent to decide which&#xD;
      patient has the greatest probability to ameliorate after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the variation of blood pressure control, lipids and glucose metabolism,&#xD;
           vascular damage, bone mineral density (BMD), clinical and morphometric vertebral&#xD;
           fractures, body composition, coagulation parameters, neuropsychological aspects and&#xD;
           quality of life (QoL) in AI patients with uncertain SH after the surgical removal of the&#xD;
           adrenal mass or after a conservative treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess in AI patients and uncertain hypercortisolism the effect of the surgical and&#xD;
           conservative approach on cardiovascular, metabolic and bone manifestations,&#xD;
           neuropsychological aspects and quality of life (QoL), in relation to the degree of&#xD;
           cortisol secretion and sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To establish the best clinical-biochemical criteria for diagnosing SH, on the basis of&#xD;
           the changes of the outcomes after the surgical or conservative approach, and therefore,&#xD;
           for addressing the treatment of choice in the individual patient with AI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods. During the enrollment period (24 months), all patients between 40 and 75 years of&#xD;
      age referred for unilateral AI larger than 1 cm will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In all subjects, adrenocorticotroph hormone (ACTH), urinary free cortisol (UFC), cortisol&#xD;
      after 1-mg overnight dexamethasone suppression test (1mgDST) and the GR polymorphisms of&#xD;
      N363S, BclI and ER22/23EK will be assessed. Patients with 1mgDST &gt;1.8 mcg/dL will undergo a&#xD;
      low dose (2 mg for 2 days) dexamethasone suppression test (LDDST). Patients with 1mgDST and&#xD;
      LDDST &gt;5 mcg/dL and suppressed (&lt;5 pg/mL) ACTH levels will be excluded as affected by&#xD;
      biochemically overt hypercortisolism, that requires surgery. AI patients with 1mgDST or LDDST&#xD;
      &lt;1.8 mcg/dL will be excluded as certainly not affected with SH. AI patients with AI &gt;5 cm&#xD;
      will leave the study as in this case surgery is mandatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eventually, after the enrollment period, 54 AI patients with uncertain SH will be included&#xD;
      and randomized to surgery (Group1) or conservative treatment (Group 2). The follow-up period&#xD;
      will last 24 months (after withdrawal of GC substitution therapy, if needed, for Group 1).&#xD;
      Group 1 patients will undergo laparoscopic or laparotomic adrenalectomy, depending on the AI&#xD;
      size and their clinical characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluations at baseline, 6, 12 and 24 months: blood pressure (BP), body weight (BW), body&#xD;
      mass index (BMI), waist circumference, glucose, lipid and coagulation parameters, body&#xD;
      composition and adenoma size by CT (Group 2 patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2 patients with a &gt;1 cm adenoma increase or appearance of overt SH will leave the&#xD;
      study. At baseline and after 24 months, bone mineral density (BMD) and quality (by trabecular&#xD;
      bone score, TBS), vertebral fractures (VFx), carotid atherosclerosis, neuropsychological&#xD;
      aspects and QoL, will be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients will be defined: i) obese, in the presence of BMI &gt;30 kg/m2; ii) hypertensive in&#xD;
      the presence of systolic BP &gt;130 mmHg and/or diastolic BP &gt;85 mmHg and/or any&#xD;
      antihypertensive treatment; iii) diabetic, in the presence of the World Health Organization&#xD;
      criteria, and/or any hypoglycemic drug, iv) dyslipidemic, in the presence of triglyceride&#xD;
      levels &gt;150 mg/dl or high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol levels &lt;40 or 50 mg/dl in&#xD;
      males and females, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The improvement/worsening during follow-up will be defined as follows: for obesity in the&#xD;
      presence of a &gt;5% BW decrease/increase, for hypertension if the non-hypertensive patients&#xD;
      passed from a pre-hypertension category to another or the hypertensive patients from a&#xD;
      hypertension grade to another; for diabetes and dyslipidemia if fasting glucose and&#xD;
      cholesterol levels pass from a category to another, respectively, following the Adult&#xD;
      Treatment Panel III criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The efficacy of the surgical and conservative approach on the basis of the changes of BP, BW,&#xD;
      glucose and lipid control, BMD, VFx incidence (primary outcomes) will be compared. The effect&#xD;
      of surgery on the coagulation parameters, carotid atherosclerosis, body composition,&#xD;
      neuropsychological aspects and QoL (secondary outcomes) will be also evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline, and at 6, 12 and 24 months, beside ACTH, 1mgDST and UFC, the midnight salivary&#xD;
      cortisol (MSalC) and urinary free cortisone (UFCo) levels and the UFC/UFCo ratio (index of&#xD;
      11HSD2 activity) will be assessed In Group 1 and Group 2 patients the association between the&#xD;
      changes of the primary and secondary outcomes with the cortisol secretion parameters and the&#xD;
      presence/absence of GC sensitizing GR polymorphisms and the degree of 11HSD2 activity, will&#xD;
      be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An algorithm for predicting the effect of the surgical or conservative approach on the&#xD;
      primary outcomes in the individual AI patient with uncertain SH. The algorithm, based on the&#xD;
      combination of the SH complications at baseline (hypertension, osteoporotic fractures,&#xD;
      diabetes) with the presence/absence of GC sensitizing GR polymorphisms, degree of 11HSD2&#xD;
      activity and parameters of cortisol secretion, will be retrospectively tested on the study&#xD;
      population, will be elaborated. This would consent to evaluate positive and negative&#xD;
      predictive value of the algorithm for predicting the response to surgery in the individual&#xD;
      patient with AI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 29, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 8, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the variation of blood pressure ambulatory systolic and diastolic blood pressure (BP, mmHg), and antihypertensive treatment at baseline and follow-up will be assessed; BP will be considered improved or worsened if the non-hypertensive patients passed from a pre-hypertension category to another or the hypertensive patients from a hypertension grade to another in accordance to giudelines, of if if antihypertensive treatment was reduced by 50%</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of glucose levels</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the variation of glucose levels, fasting glucose levels and glucose levels after oral glucose tolerance test will be evaluated at baseline and follow-up. Glucose levels will be considered improved or worsened if fasting glucose levels pass from a category to another, following the Adult Treatment Panel III criteria or if antidiabetic treatment was reduced by 50%</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of lipids</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>At baseline and follow up triglyceride levels; total cholesterol levels, HDL and LDL levels (mg/dl) will be evaluated. Dyslipidemia will be diagnosed in the presence of triglyceride levels &gt;150 mg/dl or high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol levels &lt;40 or 50 mg/dl in males and females. dyslipidemia will be defined improved or worsened if cholesterol levels pass from a category to another, following the Adult Treatment Panel III criteria</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of body weight</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>At baseline and follow up body weight (kilograms) will be evaluated. the improvement/worsening during follow-up will be defined in the presence of a &gt;5% BW decrease/increase</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of bone mineral density (BMD)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the variation of bone mineral density at baseline and follow-up a Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>occurrence of vertebral fractures</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>A dorso-lumbar spine x-ray to evaluate the presence of morphometric fractures (presence/absence) will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of intimal medial thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the variation of vascular damage a supra-aortic trunk echo-Doppler to evaluate at baseline and follow-up variations of intimal medial thickness will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of Relative wall thickness (RWT)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>the variation of Relative wall thickness (RWT) will be evaluated by an echocardiography. It will be calculated from Left ventricular end diastolic dimension (LVEDD) (mm); Interventricular septal end diastole (IV Sd, mm) and Posterior wall thickness at end-diastole (PWd) parameters (mm)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of Sheehan Disability Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Sheehan Disability Scale will be evaluated to assess perceived stress (SDS-stress scale ranges 1-10, a higher score means higher levels of stress)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive evaluation by Brief Assessment Cognition in Schizophrenia (BACS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>BACS evaluate verbal memory score (normal if &gt;33); working memory (normal if &gt;14.9); verbal fluency (normal if &gt;31.6), symbol coding (normal if &gt;40.5), tower of london (&gt;12.4)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>cortisol secretion and sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To correlate the effect of the surgical and conservative approach in relation to the degree of cortisol secretion and sensitivity we will evaluate the GR polymorphisms of N363S, BclI and ER22/23EK ,midnight salivary cortisol (MSalC) and urinary free cortisone (UFCo) levels and the UFC/UFCo ratio (index of 11HSD2 activity)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>variation of Inflammation markers and bone metabolism markers</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>irisine, Tumor Necrosing Factor (TNF)- alpha, interleukin (IL)-6, adiponectin, resistin, sclerostin, Dickkopf-related protein (DKK) 1, N-terminal propeptide of type 1 collagen (P1NP) , monocytechemoattractant protein 1 (CCL2/MCP-1) levels will be assessed (pg/ml). Paired samples T-test will be used to compare baseline and follow-up levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">61</enrollment>
  <condition>Adrenal Incidentaloma</condition>
  <condition>Subclinical Hypercortisolism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A, surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>adrenalectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B, observation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>conservative follow up</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>adrenalectomy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>A, surgery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unilateral adrenal incidentaloma larger than 1 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cortisol after 1-mg overnight dexamethasone suppression test (1mgDST) between 1.8 and&#xD;
             5 mcg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hypogonadism, thyrotoxicosis, chronic renal failure and hepatic disease, alcoholism,&#xD;
             eating, rheumatologic or hematological disorders;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intake of drugs influencing cortisol and dexamethasone metabolism or cortisol&#xD;
             secretion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signs of hypercortisolism (moon facies, striae rubrae, easy bruising);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  possible metastatic disease or radiologic features not consistent with adrenocortical&#xD;
             adenoma at computed tomography (CT);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pheochromocytoma and aldosteronoma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  non-adrenal SH.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Iacopo Chiodini, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Istituto Auxologico Italiano</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reincke M. Subclinical Cushing's syndrome. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2000 Mar;29(1):43-56. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10732263</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Terzolo M, Bovio S, Reimondo G, Pia A, Osella G, Borretta G, Angeli A. Subclinical Cushing's syndrome in adrenal incidentalomas. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2005 Jun;34(2):423-39, x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15850851</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chiodini I, Morelli V, Masserini B, Salcuni AS, Eller-Vainicher C, Viti R, Coletti F, Guglielmi G, Battista C, Carnevale V, Iorio L, Beck-Peccoz P, Arosio M, Ambrosi B, Scillitani A. Bone mineral density, prevalence of vertebral fractures, and bone quality in patients with adrenal incidentalomas with and without subclinical hypercortisolism: an Italian multicenter study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009 Sep;94(9):3207-14. doi: 10.1210/jc.2009-0468. Epub 2009 Jun 23.</citation>
    <PMID>19549741</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morelli V, Reimondo G, Giordano R, Della Casa S, Policola C, Palmieri S, Salcuni AS, Dolci A, Mendola M, Arosio M, Ambrosi B, Scillitani A, Ghigo E, Beck-Peccoz P, Terzolo M, Chiodini I. Long-term follow-up in adrenal incidentalomas: an Italian multicenter study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014 Mar;99(3):827-34. doi: 10.1210/jc.2013-3527. Epub 2014 Jan 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24423350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Dalmazi G, Vicennati V, Garelli S, Casadio E, Rinaldi E, Giampalma E, Mosconi C, Golfieri R, Paccapelo A, Pagotto U, Pasquali R. Cardiovascular events and mortality in patients with adrenal incidentalomas that are either non-secreting or associated with intermediate phenotype or subclinical Cushing's syndrome: a 15-year retrospective study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2014 May;2(5):396-405. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(13)70211-0. Epub 2014 Jan 29.</citation>
    <PMID>24795253</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manenschijn L, van den Akker EL, Lamberts SW, van Rossum EF. Clinical features associated with glucocorticoid receptor polymorphisms. An overview. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2009 Oct;1179:179-98. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.2009.05013.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19906240</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Szappanos A, Patócs A, Tõke J, Boyle B, Sereg M, Majnik J, Borgulya G, Varga I, Likó I, Rácz K, Tóth M. BclI polymorphism of the glucocorticoid receptor gene is associated with decreased bone mineral density in patients with endogenous hypercortisolism. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2009 Nov;71(5):636-43. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.2009.03528.x. Epub 2009 Jan 22.</citation>
    <PMID>19207316</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tomlinson JW, Walker EA, Bujalska IJ, Draper N, Lavery GG, Cooper MS, Hewison M, Stewart PM. 11beta-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase type 1: a tissue-specific regulator of glucocorticoid response. Endocr Rev. 2004 Oct;25(5):831-66. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15466942</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eller-Vainicher C, Morelli V, Ulivieri FM, Palmieri S, Zhukouskaya VV, Cairoli E, Pino R, Naccarato A, Scillitani A, Beck-Peccoz P, Chiodini I. Bone quality, as measured by trabecular bone score in patients with adrenal incidentalomas with and without subclinical hypercortisolism. J Bone Miner Res. 2012 Oct;27(10):2223-30. doi: 10.1002/jbmr.1648.</citation>
    <PMID>22549969</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Webb SM, Badia X, Barahona MJ, Colao A, Strasburger CJ, Tabarin A, van Aken MO, Pivonello R, Stalla G, Lamberts SW, Glusman JE. Evaluation of health-related quality of life in patients with Cushing's syndrome with a new questionnaire. Eur J Endocrinol. 2008 May;158(5):623-30. doi: 10.1530/EJE-07-0762.</citation>
    <PMID>18426820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Expert Committee on the Diagnosis and Classification of Diabetes Mellitus. Report of the expert committee on the diagnosis and classification of diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Care. 2003 Jan;26 Suppl 1:S5-20.</citation>
    <PMID>12502614</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Expert Panel on Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol in Adults. Executive Summary of The Third Report of The National Cholesterol Education Program (NCEP) Expert Panel on Detection, Evaluation, And Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol In Adults (Adult Treatment Panel III). JAMA. 2001 May 16;285(19):2486-97.</citation>
    <PMID>11368702</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vidal J. Updated review on the benefits of weight loss. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2002 Dec;26 Suppl 4:S25-8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12457296</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mancia G, De Backer G, Dominiczak A, Cifkova R, Fagard R, Germano G, Grassi G, Heagerty AM, Kjeldsen SE, Laurent S, Narkiewicz K, Ruilope L, Rynkiewicz A, Schmieder RE, Boudier HA, Zanchetti A, Vahanian A, Camm J, De Caterina R, Dean V, Dickstein K, Filippatos G, Funck-Brentano C, Hellemans I, Kristensen SD, McGregor K, Sechtem U, Silber S, Tendera M, Widimsky P, Zamorano JL, Erdine S, Kiowski W, Agabiti-Rosei E, Ambrosioni E, Lindholm LH, Viigimaa M, Adamopoulos S, Agabiti-Rosei E, Ambrosioni E, Bertomeu V, Clement D, Erdine S, Farsang C, Gaita D, Lip G, Mallion JM, Manolis AJ, Nilsson PM, O'Brien E, Ponikowski P, Redon J, Ruschitzka F, Tamargo J, van Zwieten P, Waeber B, Williams B; Management of Arterial Hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension; European Society of Cardiology. 2007 Guidelines for the Management of Arterial Hypertension: The Task Force for the Management of Arterial Hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension (ESH) and of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). J Hypertens. 2007 Jun;25(6):1105-87. Erratum in: J Hypertens. 2007 Aug;25(8):1749.</citation>
    <PMID>17563527</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Athimulam S, Delivanis D, Thomas M, Young WF, Khosla S, Drake MT, Bancos I. The Impact of Mild Autonomous Cortisol Secretion on Bone Turnover Markers. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020 May 1;105(5). pii: dgaa120. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgaa120.</citation>
    <PMID>32154561</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bancos I, Alahdab F, Crowley RK, Chortis V, Delivanis DA, Erickson D, Natt N, Terzolo M, Arlt W, Young WF Jr, Murad MH. THERAPY OF ENDOCRINE DISEASE: Improvement of cardiovascular risk factors after adrenalectomy in patients with adrenal tumors and subclinical Cushing's syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Endocrinol. 2016 Dec;175(6):R283-R295. Epub 2016 Jul 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27450696</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istituto Auxologico Italiano</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Iacopo Chiodini</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Endocrinology, MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adrenocortical Adenoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adrenal Gland Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cushing Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adrenocortical Hyperfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

