<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04864080</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00011759</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04864080</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Transdiagnostic Cognitive Biomarkers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Transdiagnostic Cognitive Biomarkers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall objective of this study is to determine the feasibility of identifying&#xD;
      transdiagnostic biomarkers of cognitive function mediated by neuromodulation of the&#xD;
      dorsolateral prefrontal cortex that are translatable across disease groups in order to more&#xD;
      accurately phenotype clusters of cognitive dysfunction. Completing behavioral paradigms with&#xD;
      electrophysiology and TMS is a challenging frontier. This study focuses on the feasibility of&#xD;
      such an endeavor for those with chronic pain or depression as well as healthy controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to test the feasibility of procedures aimed at discovering transdiagnostic&#xD;
      biomarkers for cognitive impairment in chronic pain and depression. Fifteen healthy control&#xD;
      participants and 15 participants from each disease group (chronic pain, depression) will be&#xD;
      recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using a task-based fmri, TMS will be targeted for priming of the Left DLPFC. EEG will be used&#xD;
      during our behavioral paradigm to compare changes in DLPFC function before and after primed&#xD;
      TMS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Feasibility study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>1-7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility; the overall objective of this study is to determine the feasibility of identifying transdiagnostic biomarkers of cognitive function mediated by neuromodulation of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex that are translatable across disease groups in order to more accurately phenotype clusters of cognitive dysfunction. Completing behavioral paradigms with electrophysiology and TMS is a challenging frontier. This study focuses on the feasibility of such an endeavor for those with chronic pain or depression as well as healthy controls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>1-7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Sum total of acceptability rating scale of study procedures.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Behavioral tasks and surveys online.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pain/Depression patients from clinic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MRI, TMS and EEG, and behavioral tasks and surveys online.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Computer game/task</intervention_name>
    <description>N-back, COGED, PacMan game, Bandit task, Websurf task.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pain/Depression patients from clinic</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Behavioral tasks online and in-person.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health surveys online</intervention_name>
    <description>Health surveys to study themes like pain, sleep, depression and anxiety, and PTSD.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pain/Depression patients from clinic</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PHQ-9, MASQ, GAD-7</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Arm 1, healthy controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have access to the online study platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  under 18, non-English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arm 2: pain and depression:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain or depression&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David Darrow</last_name>
    <phone>(612) 624-6666</phone>
    <email>darro015@umn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jeanine Pebbles</last_name>
    <phone>6126246666</phone>
    <email>pebbl002@umn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang YZ, Edwards MJ, Rounis E, Bhatia KP, Rothwell JC. Theta burst stimulation of the human motor cortex. Neuron. 2005 Jan 20;45(2):201-6.</citation>
    <PMID>15664172</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chung SW, Rogasch NC, Hoy KE, Fitzgerald PB. The effect of single and repeated prefrontal intermittent theta burst stimulation on cortical reactivity and working memory. Brain Stimul. 2018 May - Jun;11(3):566-574. doi: 10.1016/j.brs.2018.01.002. Epub 2018 Jan 8.</citation>
    <PMID>29352668</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schicktanz N, Fastenrath M, Milnik A, Spalek K, Auschra B, Nyffeler T, Papassotiropoulos A, de Quervain DJ, Schwegler K. Continuous theta burst stimulation over the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex decreases medium load working memory performance in healthy humans. PLoS One. 2015 Mar 17;10(3):e0120640. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0120640. eCollection 2015. Erratum in: PLoS One. 2016;11(1):e0146737.</citation>
    <PMID>25781012</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vékony T, Németh VL, Holczer A, Kocsis K, Kincses ZT, Vécsei L, Must A. Continuous theta-burst stimulation over the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex inhibits improvement on a working memory task. Sci Rep. 2018 Oct 4;8(1):14835. doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-33187-3.</citation>
    <PMID>30287868</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ekhtiari H, Tavakoli H, Addolorato G, Baeken C, Bonci A, Campanella S, Castelo-Branco L, Challet-Bouju G, Clark VP, Claus E, Dannon PN, Del Felice A, den Uyl T, Diana M, di Giannantonio M, Fedota JR, Fitzgerald P, Gallimberti L, Grall-Bronnec M, Herremans SC, Herrmann MJ, Jamil A, Khedr E, Kouimtsidis C, Kozak K, Krupitsky E, Lamm C, Lechner WV, Madeo G, Malmir N, Martinotti G, McDonald WM, Montemitro C, Nakamura-Palacios EM, Nasehi M, Noël X, Nosratabadi M, Paulus M, Pettorruso M, Pradhan B, Praharaj SK, Rafferty H, Sahlem G, Salmeron BJ, Sauvaget A, Schluter RS, Sergiou C, Shahbabaie A, Sheffer C, Spagnolo PA, Steele VR, Yuan TF, van Dongen JDM, Van Waes V, Venkatasubramanian G, Verdejo-García A, Verveer I, Welsh JW, Wesley MJ, Witkiewitz K, Yavari F, Zarrindast MR, Zawertailo L, Zhang X, Cha YH, George TP, Frohlich F, Goudriaan AE, Fecteau S, Daughters SB, Stein EA, Fregni F, Nitsche MA, Zangen A, Bikson M, Hanlon CA. Transcranial electrical and magnetic stimulation (tES and TMS) for addiction medicine: A consensus paper on the present state of the science and the road ahead. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2019 Sep;104:118-140. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.06.007. Epub 2019 Jul 2.</citation>
    <PMID>31271802</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McNeill A, Monk RL, Qureshi AW, Makris S, Heim D. Continuous Theta Burst Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation of the Right Dorsolateral Prefrontal Cortex Impairs Inhibitory Control and Increases Alcohol Consumption. Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci. 2018 Dec;18(6):1198-1206. doi: 10.3758/s13415-018-0631-3.</citation>
    <PMID>30132267</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boggio PS, Ferrucci R, Rigonatti SP, Covre P, Nitsche M, Pascual-Leone A, Fregni F. Effects of transcranial direct current stimulation on working memory in patients with Parkinson's disease. J Neurol Sci. 2006 Nov 1;249(1):31-8. Epub 2006 Jul 14.</citation>
    <PMID>16843494</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Short BE, Borckardt JJ, Anderson BS, Frohman H, Beam W, Reeves ST, George MS. Ten sessions of adjunctive left prefrontal rTMS significantly reduces fibromyalgia pain: a randomized, controlled pilot study. Pain. 2011 Nov;152(11):2477-2484. doi: 10.1016/j.pain.2011.05.033. Epub 2011 Jul 20.</citation>
    <PMID>21764215</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>To WT, De Ridder D, Hart J Jr, Vanneste S. Changing Brain Networks Through Non-invasive Neuromodulation. Front Hum Neurosci. 2018 Apr 13;12:128. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2018.00128. eCollection 2018. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29706876</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zilverstand A, Huang AS, Alia-Klein N, Goldstein RZ. Neuroimaging Impaired Response Inhibition and Salience Attribution in Human Drug Addiction: A Systematic Review. Neuron. 2018 Jun 6;98(5):886-903. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2018.03.048.</citation>
    <PMID>29879391</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sheng J, Liu S, Wang Y, Cui R, Zhang X. The Link between Depression and Chronic Pain: Neural Mechanisms in the Brain. Neural Plast. 2017;2017:9724371. doi: 10.1155/2017/9724371. Epub 2017 Jun 19. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28706741</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moran TP, Jendrusina AA, Moser JS. The psychometric properties of the late positive potential during emotion processing and regulation. Brain Res. 2013 Jun 21;1516:66-75. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2013.04.018. Epub 2013 Apr 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23603408</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

