<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04864912</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CBAS5780</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04864912</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retrospective Health Care Utilisation and Current Quality of Life in Adults With Chronic Otitis Media Who Had a Middle Ear Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Retrospective Mapping of Health Care Utilisation and Current Quality of Life Status in Adult Subjects With a History of Chronic Otitis Media With or Without Cholesteatoma Who Have Undergone a Primary Tympanoplasty</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cochlear</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Trium Clinical Consulting</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Suministros Hospitalarios Medical Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cochlear</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this multicentre study is to evaluate the standard of care of participants&#xD;
      diagnosed with Chronic Otitis Media that have already gone through a first middle ear surgery&#xD;
      but still have at least a moderate hearing loss. The study has a retrospective part&#xD;
      (extraction of medical chart data) and a prospective part with a survey and three&#xD;
      questionnaires collecting data on the use of health care services, on health related quality&#xD;
      of life and hearing performance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and type of contacts with health care providers</measure>
    <time_frame>From primary tympanoplasty to time of enrolment, up to 11 years</time_frame>
    <description>Contacts are obtained from medical records, counted and categorized.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and type of interventions and/or procedures</measure>
    <time_frame>From primary tympanoplasty to time of enrolment, up to 11 years</time_frame>
    <description>Medical examinations, surgical procedures and hearing rehabilitation are obtained from medical records, counted and categorized.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and type of medications and therapies</measure>
    <time_frame>From primary tympanoplasty to time of enrolment, up to 11 years</time_frame>
    <description>Medications are obtained from medical records, counted and categorized. Therapies from medical records are listed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hearing performance assessed via an audiogram</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-primary tympanoplasty</time_frame>
    <description>PTA4 (0.5, 1, 2 and 4 kHz) for both air and bone conduction, under unaided and when applicable aided conditions. Data obtained from participant medical records.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hearing performance assessed via an audiogram</measure>
    <time_frame>Post- primary tympanoplasty during follow-up appointment (clinic dependent)</time_frame>
    <description>PTA4 (0.5, 1, 2 and 4 kHz) for both air and bone conduction, under unaided and when applicable aided conditions. Data obtained from participant medical records.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hearing performance assessed via an audiogram</measure>
    <time_frame>Not older than one year at the time of enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>PTA4 (0.5, 1, 2 and 4 kHz) for both air and bone conduction, under unaided and when applicable aided conditions. Data obtained from participant medical records.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health care costs</measure>
    <time_frame>From primary tympanoplasty to time of enrolment.</time_frame>
    <description>Direct medical costs associated to Chronic Otitis Media (COM)-related health care utilisation are obtained from medical records and calculated for each participant using unit cost in each participating country</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Socio-economic status and health care data via the Client Service Receipt Inventory (CSRI) survey</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Demographic data, medical history, hearing rehabilitation, health care utilisation related to ear infection and hearing difficulties and employment information data are collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported health status and health related quality of life via the Health Utilities Index Mark III (HUI3) questionnaire.</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>HUI provides descriptive evidence on multiple dimensions of health status, a score for each dimension of health and an overall Health Related Quality of life score. The HUI3 classification system is comprised of 8 attributes: Vision, Hearing, Speech, Ambulation, Dexterity, Emotion, Cognition and Pain - each with 5 or 6 levels of ability/disability The scoring systems provide utility (preference) scores on a generic scale where 0.00 indicates death and 1.00 indicates perfect health.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported health related quality of life of participants with COM via the Chronic Otitis Media Outcome Test-15 (COMOT-15) questionnaire.</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>COMOT-15 measures Health Related Quality of life of participants with COM. It consists of three subscales: ear symptoms, hearing function, and mental health forming the overall score. In addition, two questions related to COM are asked: one on the general evaluation of quality of life and one on the frequency of doctor visits in the last six months. The total score and the sub-scores are transformed to a 0-100 scale by dividing the sum of the raw scores of the items by the sum of spans of the items, then multiplying by 100. A higher score indicates a worse health-related quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported auditory disability via the Speech, Spatial and Qualities of Hearing Scale (SSQ-12) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>SSQ-12 measures speech, spatial and hearing experiences. The total score summarizes these parameters. A scale from 0 to 10 is used. A mark 0 means &quot;be quite unable to do or experience what is described&quot; and a mark 10 means &quot;be perfectly able to do or experience what is described in the question&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Validation of the COMOT-15 questionnaire in French and Spanish</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one year of questionnaire completion</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire to be completed by a minimum of 30 participants per language with an accompanying audiogram done within 12 months of questionnaire completion and with completed SSQ-12 and HUI3 questionnaires. The Cronbach's alpha value of 0.7 is used as a cut-off to measure consistency between the data.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Otitis Media</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaires and survey</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaires: Health Utilities Index Mark III, Chronic Otitis Media Outcome Test-15 and Speech, Spatial, and Qualities of Hearing Scale-12 Survey: Client Service Receipt Inventory (adapted version)</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult participants with a history of chronic otitis media who have undergone a primary&#xD;
        tympanoplasty to improve hearing between 2010-2015 but still have conductive or mixed&#xD;
        hearing loss.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult subjects, 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with conductive or mixed hearing loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with historically documented diagnosis of Chronic Otitis Media (COM) with or&#xD;
             without cholesteatoma in the operated ear.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have undergone primary tympanoplasty type I-V to improve hearing between&#xD;
             2010-2015.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with an air-bone gap ≥30 decibels (dB) within 3 months after primary&#xD;
             tympanoplasty in the operated ear. For Spain only: Subjects with an air-bone gap ≥30&#xD;
             decibels (dB) within 6 months after primary tympanoplasty in the operated ear.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have tried a hearing aid to improve hearing in the operated ear.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-op audiogram, maximum 1 year prior to the primary tympanoplasty, and post-op&#xD;
             audiogram for the primary tympanoplasty are available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Available aided audiogram, unaided if no hearing device is used, not older than one&#xD;
             year at the point of enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are fluent in the language used for study questionnaires: German, French,&#xD;
             Spanish.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are willing and able to provide written informed consent. For France:&#xD;
             subjects do not oppose to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical Record data is available throughout the defined data search period, from&#xD;
             primary tympanoplasty to point of enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are unable or unwilling to comply with the requirements of the study as&#xD;
             determined by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigator site personnel directly affiliated with this study and/or their immediate&#xD;
             families; immediate family is defined as a spouse, parent, child, or sibling.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cochlear employees or employees of Contract Research Organizations or contractors&#xD;
             engaged by Cochlear for the purposes of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For France only:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are not affiliated to social security.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are under legal protection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karin Ganlöv</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Cochlear</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Karin Ekström</last_name>
    <phone>+46317924400</phone>
    <email>kekstrom@cochlear.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Johan Blechert</last_name>
    <email>jblechert@cochlear.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Bicêtre, Hôpitaux universitaires Paris Sud AP-HP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Le Kremlin-Bicêtre</city>
        <zip>94275</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ENT department - Bâtiment Pierre Paul Riquet - Hôpital Purpan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UKB Universitätsklinikum BONN</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <zip>53127</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinik für Hals-, Nasen und Ohrenheilkunde</name>
      <address>
        <city>Freiburg</city>
        <zip>79106</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hals-, Nasen- und Ohrenklinik, Universitätsklinikum Heidelberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen Macarena</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Primary tympanoplasty</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Otitis Media</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Cochlear do not have an approved platform for public sharing of IPD collected in this study. Data may be provided to individual researchers on request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

