<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04863950</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CTMS# 20-0148</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04863950</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigator-Initiated Study of Imipramine Hydrochloride and Lomustine in Recurrent Glioblastoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Investigator-Initiated Study of Imipramine Hydrochloride and Lomustine in Recurrent Glioblastoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed as a single center, prospective, open label, single-arm therapeutic&#xD;
      trial with both surgical and non-surgical cohorts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Imipramine Hydrochloride/Lomustine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lomustine</intervention_name>
    <description>For surgical cohort patients, lomustine will be initiated (C1D1) within 6 weeks of surgery as soon as patient is deemed by the investigator (or designee) to be recovered enough for chemotherapy. Initiation of lomustine must be initiated within 6 weeks. If patient cannot be safely initiated on lomustine within this timeframe then they will be replaced.&#xD;
For non-surgical cohort patients (the decision for surgery is made independent of study participation), lomustine will be initiated on C1D1.&#xD;
For both cohorts, lomustine will be administered as 110 mg/m2 PO once every 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Imipramine Hydrochloride/Lomustine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gleostine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Imipramine Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>For the surgical cohort, imipramine hydrochloride will be initiated within a minimum of 16 days to a maximum of 3 weeks prior to surgery. Imipramine hydrochloride will be administered as 50mg PO (oral) QHS (at bedtime) for 4 days followed by a dose increase (taper-up) of 50mg/day every fourth day to attain a maximum dose of 200mg/day in 16 days.&#xD;
For non-surgical cohort patients (the decision for surgery is made independent of study participation), imipramine hydrochloride will be initiated on Cycle 1 Day 1. Imipramine hydrochloride will be administered as 50mg PO (oral) QHS (at bedtime) for 4 days followed by a dose increase (taper-up) of 50mg/day every fourth day, if tolerated, to attain a maximum dose of 200mg/day in 16 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Imipramine Hydrochloride/Lomustine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Trofranil</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has the ability to understand the purposes and risks of the study and to&#xD;
             have signed a written informed consent form approved by the investigator's IRB/Ethics&#xD;
             Committee&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has histologically confirmed glioblastoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has progression following standard combined modality treatment with&#xD;
             radiation and temozolomide chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has an ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) performance status ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a life expectancy of at least 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has acceptable liver function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AST (aspartate aminotransferase) (SGOT) and ALT (alanine transaminase 0 (SGPT) ≤ 3.0&#xD;
             times upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has acceptable renal function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine ≤ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has acceptable hematologic status (without hematologic support):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ANC (absolute neutrophil count) ≥1500 cells/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count ≥100,000/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All women of childbearing potential (not surgically sterilized or at least 1 year&#xD;
             post-menopausal) must have a negative serum pregnancy test. Additionally, male and&#xD;
             female subjects must agree to use effective means of contraception (surgical&#xD;
             sterilization or the use or barrier contraception with either a condom or diaphragm in&#xD;
             conjunction with spermicidal gel or an IUD) with their partner from entry into the&#xD;
             study through 6 months after the last dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is receiving warfarin (or other coumarin derivatives) and is unable to&#xD;
             switch to low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) before the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has evidence of acute intracranial or intratumoral hemorrhage either by&#xD;
             MRI or computerized tomography (CT) scan. Subjects with resolving hemorrhage changes,&#xD;
             punctate hemorrhage, or hemosiderin are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is unable to undergo MRI scan (eg, has pacemaker).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has received enzyme-inducing anti-epileptic agents within 14 days of study&#xD;
             drug (eg, carbamazepine, phenytoin, phenobarbital, primidone).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has not recovered to National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology&#xD;
             Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v5.0 Grade ≤ 1 from AEs (except alopecia, anemia&#xD;
             and lymphopenia) due to surgery, antineoplastic agents, investigational drugs, or&#xD;
             other medications that were administered prior to study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has evidence of wound dehiscence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has a history of cardiac disease, including arrhythmia, conduction&#xD;
             abnormality, congenital prolonged QT syndrome, myocardial infarction, unstable angina&#xD;
             pectoris or congestive heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A prolonged QTc rhythm noted during initial ECG &gt;480 ms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has serious intercurrent illness, such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension (two or more blood pressure [BP] readings performed at screening of &gt; 150&#xD;
             mmHg systolic or &gt; 100 mmHg diastolic) despite optimal treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-healing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated hypothyroidism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unhealed rectal or peri-rectal abscess&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled active infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stroke, or transient ischemic attack within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has received any of the following prior anticancer therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-standard radiation therapy such as brachytherapy, systemic radioisotope therapy&#xD;
             (RIT), or intra-operative radiotherapy (IORT). Note: stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS)&#xD;
             is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-bevacizumab systemic therapy (including investigational agents and small-molecule&#xD;
             kinase inhibitors) or non-cytotoxic hormonal therapy (eg, tamoxifen) within 7 days or&#xD;
             5 half-lives, whichever is shorter, prior to first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biologic agents (antibodies, immune modulators, vaccines, cytokines) within 21 days&#xD;
             prior to first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nitrosoureas or mitomycin C within 42 days, or metronomic/protracted low-dose&#xD;
             chemotherapy within 14 days, or other cytotoxic chemotherapy within 28 days, prior to&#xD;
             first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with carmustine wafers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of mood disorders, psychosis or past suicide attempts&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of SSRI (selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor), SNRI (serotonin and&#xD;
             norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors), MAO (Monoamine oxidase) inhibitor, tramadol or&#xD;
             trazodone; or use of these agents within 14 days of expected start of imipramine&#xD;
             hydrochloride therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William Kelly, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center - Mays Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Epp Goodwin</last_name>
    <phone>210 450 5798</phone>
    <email>goodwine@uthscsa.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maggie Tomasini</last_name>
    <phone>210 450 5962</phone>
    <email>tomasinim@uthscsa.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>William Kelly</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lomustine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Imipramine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

