<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04862351</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020.621</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04862351</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of TechCR Among CHD Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>TechCR</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Technology-assisted Interventions in Hybrid Cardiac Rehabilitation (TechCR) Among Coronary Heart Disease Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      During this ongoing pandemic, there is a crucial need for innovative approaches to deliver CR&#xD;
      programmes other than frequent face-to-face sessions at the centre-based CR to reduce the&#xD;
      number of times people come close in contact with others or gathering in large groups. This&#xD;
      is a single setting, 2-arm parallel randomised clinical trial which aims to examine the&#xD;
      effects of technology-assisted interventions in hybrid cardiac rehabilitation (TecHCR) among&#xD;
      the coronary heart disease patients. Eligible participants will be randomly assigned into&#xD;
      either intervention group (IG) or control group (CG) in 1:1 ratio using the computerised&#xD;
      permuted blocks, alternating block sizes of 4 or 6. All participants will be followed up for&#xD;
      three months and six months with data collection at baseline, (T0), three-month (T1) and&#xD;
      six-month (T2) time points.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In recent years, CR delivery platforms and approaches have been changing as technology has&#xD;
      become an integral part of our daily lives. Some of the barriers to CR may be able to be&#xD;
      tackled with the advancement of technology, as it provides an alternative to the traditional&#xD;
      centre-based CR through virtual consultations and remote monitoring that may eliminate the&#xD;
      hassle of face-to-face consultations, work and time conflicts. During this ongoing pandemic,&#xD;
      there is a crucial need for innovative approaches to deliver CR programmes other than&#xD;
      frequent face-to-face sessions at the centre-based CR to reduce the number of times people&#xD;
      come close in contact with others or gathering in large groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall aim of this proposed study is to examine the effects of technology-assisted&#xD;
      interventions in hybrid cardiac rehabilitation (TecHCR) among the coronary heart disease&#xD;
      patients. The objectives are as followings:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. to determine the effects of TecHCR on self-efficacy related to exercise;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. to determine the effects of TecHCR on health promoting behaviours;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. to determine the effects of TecHCR in adherence;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. to determine the effects of TecHCR in exercise capacity;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. to determine the effects of TecHCR on fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high&#xD;
           density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol, systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood&#xD;
           pressure, body mass index and waist circumference;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. to determine the effects of TecHCR anxiety and depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the attrition rate of 20%, a total of 160 eligible participants with 80 per group will&#xD;
      be recruited. The control group receives usual care including outpatient medical follow-up&#xD;
      with the cardiologists and dietician counselling before hospital discharge. Then, the&#xD;
      participants will have their first follow-up by the physicians in cardiac rehabilitation&#xD;
      clinic and followed by monthly follow-up. Subsequently, they will have weekly, centre-based&#xD;
      supervised exercise training by physiotherapist and follow-up with occupational therapist for&#xD;
      12 weeks. In addition of the usual care of outpatient medical follow-ups and dietary&#xD;
      education, the intervention group will receive 3 times supervised exercise in the centre,&#xD;
      weekly upload of CR education (audio-visual video) on WhatsApp for six weeks (Week 1 to Week&#xD;
      6). The prescribed exercise will then be continued at home with a pedometer as the &quot;cue to&#xD;
      action&quot; to be worn by the participant; he or she will be required to upload the data daily to&#xD;
      the web app on the smartphone. Participants will also receive a weekly&#xD;
      audio/video-conferencing follow-up (Week 1 to Week 12). The outcome measures include&#xD;
      Socio-demographic and Clinical Data, Bandura's exercise self efficacy scale (ESE), Health&#xD;
      Promoting Lifestyle Profile II (HPLP II), adherence referring to the attendance to 12 weeks&#xD;
      (supervised exercise training) for CG, and attendance (3 times supervised exercise training)&#xD;
      and upload of exercise data (for 9 weeks) to web app for IG; and 12-week assessment for both&#xD;
      groups, exercise capacity by Exercise Stress Test measuring the metabolic equivalents METs)&#xD;
      and Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). The data entry and analysis will be&#xD;
      performed using the IBM Social Package Statistical Software (SPSS) version 26.0 with a p&#xD;
      value &lt; 0.05 will be consider significant of the result.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The eligible participants will be randomly assigned into either intervention group (IG) or control group (CG) in 1:1 ratio using the computerised permuted blocks, alternating block sizes of 4 or 6. Once the eligible participants have consented to participate and the baseline data is collected, they will be given an opaque sealed envelope prepared by an independent statistician (not involved in the research) with assignment information and group allocation specified in the envelope. According to Polit and Beck (2017), the risk of selection bias can be reduced through allocation concealment by shielding the researcher from knowing the next group allocation of an individual.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>A single blinding will be implemented for the outcome assessor as the participants will not be able to be blinded due to the nature of the interventions. The participants will not be informed directly whether they are in the intervention group or control group but the information regarding the intervention will be stated in the Participant Information Sheet. Thus, the participants may know their group allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>self-efficacy related to exercise (Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy to determine the effects of TecHCR on self-efficacy related to exercise before intervention (baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>self-efficacy related to exercise (Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy to determine the effects of TecHCR on self-efficacy related to exercise post intervention (at 3-month)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>self-efficacy related to exercise (Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Bandura's Exercise Self-efficacy to determine the effects of TecHCR on self-efficacy related to exercise 3-month post intervention (T2) (at 6 month)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>behavioural outcomes (Health-promoting Lifestyle Profile II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Health-promoting lifestyle Profile II to determine the effects of TecHCR on health promoting behaviours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>behavioural outcomes (Health-promoting Lifestyle Profile II)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Health-promoting lifestyle Profile II to determine the effects of TecHCR on health promoting behaviours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>behavioural outcomes (Health-promoting Lifestyle Profile II)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Health-promoting lifestyle Profile II to determine the effects of TecHCR on health promoting behaviours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>psychological outcomes (Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale to determine the effects of TecHCR on anxiety and depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>psychological outcomes (Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale to determine the effects of TecHCR on anxiety and depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>psychological outcomes (Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>Using Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale to determine the effects of TecHCR on anxiety and depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (from laboratory blood test result)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (mmol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (from laboratory blood test result)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (mmol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (from laboratory blood test result)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on fasting low density lipoprotein (LDL), high density lipoprotein (HDL), total cholesterol (mmol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>systolic and diastolic blood pressure (using blood pressure monitoring device)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on systolic and diastolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>systolic and diastolic blood pressure (using blood pressure monitoring device)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on systolic and diastolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>systolic and diastolic blood pressure (using blood pressure monitoring device)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on systolic and diastolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (BMI) (weight in kilogrammes*height in metres^2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on BMI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (BMI) (weight in kilogrammes*height in metres^2)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on BMI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (BMI) (weight in kilogrammes*height in metres^2)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on BMI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist circumference (measured by measuring tape in centimetres)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (T0) - at 0 week, before initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on waist circumference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist circumference (measured by measuring tape in centimetres)</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (T1) - at 12 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on waist circumference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist circumference (measured by measuring tape in centimetres)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-month post intervention (T2) - at 24 weeks after initiation of interventions</time_frame>
    <description>to determine the effects of TecHCR on waist circumference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TecHCR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>12 weeks Hybrid between supervised exercise training and video call sessions Educational videos Dietary and exercise log</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Centre-based</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>12 weeks usual care provided by the centre-based, outpatient cardiac rehabilitation clinic Dietary and exercise log</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>exercise training for TechCR</intervention_name>
    <description>3 times of supervised exercise training at the centre-based, outpatient cardiac rehabilitation clinic</description>
    <arm_group_label>TecHCR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>audio/video conference</intervention_name>
    <description>weekly audio/video conference</description>
    <arm_group_label>TecHCR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>educational video</intervention_name>
    <description>weekly for 6 weeks, duration of video about 10-15 minutes</description>
    <arm_group_label>TecHCR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daily log</intervention_name>
    <description>daily dietary and exercise log</description>
    <arm_group_label>Centre-based</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TecHCR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>exercise training for centre-based</intervention_name>
    <description>6 times of supervised exercise training</description>
    <arm_group_label>Centre-based</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. adults ≥ 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. patients with documented acute myocardial infarction, treated with thrombolysis,&#xD;
             angioplasty or revascularisation surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. patients who own a mobile phone with internet access;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. patients who have at least completion of primary school education;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. understand English or Malay language;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. patients who will return home for living after hospital discharge;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. patients who are medically stable and referred to CR programme and able to give&#xD;
             informed consent to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. patients who are participating in other studies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. patients who will undergo any repeat cardiac or other procedure in next 12 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. patients with comorbidities such as dementia, impaired hearing or vision or&#xD;
             psychiatric illness which may affect the ability to participate in the CR programme;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. patients with pre-existing mobility problems which prevent them from exercising&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mei Sin Chong</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mei Sin Chong</last_name>
    <phone>+85261460016</phone>
    <email>jomeisin@link.cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Malaya Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kuala Lumpur</city>
        <state>Wilayah Persekutuan</state>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anwar Suhaimi</last_name>
      <phone>+60166591383</phone>
      <email>anwar@ummc.edu.my</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mei Sin Chong</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mei Sin CHONG</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>technology-assisted interventions</keyword>
  <keyword>hybrid cardiac rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>coronary heart disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

