<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04866238</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UDDS-Ortho-04-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04866238</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Oral Health Related Quality of Life Changes Between Clear Aligners and Vestibular Fixed Appliances</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness of Clear Aligners vs Fixed Appliances on Oral Health-related Quality of Life in Patients With Severe Crowding: A 12-months Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Damascus University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Damascus University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients who have severe crowding that required four premolars extraction will be treated in&#xD;
      this study. The effects of clear aligners therapy on oral health related quality of life&#xD;
      (OHRQoL) in comparison with vestibular fixed appliances using the validated OHIP-14 tool&#xD;
      during orthodontic treatment. So the aim of the study was to compare the changes in OHRQoL&#xD;
      between patients receiving clear aligners or fixed appliances during the first year of the&#xD;
      orthodontic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are two groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      First group (Experimental): the patients in this group will be treated using clear aligners.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Second group (Control): the patients in this group will be treated using fixed appliances.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For years, orthodontists and dentists have used removable appliances for orthodontic&#xD;
      treatment. Today, with the CAD/CAM technology, clear aligners treat a broader range of cases&#xD;
      with greater precision. They consists of a series of plastic aligners that are intended to&#xD;
      replace conventional wire and bracket technology for many orthodontic cases. Each custom&#xD;
      manufactured aligner exerts gentle, continuous forces to move teeth incrementally from their&#xD;
      original state to a final, treated state. Each aligner is worn for about two weeks, then&#xD;
      replaced by the next in the series until the final position is achieved.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in oral health related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>T0: immediately before the start of orthodontic treatment, T1: after 1 week, T2: after 2 weeks, T3: after 1 month, T4: after 6 months, T5: after 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients in both groups will be given a questionnaire to be filled. The questionnaire to be used is called Oral-Health-Impact-Profile with 14 items (OHIP-14) which can be filled in 3 minutes. OHIP-14 includes a subjective evaluation of the individual's oral health, functional well-being, emotional well-being, expectations and satisfaction with care and sense of self.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Teeth Crowding</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vestibular fixed appliances</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult patients in this group will be treated using fixed appliances.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Clear aligners</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult patients in this group will be treated using clear aligners.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vestibular fixed appliances</intervention_name>
    <description>The fixed appliances will be applied in class1 malocclusion patients who have dental crowding, then they will be followed up for 12 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vestibular fixed appliances</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clear aligners</intervention_name>
    <description>The clear aligners will be applied in class1 malocclusion patients who have dental crowding, then they will be followed up for 12 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Clear aligners</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Class I malocclusion with severe crowding (more than 5 mm of&#xD;
             tooth-size-arch-length-discrepancy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good oral hygiene and periodontal health.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No congenitally missing or extracted teeth (except for the third molars).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of previous trauma to the maxillofacial region or surgical interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous orthodontic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with psychological abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with systemic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has known allergy to latex and plastic&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samer T Jaber, DDS,MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>PhD student at the Orthodontic Department, University of Damascus</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohammad Y Hajeer, DDS,MSc,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Associate Professor of Orthodontics, University of Damascus Dental School, Damascus, Syria</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Orthodontics, University of Damascus Dental School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Damascus</city>
        <country>Syrian Arab Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Syrian Arab Republic</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azaripour A, Weusmann J, Mahmoodi B, Peppas D, Gerhold-Ay A, Van Noorden CJ, Willershausen B. Braces versus Invisalign®: gingival parameters and patients' satisfaction during treatment: a cross-sectional study. BMC Oral Health. 2015 Jun 24;15:69. doi: 10.1186/s12903-015-0060-4.</citation>
    <PMID>26104387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demirovic K, Habibovic J, Dzemidzic V, Tiro A, Nakas E. Comparison of Oral Health-Related Quality of Life in Treated and Non-Treated Orthodontic Patients. Med Arch. 2019 Apr;73(2):113-117. doi: 10.5455/medarh.2019.73.113-117.</citation>
    <PMID>31391699</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Slade GD. Derivation and validation of a short-form oral health impact profile. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 1997 Aug;25(4):284-90.</citation>
    <PMID>9332805</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang B, Huang X, Huo S, Zhang C, Zhao S, Cen X, Zhao Z. Effect of clear aligners on oral health-related quality of life: A systematic review. Orthod Craniofac Res. 2020 Nov;23(4):363-370. doi: 10.1111/ocr.12382. Epub 2020 May 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32340082</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang M, McGrath C, Hägg U. The impact of malocclusion and its treatment on quality of life: a literature review. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2006 Nov;16(6):381-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17014535</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zheng DH, Wang XX, Su YR, Zhao SY, Xu C, Kong C, Zhang J. Assessing changes in quality of life using the Oral Health Impact Profile (OHIP) in patients with different classifications of malocclusion during comprehensive orthodontic treatment. BMC Oral Health. 2015 Nov 20;15:148. doi: 10.1186/s12903-015-0130-7.</citation>
    <PMID>26589825</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Clear aligners</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral health related quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Orthodontic</keyword>
  <keyword>Vestibular fixed appliances</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral health impact profile</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malocclusion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

