<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04861025</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CSAPG-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04861025</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Siderails as a Measure of Physical Restraint. GERBAR Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>GERBAR</acronym>
  <official_title>Perception of Users and Healthcare Professionals on Siderails Prescription as a Measure of Physical Restraint, and Perception's Impact on Using of Siderails</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Consorci Sanitari de l'Alt Penedès i Garraf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Consorci Sanitari de l'Alt Penedès i Garraf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is a controversy about if siderails should be considered as a method of physical&#xD;
      restraint in older hospitalized patients. This study aims to investigate the opinion of older&#xD;
      patients and health professionals about this controversy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim: to know the perception of older patients and health professionals regarding bedrails&#xD;
      using as a method of physical restraint. Additionally, we will evaluate if the health&#xD;
      professsional's knowledge on patient´s desire regarding bedrails using produce a change on&#xD;
      that using.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: quasi-experimental study (&quot;before-after&quot;).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration: 18 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two samples will be recruited: one from older patients who are hospitalized at Geriatric&#xD;
      Hospitalization Units participating in the study, and the other one including all health&#xD;
      professionals working at the 3 hospitals which belong to the Consorci Sanitari de l'Alt&#xD;
      Penedès i Garraf.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Being the main objective of the study the estimation of a proportion (proportion of users who&#xD;
      consider the siderails as a method of physical restraint), and having a preliminary&#xD;
      estimation (65%) of this perception in older patients from a preliminary study, we calculated&#xD;
      a sample size of 270 participants, considering a confidence level of 95% with a precision +/-&#xD;
      6%, and a necessary replacement rate of 10%. In the case of healthcare professionals, we&#xD;
      calculated a sample size of 85 participants, considering an estimated proportion of 30%, a&#xD;
      confidence level of 95% with a precision of +/- 10%, and a necessary replacement proportion&#xD;
      of 5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During month 1 a measurement of the use of bedrails at the Geriatric Hospitalization Units&#xD;
      will be performed. In the sample of health professionals, a single online survey&#xD;
      questionnaire is expected in month 2 with the purpose of knowing the health professional's&#xD;
      perception of siderails as a method of physical restraint.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the health professionals' evaluations are finalized, the older patient recruitment will&#xD;
      start. In the sample of hospitalized older patients, 4 evaluations are expected. A baseline&#xD;
      evaluation (interview) will be performed within days 0-2 of admission at the hospitalization&#xD;
      unit. In this evaluation, basal data, the perception of bedrails as a method of physical&#xD;
      restraint, and a register of patient's desire on using bedrails during their hospitalization&#xD;
      will be collected. Then, two follow-up evaluations (days +1 and +2 from baseline evaluation)&#xD;
      will be done to record the use of the siderails. Finally, a clinical, functional, and mental&#xD;
      assessment will be performed at discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the trial, using bedrails at the Geriatric Hospitalization Units will be registered in&#xD;
      3 different moments of the study: at the beginning of the study, after health professional's&#xD;
      interviews, and finally after the period of patients' recruitment. For this, one of the&#xD;
      collaborating researchers (external to the nursing team) of each hospitalization unit will&#xD;
      proceed to count the number of beds using siderails, number of occupied beds, and number of&#xD;
      free beds available in the corresponding unit, and the user's position (at bed or chair) will&#xD;
      be recorded at the time of assessment. This counting will be done one day a week, first thing&#xD;
      in the morning and before users start to get up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants' recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the first register of use of bedrails at the Geriatric Hospitalization Units, the&#xD;
      researchers will inform the health professionals about the objectives and design of the&#xD;
      study, and compliance with the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be verified. If the&#xD;
      health professional agrees to participate, the information sheet will be delivered and the&#xD;
      informed consent will be collected. All health professionals will complete the survey&#xD;
      questionnaire individually, anonymously, and in electronic format.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Older patient's recruitment and their baseline assessment will take place on the same day.&#xD;
      The collaborating investigator of the study will invite all those users who undergo the&#xD;
      clinical admission interview in the participating hospitalization unit to participate in the&#xD;
      study, and within the first two days of admission. Once the study admission criteria have&#xD;
      been confirmed, and the participant's informed consent has been obtained, the baseline&#xD;
      interview will be carried out. In this interview, the user's perception of the bedrails and&#xD;
      their willingness to use them during their hospitalization will be registered. Subsequently,&#xD;
      the collaborator will communicate the patient's desire to the nursing team orally and&#xD;
      registering the desire at the clinical record.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case of participants with Pfeiffer test ≥ 5 errors or a positive result for the&#xD;
      Confusional Assessment Method test, a patient's relative or accompanying person will also be&#xD;
      interviewed. In the event that the participant is not clinically stable to be interviewed&#xD;
      according to the criteria of the interviewer, the interview will be carried out exclusively&#xD;
      with the family member or accompanying person.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients considering siderails as a physical restraint method</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of older patients (regard to all of hospitalized older patients) who consider siderails as a physical restraint's method</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of health professionals considering siderails as a physical restraint method</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of health professionals (regard to all health professionals working at the hospital) who consider siderails as a physical restraint's method</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change at the use of siderails</measure>
    <time_frame>16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Difference on the proportion of hospitalized older patients using siderails at the starting and ending of the trial</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors associated to using of siderails by older hospitalized patients</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Factors associated to using of siderails by older hospitalized patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors associated to prescription of siderails by health professionals</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Factors associated to prescription of siderails by health professionals</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">355</enrollment>
  <condition>Restraint, Physical</condition>
  <condition>Aged</condition>
  <condition>Aged, 80 and Over</condition>
  <condition>Patient Safety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Users Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted to any Hospitalization Unit belonging to Geriatrics Department</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health Professionals Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>All health professionals working at some Hospitalization Unit belonging to CSAPG Institution</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All older patients admitted to Hospitalization Units belonging to Geriatrics Department.&#xD;
&#xD;
        All health professionals working at a Secondary Care Center.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Group 1 (Healthcare professionals):&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Any health professional (nursing assistant, nurse, or doctor) who works at any&#xD;
             Hospitalization Unit belonging to CSAPG Institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Group 2 (Users):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patient aged 65 or more years admitted to one of the participating&#xD;
                  Hospitalization Units belonging to Geriatrics Department.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Group 1 (Healthcare professionals):&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Refusal to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Group 2 (Users):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Users in palliative sedation or with short /very short life expectancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Inability to consent and absence of a legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Refusal to participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oscar Macho Perez, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Consorci Sanitari d'Alt Penedès i Garraf</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Oscar Macho Perez, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+34 938960025</phone>
    <phone_ext>6243</phone_ext>
    <email>omacho@csg.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>César Gálvez-Barrón, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+34 938960025</phone>
    <email>cgalvez@csg.cat</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Macho-Perez O, Arroyo-Huidobro M, Giménez Buendía MDC, Gálvez-Barrón C. [Does the healthcare user consider rails as physical subjugation?]. Rev Esp Geriatr Gerontol. 2021 Jan-Feb;56(1):59-60. doi: 10.1016/j.regg.2020.06.008. Epub 2020 Oct 17. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>33081978</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

