<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04864106</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300004915</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04864106</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comprehensive Preoperative Airway Grading</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comprehensive Preoperative Airway Grading</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of study: To contrast and compare the Mallampatti test to a comprehensive airway&#xD;
      grading test using a rigid 75-degree angle laryngoscope (CPAG) Study Hypothesis: The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that the CPAG will have greater sensitivity and specificity for&#xD;
      predicting difficulty laryngoscopy as compared to the Mallampati test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to test this hypothesis by comparing the correlation of (a) airway&#xD;
      Mallampati airway grading (predicted airway difficulty) versus (b) CPAG view grading and&#xD;
      Cormack Laryngoscopy assessment (observed airway difficulty).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate a comprehensive preoperative airway examination&#xD;
      using a 75-degree rigid laryngoscope. (It is important to note that this laryngoscope is&#xD;
      routinely used in the speech pathology clinic where patients are not required to provide a&#xD;
      written consent because of the limited and non-invasive nature of the examination) The&#xD;
      investigators plan to accomplish this by grading a person's airway using a laryngoscopy view&#xD;
      and obtain pictures to describe a person's supraglottic airway. The investigators will use&#xD;
      these measures to assist the anesthesiologists of the day of surgery with the approach of&#xD;
      securing the airway (traditional laryngoscopy versus video-assisted laryngoscopy versus&#xD;
      fiberoptic-guided laryngoscopy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The traditional test and parameters for the assessment of the airway are: The Mallampatti&#xD;
      test, the Wilson airway assessment, evaluation of the atlantooccipital joint extension (neck&#xD;
      mobility), the thyro-mental distance, the sterno-mental distance, mandibulo-hyoid distance,&#xD;
      inter-incisor distance (mouth opening). Other investigators have proposed the use of&#xD;
      radiographic assessment methods. These traditional tests are limited by the inability to&#xD;
      visualize the posterior pharynx, tongue base, and glottis. Difficulty in intubation can be&#xD;
      classified according to the view obtained during direct laryngoscopy into 4 grades. These&#xD;
      four grades of laryngoscopic views were defined by Cormack and Lehane. At the present time,&#xD;
      no single airway test can provide a high index of sensitivity and specificity for the&#xD;
      prediction of a difficult airway. Therefore, it is common practice to use a combination of&#xD;
      multiple tests and accept that there is still ambiguity when predicting airway challenges and&#xD;
      the best approach to securing an airway.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 3, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We are adding a direct laryngoscopy based airway examination to the routine patient examination. Investigators will have two (complementary) methods of a preoperative airway examination; (a) the traditional Malampati airway examination and (b) the new laryngoscopy based examination. Both airway examination methods will be correlated with the airway grading during the induction of anesthesia (Cormack airway grading). The correlation strength of these two preoperative airway assessment methods and the intraoperative Cormack airway grading will be compared.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participants comparison of grading scores on the traditional procedure verses the comprehensive airway grading</measure>
    <time_frame>Preoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Cormack-Lehane system- Grading I-IV looking at the Vocal Cords and Epiglottis (1 is less restricted visibility, 4 is most restricted visibility)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia Intubation Complication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will undergo a endoscopic airway assessment in addition to the airway classification using the Mallampati score.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Endoscopic Examination</intervention_name>
    <description>Endoscopic airway grading using a rigid 75-degree angle laryngoscope.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18+&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA status 1-4&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients unwilling to do the comprehensive airway examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients unable to do the comprehensive airway examination&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Froelich, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adam Sturdivant, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>205-934-4042</phone>
    <email>Adamsturdivant@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael Froelich</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Airway Grading</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>To be determined.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

