<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04868578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-APN-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04868578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PyROphosPHate Supplementation to Fight ECtopIc Calcification in PseudoXanthoma Elasticum</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROPHECI</acronym>
  <official_title>PyROphosPHate Supplementation to Fight ECtopIc Calcification in PseudoXanthoma Elasticum: PROPHECI Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pseudoxanthoma elasticum (PXE) is a rare inherited metabolic disorder (OMIM 264800, frequency&#xD;
      1/25000) characterized by progressive ectopic calcification of connective tissues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PXE mainly affects the skin (unsighting skin folds and papules), the retina (central&#xD;
      blindness), the vasculature (peripheral arterial occlusive disease and stroke) and the renal&#xD;
      system (renal lithiasis) in adulthood. Although rarely, early lethal forms have been&#xD;
      reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This chronic and highly disabling condition results from a loss of function of the gene&#xD;
      encoding for the ABCC6 membrane transporter primarily expressed in the hepatocytes and renal&#xD;
      tubular cells. Recently, it has been reported that PXE was characterized by a 50-60% decrease&#xD;
      in the plasma level of inorganic pyrophosphate (PPi), a major physiological anti-calcifying&#xD;
      factor. PXE is an incurable disease although encouraging advances with animals PXE models and&#xD;
      human patients were obtained with the use of etidronate (Eti), a stable, non-hydrolysable&#xD;
      analog of PPi.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, this proof-of-concept study was statistically underpowered, mitigating the overall&#xD;
      results, notably with respect to the effect on vascular calcification and ocular lesions.&#xD;
      Renal lithiasis was also not investigated in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, the long term use of Eti maybe a concern because of its side-effects&#xD;
      (spontaneous fracture and mandibular necrosis) and the fact that non-hydrolysable&#xD;
      bisphosphonate lead to stable and irreversible calcification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent studies in animals and healthy volunteers have shown that, contrary to what was&#xD;
      initially reported and thought, the oral administration of PPi salts resulted in increased&#xD;
      PPi plasma levels, opening up new therapeutic perspectives in PXE by using PPi in place of&#xD;
      Eti.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore,the investigators propose to perform the first Phase II randomized controlled trial&#xD;
      (RCT) to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a daily and oral administration of PPi salts&#xD;
      against safety and efficacy of treatment with Eti (reference treatment) in PXE patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Arterial calcification score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Using manufacturer dedicated software, the investigator, will determine the calcification score from CT images according to the validated Agatston score method. A threshold of 130 Hounsfield Units for calcium detection will be used for the study. Voxels above this threshold representing arterial wall calcifications will be manually identified and selected by the observer on the CT image. Calcifications mass in the studied arterial segments will be analyzed and quantified. The length and antero-posterior mean diameter of each arterial segment will be determined for further normalization of the calcification score to the arterial wall surface (data expressed as HU/mm2 of arterial surface). The intraclass correlation and Bland-Altman coefficient for inter-observer reliability of the total peripheral artery calcium mass measurement will be determined by scoring 10 random scans by two independent investigators.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical observation of dermatological changes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>number of patient with dematological changes. Dermatological changes will be monitored by a dermatoscopic study of the skin according to the following protocol: Images will be acquired from commonly affected areas (neck, axilla, antecubital fossae, armpits and periumbilical area) by a contact dermatoscope (SD) with non-polarized light and recorded, as previously described .&#xD;
The investigators will ensure that the very same areas are imaged at baseline and at the end of the study. The surface of SD elementary changes featuring yellow papulae (presenting as &quot;dots&quot; or &quot;reticular networks&quot;) on digitized images will be compared using an open image processing software (ImageJ, https://imagej.nih.gov/ij/index.html NIH).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical observation of ophtalmologic changes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Montths</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patietns with ophtalmologic changes. These changes will be monitored (blinded to treatment) by the occurrence of subretinal neovascularization events, the frequency of anti-VEGF administration and the best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA). A sub-retinal neovascularization event will be defined as any of the following that provide an indication to start or intensify anti-VEGF injections to prevent (further) visual impairment: 1) retinal bleeding suspected to be caused by sub-retinal neovascularization (if needed confirmed by fluorescein angiography); 2) a significant increase in sub retinal or intraretinal fluid; and/or 3) growth of a sub retinal neovascular complex. These events will be scored by the trained ophthalmologist of the PXE reference center (Dr Th Bresson) who will be blinded for the treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>vascular changes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ankle Brachial Index (ABI) at rest: Systolic arterial blood pressure will be recorded using a pneumatic cuff wrapped around the ankle. An ultrasound probe allows recording the blood flow in the left and right ankle arteries (namely posterior and anterior tibial arteries) and brachial arteries supine at rest. The ABI is determined by the ratio between the lowest ankle artery pressure and the highest brachial artery blood pressure.&#xD;
A peripheral arterial occlusive disease (PAOD) is defined according to the actual recommendations: an ABI &lt;0.90) and an incompressible arterial wall reflecting mediacalcosis defined by ABI&gt;1.40.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">99</enrollment>
  <condition>Pseudoxanthoma Elasticum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PPI+Eti placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>the patient take PPI caps and Etidronate placebo caps</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PPI placebo+Eti</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patient take PPI placebo caps and Etidrontate caps</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>study treatment PPI</intervention_name>
    <description>patient take PPI every day and Etidronate placebo only 2 weeks every 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>PPI+Eti placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Study comparator ETI</intervention_name>
    <description>patient take PPI placebo every day ans Etidronate only 2 weeks every 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>PPI placebo+Eti</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients (&gt;18 years and &lt;65 years), men and women, presenting a clinically and biologically&#xD;
        authenticated PXE (genotype + phenotype) according to the international diagnostic criteria&#xD;
        (25).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Efficient contraceptive method in woman of childbearing age at inclusion and during&#xD;
             the overall study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affiliated to a social security insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient without acute complication linked or not to the pathology at the time of the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
        NON-INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal insufficiency (i.e. defined by a renal clearance &lt;30ml / min / 1.73 m²)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known abnormality of the esophagus that would interfere with the passage of the drug,&#xD;
             (e.g. esophagus stenosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with osteomalacia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic diarrhea (&gt; 1 month)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known sensitivity to Etidronate or its derivatives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactating or fertile women who may wish to become pregnant within three&#xD;
             years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other medical condition that may be considered in the opinion of the Principal&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of bisphosphonate during last 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypocalcemia (calcium &lt;2.20 mmol/L and ionized calcium &lt;1.15 mmol/L) *.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vitamin D deficiency &lt;35 nmol/L *&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrollment in another inteventional clinical trial which could interfere with the&#xD;
             present study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  After correcting the hypocalcemia and/or vitamin D deficiency, a participant is&#xD;
                  again suitable for participation in the trial, as long as the participant meets&#xD;
                  the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Georges LEFTHERIOTIS, PUPH</last_name>
    <phone>33 4 92 03 29 41</phone>
    <email>leftheriotis.g@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sophie Bonnet</last_name>
    <email>bonnet.s@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Angers Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Angers</city>
        <zip>49000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>ludovic Martin, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>33 2 41 35 34 19</phone>
      <email>LuMartin@chu-angers.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>ludovic Martin</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Emmanuel Letavernier</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Samir Henni</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nice Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Georges leftheriotis</last_name>
      <phone>04 92 03 29 41</phone>
      <email>leftheriotis.g@chu-nice.Fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>georges Leftheriotis</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pseudoxanthoma Elasticum</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

