<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04865120</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ACR_LUVA_1311</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04865120</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Photoprotection Efficacy With Sunscreen Formulas Containing the Cyclic Merocyanine Long-UVA Absorber MCE Under Long-UVA Exposure.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Monocenter, Double-blind, Comparative, Controlled, Randomized Study to Evaluate the Effect of E212657 Compared to Placebo on Long UVA Induced Pigmentation in Healthy Volunteers.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>L'Oreal</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>L'Oreal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the photo-protector effect of BC_3 (E212657) formulated in SPF compared to SPF&#xD;
      alone on long-UVA induced pigmentation in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The sun emits numerous radiations, of which 10% are constituted by ultraviolet light. Only&#xD;
      ultraviolet B (UVB, 280-320 nm) and ultraviolet A (UVA, 320-400 nm) reach the surface of the&#xD;
      earth. Poor penetrating UVB reach only to the deepest layers of the epidermis and cause DNA&#xD;
      damage. UVA rays pass through the epidermis and reach the dermis due to their greater&#xD;
      penetration property. UVA mainly generate intracellular oxidative stress. We can distinguish&#xD;
      short UVA (320-340 nm) and long UVA (340-400 nm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sun exposure causes short-term consequences such as sunburn and reflects a reaction erythema,&#xD;
      inflammatory type, and stimulation of pigmentation. One of the long-term deleterious&#xD;
      consequences is represented by the development of skin cancers, which are the most dramatic&#xD;
      result of sun exposure and are associated with mutations resulting from DNA damage badly&#xD;
      repaired. The other long-term consequence is illustrated by the clinical signs of photoaging,&#xD;
      associated with a major disruption in the dermal structure, linked both the decrease in&#xD;
      collagen content and an increase in its degradation by some enzymes in the family of MMPs&#xD;
      (matrix metalloproteinases). At the cellular and molecular level, many genes have their basal&#xD;
      expression modulated in response to UV exposure (transcription factors and genes involved in&#xD;
      DNA repair, inflammation, apoptosis, cell adhesion). Chronic sun exposure is also associated&#xD;
      with the development or aggravation of pigmentary disorders, zones of hypo- or&#xD;
      hyperpigmentation, actinic lentigo, melasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To protect ourselves from harmful effects of sun exposure, solar formulas applied to the&#xD;
      skin, constitute a &quot;barrier&quot; against UV radiation. Currently, the most efficient sunscreen&#xD;
      formulas from the market can absorb very efficiently and most of UVB and UVA rays. However, a&#xD;
      part of long UVA (370-400nm) is not absorbed by these formulas, while these wavelengths seem&#xD;
      to be involved in the generation of adverse biological effects on the skin, which may&#xD;
      participate in clinical consequences of sun exposure, such as photo-aging and carcinogenesis.&#xD;
      Biologically these wavelengths have been found to induce alteration at the tissue level, in&#xD;
      particular the dermal layer, but also at the cellular and molecular levels, with for example&#xD;
      the generation of oxidative stress and DNA damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Internal in vitro studies on skin cells in culture or on reconstructed skin showed that long&#xD;
      UVA were the generators of oxidative stress, damage to DNA, cytotoxicity and modulation of&#xD;
      genes or proteins involved in inflammation, the response to oxidative stress or photo-aging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      New sunscreens that are able to absorb beyond 370 nm, are now available. We have shown in an&#xD;
      in vitro cultured cells or reconstructed skin that adding this type of filter in a state of&#xD;
      the art formulation, allowed to shift the absorption spectrum beyond 370 nm and more. Thus it&#xD;
      is possible to significantly reduce the biological impact of UVA long. These in vitro results&#xD;
      strongly suggest a gain of biological protection by shifting the spectrum absorption beyond&#xD;
      370 nm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this clinical proof of concept study is to demonstrate that the addition of&#xD;
      the Merocyanine BC_3 (E212657), a new long UVA filter, in a reference formula improves&#xD;
      protection against a long UVA exposure in vivo in human. Safety studies have demonstrated&#xD;
      that BC_3 (E212657) is a safe product (Non phototoxic, non irritant, non sensitizer, non&#xD;
      photosensitizer and non Genotoxic). In vitro studies have shown versus reference a&#xD;
      photo-protector effect on fibroblast, MMP1 and Cytokines after an 60J/cm² exposure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 10, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized double-blind mini-zones on volunteers back</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biophysical of skin color</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline at Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>skin color by using Chromameter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical investigator's assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline at Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Visual scoring of pigmentation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recording Adverse Events, including cutaneous reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline at Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Safety</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Sunscreen Sensitivity</condition>
  <condition>Ultraviolet-Induced Change in Normal Skin</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>merocyanine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cream cyclic merocyanine</intervention_name>
    <description>cream long-UVA absorber</description>
    <arm_group_label>merocyanine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy female or male volunteer;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  from 18 to 40 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uniform skin color all over on the investigational zones;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  skin type III or IV according to the Fitzpatrick classification;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ITA° between 10° and 35° at screening visit with an authorize delta of ± 2° at&#xD;
             inclusion visit (D1) (Individual Typologic Angle calculated value);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  female of childbearing age using a reliable mean of contraception (for at least three&#xD;
             month before the beginning of the study, and throughout the study);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  informed about the study objectives and procedures, and able to understand them;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  willing and able to fulfill the study requirements and schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects will have to give their written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female in pregnancy (positive pregnancy-test performed before inclusion) or lactation&#xD;
             or without effective contraception ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having planned U.V. exposure of the investigational zones (sunlight or sunbeds)&#xD;
             throughout the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having used sunbed or sun exposure of the investigational zones within the 3 months&#xD;
             before inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having sunburn (erythema) on the back;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dermatological disorders affecting the investigational zones (presence of naevi,&#xD;
             freckles, excess hair or uneven skin tones, vitiligo, photo-dermatological problems);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of skin cancer;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of abnormal response to sun;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of recent suntan (according to Investigator opinion) or photo-test marks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of allergy, hypersensitivity, or any serious reaction to any cosmetic product;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any concomitant medical condition that may interfere with the study conduct in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having used within the month before inclusion any systemic medication for more than 5&#xD;
             consecutive days (e.g. steroidal and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, insulin,&#xD;
             antihistamines, antihypertensive, antibiotics -e.g. quinolone, tetracycline,&#xD;
             thiazides, fluoroquinolones-), or any medication known to cause abnormal responses to&#xD;
             U.V. exposure (e.g. vitamin A derivatives, psoralen, aminolevulinic acid derivatives,&#xD;
             etc.), or having planned to use these medications during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having used within the 3 months before inclusion any depigmenting / whitening or&#xD;
             propigmenting topical treatments, or any systemic treatment that would interfere with&#xD;
             the study assessments (antiinflammatory drugs, corticoids, retinoids, hydroquinone,&#xD;
             etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to be contacted by phone in case of emergency;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having participated within the 30 days before inclusion or currently participating in&#xD;
             another clinical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deprived of liberty by adjunction or by official decision.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>from 18 to 40 years old</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>AUDREY G GUENICHE, pHD</last_name>
    <phone>+33660992467</phone>
    <email>agueniche@rd.loreal.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>ROMAIN DE DORMAEL, pHD</last_name>
    <phone>+33609556837</phone>
    <email>rdedormael@rd.loreal.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CIDP Biotechnology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bucharest</city>
        <zip>011607</zip>
        <country>Romania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alina GHITA, pHD</last_name>
      <phone>0 317 181</phone>
      <phone_ext>182 / 183</phone_ext>
      <email>AlinaNanu@eurofins.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Romania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ultraviolet A</keyword>
  <keyword>pigmentation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Report final</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

