<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04861792</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R18HS027076</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04861792</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Michigan SPARC Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>MI-SPARC</acronym>
  <official_title>The Michigan Sustained Patient-centered Alcohol-Related Care (MI-SPARC) Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kaiser Permanente</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) - Funder</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Altarum Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NORC at the University of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kaiser Permanente</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Unhealthy alcohol use is a major contributor to morbidity and mortality in the US. Although&#xD;
      effective prevention for unhealthy alcohol use and medication treatment for alcohol use&#xD;
      disorders (AUDs) can be provided in primary care (PC), they have historically not been&#xD;
      included in routine services. As a result, most patients do not receive evidence-based&#xD;
      prevention or treatment for unhealthy alcohol use. Several efforts have successfully&#xD;
      implemented alcohol-related preventive care-referred to as screening and brief intervention&#xD;
      (SBI), but efforts to increase treatment of AUDs with medications have been less successful.&#xD;
      Moreover, implementation efforts have usually neglected smaller PC practices, in which most&#xD;
      PC is provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Michigan SPARC trial is a partnership between Kaiser Permanente Washington Health&#xD;
      Research Institute (KPWHRI) in Seattle, bringing extensive expertise implementing&#xD;
      evidence-based alcohol-related care, and Altarum Institute in Ann Arbor, Michigan, bringing&#xD;
      demonstrated success engaging over 500 small to medium Michigan-based PC practices in&#xD;
      effective quality improvement (QI) efforts. The project builds on Altarum's innovative&#xD;
      approach to implementing new or improved clinical care using practice facilitators to provide&#xD;
      continuing medical education and maintenance of certification (CME/MOC) programs to PC&#xD;
      providers, along with ongoing support for QI using evidence-based implementation strategies.&#xD;
      The KPWHRI team recently finished the highly successful AHRQ-funded Sustained&#xD;
      Patient-centered Alcohol-Related Care (SPARC) trial using similar implementation strategies&#xD;
      in KP Washington, including use of electronic health records and performance monitoring and&#xD;
      feedback, and also developed a patient decision aid to support shared decision-making between&#xD;
      patients with high-risk drinking and/or AUDs and their PC providers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Michigan SPARC trial combines Altarum's expertise in QI in small-medium PC practices in&#xD;
      Michigan with KPWHRI's expertise implementing evidence-based prevention and treatment of&#xD;
      unhealthy alcohol use-specifically alcohol SBI and medication treatment for AUDs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims of the Michigan SPARC trial are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Test whether the Michigan SPARC model increases (a) alcohol SBI and/or (b) initiation of&#xD;
           medication treatment for AUDs, in small to medium PC practices in Michigan, in a&#xD;
           stepped-wedge trial with 6 waves, and&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Test whether adding an innovative decision aid for AUDs to Michigan SPARC implementation&#xD;
           increases rates of (a) SBI, and/or (b) initiation of medication treatment for AUDs, in a&#xD;
           nested two-arm cluster randomized trial (with 1:1 randomization within each wave).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stepped-wedge cluster randomized design (6 waves, with randomization stratified into 3 periods) to evaluate the Michigan SPARC quality improvement intervention compared to usual care. In addition, this trial includes an embedded 2-arm cluster randomized trial to evaluate a patient decision aid for alcohol use disorder (with primary care practices randomized to the decision aid or not within each wave).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevention - Screening and brief intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>For Aim 1 the period up to 6 months before the randomly assigned launch date will be compared to the 6 month period after the launch date. For Aim 2 the two randomly assigned decision aid arms will be compared in the 6 months after the launch date.</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of PC patients who screen positive for unhealthy alcohol use and have BI documented in their EHR (the outcome for Aim 1a and Aim 2a).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment - Prescription of AUD medications</measure>
    <time_frame>For Aim 1 the period up to 6 months before the randomly assigned launch date will be compared to the 6 month period after the launch date. For Aim 2 the two randomly assigned decision aid arms will be compared in the 6 months after the launch date.</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of PC patients who are diagnosed with AUD at a visit who also receive a prescription for medications to treat AUD and are seen for follow-up within 14 days (the outcome for Aim 1b and Aim 2b).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">46134</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol</condition>
  <condition>Drinking</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol Use Disorder (AUD)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients seen before the randomly assigned intervention launch date.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Quality Improvement Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients seen after the randomly assigned intervention launch date.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Quality Improvement Intervention Plus Decision Aid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients at 50% of practices (nested within waves) that are randomized to receive the patient decision aid for AUD in addition to the Michigan SPARC intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Michigan SPARC Quality Improvement Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Practice facilitation, electronic health record (EHR) support, and performance monitoring and feedback combined with alcohol-related continuing medical education (CME) and maintenance of certification (MOC).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Quality Improvement Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Quality Improvement Intervention Plus Decision Aid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Decision Aid for AUD</intervention_name>
    <description>Decision aid for shared decision making about alcohol use disorder (AUD) is provided to primary care practices as part of CME. The decision aid for AUD will be available to give to patients with high risk drinking or AUD.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Quality Improvement Intervention Plus Decision Aid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults age 18 years and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seen in primary care at a study practice during the practice's study period&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Katharine Bradley, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>206-287-2151</phone>
    <email>Katharine.A.Bradley@kp.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Megan Addis</last_name>
    <phone>206-287-2052</phone>
    <email>Megan.J.Addis@kp.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Altarum Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anya Day, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>734-302-4738</phone>
      <email>Anya.Day@altarum.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Rachelle May-Maki, MPA</last_name>
      <phone>734-302-4681</phone>
      <email>Rachelle.May-Maki@altarum.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Alcohol misuse</keyword>
  <keyword>Unhealthy alcohol use</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol dependence</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol abuse</keyword>
  <keyword>Risky drinking</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Deidentified data will be shared in the following ways:&#xD;
External Evaluator. The Michigan SPARC investigators are committed to working with AHRQ's external evaluator (NORC) on the cross-grant evaluation.&#xD;
Other data sharing. We will also make de-identified data available, upon request, after Michigan SPARC trial results are completed and published. No PC practices will be identified in the dataset. Data will be available to investigators who propose a cogent analysis not already part of planned secondary analyses. Proposals must include a biosketch of the Investigator(s), as well as research question(s), sample, measures, methods and statistical issues. Proposals will be reviewed by the Multiple PIs and the leaders of the Michigan SPARC Data and Evaluation team. For approved projects, a data sharing agreement will be developed and subsequently data will be made available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

