<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04180059</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC16_0157</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04180059</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I Study of CTL Anti-DP Infusion Post-hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
  <acronym>CTL-DP 01</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Dose-escalation Study Testing the Feasibility and the Tolerance of Infusion of a Specific Third Party Suicide Gene-transduced Anti-HLA-DPB1*0401 CD4+ T Cell Clone in HLA-DPB1*04:01 Positive Tumor Recipients Receiving an Allotransplant From a HLA-DPB1*04:01 Negative Donor.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nantes University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>INSERM U01232 CRCINA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nantes University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      For several decades, allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell trans-plantation (allo-HSCT) has&#xD;
      remained an important strategy in the management of patients with high-risk hematological&#xD;
      malignancies. The acceptance of umbilical cord blood (UCBT) and haploidentical grafts (Haplo)&#xD;
      as viable alternative donors for allo-HSCT has increased the options for patients with no&#xD;
      matched donors and now ensures that a donor can be identified for virtually all patients.&#xD;
      Relapsed disease is a principal threat to these patients and affects 30-50% of them. The&#xD;
      therapeutic options for these relapsing patients are diverse but remain largely ineffective&#xD;
      in altering their long-term outcomes. Therefore, pre-emptive treatment post allo-HSCT is&#xD;
      considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MHC (major histocompatibility complex) class II molecules are a family of molecules normally&#xD;
      found only on hematopoietic cells. cell-surface proteins are responsible for the regulation&#xD;
      of the immune system in humans and are important in disease defense.&#xD;
&#xD;
      They are the major cause of organ transplant rejections. Different HLA-DPB1 alleles exist in&#xD;
      the general population. HLA-DPB1*04:01 is the most frequent (70.5%) while HLA-DPB1*02:01&#xD;
      represents 32% and HLA-DPB1*03:01 20%. In allo-HSCT, the donor and the recipient may express&#xD;
      different HLA-DPB1 molecules. HLA-DPB1 matching status has an impact on GVL (graft versus&#xD;
      leukemia) and GVHD. In recipients of HSCT, a match for DPB1 is associated with a&#xD;
      significantly increased risk of disease relapse, irrespective of the matching status of other&#xD;
      HLA molecules.. Therefore, one could anticipate that a mismatched of HLA class II could&#xD;
      induce a selective GVL reactivity without GVHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HLA-DP-expressing B cell and myeloid malignancies can be recognized and lysed by&#xD;
      HLA-DP-specific T cells. The majority of leukemic cells (Acute Myeloid Leukemia, Acute&#xD;
      Lymphoid Leukemia, Chronic Lymphoid Leukemia) express HLA-DP. A T cell clone recognizing&#xD;
      specifically HLA-DPB1*0401 has been developed as a permanent cell line This clone has been&#xD;
      demonstrated to be able to kill HLA-DPB1*0401 positive leukemic cells. In addition, this&#xD;
      clone harbors a special suicide gene allowing the destruction of the clone in presence of a&#xD;
      specific anti-viral drug named ganciclovir.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that infusion of a third party suicide gene-transduced T cell clone directed&#xD;
      against HLA-DPB1*401 might protect against possible relapse of hematological malignancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We propose to inject iv escalating dose of a third party clone recognizing HLA-DPB1*04:01, 4&#xD;
      to 5 months following transplantation (when immunosuppressive drugs have been discontinued)&#xD;
      in patients HLA-DPB1*04:01 positive with a donor HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative to evaluate the&#xD;
      feasibility, toxicity, benefits of this immune intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale Despite graft-versus-tumor effect, relapse remains one of the main causes of&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality in allo-HSCT recipients. Forty to 50% of deaths following allo-HSCT&#xD;
      are due to disease relapse. In case of relapse, the prognosis is very poor and disease burden&#xD;
      remains a challenge for the use of adoptive cellular therapy alone. The 3 year overall&#xD;
      survival (OS) in case of post-transplant relapse is dismal. The post-transplant period is&#xD;
      characterized by a prolonged phase of immunodeficiency leading to increased vulnerability to&#xD;
      infections and risk of relapse. For this reason, maintenance or pre-emptive therapies for&#xD;
      patients in CR (complete remission) are now considered to prevent future relapse. Following&#xD;
      allo-HSCT, the recognition by donor T lymphocytes of recipient HLA antigens may result in&#xD;
      different consequences. On one side, T cells may recognize antigens present on malignant&#xD;
      cells and eradicate residual disease or prevent tumor relapse. On the other side, injection&#xD;
      of unselected T cells may induce a graft-versus-host-disease (GVHD).&#xD;
&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1 is one of MHC class II molecule lying centromeric to other class II loci on&#xD;
      chromosome 6p21.3. Increase recombination events are found in the region between the HLA-DP&#xD;
      loci and other class II loci, explaining the relative lack of linkage disequilibrium (LD)&#xD;
      between HLA-DP (* HLA- DP: Human Leucocytes Antigen (DP allele))and the rest of MHC&#xD;
      haplotype. For this reason, it is difficult to find a donor matched for DPB1 in addition to&#xD;
      other classic HLA molecules. In sibling donors, the rate of incompatibility has been&#xD;
      estimated to be as high as 10.9% and in unrelated donors a mismatch rate can be up to 89%.&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1 is often not taken into consideration in donor selection. However HLA-DPB1 matching&#xD;
      status has an impact on GVL and GVHD. In recipients of HSCT, a match for DPB1 is associated&#xD;
      with a significantly increased risk of disease relapse, irrespective of the matching status&#xD;
      of other HLA molecules. HLA class II molecules expression is mainly restricted to&#xD;
      hematopoietic cells. Therefore, one could anticipate that a mismatched of HLA class II could&#xD;
      induce a selective GVL reactivity without GVHD. However, HLA class II expression can be&#xD;
      upregulated on various tissues following exposure to pro-inflammatory cytokines with a risk&#xD;
      of GVHD as it is the case following some conditioning regimens or infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The frequency of the different HLA-DPB1 alleles in the general population is well known:&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1*04:01 is the most frequent (70.5%) HLA-DPB1*02:01 and and HLA-DPB1*03:01 represent&#xD;
      32% and 20% respectively. 96% of leukemic cells could potentially be targeted with only three&#xD;
      CTL clones directed against HLA-DPB1*04:01, 03:01 and 02:01.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HLA-DP-expressing B cell and myeloid malignancies can be recognized and lysed by&#xD;
      HLA-DP-specific CD4+ cells ( CD4+ : cluster of differentiation 4+). The majority of leukemic&#xD;
      cells (AML, ALL, CLL) express HLA-DP. CD4+ cytotoxic T cell (CTL) clones recognizing&#xD;
      specifically HLA-DPB1*04:01 can be identified and have been demonstrated to be able to kill&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1*04:01 positive leukemic cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, it has already been shown that HLA-DP-specific CD4+ T cells can induce&#xD;
      graft-versus-leukemia reactivity in the presence or absence of graft-versus-host disease. In&#xD;
      this study the presence of HLA-DP-specific CD4+ T cells correlated with the clinical response&#xD;
      to DLI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The team of the Inserm unit 1232 (H. Vié, B. Clemenceau, both co-investigators of this&#xD;
      project) has developed a suicide gene-transduced CD4+ T cell clone that recognizes the&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1*401, which is the most frequent HLA-DPB1 allele expressed by leukemic blasts (70%).&#xD;
      This clone has been described in detailed in :&quot;The doubling potential of T lymphocytes allows&#xD;
      clinical-grade production of a bank of genetically modified monoclonal T-cell populations&quot; by&#xD;
      Vivien R et al. Cytotherapy. 2018 Mar;20(3):436-452.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several clinical trials have evaluated the possibility to inject, following allo-HSCT, donor&#xD;
      lymphocytes transduced with a suicide gene either to treat tumor relapse or to accelerate the&#xD;
      immune reconstitution. No acute infusion-related toxicity has been reported. Ganciclovir was&#xD;
      used in some patients to control GVHD, leading to a rapid elimination of TK+ cells (tyrosine&#xD;
      kinase +).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clone was obtained by performing a mixed lymphocytes culture (MLR) between two&#xD;
      populations differing only by HLA-DP, and subsequently by transducing reactive T cells with&#xD;
      high efficiency, and finally cloning them directly, before selecting each clone for the&#xD;
      desired characteristics. Thanks to a clinical grade Herpes-simplex-virus-TK vector, the clone&#xD;
      harbors a suicide gene and can be killed in presence of ganciclovir (GCV).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This clone presents several important characteristics in terms of efficiency and safety. The&#xD;
      clone is stable following thawing. It can be grown and amplified in vitro following thawing&#xD;
      (at least more than one million times), while maintaining its cytotoxic capacity. It produces&#xD;
      TH1-type cytokines in large amounts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the safety of the CTL antiDP under study, we emphasized on two major points:&#xD;
      Specificity and sensitivity to ganciclovir:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specificity. The clone is specific for HLA-DPB1*04:01. The clone was selected against a donor&#xD;
      homozygous for HLA-DPB1*04:01 (and identical for HLA-A, B, C, DQ, DR). Specificity testing&#xD;
      confirmed the recognition of HLA-DPB1*:04:01. Yet, HLA-DPB1 alleles described are numerous&#xD;
      (447 proteins to date IMGT (ImMunoGeneTics database)/HLA release,&#xD;
      www.ebi.ac.uk/ipd/index.html), and it is just impossible to anticipate the cross reactions&#xD;
      exhaustively (beyond some against HLA-DPB1*04:02 and HLA-DPB1*05:01 that have been observed&#xD;
      against particular cell lines). The risk, since we are in a context of allo-HSCT, would be&#xD;
      the recognition of donor cells and thus a possibility of graft rejection. For this reason, we&#xD;
      will perform a pre-inclusion testing where donor cells will be used as targets for the clone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sensitivity to ganciclovir (GCV) : The proliferation tests in the presence of GCV confirms&#xD;
      the efficacy of GCV with sufficient margin according to GCV blood levels reached during a&#xD;
      conventional treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from our colleagues show a low number of T cells detectable during the first months&#xD;
      post-transplant, with a relative increased of Treg cells meaning that the clone may not be&#xD;
      eliminated rapidly by donor T-cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reasons to administer a suicide gene-transduced CD4+ T cell clone recognizing&#xD;
      HLA-DPB1*04:01 following allogeneic transplantation can be summarized in the following points&#xD;
      :&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Relapse of the hematological malignancy remains a serious concern in these types of&#xD;
      transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3. The immune reconstitution is very delayed allowing for injection of a third party T cell&#xD;
      clone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4. In case of GVHD following the CTL infusion, the CTL clone can be rapidly eliminated using&#xD;
      ganciclovir.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis We hypothesize that the infusion of a third party suicide gene-transduced T cell&#xD;
      clone directed against HLA-DPB1*04:01 following allogeneic transplantation can be safe and&#xD;
      might protect against possible relapse of hematological malignancies&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detailed description of the methodology (number of necessary subjects) Patients candidate for&#xD;
      allogeneic transplantation who are both HLA-DPB1*04:01 and with aHLA-DPB1*04:01-expressing&#xD;
      hematological malignancy (almost 100% of cases) with a donor HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative, will be&#xD;
      proposed to receive one single infusion of the T cell clone at 4-5 months&#xD;
      post-transplantation, once the immunosuppression by cyclosporine and/or mycophenolate mofetil&#xD;
      has been discontinued. The expression of HLA-DPB1* by tumor cells will be checked by&#xD;
      cytometry or immunohistochemistry. Any possible cross-reactivity of the clone against donor&#xD;
      cells will also be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
      A standard 3 + 3 phase 1 dose-escalation study will be used:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Level 1: 1 x 104 cells/kg of recipient, Level 2: 5 x 104 cells/kg, Level 3: 25 x 104&#xD;
      cells/kg, Level 4: 50 x 104 cells/kg, Level 5: 100 x 104 cells/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conditioning regimens : no restriction&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of DLI in case of mixed chimerism or relapse is permitted after the clone infusion if&#xD;
      necessary. In case of acute GVHD post CTL clone infusion, ganciclovir will be administered&#xD;
      (at the dose of 5 mg/kg twice daily) for 14 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Biological, T cell clone&#xD;
A standard 3 + 3 phase 1 dose-escalation study will be used:&#xD;
Level 1: 1 x 104 cells/kg of recipient, Level 2: 5 x 104 cells/kg, Level 3: 25 x 104 cells/kg, Level 4: 50 x 104 cells/kg, Level 5: 100 x 104 cells/kg.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>determine maximal tolerated dose f infusion of a third party suicide gene-transduced anti-HLA-DPB1*04:01 CD4+ T cell clone in HLA-DPB1*04:01 tumor positive recipients receiving an allo-HSCT from a HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative alternative donor.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after CTL injection</time_frame>
    <description>the most likely side effects of the injection of the clone is the induction of an acute GVHD (severity measured by organ staging and overall clinical grading).&#xD;
acute GVHD will be evaluated for each patient. Maximal tolerated dose is defined as : none acute GVHD for 3 patients on 3 or for at least 5 patients on 6.&#xD;
A standard 3 + 3 phase 1 dose-escalation study will be used:&#xD;
Level 1: 1 x 104 cells/kg of recipient, Level 2: 5 x 104 cells/kg, Level 3: 25 x 104 cells/kg, Level 4: 50 x 104 cells/kg, Level 5: 100 x 104 cells/kg.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>survival and persistence of the clone injected</measure>
    <time_frame>60 first days post injection, 6 months post injection, 12 months post injection</time_frame>
    <description>The survival of the clone will be tracked by PCR (polymerase chain reaction) during the 60 first days post injection as well as 6 and 12 months post injection in the blood and in the marrow</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>immune reconstitution</measure>
    <time_frame>day of clone injection, 30 days after clone injection, 60 days after clone injection, 9 months after clone injection, 12 months after clone injection</time_frame>
    <description>T cell reconstitution will be evaluated by measuring the levels of CD4+, CD8+, Natural Killer cells</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative incidence of relapse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>event free survival, overall survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>GVHD incidence</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>cumulative incidence of acute and chronic GVHD</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>death not related to relapse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>complete remission</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>for lymphoma patients in partial response before allograft</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>side effects of Clone</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post allograft</time_frame>
    <description>events related to clone (except GVHD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Haematologic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CTL 19 : T cell therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Level 1: 1 x 104 cells/kg of recipient, Level 2: 5 x 104 cells/kg, Level 3: 25 x 104 cells/kg, Level 4: 50 x 104 cells/kg, Level 5: 100 x 104 cells/kg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CTL 19</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients candidate for allogeneic transplantation who are both HLA-DPB1*04:01 and with a HLA-DPB1*04:01-expressing hematological malignancy (almost 100% of cases) with a donor HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative, will be proposed to receive one single infusion of the T cell clone at 4-5 months post-transplantation, once the immunosuppression by cyclosporine and/or mycophenolate mofetil has been discontinued.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CTL 19 : T cell therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>T cell therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients HLA-DPB1*04:01 positive, with confirmed diagnosis of hematologic malignancies&#xD;
             (AML, Myelodysplasic syndrome, ALL, non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, Hodgkin's disease, CLL),&#xD;
             undergoing an allo-HSCT using a HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The graft can be PBSC (peripheric blood stem cells) or bone marrow.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged between 18-75 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in complete remission or &gt;50% of response (for lymphoma) at time of&#xD;
             transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a donor with no contra-indications for mobilization of peripheral blood stem&#xD;
             cells using G-CSF (colony-stimulating factors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliation number to the National Health Care System&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of reactivity of the clone against the donor's cells (PHA-blasts prepared for&#xD;
             from PBMCs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For cord blood transplants: cord blood must be HLA-DPB1*04:01 negative and the HLA&#xD;
             compatibility (A, B, DR) between the cord blood and the recipient must be 4/6, 5/6 or&#xD;
             6/6.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG &lt;=2 or Karnofsky &gt;60%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neutrophils ≥ 1 000 cells /μl and/or platelets ≥ 50 000 cells/μl (growth factor&#xD;
             allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant or breastfeeding woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient refusing contraception measure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  minor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients under guardianship, curatorship or justice protection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with post-transplant relapse within the clone injection time (before D100)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance score below 60%or ECOG &gt;2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute and chronic heart failure (NYHA Class III or IV) or symptomatic ischemic heart&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe liver failure (bilirubin &gt;30 µmoles/L, SGPT (Serum Glutamo-Oxalacetic&#xD;
             Transaminase)&gt; 4 X upper limit of normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired renal function (creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/min)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute GVHD &gt; grade 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active uncontrolled infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Denied to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe neurological or psychiatric disorders as determined by the study physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with other investigational drugs following allogeneic transplantation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>thierry GUILLAUME, MD</last_name>
    <email>thierry.guillaume@chu-nantes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Henri Vie</last_name>
    <email>henri.vie@univ-nantes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chu de Nantes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nantes</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thierry GUILLAUME, MD</last_name>
      <email>thierry.guillaume@chu-nantes.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 25, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 25, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hematopoietic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>lymphocyte infusion</keyword>
  <keyword>cytotoxic T lymphocyte</keyword>
  <keyword>HLA-DP</keyword>
  <keyword>T cell therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

