<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05072925</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BIDI-PK-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05072925</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BIDI Stick ENDS Abuse Liability and Puffing Topography Assessment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Abuse Liability and Puffing Topography Assessments of the BIDI Stick Electronic Nicotine Delivery System (ENDS) in Comparison to a Combustible Cigarette and JUUL Pod-Based ENDS</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>BIDI Vapor</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>BIDI Vapor</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study assessed the abuse liability (measured by assessing how much nicotine enters the&#xD;
      body when the BIDI Stick is used, and how this makes users feel) and puffing topography (puff&#xD;
      characteristics like volume and duration) of the BIDI Stick ENDS, a type of electronic&#xD;
      cigarette.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a part-randomized, open label abuse liability assessment (ALA) and puffing topography&#xD;
      study of nicotine-containing products carried out in 18 healthy adult volunteers who smoke&#xD;
      combustible cigarettes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will attend the study site 8 times (Visits 2-9) during the main study for ALA and&#xD;
      puff topography assessments. Prior to each visit, subjects will be required to refrain from&#xD;
      using any nicotine-containing products for a period of at least 12 hours before study product&#xD;
      use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 2, the subjects will smoke their usual brand cigarette during 2 use sessions. In the&#xD;
      first session, subjects will smoke a single combustible cigarette of their usual brand by&#xD;
      taking 10 puffs, 30 seconds apart. Blood samples will be obtained for plasma nicotine&#xD;
      analysis, and blood pressure and heart rate will be recorded. Subjects will be asked to&#xD;
      complete subjective effects questionnaires at various points either before, during, or after&#xD;
      product use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the second session, which will begin immediately after the last blood draw following the&#xD;
      first session and after all questionnaires have been completed, subjects will be allowed to&#xD;
      take ad libitum puffs on their usual brand cigarette for a period of 60 minutes (1 hour). In&#xD;
      a randomly-selected subset of 8 subjects, during this ad libitum puffing session puffing&#xD;
      topography measurements will be made with a CReSS Pocket device. Subjects may smoke as many&#xD;
      cigarettes as they like. In all subjects, a blood sample for nicotine PK analysis will be&#xD;
      drawn at the end of the session. Blood pressure and heart rate will be recorded at this time.&#xD;
      Subjective effects questionnaires will also be completed at specified timepoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visits 3-9, the subjects will use their randomly-assigned ENDS product during 2 use&#xD;
      sessions. These use sessions, and the assessments made, will be the same as at visit 2. Prior&#xD;
      to visit 3-9, subjects will be provided with a supply of their randomly-assigned product to&#xD;
      use at home before their next visit (familiarization). This familiarization period should&#xD;
      last a minimum of 2 and a maximum of 5 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 23, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 23, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Cmax0-120</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum baseline-adjusted plasma concentration of nicotine from time zero to 120 minutes after the start of product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Tmax0-120</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Tmax following defined product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine AUC0-120</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline-adjusted area under the plasma nicotine concentration-versus-time curve from time zero to 120 minutes after the start of product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Cmax0-180</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum baseline-adjusted plasma concentration of nicotine from time zero to 180 minutes after the start of product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Tmax0-180</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine Tmax following both defined and ad libitum product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline-adjusted plasma nicotine AUC0-180</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline-adjusted area under the plasma nicotine concentration-versus-time curve from time zero to 180 minutes after the start of product use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Product liking</measure>
    <time_frame>180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analog scale product liking assessment; scale from 0 to 100 with higher scores representing stronger liking.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intent to Use Product Again</measure>
    <time_frame>180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analog scale intent to use product again assessment; scale from 0 to 100 with higher scores representing stronger intent to use the product again.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Urge to Smoke</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analog scale urge to smoke assessment; scale from 0 to 100 with higher scores representing stronger urge to smoke.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Product Evaluation Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective effects assessment using Product Evaluation Scale, which included 21 items with responses recorded on a scale of 1 to 7 ranging from 'Not at all' to 'Extremely'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mass change</measure>
    <time_frame>0-5 minutes and 120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Mass change in grams of ENDS products during use sessions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Puff duration</measure>
    <time_frame>120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Puff duration from puffing topography measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Puff volume</measure>
    <time_frame>120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Puff volume from puffing topography measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak puff flow rate</measure>
    <time_frame>120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Peak puff flow rate from puffing topography measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average puff flow rate</measure>
    <time_frame>120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Average puff flow rate from puffing topography measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inter-puff interval</measure>
    <time_frame>120-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Time between puffs from puffing topography measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Heart rate measurements made to assess safety</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Blood pressure measurements made to assess safety</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse event reporting</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>E-cigarette Use</condition>
  <condition>Cigarette Smoking</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combustible Cigarette</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The usual brand of combustible cigarette smoked by study subjects, with a minimum Federal Trade Commission tar yield of 8mg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Arctic flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Arctic flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Classic flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Classic flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Zest flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Zest flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Regal flavour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Regal flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Winter flavour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Winter flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Solar flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BIDI Stick ENDS containing 6% nicotine and Solar flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>JUUL ENDS Virginia Tobacco flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>JUUL ENDS containing 5% nicotine and Virginia Tobacco flavor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tobacco products</intervention_name>
    <description>Products will be used under defined (10 puffs, 30 seconds apart) and ad libitum puffing conditions</description>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Arctic flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Classic flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Regal flavour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Solar flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Winter flavour</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BIDI Stick ENDS Zest flavor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Combustible Cigarette</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>JUUL ENDS Virginia Tobacco flavor</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy males or females within the ages of 21 to 65 years, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects will have a body mass index (BMI) of 18.5 to 35.0 kg/m2, inclusive, and a&#xD;
             body weight exceeding 52 kg (males) or 45 kg (females).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must be current smokers (≥10 per day) of factory-made, high tar (10mg)&#xD;
             combustible cigarettes (eCO &gt;10 ppm at screening) for at least one continuous year&#xD;
             before Visit 1 and may be occasional or dual users of e-cigarettes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Urine cotinine &gt;200 ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject demonstrates understanding of the study and willingness/consent to participate&#xD;
             as evidenced by voluntary written informed consent and has received a signed and dated&#xD;
             copy of the consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject understands and is willing, able, and likely to comply with all the study&#xD;
             procedures and restrictions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject is in good general health in the opinion of the investigator, with no&#xD;
             clinically significant and relevant abnormalities of medical history (e.g.,&#xD;
             uncontrolled hypertension, recent myocardial infarction or unstable angina, history of&#xD;
             seizures or recent stomach ulcer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has a seated systolic blood pressure ≤160 mmHg, diastolic blood pressure ≤95&#xD;
             mmHg, and heart rate ≤100 bpm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Females of childbearing potential are, in the opinion of the investigator, practicing&#xD;
             a reliable method of contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who, in the judgment of the study physician, have recent or active COVID 19&#xD;
             infection, as evidenced by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Endorsement of symptoms that could indicate COVID-19 during screening (Section&#xD;
                  13.1) and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Body temperature ≥38.0°C and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Laboratory test results suggestive of active or recent exposure to SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
                  (Section 9.4).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Laboratory serology results positive for HBsAg, hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody,&#xD;
             (HIV) type 1 or 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects who have participated in another clinical study within 30 days of Visit 1 or&#xD;
             who have previously participated in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects who have an acute illness (e.g., upper respiratory tract infection, viral&#xD;
             infection) requiring treatment in the 4 weeks prior to Visit 1, or an active&#xD;
             respiratory infection at time of the Screening Visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has a clinically significant abnormal finding on the physical examination,&#xD;
             medical history, vital signs, ECG, lung x-ray or clinical laboratory results that&#xD;
             could interfere with, or for which use of the study products might interfere with, the&#xD;
             conduct of the study, or that would, in the opinion of the investigator, pose an&#xD;
             unacceptable risk to the subject in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects who have used any nicotine or tobacco product other than e-cigarettes or&#xD;
             factory-made combustible cigarettes in the 14 days prior to the Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects who are self-reported or observed (during the trial session at Visit 2) non&#xD;
             inhalers during ENDS/cigarette use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects who have used any prescription or over-the-counter (OTC) smoking cessation&#xD;
             treatments, including, but not limited to any form of nicotine replacement therapy&#xD;
             (NRT), varenicline, cytisine, or bupropion within 30 days prior to Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Is planning to quit smoking during the study or postponing a quit attempt in order to&#xD;
             participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who have used prescription or OTC bronchodilator medication (e.g., inhaled or&#xD;
             oral β adrenergic agonists, anticholinergics, glucocorticoids, cromones, or&#xD;
             theophylline) to treat a chronic condition within the 12 months prior to Visit 1 or&#xD;
             have a history of lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who have received any medications or substances that interfere with the&#xD;
             cyclooxygenase pathway within 14 days prior to Visit 1 or are known to be strong&#xD;
             inducers or inhibitors of cytochrome P450 (CYP) enzymes within 14 days or 5 half lives&#xD;
             of the drug (whichever is longer) prior to Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women who are pregnant or who have a positive urine pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Women who are breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject has a history or diagnosis of adult asthma, COPD (including emphysema and&#xD;
             chronic bronchitis), or use of an inhaler within the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject has been hospitalized in the 28 days prior to the Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subject has a history of schizophrenia, psychosis, or bipolar disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subject provides a positive drugs of abuse urine test at Visit 1. Tested drugs will&#xD;
             include cocaine, amphetamines, methamphetamines, opiates (morphine, heroin),&#xD;
             barbiturates, and benzodiazepine.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subject has a self-reported use of more than 21 drinks per week. A drink is defined as&#xD;
             25 ml of spirits (e.g., whisky, vodka), 250 ml of beer, or 75 ml of wine.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subjects who have lost or donated more than 450 mL of blood within the 2 months&#xD;
             preceding the first product use.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject is an employee of the sponsor or the study site, or members of their immediate&#xD;
             family.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. In the opinion of the investigator, the subject should not participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. A history of allergy/oversensitivity to the ingredients of the study products.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anna O Popko, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MTZ Clinical Research Sp z.o.o.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MTZ Clinical Research Sp. z o.o.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warsaw</city>
        <zip>02-106</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

