<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05074888</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MMH-MAP-006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05074888</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Сlinical Trial of Efficacy and Safety of Prospekta in the Treatment of Post-COVID-19 Asthenia.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Parallel-group, Randomized Clinical Trial of Efficacy and Safety of Prospekta in the Treatment of Patients With Post-COVID-19 Asthenia.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Materia Medica Holding</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Materia Medica Holding</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The multicenter, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, randomized clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Prospekta in the&#xD;
      treatment of asthenia in patients after the coronavirus infectious disease (COVID-19).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Design: the multicenter, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, randomized&#xD;
      clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll adult patients of either gender aged 18 to 65 years after new&#xD;
      coronavirus infection of 2019 (COVID-19) with symptoms of asthenia that appeared during or&#xD;
      after an acute coronavirus infection (COVID-19) and persisting 4 to 12 weeks from the onset&#xD;
      of coronavirus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the patient signs the patient information sheet and the informed consent form for&#xD;
      participation in the study, complaints, medical history, physical examination, registration&#xD;
      of vital signs are collected, the patient fills in the Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS) and&#xD;
      Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). A six-minute walk test (6MWT) is carried out.&#xD;
      The physician evaluates the severity of asthenia with FSS scale and records concomitant&#xD;
      medications, co-morbidities and concurrent conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a patient meets all inclusion criteria and does not have any of the exclusion criteria at&#xD;
      Visit 1 (Day 1), he/she is randomized to one of two groups: Group 1 - patients receive&#xD;
      Prospekta at a dose of 1 tablet twice daily for 4 weeks; Group 2 - patients receive placebo&#xD;
      on the study drug regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will use electronic patient diaries (EPD). The patient should record any possible&#xD;
      deterioration (if applicable) in the EPD. At Visit 1 (Day 1), the physician will provide&#xD;
      guidance on how to work with EPD, so that the patient can use it independently in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 2 (Week 4 ± 3 days), the physician will collect patient's complaints, record&#xD;
      physical examination data and vital signs as well as any changes in concurrent diseases and&#xD;
      conditions. The patient fills out the FSS and HADS scales. A 6MWT is carried out. The&#xD;
      physician monitors the prescribed treatment and use of concomitant medications, evaluates the&#xD;
      safety of the study treatment and patient's compliance, filling out the diary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient stops taking the study drug. At the end of the study treatment period, the&#xD;
      patient is monitored for 4 weeks (follow-up period).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 3 (final visit, Week 8 ± 3 days), the physician collects patient's complaints,&#xD;
      records physical examination data and vital signs, changes in concomitant diseases and&#xD;
      conditions. The patient fills in the FSS and HADS scales. A 6MWT is carried out. The&#xD;
      physician evaluates the safety of the study treatment, checks the completion of the diary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study the patients are allowed to take medications for their chronic conditions,&#xD;
      except for medicines listed as &quot;Prohibited concomitant treatment&quot;.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, randomized</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the mean FSS score.</measure>
    <time_frame>after 4 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS). Change in the mean FSS score after 4 weeks of treatment. Based on medical records.1 indicates &quot;strongly disagree&quot; and 7 indicates &quot;strongly agree.&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in distance of the 6-minute walk test.</measure>
    <time_frame>after 4 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Change in distance when performing the 6-minute walk test after 4 weeks of treatment. The test is carried out with the aim of objectively assessing the patient's physical tolerance. The patient should walk the maximum possible distance for himself at his own pace on a flat surface in 6 minutes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the severity of anxiety and depression on the HADS subscales.</measure>
    <time_frame>after 4 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Change in the severity of anxiety and depression on the HADS subscales after 4 weeks of treatment. The scale is composed of 14 statements serving 2 subscales: &quot;anxiety&quot; (odd items - 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13) and &quot;depression&quot; (even items - 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 , 14). Each statement corresponds to 4 answer options, reflecting the gradation of the severity of the sign and coded according to the increase in the severity of the symptom from 0 (no) to 3 (maximum severity). When interpreting the results, the total indicator for each subscale is taken into account, while there are 3 areas of its values:&#xD;
0-7 - &quot;norm&quot; (absence of reliably expressed symptoms of anxiety and depression); 8-10 - &quot;subclinical anxiety / depression&quot;; 11 and above - &quot;clinical anxiety / depression&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the mean FSS score within follow-up period.</measure>
    <time_frame>within 4 weeks of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean FSS score over 4 weeks of follow-up period at the end of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in distance of the 6-minute walk test within follow-up period.</measure>
    <time_frame>within 4 weeks of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Change in distance when performing the 6-minute walk test over a 4-week follow-up period at the end of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the severity of anxiety and depression on the HADS subscales within follow-up period.</measure>
    <time_frame>within 4 weeks of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the severity of anxiety and depression on the HADS subscales over a 4-week follow-up period at the end of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in vital signs (pulse rate (heart rate)).</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in vital signs aafter 4 weeks of treatment and within 4 weeks of the follow-up period at the end of the treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Based on medical records. Vital signs will be measured in a medical setting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in vital signs (respiration rate (breathing rate)).</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in vital signs aafter 4 weeks of treatment and within 4 weeks of the follow-up period at the end of the treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Based on medical records. Vital signs will be measured in a medical setting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in vital signs (blood pressure).</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in vital signs aafter 4 weeks of treatment and within 4 weeks of the follow-up period at the end of the treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Based on medical records. Vital signs will be measured in a medical setting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The presence and nature of of adverse events (AEs).</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks of treatment and within 4 weeks of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The presence and nature of adverse events, their intensity (severity), causal relationship to the study drug, outcome. Based on medical records.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">680</enrollment>
  <condition>Post-acute COVID-19 Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospekta</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tablet for oral use. 1 tablet twice daily. The tablets are taken outside of meals (between meals or 15 minutes before eating or drinking), keep the tablets in the mouth, without swallowing, until completely dissolved.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tablet for oral use. Placebo using Prospekta scheme.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prospekta</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral administration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospekta</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral administration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults of either gender aged 18 to 65 years inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients within 4-12 weeks of the confirmed COVID-19 onset .&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Symptoms of asthenia that appeared during or after an acute new coronavirus infection&#xD;
             (COVID-19), persisting from 4 to 12 weeks from the onset of coronavirus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of asthenia (≥36 on the FSS scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who agreed to use a reliable method of contraception during the study (for&#xD;
             men and women with reproductive potential).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of a signed information sheet and informed consent form for participation in&#xD;
             a clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History / suspicion of cancer of any localization (with the exception of benign&#xD;
             neoplasms).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. More than 75% of lung tissue damage during the period of COVID-19 disease (CT 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Cerebrovascular diseases with the development of moderate to severe cognitive&#xD;
             impairments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Uncontrolled arterial hypertension characterized by the following blood tension&#xD;
             values: systolic blood pressure &gt; 180 mm Hg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 110 mm&#xD;
             Hg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Myocardial infarction, stroke in the previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Nervous system disorders with persistent neurological impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Autoimmune diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Decompensated diseases of the cardiovascular system, liver, kidney, gastrointestinal&#xD;
             tract, and metabolic, respiratory, endocrine or hematological diseases, peripheral&#xD;
             vascular disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any severe comorbidity which, in the opinion of the investigator, may affect patient&#xD;
             participation in the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Hypersensitivity to any of the components of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Hereditary lactose intolerance, lactose malabsorption, including congenital or&#xD;
             acquired lactase or other disaccharidase deficiency, galactosemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Pregnancy, breast-feeding; childbirth less than 3 months prior to the inclusion in the&#xD;
             trial, unwillingness to use contraceptive methods during the trial (for men and women&#xD;
             with reproductive potential).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients, who, from the investigator's point of view, will not comply with study&#xD;
             observation requirements or study drug administration procedures..&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prior history of mental illness, alcoholism or drug abuse, that the investigator's&#xD;
             opinion, will interfere with successful study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Use of any medications listed in &quot;Prohibited concomitant treatment&quot; within 1 week&#xD;
             before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Participation in other clinical studies within 3 months prior to enrollment in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients who are related to any of the on-site research personnel directly involved in&#xD;
             the conduct of the trial or are an immediate relative of the study investigator.&#xD;
             &quot;Immediate relative&quot; means husband, wife, parent, son, daughter, brother, or sister&#xD;
             (regardless of whether they are natural or adopted).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Participants who work for OOO &quot;NPF &quot;MATERIA MEDICA HOLDING&quot; (i.e. the company's&#xD;
             employees, temporary contract workers, designated officials responsible for carrying&#xD;
             out the research or any immediate relatives of the aforementioned).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mikhail Putilovskiy, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+74952761571</phone>
    <phone_ext>302</phone_ext>
    <email>PutilovskiyMA@materiamedica.ru</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Belgorod Regional Clinical Hospital of St. Joasaph</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belgorod</city>
        <zip>308007</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zhanna Chefranova, MD,PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Zhanna Chefranova, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC &quot;Family Clinic&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ekaterinburg</city>
        <zip>620109</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elena Vishneva, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elena Vishneva, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ivanovo clinical hospital named after Kuvaevs/Polyclinic #10</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ivanovo</city>
        <zip>153025</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Svetlana Ushakova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Svetlana Ushakova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Clinical Hospital # 9 of the Ministry of Health of the Udmurt Republic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Izhevsk</city>
        <zip>426063</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrey Ezhov, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrey Ezhov, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kazan State Medical University, Department of Propedeutics of Internal Diseases named after prof. S.S. Zimnitsky</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kazan</city>
        <zip>420012</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elena Khazova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elena Khazova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kirov State Medical University, Hospital Therapy Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kirov</city>
        <zip>610027</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Svetlana Malchikova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Svetlana Malchikova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kuban State Medical University, Infectious Diseases and Phthisiopulmonology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Krasnodar</city>
        <zip>350063</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marina Avdeeva, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marina Avdeeva, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moscow State Medical and Dental University named after A.I. Evdokimov, Department of Faculty Therapy and Occupational Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>127473</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kirill Zykov, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kirill Zykov, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nizhny Novgorod Research Institute of Hygiene and Occupational Pathology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nizhny Novgorod</city>
        <zip>603005</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ekaterina Makarova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ekaterina Makarova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Llc &quot;Nizhmedklinika&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nizhny Novgorod</city>
        <zip>603159</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anastasia Khaletskaya, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anastasia Khaletskaya, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Podolsk City Clinical Hospital # 3, Polyclinic department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Podolsk</city>
        <zip>142105</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marina Chernogorova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marina Chernogorova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ryazan State Medical University named after acad. I.P. Pavlov, Department of Outpatient Therapy and Preventive Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ryazan</city>
        <zip>390026</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Evgeniy Filippov, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Evgeniy Filippov, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC &quot;Energy of Health&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>194156</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Natalia Egorova, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Natalia Egorova, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC Medical center&quot; Reavita Med SPb &quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>194354</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Veronika Popova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Veronika Popova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Polyclinic # 34</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>197198</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yuliya Drozdova, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yuliya Drozdova, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Polyclinic # 43</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <zip>198207</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sergey Rodygin, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sergey Rodygin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samara City Hospital # 4</name>
      <address>
        <city>Samara</city>
        <zip>443056</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elena Makova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elena Makova, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saratov State Medical University named after V. I. Razumovsky, Neurology Department named after K.N. Tretyakov</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saratov</city>
        <zip>410012</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oleg Kolokolov, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Oleg Kolokolov, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bashkir State Medical University, Internal Medicine Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ufa</city>
        <zip>450008</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Khalida Gantseva, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Khalida Gantseva, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Volgograd State Medical University, Department of Neurology, Neurosurgery with the Course of Medical Genetics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Volgograd</city>
        <zip>400131</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Olga Kurushina, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olga Kurushina, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LLC &quot;Center for Medical Consulting and Research - PRACTICE&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yaroslavl</city>
        <zip>150003</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Olga Ershova, Prof.</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olga Ershova, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Hospital # 9</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yaroslavl</city>
        <zip>150042</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anna Snegireva, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Snegireva, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Asthenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

