<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05078567</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NLACCLAS02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05078567</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploratory Study to Evaluate the Application of NLAC Cream in Adults With Plaque Psoriasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Labeled Exploratory Study to Evaluate the Application of Natural Lactic Acid Enriched Cream in Adults With Plaque Psoriasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Microbio Co Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Microbio Co Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Psoriasis is a chronic and immune mediated skin disorder that presents with plaques of&#xD;
      thickened, scaly skin. Up to 71% patients suffer from psoriasis, leading to high impact on&#xD;
      their daily life. Plaque psoriasis is the most common type which causes thick, scaly patches&#xD;
      of skin. Although the treatment of moderate-to-severe psoriasis has been improved with the&#xD;
      new launched biologics, topical therapies continue to play a key role in the management of&#xD;
      mild-to-moderate psoriasis. Up to 80% of patients of psoriasis use topical agents as their&#xD;
      first-line therapy, including topical vitamin D analogs, corticosteroids, vitamin A analogs,&#xD;
      and anthralin. There are well-documented concerns and limitations with current topical&#xD;
      treatments. In this study, we propose a nature lactic acid enriched cream with a high safety&#xD;
      profile as an alternative choice for patients with plaque psoriasis. Lactic acid is a natural&#xD;
      moisturizing factor, which exists in healthy skin. It can efficiently prevent water loss from&#xD;
      the skin and alleviate allergic reactions caused by dry skin. The moisturized function of&#xD;
      lactic acid has made it became a commonly used additive in a wide variety of skincare&#xD;
      products, such as lotion, cream, butter and spray. This product is rich in natural lactic&#xD;
      acid generated by the fermentation of probiotics, and therefore can relieve skin itching&#xD;
      caused by skin dryness, and resume the water-holding capability of the skin by removing&#xD;
      abnormally proliferative stratum corneum as well as inducing collagen production.&#xD;
      Importantly, this product is a steroid-free product with safety and without any induced&#xD;
      adverse effects in use. This product is also can be a promising option other than steroids to&#xD;
      be applied for the mitigation of recurrent symptoms in plaque psoriasis by resuming the&#xD;
      water-retention ability of skin and rebuilding skin barrier function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      I. Study Purpose&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Hypothesis: Natural lactic acid-enriched cream improves the Psoriasis Area and Severity&#xD;
      Index scores in plaque psoriasis patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Primary Objective: To assess the clinical efficacy of natural lactic acid-enriched cream&#xD;
      for the proportion of subjects who achieve a Physician Global Assessment (PGA) score of clear&#xD;
      (0) or almost clear (1) with a minimum 2-grade improvement from Baseline in patients with&#xD;
      plaque psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. To assess the safety of 12 week-treatment of natural lactic acid-enriched cream&#xD;
                application, as determined by the count of serious and non-serious&#xD;
                treatment-emergent adverse events (AEs) during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. To evaluate the clinical efficacy of natural lactic acid-enriched cream in subjects&#xD;
                with plaque psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. To assess the TEWL, transepidermal water loss of natural lactic acid-enriched&#xD;
                cream.&#xD;
&#xD;
                II. Study Design and Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subject This is an open-labeled exploratory study to evaluate safety and efficacy of&#xD;
           natural lactic acid-enriched cream in adults with plaque psoriasis. The study was&#xD;
           conducted at one medical center in Taiwan.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sample size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 10 subjects who meet the criteria for study enrollment, will be treated with&#xD;
      natural lactic acid-enriched cream.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Treatment duration: The subjects were required to topically apply natural lactic&#xD;
      acid-enriched cream twice daily in the morning and evening for the treatment duration of 12&#xD;
      weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study includes 3 periods: screening (up to 4 weeks), treatment (12 weeks), and&#xD;
      post-treatment follow-up (4 weeks). Study visits occur at screening; at weeks 1, 2, 4, 8 and&#xD;
      12; and 2 and 4 weeks after the completion of treatment (weeks 14 and 16). The study will be&#xD;
      conducted in the Department of Dermatology, Taipei Medical School Shuang Ho Hospital,&#xD;
      Ministry of Health and Welfare.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Investigational Product (IP) Natural lactic acid enriched cream: The natural lactic acid&#xD;
      enriched cream was produced by Microbio Co. Ltd. and contained active ingredient 5% lactic&#xD;
      acid is listed at 7 CFR Part 205.605 (a) as an approved nonsynthetic material produced by&#xD;
      microbial fermentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Male and female subjects ages 20 to 65 years with clinical diagnosis of chronic&#xD;
           plaque psoriasis and stable disease for at least 6 months prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2. Capable of giving written informed consent 3. BSA involvement ≥ 5% and ≤ 10% 4. A PGA&#xD;
           score of 3 (moderate) at screening and baseline 5. One target plaque located on the&#xD;
           trunk or proximal parts of extremities (excluding knees, elbows, and intertriginous&#xD;
           areas) that is at least 3 (centimeter) cm х 3 cm in size at Screening and Baseline with&#xD;
           a severity representative of the subject's overall disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
           6. Females of child bearing potential and male subjects who are engaging in sexual&#xD;
           activity that could lead to pregnancy agree to follow the specified contraceptive&#xD;
           guidance throughout the study, including screening, during the treatment period, and for&#xD;
           at least 4 weeks after the last exposure to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Psoriasis other than plaque variant 2. Acute active bacterial, fungal, or viral&#xD;
           (herpes simplex, herpes zoster, chicken pox) skin infection within 1 week prior to the&#xD;
           Baseline visit; chronic or acute infection requiring treatment with systemic&#xD;
           antibiotics, antivirals, antiparasitics, antiprotozoals, or antifungals within 4 weeks&#xD;
           prior to the Baseline visit Significant dermatologic or inflammatory condition other&#xD;
           than plaque psoriasis that, in the Investigator's opinion, would make it difficult to&#xD;
           interpret data or assessments during the study 4. Ultraviolet (UV) light therapy or&#xD;
           prolonged exposure to natural or artificial sources of UV radiation within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
           to the Baseline visit and/or plans to have such exposures during the study which could&#xD;
           potentially impact the subject's psoriasis 5. Use of any prohibited medication within&#xD;
           the indicated period before the first dose of study drug:&#xD;
&#xD;
           -- Within a minimum of 5 half lives for biologic agents&#xD;
&#xD;
           -- Within 4 weeks for systemic immunosuppressive or immunomodulating agents, fumaric&#xD;
           acid derivatives, vitamin D3 and analogs, retinoids, psolarens, corticosteroids,&#xD;
           adrenocorticotropic hormone analogs, and tazarotene&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  2 weeks for immunizations with a live viral component&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Drugs known to possibly worsen psoriasis, unless on a stable dose for &gt; 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  With the exception of non medicated emollients, 1 week for topical treatments&#xD;
                including corticosteroids, immunomodulators, anthralin (dithranol), vitamin D&#xD;
                derivatives or coal tar&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Any investigational product within 30 days, 5 half lives, or twice the duration of&#xD;
                the biological effect of the study drug (whichever is longer) prior to first dose&#xD;
                of study drug 6. Pregnant females or lactating females 7. Subjects have an allergic&#xD;
                history of soybean and soybean derivatives. 8. History of sensitivity to the study&#xD;
                drugs, or components thereof or a history of drug or other allergy that, in the&#xD;
                opinion of the Investigator or Medical Monitor, contraindicates the subject's&#xD;
                participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Primary Endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Numbers of subjects who achieve a Physician Global Assessment (PGA) score of clear (0) or&#xD;
      almost clear (1) with a minimum 2 grade improvement from Baseline at Week 12&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Secondary Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Number of subjects with ≥ 75% improvement in Psoriasis Area and Severity Index (PASI)&#xD;
           from Baseline at Week 4, 8 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Number of subjects with a PGA score of 0 or 1 at Week 4, 8, and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Mean change in percent of total body surface area (%BSA) affected from Baseline to at&#xD;
           Week 4, 8 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Number of subjects with ≥90% improvement in PASI score from Baseline to Week 4, 8 and&#xD;
           12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Mean Change in PASI Score From Baseline to Week 4, 8 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Mean Change in PGA Score From Baseline to Week 4, 8 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. The mean percentage change from baseline in trans epidermal water loss (TEWL) to Week 4,&#xD;
           8 and 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Safety Endpoint: The incidence of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Experimental Groups: single arm, natural lactic acid enriched cream Clinical sample&#xD;
           collection: To explore the diversity of the skin microbiome, skin microbiota will be&#xD;
           harvested by swapping method at day 1 baseline visit, weeks 4, 12 and 16. DNA sequencing&#xD;
           will be applied to clarify the composition of cutaneous microbiota at indicated time&#xD;
           points.&#xD;
&#xD;
           III. Statistical Analysis - General Statistics: For continuous variables, the following&#xD;
           will be presented: mean, median, standard deviation, minimum and maximum. The comparison&#xD;
           between two treatment groups and the comparison within group will be tested by using two&#xD;
           independent t-test and paired t-test, respectively. If the normal assumption is&#xD;
           violated, the Wilcoxon rank-sum and Wilcoxon signed-rank test will be conducted,&#xD;
           respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
           For categorical variables, the numbers and percentages of subjects will be listed and&#xD;
           summarized. Comparison for percentages will be performed using the Chi-square test and&#xD;
           McNemar's test when comparing results in the same patient. The Fisher's exact test will&#xD;
           replace the Chi-square test when any counting of the expected frequency is less than 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Endpoints: To perform the primary efficacy and other endpoints for continuous&#xD;
           variable, two independent t-test will be used. If the normal assumption is violated, the&#xD;
           non-parametric method of Wilcoxon rank-sum test will be applied for analysis.&#xD;
           Significant level will be adopted with two-side at 0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
           For categorical variables, the Chi square test will be used. When any counting of the&#xD;
           expected frequency is less than 5, the Fisher's exact test will be conducted.&#xD;
           Significant alpha level will be adopted at 0.05&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Safety: Adverse events will be coded by preferred term (PT) and system organ class&#xD;
           (SOC) by the latest version of MedDRA. Adverse events will be summarized by severity,&#xD;
           relationship to study drug, SAEs, and AEs leading to discontinuation of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Physical examination findings will be presented in a tabulated listing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician Global Assessment (PGA) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Numbers of subjects who achieve a Physician Global Assessment (PGA) score of clear (0) or almost clear (1) with a minimum 2 grade improvement from Baseline at Week 12</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Plaque Psoriasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm open label study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Topical used natural lactic acid-enriched cream twice daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>5% Natural Lactic Acid-enriched Cream</intervention_name>
    <description>The subjects were required to topically apply natural lactic acid-enriched cream twice daily in the morning and evening for the treatment duration of 12 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm open label study</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female subjects ages 20 to 65 years with clinical diagnosis of chronic plaque&#xD;
             psoriasis and stable disease for at least 6 months prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Capable of giving written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. BSA involvement ≥ 5% and ≤ 10%&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A PGA score of 3 (moderate) at screening and baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. One target plaque located on the trunk or proximal parts of extremities (excluding&#xD;
             knees, elbows, and intertriginous areas) that is at least 3 (centimeter) cm х 3 cm in&#xD;
             size at Screening and Baseline with a severity representative of the subject's overall&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females of child bearing potential and male subjects who are engaging in sexual&#xD;
             activity that could lead to pregnancy agree to follow the specified contraceptive&#xD;
             guidance throughout the study, including screening, during the treatment period, and&#xD;
             for at least 4 weeks after the last exposure to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Psoriasis other than plaque variant&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute active bacterial, fungal, or viral (herpes simplex, herpes zoster, chicken pox)&#xD;
             skin infection within 1 week prior to the Baseline visit; chronic or acute infection&#xD;
             requiring treatment with systemic antibiotics, antivirals, antiparasitics,&#xD;
             antiprotozoals, or antifungals within 4 weeks prior to the Baseline visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Significant dermatologic or inflammatory condition other than plaque psoriasis that,&#xD;
             in the Investigator's opinion, would make it difficult to interpret data or&#xD;
             assessments during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ultraviolet (UV) light therapy or prolonged exposure to natural or artificial sources&#xD;
             of UV radiation within 4 weeks prior to the Baseline visit and/or plans to have such&#xD;
             exposures during the study which could potentially impact the subject's psoriasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Use of any prohibited medication within the indicated period before the first dose of&#xD;
             study drug:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Within a minimum of 5 half lives for biologic agents&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Within 4 weeks for systemic immunosuppressive or immunomodulating agents, fumaric&#xD;
                  acid derivatives, vitamin D3 and analogs, retinoids, psolarens, corticosteroids,&#xD;
                  adrenocorticotropic hormone analogs, and tazarotene&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  2 weeks for immunizations with a live viral component&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Drugs known to possibly worsen psoriasis, unless on a stable dose for &gt; 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  With the exception of non medicated emollients, 1 week for topical treatments&#xD;
                  including corticosteroids, immunomodulators, anthralin (dithranol), vitamin D&#xD;
                  derivatives or coal tar&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any investigational product within 30 days, 5 half lives, or twice the duration&#xD;
                  of the biological effect of the study drug (whichever is longer) prior to first&#xD;
                  dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant females or lactating females&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects have an allergic history of soybean and soybean derivatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of sensitivity to the study drugs, or components thereof or a history of drug&#xD;
             or other allergy that, in the opinion of the Investigator or Medical Monitor,&#xD;
             contraindicates the subject's participation in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

