<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05078385</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AGLE-102-102</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05078385</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety of Mesenchymal Stem Cell Extracellular Vesicles (BM-MSC-EVs) for the Treatment of Burn Wounds</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Safety Study of the Administration of Mesenchymal Stem Cell Extracellular Vesicles in the Treatment of Burn Wounds.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aegle Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Congressionally Directed Medical Research Programs</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aegle Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have been used in a variety of clinical applications to repair&#xD;
      and regenerate damaged tissue. Previous research has demonstrated the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      delivering bone marrow cells including MSCs to chronic wounds with significant improvement in&#xD;
      healing and scarring. Application of mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) therapy to severe burn&#xD;
      wounds represents an opportunity for improved outcomes where alternate therapies are limited&#xD;
      and often ineffective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this protocol, 2nd degree burn wounds will receive direct application of EVs derived from&#xD;
      bone marrow MSCs. We have observed success with this type of approach in the past using bone&#xD;
      marrow stem cells including MSCs. We have evidence that EVs derived from MSCs are responsible&#xD;
      for many of the healing effects produced by MSCs and may be a safer, more reliable&#xD;
      alternative to allogeneic cell therapy. This protocol is designed to develop a safe and ideal&#xD;
      method of administering bone marrow cell Extracellular Vesicles to wounds.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to examine the safety of administering EVs derived from allogeneic MSCs&#xD;
      to 2nd degree burn wounds of less than 20% TBSA. The study will consist of a single dose&#xD;
      level which will evaluate the safety of administering allogeneic Extracellular Vesicles-with&#xD;
      a total of 10 patients. The chosen dosage will correlate to a dose of MSCs administered under&#xD;
      another protocol (IND 14810). The dose level delivered will be EVs derived from approximately&#xD;
      1 X 104 MSCs for each cm2 treated area not to exceed 20% TBSA in total (cumulative, if more&#xD;
      than one area is treated). The limitation in wound sizes to be treated will not change&#xD;
      throughout the study. Up to 2 additional administrations of EVs will be given over a period&#xD;
      of no more than 8 weeks. The first treatment will be administered within 48 hours of the burn&#xD;
      injury. The subsequent treatments will be administered no less than 7 days and no more than 6&#xD;
      weeks apart.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Objective</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective will be to determine the safety of administering allogeneic Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cell Extracellular Vesicles (BM-MSC-EVs) to second degree burn wounds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary Objective</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Observe the healing effect of the administration of allogeneic BM-MSC-EVs to 2nd degree burn wounds</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary Objective</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Determine if administration of BM-MSC-EVs can affect the progression of second degree burn wounds</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Burns</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AGLE-102</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The study is designed to examine the safety of administering EVs derived from allogeneic MSCs to 2nd degree burn wounds of less than 20% TBSA. The study will consist of a single dose level which will evaluate the safety of administering allogeneic Extracellular Vesicles-with a total of 10 patients. The chosen dosage will correlate to a dose of MSCs administered under another protocol (IND 14810). The dose level delivered will be EVs derived from approximately 1 X 104 MSCs for each cm2 treated area not to exceed 20% TBSA in total (cumulative, if more than one area is treated). The limitation in wound sizes to be treated will not change throughout the study. Up to 2 additional administrations of EVs will be given over a period of no more than 8 weeks. The first treatment will be administered within 48 hours of the burn injury. The subsequent treatments will be administered no less than 7 days and no more than 6 weeks apart.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AGLE-102</intervention_name>
    <description>In this protocol, 2nd degree burn wounds will receive direct application of EVs derived from bone marrow MSCs. We have observed success with this type of approach in the past using bone marrow stem cells including MSCs. We have evidence that EVs derived from MSCs are responsible for many of the healing effects produced by MSCs and may be a safer, more reliable alternative to allogeneic cell therapy. This protocol is designed to develop a safe and ideal method of administering bone marrow cell Extracellular Vesicles to wounds.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AGLE-102</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female subjects 18 years of age or older with 2nd Degree Burn Wounds&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Injury within the prior 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must understand and give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must agree to have blood draws performed as per protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects must be accessible for wound treatment and assessment visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Males and females must agree to use an acceptable method of contraception. Exceptions&#xD;
             will be females of non-childbearing age and monogamous males who are partners of&#xD;
             females of non-childbearing age. Acceptable methods of birth control include; history&#xD;
             of sterilization, oral contraceptives, depo-progesterone injections, a barrier&#xD;
             contraceptive such as a condom with or without spermicide cream or gel, diaphragms or&#xD;
             cervical cap with or without spermicide cream or gel, or an intrauterine device (IUD).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Maximum wound size limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Single wound: ≤ 5% body surface area (BSA)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple wounds treated in a defined anatomical region with ≤ 20% cumulative TBSA&#xD;
                  as would correspond to a 70kg subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Solely 1st degree or solely 3rd degree burns&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects with superficial 2nd degree burn who are expected to heal within 2 weeks post&#xD;
             standard therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of active infection at the wound site&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of significant wound healing prior to treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Burn wounds requiring skin grafting&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Wound exclusively located in the area of fingers, toes, face, or perineum&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have any requirement for the use of systemic steroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects Allergic to human albumin, streptomycin, or penicillin&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Be a pregnant female or nursing mother&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who are known or found to be HIV positive&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of alcohol or substance abuse requiring treatment within the past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients with severe medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Malignancy (other than non melanoma skin cancer) not in remission or in remission&#xD;
                  less than 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Life expectancy less than two years&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Severe cardiopulmonary disease restricting ambulation to the clinical facility&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. WBC &lt;3 or &gt; 20 x109/L, Hgb &lt; 7g/dL, platelets count 50x109/L or less, serum creatinine&#xD;
             &gt; 2 times the upper normal limit&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Those with a known history of coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subjects who are potential recipients of tissue or organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects with circulating Hepatitis B antigen and/or who are seropositive for&#xD;
             Hepatitis C antibody&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of poor compliance, unreliability&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shelley Hartman</last_name>
    <phone>781-918-8849</phone>
    <email>shartman@aegletherapeutics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burns</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

