<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05077202</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>6930</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05077202</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A New Scoring Model to Diagnose COVID-19 Using Lung Ultrasound in the Emergency Department</brief_title>
  <acronym>LungUltrasound</acronym>
  <official_title>A New Scoring Model to Diagnose COVID-19 Using Lung Ultrasound in the Emergency Department</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zagazig University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zagazig University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mortality in COVID-19 patients is significantly correlated with age, fever duration, cardiac&#xD;
      history, and B-profile and areas of consolidation in LUS. However, it is negatively&#xD;
      correlated with initial O2 saturation and ejection fraction. This study was aiming to design&#xD;
      a new scoring model to diagnose COVID-19 using bedside lung ultrasound (LUS) in the emergency&#xD;
      department (ED).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study recruited all patient with pulmonary symptoms and presented to ED between 27th&#xD;
      March 2020 and 17th May 2020. Exclusion criteria were (i) patients with congestive heart&#xD;
      failure (n= 7), (ii) patients with known interstitial lung fibrosis (n= 4), and (iii)&#xD;
      patients with poor echo-window (n= 4). Patients were seen first at ED where they underwent&#xD;
      the required investigations and then classified. Patients were questioned about symptoms&#xD;
      suspecting COVID-19 infection. Those who met the suspected clinical and investigational&#xD;
      criteria were given a standard mask and were rapidly transferred safely to a separate waiting&#xD;
      and isolation area with available infrastructure and tools for hand and respiratory hygiene&#xD;
      practice. If the patient was proved to be positive for COVID-19, he was sent to quarantine.&#xD;
      For negative patients, they were admitted to intermediate or ICU according to their clinical&#xD;
      status. All recruited patients underwent the followings: complete blood count (CBC), arterial&#xD;
      blood gas (ABGs), RT-PCR assay to detect COVID-19, chest X-ray, chest CT, LUS, and&#xD;
      echocardiography (according to its availability, with precautions for the operators and the&#xD;
      probe similar to those exerted to LUS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      LUS examination:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two trained medical personnel, one ICU physician and one ICU nurse, entered the isolation&#xD;
      room respecting all the preventive measures for respiratory, droplet, and contact isolation&#xD;
      provided by the world health organization for the COVID-19 outbreak. The ultrasound probe and&#xD;
      the tablet were put in two different sterile, plastic probe and tablet covers. Imaging was&#xD;
      performed using a curvilinear probe (2-5 MHz) with different devices according to the&#xD;
      availability in each centre. Six-point LUS (three in each hemithorax) was performed as&#xD;
      described in the bedside lung ultrasonography in emergency (BLUE) protocol [13].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis included comparing different parameters between COVID-19&#xD;
      positive-patients and COVID-19 negative-patients, using independent t-test for numerical&#xD;
      variables and chi-square for categorical variables. All significantly different variables&#xD;
      were entered in a forward stepwise binary logistic regression analysis to select the best&#xD;
      model. After selecting the best model. The variable chosen in the last step was weighed using&#xD;
      the odds ratios (ORs) calculated from the regression coefficient (β) for each variable, the&#xD;
      ORs were multiplied by 0.125 to calculate a score for each variable and the number was&#xD;
      rounded to the nearest integer giving of scoring system of 10 points. All study patients were&#xD;
      scored. The cutoff point of the score was calculated using ROC analysis, and calculation of&#xD;
      sensitivity and specificity was performed. Also, variables associated with mortality in&#xD;
      COVID-19 positive were entered in a forward binary logistic regression, which selected the&#xD;
      best model and the ORs were calculated for each variable using the regression coefficient&#xD;
      (β). Before adding the variables in the regression analysis, the determination of the proper&#xD;
      cutoff values of different contentious variables was done using ROC analysis. Patient Data&#xD;
      were entered, checked, and analyzed using SPSS for Windows version 16 (SPSS, Inc. Chicago,&#xD;
      IL, USA). For all the above mentioned statistical tests, the threshold of significance is&#xD;
      fixed at a 5% level (p &lt; 0.05).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 19, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 17, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>lung ultra sound criteria for covid19 pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>about 2 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>areas of consolidation in COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>about 2 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Pneumonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ultra sound</arm_group_label>
    <description>lung ultrasound</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ct chest</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients had done CT chest already and we receive it from hospital files</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ultra sound</intervention_name>
    <description>chest ultrasound</description>
    <arm_group_label>ultra sound</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        covid19 pneumonia at emergency room&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        covid19 patients at emergency room.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (i) patients with congestive heart failure (n= 7), (ii) patients with known interstitial&#xD;
        lung fibrosis (n= 4), and (iii) patients with poor echo-window (n= 4).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>zagazigU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zagazig</city>
        <zip>44519</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Zagazig University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Waleed Mansour</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>ZagazigU</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lung ultrasound</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>research</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

