<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05072821</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MOHW109-TDU-B-211-114003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05072821</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Botulinum Toxin Type A Injection to Prevent Keloid Recurrence</brief_title>
  <official_title>Immediate Injection of Botulinum Toxin Type A After Keloid Scar Revision to Prevent Keloid Recurrence: a Prospective, Split-scar, Double-blind, Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cheng-Kung University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tainan Hospital, Ministry of Health and Welfare</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cheng-Kung University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The prospective, split-scar, double-blind, randomized controlled study will enroll the&#xD;
      patients who are older than 20 years with progressive keloid lesion which is symmetric.&#xD;
      Botulinum toxin A will be injected into half of each keloid revision wound immediately after&#xD;
      skin closure. The scars will be assessed at 1-year follow-up with Vancouver Scar Scale (VSS),&#xD;
      Patient and Observer Scar Assessment Scale (POSAS), and the Cutometer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Continuous variables will be reported as the mean ± SD. Each aspect of the VSS score, POSAS&#xD;
      score, and the Cutometer parameters of each scar half between the BTA and control groups will&#xD;
      be analyzed longitudinally using the paired t test. The interrater consistency will be&#xD;
      evaluated using the Spearman rho. All analyses will be performed with IBM SPSS Version 23.0&#xD;
      (IBM Corp., Redmond, Wash.). A value of p &lt; 0.05 is considered to indicate statistical&#xD;
      significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size was calculated based on the results of the investigators' aforementioned&#xD;
      study published in 2019. Thirty patients underwent keloid revision and then received&#xD;
      radiation therapy based on our treatment protocol. The postoperative Vancouver Scar Scale&#xD;
      score was 4.15 ± 1.74. If treatment could improve VSS score by 1, which was considered&#xD;
      clinically significant, approximately 26 patients would have been necessary to provide a&#xD;
      result with a real significance (using the same SD and considering the standard α error of&#xD;
      0.05 and a power of 0.8). Assuming a 20% non-compliance rate for follow-up evaluation, the&#xD;
      sample size was increased to 32 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Keloid recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>The recurrence of keloid will be determined by clinical examination evaluated by a dermatologist.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The subjective symptoms will be measured by the Patient Scale of the Patient and Observer Scar Assessment Scale. The Patient Scale consists six items and scores from 1 to 10 for each items. The score of 1 means much alike the normal skin and the score of 10 means worst imaginable scar.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The subjective symptoms will be measured by the Observer Scale of the Patient and Observer Scar Assessment Scale. The Observer Scale consists six items and scores from 1 to 10 for each items. The score of 1 means much alike the normal skin and the score of 10 means worst imaginable scar.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vancouver Scar Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>One dermatologist will evaluate the scar with the Vancouver Scar Scale. The Vancouver Scar Scale consists 4 items. The minimum score is 0, which means the scar is much alike normal skin. The maximal score is 13, which means purple, hyperpigmentation, contracture and elevated scar.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Scar firmness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The scar firmness is determined by the Cutometer parameter R0. R0 is maximum amplitude of the curve (the total elongation). The larger R0 is, the softer the scar is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Scar Keloid</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Botulinum Toxin type A injection side</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Botulinum Toxin type A will be injected into the dermal layer before skin closure in keloid excision surgery. The concentration of Botulinum Toxin type A is 100 units in 2 mL and dosage is 8 units/cm. The maximal dose is 100 units for each participant.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.9% saline injection side</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The 0.9% saline will be injected into the dermal layer before skin closure in keloid excision surgery. The dosage is 0.16 mL/cm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Botulinum Toxin Type A Injection [Botox]</intervention_name>
    <description>After the whole surgical procedures of keloid revision are done, the participants will receive Botulinum Toxin type A (BTA) injection. The investigators split the scar into the right side and the left side. BTA and 0.9% saline, respectively, are used for the two arms of the study. Vials containing 100 units of BTA (BotoxⓇ, Allergan) are mixed with 2mL 0.9% injectable saline. The injection depth will be the intradermal layer. Injections will be performed with a 30-gauge needle and 1 mL syringe. Just before skin closure, the entire scar was treated, with sides randomized to receive treatment with either BTA or 0.9% normal saline. The dosage is 8 units / cm based on aforementioned studies. The maximal dose won't exceed 100 units.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Botulinum Toxin type A injection side</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% Sodium Chloride Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>After the whole surgical procedures of keloid revision are done, the participants will receive 0.9% saline injection. The investigators split the scar into the right side and the left side. BTA and 0.9% saline, respectively, are used for the two arms of the study. Only 0.9% saline is injected on the control side. The injection depth will be the intradermal layer. Injections will be performed with a 30-gauge needle and 1 mL syringe. Just before skin closure, the entire scar was injected, with sides randomized to receive treatment with either BTA or 0.9% normal saline. The dosage is 0.16 mL / cm.</description>
    <arm_group_label>0.9% saline injection side</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (20 years or older)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive keloid lesion that is bilaterally symmetric, mandibular area, anterior&#xD;
             chest or suprapubic area, for example&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 4 cm in length&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Repeated or uncontrolled recurrence, and unendurable symptoms with poor response to&#xD;
             conservative modalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Valid written informed consent provided for surgery and trial inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to botulinum toxin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous botulinum toxin injection at the lesion within 6 months before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myasthenia gravis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Focal infection signs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding woman&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yuan-Yu Hsueh, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cheng-Kung University and Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yuan-Yu Hsueh, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>886-6-2353535</phone>
    <phone_ext>4275</phone_ext>
    <email>yyhsueh@mail.ncku.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cheng Kung University Hospital, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tainan</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yuan-Yu Hsueh, MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>886-6-2353535</phone>
      <phone_ext>4275</phone_ext>
      <email>yyhsueh@mail.ncku.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Keloid</keyword>
  <keyword>Botulinum Toxin type A</keyword>
  <keyword>Radiotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Keloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

