<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05076279</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B-2107-696-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05076279</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Single or Reduced Ports Laparoscopic Gastrectomy for Advanced Gastric Cancer (SPACE-01)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety and Efficacy of Single or Reduced Ports Laparoscopic Gastrectomy for Advanced Gastric Cancer (SPACE-01) Phase II Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seoul National University Bundang Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seoul National University Bundang Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to verify the safety and efficacy of single or reduced ports&#xD;
      laparoscopic gastrectomy for advanced gastric cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Since two cases of single-incision laparoscopic gastrectomy in early gastric cancer were&#xD;
      reported in 2011, the safety and efficacy of single-incision laparoscopic gastrectomy in&#xD;
      early gastric cancer have been reported several times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, the feasibility of laparoscopic single-incision gastrectomy in some advanced&#xD;
      gastric cancer has already been reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total number of retrieved lymph nodes during gastric cancer surgery is one of the most&#xD;
      important indicators for securing oncological safety and predicting the therapeutic effect in&#xD;
      gastric cancer surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, in order to prospectively evaluate the efficacy of single-incision or reduced-port&#xD;
      laparoscopic gastrectomy for advanced gastric cancer as an oncological operation, the purpose&#xD;
      of this study is to evaluate the number of resected lymph nodes after D2 lymph node&#xD;
      dissection in single-incision or reduced-port laparoscopic gastrectomy for advanced gastric&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All surgeries are performed as single-incision laparoscopic surgery using a 3-4 cm umbilical&#xD;
      incision, and D2 lymph node dissection is performed according to the Japanese gastric cancer&#xD;
      treatment guidelines 2018 by the Japanese Gastric Cancer Association.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When an additional trocar is required, it is classified as reduced port laparoscopy when one&#xD;
      additional trocar is added.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For surgical assistance, including effective visual field development during surgery, a self&#xD;
      intra-corporeal retractor (FJ clip®, or Internal organ retractor®) or an additional trocar&#xD;
      (up to 1 trocar) could be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An articulating laparoscopic surgical instrument (Artisential ®) can be used for safe access&#xD;
      to difficult areas of the D2 lymph node dissection, such as the superior border of the&#xD;
      pancreas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the end of the surgery, the surgeon evaluates the completeness of D2 lymph node&#xD;
      dissection and radical resection of the primary tumor(R0 resection). If insufficient, the&#xD;
      operation is converted to multi-port laparoscopic surgery or open surgery, and additional D2&#xD;
      lymph node dissection and tumor resection are performed, and those cases are recorded&#xD;
      separately in the registry as multiport/open conversion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of retrieved lymph nodes</measure>
    <time_frame>during operation</time_frame>
    <description>number of retrieved lymph nodes during operation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>3 year</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative complications are problems that can happen after participants have had surgery but which were not intended.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life of the participants</measure>
    <time_frame>before surgery (within 1 month before the day of surgery), within 1 week after surgery, within 1 month after surgery, within 3 months after surgery, within 6 months after surgery, and within 12 months after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The patient's quality of life is assessed using the widely used quality of life questionnaire (European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-C30), sto22) before surgery (within 1 month before the day of surgery), within 1 week after surgery, within 1 month after surgery, within 3 months after surgery, within 6 months after surgery, and within 12 months after surgery, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3 year relapse-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 year</time_frame>
    <description>3 year relapse-free survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Gastric Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastric Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single port or reduced ports</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single port or reduced ports laparoscopic distal gastrectomy and D2 lymph node dissection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Single port or reduced ports laparoscopic distal gastrectomy and D2 lymph node dissection</intervention_name>
    <description>Single port or reduced ports laparoscopic distal gastrectomy and D2 lymph node dissection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single port or reduced ports</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have confirmed that participants have advanced gastric cancer at clinical&#xD;
             stage T2 or higher and who can undergo distal gastrectomy for primary gastric cancer&#xD;
             who have consented to single-port and reduced-port laparoscopic gastric cancer surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with locally advanced gastric cancer in which no enlarged lymph&#xD;
             nodes were observed in the preoperative examination, or lymph node metastases confined&#xD;
             to the left gastric artery or perigastric area were suspected.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have not been treated for systemic inflammatory disease before surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have previously had gastrectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have a laparotomy except for appendectomy, cholecystectomy or cesarean&#xD;
             section.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinical (preoperative or intraoperative) stage T4b accompanied by&#xD;
             infiltration of surrounding organs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with bulky lymph nodes (single nodules over 3 cm or multiple nodules over 1.5&#xD;
             cm)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with confirmed distant metastasis (M1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe liver cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who is judged by the investigator to be inappropriate for this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are taking antithrombotic drugs, including antiplatelet drugs and&#xD;
             anticoagulants, and cannot safely stop before surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>YunSuhk Suh, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ysksuh@gmail.com</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eunju Lee, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>820317876352</phone>
    <email>lunajew@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee JH, Lee MS, Kim HH, Park DJ, Lee HJ, Yang HK, Park KU. Comparison of single-incision laparoscopic distal gastrectomy and laparoscopic distal gastrectomy for gastric cancer in a porcine model. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A. 2011 Dec;21(10):935-40. doi: 10.1089/lap.2011.0280. Epub 2011 Nov 1.</citation>
    <PMID>22044252</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Omori T, Fujiwara Y, Moon J, Sugimura K, Miyata H, Masuzawa T, Kishi K, Miyoshi N, Tomokuni A, Akita H, Takahashi H, Kobayashi S, Yasui M, Ohue M, Yano M, Sakon M. Comparison of Single-Incision and Conventional Multi-Port Laparoscopic Distal Gastrectomy with D2 Lymph Node Dissection for Gastric Cancer: A Propensity Score-Matched Analysis. Ann Surg Oncol. 2016 Dec;23(Suppl 5):817-824. Epub 2016 Aug 10.</citation>
    <PMID>27510844</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Omori T, Fujiwara Y, Yamamoto K, Yanagimoto Y, Sugimura K, Masuzawa T, Kishi K, Takahashi H, Yasui M, Miyata H, Ohue M, Yano M, Sakon M. The Safety and Feasibility of Single-Port Laparoscopic Gastrectomy for Advanced Gastric Cancer. J Gastrointest Surg. 2019 Jul;23(7):1329-1339. doi: 10.1007/s11605-018-3937-0. Epub 2018 Sep 5.</citation>
    <PMID>30187335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Seoul National University Bundang Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yun-Suhk Suh</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gastric cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastric adenocarcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastrectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Single port</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

