<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05077813</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>How to kill Tuberculosis</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05077813</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Utilizing the Crosstalk Among Chicoric Acid, 13-Cis Retinoic Acid(Aerosolized), Minocycline and Vitamin D as a Potent Quadrate Therapy for Treating Patients With Multidrug-resistant TB and Patient With Both Multidrug-resistant TB and COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Utilizing the Crosstalk Among Chicoric Acid, 13-Cis Retinoic Acid(Aerosolized), Minocycline and Vitamin D as a Potent Quadrate Therapy for Treating Patients With Multidrug-resistant TB and Patient With Both Multidrug-resistant TB and COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kafrelsheikh University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Health, Saudi Arabia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kafrelsheikh University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Utilizing the Crosstalk Among Chicoric Acid, 13-Cis Retinoic Acid(Aerosolized), Minocycline&#xD;
      and Vitamin D as a Potent Quadrate Therapy for treating patients with Multidrug-resistant TB&#xD;
      and patient with both Multidrug-resistant TB and COVID-19 . A double-edged sword Clinical&#xD;
      Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      I)Part of Tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tuberculosis (TB) is a major infectious disease killer globally. It affected 10 million and&#xD;
      killed 1.4 million people in 2019 alone. The predicted impact of the COVID-19 pandemic is an&#xD;
      additional 190,000 TB deaths in 2020, and it is expected in the next 5 y that there will be&#xD;
      up to a 20% increase in the global TB disease burden , stressing the critical need for new&#xD;
      safe and effective drugs against Mycobacterium tuberculosis (Mtb). In addition, controlling&#xD;
      multidrug-resistant TB (MDR-TB) presents a huge public health challenge . New drug discovery&#xD;
      could require several years with no guarantee but repurposing established may be useful to&#xD;
      treat patients with tuberculosis . Here we demonstrate that we could utilize the crosstalk&#xD;
      among Chicoric Acid, 13-Cis Retinoic Acid, Minocycline , and vitamin D as a novel quadrate&#xD;
      therapy against TB.Drug-resistant tuberculosis represents a global emergency, requiring new&#xD;
      drugs. Recently Minocycline was found to be highly potent in laboratory strains of&#xD;
      Mycobacterium TB, and 30 drug-sensitive and multidrug/extensively drug-resistant clinical&#xD;
      strains were susceptible to clinically attainable dosages. The lung concentration-time&#xD;
      profiles of a 7 mg/kg/day human-equivalent minocycline dosage yielded bacterial kill rates&#xD;
      comparable to first-line antituberculosis drugs. Extracellular bacilli were destroyed&#xD;
      directly by minocycline. Minocycline also killed intracellular bacilli indirectly through&#xD;
      granzyme A-driven apoptosis. Furthermore, minocycline showed dose-dependent antiinflammatory&#xD;
      effect, suggesting that it may protect tuberculosis patients against immunopathology. A study&#xD;
      showed that M. tuberculosis induced the expression of indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO), an&#xD;
      enzyme involved in tryptophan catabolism, in macrophages and in the lungs of animals (mice&#xD;
      and macaque) with active disease. In a macaque model of inhalation TB, suppression of IDO&#xD;
      activity reduced bacterial burden, pathology, and clinical signs of TB disease, leading to&#xD;
      increased host survival. This increased protection was accompanied by increased lung T cell&#xD;
      proliferation, induction of inducible bronchus-associated lymphoid tissue and correlates of&#xD;
      bacterial killing . A recent study showed that Minocycline-induced significantly inhibition&#xD;
      of IDO expression. But Minocycline-induced inhibition of IDO expression is&#xD;
      retinoid-dependent. The combined treatment with minocycline and retinol, however, resulted in&#xD;
      a striking, statistically significant decrease in IDO. Co-treatment with minocycline and&#xD;
      retinol again resulted in decreased TNF-α and IL-6 levels. A study showed that IL-6 inhibits&#xD;
      IFN-γ induced autophagy in Mycobacterium (TB) H37Rv infected macrophages. As well as&#xD;
      neutralization of endogenous IL-6 by anti-IL-6 antibody significantly enhances the IFN-γ&#xD;
      mediated killing of the intracellular bacteria. Minocycline's anti-inflammatory effects are&#xD;
      mediated through RAR signaling. Therefore, The combined treatment with minocycline and&#xD;
      retinol is expected to effectively inhibit (TB) and its inflammatory complication,&#xD;
      Fortunately, Retinoic Acid significantly inhibits the in vivo growth of M. tuberculosis and&#xD;
      the development of tuberculosis. In addition to, 13-Cis RA and Chicoric Acid ( CA ) enhanced&#xD;
      the cell surface expression of HLA-DR and CD14 molecules on U937 macrophages and prevented&#xD;
      the growth of Mtb within macrophages. Moreover, 13-cis RA and CA, have increased NO&#xD;
      generation compared to untreated control macrophages, significantly . Both drugs have a&#xD;
      significant inhibitory effect on Mtb growth but CA at the highest concentration was more&#xD;
      potent than 13-cis RA . Therefore we will use retinoic acid to induce the effect of&#xD;
      Minocycline as well as its ability to inhibit tuberculosis in combination with CA .Recent&#xD;
      data showed that Vitamin D support innate immune responses to Mycobacterium TB and Low&#xD;
      vitamin D levels were associated with a 5-fold increased risk for progression to&#xD;
      tuberculosis. Deficiency of vitamin D has long been implicated in activation of (TB) . Serum&#xD;
      vitamin D in TB patients are lower than in healthy controls . Vitamin D has been found to&#xD;
      speed up the clearance of (TB) bacteria from the lungs of people with multi-drug resistant&#xD;
      TB, according to a study of 1,850 patients. It was showed that Vitamin D receptor (VDR) must&#xD;
      form a heterodimer complex with retinoid X receptor (RXR) to regulate gene transcription.&#xD;
      Retinol plays a crucial role in lung development and signaling the vitamin D pathway.&#xD;
      9-cis-retinoic acid, an active vitamin A metabolite and the ligand of RXR, assists VDR&#xD;
      signaling and suppresses the degradation of circulating vitamin D.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This double blinded, randomized, placebo controlled trial on the clinical efficacy and&#xD;
      antimicrobial mechanisms of quadrate therapy(Chicoric Acid, 13-Cis Retinoic&#xD;
      Acid(Aerosolized), Minocycline and Vitamin D) as a Potent Quadrate Therapy Against&#xD;
      Tuberculosis. 200 men and women will be enrolled , who are age 18 to 65 years inclusive, have&#xD;
      at least two positive sputum smears for tuberculosis (TB), and have given informed consent to&#xD;
      participate in the study. All of the enrollees will have active TB . The effect of the&#xD;
      quadrate therapy status will be examined in the context of a randomized trial conducted in&#xD;
      Egyptian or Saudi Arabian Subjects will be randomized to receive either the quadrate therapy&#xD;
      or placebo from the start of their TB therapy, through the 1 months of anti-TB therapy, and&#xD;
      until the last recruited patient reaches 6 months of follow up. Thus, the first subject is&#xD;
      likely to be followed for 12 months, assuming the duration of recruitment is 12 months. The&#xD;
      endpoints of interest include bacteriologic cure, immune response parameters, and clinical&#xD;
      outcomes. The researchers will also examine the utility of these immune response parameters&#xD;
      as surrogate markers for treatment efficacy in TB, irrespective of the quadrate therapy and&#xD;
      other risk factors. The study will be carried out as a collaborative effort between. Kafr&#xD;
      elshiekh university ,Faculty of Medicine, Egypt and First health cluster ,Ministry of health&#xD;
      ,Saudia Arabia. Subjects will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg&#xD;
      gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg&#xD;
      to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid or All trans retinoic acid&#xD;
      or 9 cis retinoic acid gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day&#xD;
      as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea&#xD;
      Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid .Chicoric acid (also known as cichoric&#xD;
      acid and dicaffeoyltar- taric acid) is the main phenolic compound found in Echinacea&#xD;
      purpurea. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275&#xD;
      mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried&#xD;
      extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets Caffeic acid&#xD;
      derivative levels are typically as follows: caftaric acid = 0.5 to 2.0 mg/tablet; cichoric&#xD;
      acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet; chlorogenic acid = &lt; 0.5 mg/tablet; dicaffeoyl quinic acids&#xD;
      (including cynarin) = 0.7 to 2.0 mg/tablet; echinacoside = 1.0 to 1.7 mg/tablet. Furthermore,&#xD;
      the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units&#xD;
      of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4 (b) placebo. The primary objectives&#xD;
      are to: (1) determine the efficacy of the quadrate therapy on sputum and culture negativity&#xD;
      at one month and two months; (2) determine the efficacy of micronutrient supplements on&#xD;
      survival between two arms at 8 and 24 months; and (3) determine the efficacy of micronutrient&#xD;
      supplements on TB relapse and reinfection. Secondary study objectives are to: (1) compare the&#xD;
      treatment arms with respect to absolute change in CD4 counts from 0 to 1, 6, 12 months; (2)&#xD;
      compare the treatment arms with respect to weight change from baseline and1 months, 6 months,&#xD;
      and 12 months; (3) compare the treatment arms with respect to immunological parameters,&#xD;
      namely ex vivo lymphocyte proliferation; and cytokine production, namely IL-2, IL-6, INF-g&#xD;
      INF-Alpha, IL-12, and TNF-a, and Interferon alpha at 1, 6, 12 months; and (4) correlate the&#xD;
      above mentioned immunological markers with smear conversion rates at 1 month, 2 months, cure,&#xD;
      relapse, and death. Finally, we suggest that this combination therapy will effectively&#xD;
      inhibit tuberculosis infection and achieve treatment with significant effect against (TB)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first negative SARS-CoV-2 PCR in NP swap and Mycobacterium tuberculosis sputum culture</measure>
    <time_frame>within 4 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sputum culture result (positive or negative)&amp; COVID-19 PCR (positive or negative)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks after therapy start date</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum levels of CRP and ESR</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute lymphocyte counts (CD4,CD8 and CD25+FOXP3+ Regulatory T)</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of cytokine (IFN-gamma and alpha , IL-6, IL-10, TNF-alpha, TGF-beta) levels produced in response to M. tb.</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vitamin D status</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
    <description>Serum 25(OH)D concentrations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinoic acid status</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
    <description>Serum Retinoic acid concentrations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minocycline status</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
    <description>Serum Minocycline concentrations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO) enzyme status</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
    <description>Serum indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO) enzyme concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chicoric Acid status</measure>
    <time_frame>one month</time_frame>
    <description>Serum Chicoric Acid concentrations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 Subjects will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>9 cis retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 Subjects will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 9 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 Subjects will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 Subjects with confection of COVID-19 and multidrug-resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 Subjects with confection of COVID-19 and multidrug-resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The standard therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The standard therapy 100 infected patients with confection of COVID-19 and MDR-TB will receive the standard therapy for tuberculosis for 30 days 50- 50-</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</intervention_name>
    <description>A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>9 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</intervention_name>
    <description>A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 9 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>9 cis retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>All trans retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</intervention_name>
    <description>Active Comparator: All trans retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D 50 Subjects will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid , Minocycline,Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D for (MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>All trans retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</intervention_name>
    <description>50 Subjects with confection of COVID-19 and multidrug-resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</intervention_name>
    <description>50 Subjects with confection of COVID-19 and multidrug-resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB) will be randomly assigned to receive A) Minocycline i.v. 4,5 mg/kg gradual in 2 divided doses increases from 4,5 mg/kg from the first week to 7.5 and 10 mg/kg to the last week. In addition to Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual 2 divided doses increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled retinoic acid therapy for 30 days. Moreover, the patients will receive Echinacea Purpurea Extract Capsules Polyphenols Chicoric Acid. Echinacea phytochemical profile Each tablet is comprised of the equivalent of 1275 mg of echinacea root, as follows: A) Echinacea purpurea - 675 mg root yields 112.5 mg dried extract, standardized to contain 2.1mg alkamides. Each batch of tablets contain choric acid = 3.4 to 8.5 mg/tablet. Furthermore, the patients will receive Cholecalciferol(Vitamin D) Intramuscular injection of 600,000 units of Cholecalciferol for 2 doses given at week 0 and week 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid, Minocycline, Chicroic Acid and Vitamin D For (COVID-19 and MDR-TB)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The standard therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>The standard therapy 100 infected patients with confection of COVID-19 and MDR-TB will receive the standard therapy for tuberculosis for 30 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>The standard therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age above 18 up to 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Microbiologically or histologically confirmed active tuberculosis as well as confirmed&#xD;
             positive with COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically confirmed latent tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug resistant MTb&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test for 18-40 year-old females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to sign consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known intolerance of vitamin D&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sarcoidosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hyperparathyroidism or nephrolithiasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking vitamin D or A supplementation in the two months preceding enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline serum corrected calcium &gt;2.65 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current haemodialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children, pregnant or breastfeeding individuals&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant benzothiadiazine derivative, cardiac glycoside, carbamazepine,&#xD;
             phenobarbital, phenytoin, primidone or long-term immunosuppressant therap&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extra-pulmonary or smear negative tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving steroids, cytotoxic drugs, post transplant or metastatic&#xD;
             malignancy, or not expected to survive for the duration of ATT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active diarrhoea, indicating possible fat-soluble vitamin malabsorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline Hypercalcemia &gt;10.5 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent use of cyclosporin, cisplatin, amfotericin B, cephalosporins, polymyxins&#xD;
             and vancomycin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of adverse events on previous Minocycline or other tetracycline use (by&#xD;
             spontaneous reporting nor by active questioning).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Depressive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index less than 18 points or higher than 25 points&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications for hormonal contraception or intrauterine device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune diseases A history of organ, bone marrow or hematopoietic stem cell&#xD;
             transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving anti-hcv treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent blindness in one eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of iritis, endophthalmitis, scleral inflammation or retinitis 15-90 days of&#xD;
             retinal detachment or eye surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Mahmoud R Elkazzaz, M.Sc of Biochemistry</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Science , Damietta University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amr K Ahmed</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ministry of Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dr Mahmoud R Elkazzaz, M.Sc of Biochemistry</last_name>
    <phone>00201090302015</phone>
    <email>mahmoudramadan2051@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Amr K Ahmed</last_name>
    <phone>00966597310032</phone>
    <email>drmedahmed@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kafr El-sheikh University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <state>Kafr El-sheikh</state>
        <zip>33561</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ministry of health. First health cluster</name>
      <address>
        <city>Riyadh</city>
        <state>Riaydh</state>
        <zip>12221</zip>
        <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
    <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kafrelsheikh University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Ramadan mohamed Elkazzaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Multidrug-Resistant</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Minocycline</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alitretinoin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

