<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05079204</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PO20159*</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05079204</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intraoral Scanners as a Motivation Method for Oral Hygiene Instruction</brief_title>
  <acronym>Perio3D</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Intraoral Scanners as a Motivation Method for Oral Hygiene Instruction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CHU de Reims</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CHU de Reims</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Periodontal diseases are highly prevalent inflammatory diseases. These diseases are mostly&#xD;
      due to the development and the maturation of bacterial plaque which lead to local&#xD;
      inflammation. Individuals can develop severe attachment loss which could lead to dental loss.&#xD;
      To prevent them, individual plaque removal procedures self-performed by the patient by tooth&#xD;
      brushing or interdental brushes or made by professional care (scaling), are known to improve&#xD;
      periodontal health, and thus to prevent periodontal diseases. Moreover, oral hygiene is a&#xD;
      major factor to increase increasing the outcomes when treatments are needed. However,&#xD;
      patients' compliance in oral health program is one of the major limits to periodontal&#xD;
      therapeutics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the investigators evaluate the effectiveness of 3D intra-oral camera compared&#xD;
      with conventional oral hygiene instructions, to improve oral health motivation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The present study explores the effectiveness of intraoral scanners in the field of oral&#xD;
      hygiene motivation and instruction to improve the patient's motivation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients presenting periodontitis or gingivitis are recruited and randomized in 2 groups:&#xD;
      conventional motivation procedures and conventional motivation procedures supported with 3D&#xD;
      representations of their mouth obtained by intraoral scanners. Periodontal diseases&#xD;
      (periodontitis and gingivitis) will be diagnosed according to the international&#xD;
      classification of periodontal diseases, based on the decision-making algorithms. A&#xD;
      periodontal charting, socio-demographic data and clinical data will be collected. Then, oral&#xD;
      mucosa dermatological manifestations, treatment needs (ICDAS) and quality of life related to&#xD;
      oral health (GOHAI) will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After inclusion, patients will be randomized between conventional motivation procedures and&#xD;
      conventional motivation procedures associated with 3D intra oral procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesized that the 3D intra oral representations could improve oral&#xD;
      hygiene in patients compared with those receiving only a classical motivation procedure. The&#xD;
      primary objective is to evaluate if patients instructed to oral hygiene procedures using a&#xD;
      representation of their mouth obtained by the use of a intraoral scanner present fewer plaque&#xD;
      than the ones instructed without it. This could be achieved by the analysis of plaque control&#xD;
      record index in both group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the evolution of the bleeding on probing clinical index between the two&#xD;
           groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the evolution of mean periodontal pocket depths, mean recessions and mean&#xD;
           clinical attachment level between the two groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the quality of life related to oral health between the two groups&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the time needed to add intraoral scans in the procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the relevance of the received information.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>The investigator which perform the periodontal examination will be blinded of the motivation procedure</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plaque Control Record Evolution</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Recording the presence of plaque on individual tooth surfaces (mesial, distal, facial, lingual). The plaque is highlighted by a periodontal probe.&#xD;
PCR is calculated according the following formula :&#xD;
PCR = (Number of faces with plaque / Total number of faces) x 100</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Gingivitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional motivation procedure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Conventional motivation procedures defined as a presentation of the modified Bass technique on a dental teaching macro model plus intra oral instruction provided in patient's mouth with a hand mirror.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional motivation procedure supported by 3D representations</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Conventional motivation procedures associated with 3D intra oral procedures. A 3D intra-oral modelization will added to the previously described procedure. Then, a periodontist will show the sites contaminated by dental plaque to the patient.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intra oral scan</intervention_name>
    <description>Cover key details of the intervention. Must be sufficiently detailed to distinguish between arms of a study and/or among similar interventions Intervention consists in an 3D intra oral representation of the oral cavity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional motivation procedure supported by 3D representations</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Conventional motivation procedures supported by 3D representations</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional motivation procedure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  consulting the Dental Care Service of the university hospital of Reims&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presenting gingivitis or periodontal diseases according to the international&#xD;
             classification of periodontal diseases (Chicago, 2017)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presenting at least 10 pairs of opposing teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to perform oral hygiene procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  speaking French&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who signed the informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  affiliated to the French Social Security system&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-inclusion criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients presenting :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a medical history likely to compromise protocol (psychiatric disorders, medical or&#xD;
             pharmacological antecedents altering or modifying immune response in last 3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eating disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  orthodontic treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients under legal protection, trusteeship or guardianship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to understand auto-questionary&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients presenting :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presenting exacerbations signs of periodontal diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  benefiting a professional plaque removal procedure outside of the experimental&#xD;
             procedure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julien BRAUX</last_name>
    <phone>326787878</phone>
    <phone_ext>0033</phone_ext>
    <email>jbraux@chu-reims.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chu Reims</name>
      <address>
        <city>Reims</city>
        <zip>51092</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Damien JOLLY</last_name>
      <phone>326788472</phone>
      <phone_ext>33</phone_ext>
      <email>djolly@chu-reims.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gingivitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

