<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05075369</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B2021 060</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>Karla Zuniga</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05075369</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Water Drinking Test Study and Disc Hemorrhages in Normal Tension Glaucoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Correlation Between Water Drinking Test Study and Disc Hemorrhages in Normal Tension Glaucoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Manitoba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Manitoba</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Disc hemorrhages are a known risk factor for progression of glaucoma. A positive water&#xD;
      drinking test is also associated with progression of primary open glaucoma. The purpose of&#xD;
      this study is to determine if patients with normal tension glaucoma and disc hemorrhages have&#xD;
      a positive water drinking test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with normal tension glaucoma and a disc hemorrhage will be recruited to undergo a&#xD;
      water drinking test prior to any change in their treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patient with normal tension glaucoma under the care of a fellowship trained glaucoma&#xD;
      specialist and noted to have a disc hemorrhage in one or both eyes when examined in the&#xD;
      office will be recruited to undergo a water drinking test (WDT). After an informed consent is&#xD;
      obtained, arrangements will be made to undergo the WDT either at the ophthalmologist's office&#xD;
      or the local hospital clinic(Misericordia). The test will be administered in the following&#xD;
      way:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon arrival the patients baseline intraocular pressure (IOP) will be measured, then shortly&#xD;
      afterwards the patient will drink 800 ml of water in a period of 5 minutes. Immediately after&#xD;
      the water ingestion has finished a second IOP will be measured, followed by IOP measurements&#xD;
      every 15 minutes for 60 minutes with a Goldman applanation tonometer by the same examiner.&#xD;
      All of these measurements will be collected in a data sheet for the WTD. A total of 60&#xD;
      minutes would be the duration of the activity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>patients with a diagnosis of normal tension glaucoma and noted to have a disc hemorrhage</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline intraocular pressure(IOP) with water drinking test</measure>
    <time_frame>The water drinking test takes 60 minutes, and the participant is then finished and can leave.</time_frame>
    <description>The change in intraocular pressure in patients with normal tension glaucoma and a disc hemorrhage after undergoing the water drinking test will be measured with Goldmann applanation tonometry. A change from baseline IOP of 5 mm Hg is considered abnormal .</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Normal Tension Glaucoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>baseline Intraocular pressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants will have their intraocular pressure measured with Goldmann Application Tonometry immediately prior to beginning the water drinking test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Change in Intraocular pressure with Water drinking test</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants will undergo the water drinking test as previously described, i.e. after drinking 800 mls of water over a 5 minute period, the intraocular pressure will be measured immediately after completion of ingestion, followed by intraocular pressure measurements every 15 minutes for 60 minutes, using etc Goldmann apllantion tonometer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>water drinking test</intervention_name>
    <description>Water drinking test-glaucoma diagnostic test - marker for outflow facility reserve to detect IOP instability when the body ingests 800 ml of water within a 5 minute period of time</description>
    <arm_group_label>Change in Intraocular pressure with Water drinking test</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of normal tension glaucoma by a fellowship trained glaucoma&#xD;
             specialist,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of a disc hemorrhage diagnosed by a fellowship trained glaucoma&#xD;
             specialist,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to swallow water&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to be positioned to allow accurate measurement of the Intraocular&#xD;
             pressure with a slit lamp mounted Goldmann applanation tonometer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a smooth corneal surface to allow for accurate Goldmann application&#xD;
             tonometry measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A sufficient level of education to understand study procedures and be able to&#xD;
             communicate with site personnel&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of refractive surgery,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active ocular infection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac or renal diseases, history of urinary retention,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corneal abnormalities preventing reliable IOP measurements,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous trabeculectomy or glaucoma shunt surgery,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous laser iridotomy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment or language barrier preventing ability to provide an informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisa Gould, MD FRCS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manitoba</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisa Gould, MD, FRCS</last_name>
    <phone>204-957-3252</phone>
    <email>lisa.gould@umanitoba.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Karla Zuniga, MD</last_name>
    <phone>204-583-2762</phone>
    <email>kzunigak@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Susanna R Jr, Vessani RM, Sakata L, Zacarias LC, Hatanaka M. The relation between intraocular pressure peak in the water drinking test and visual field progression in glaucoma. Br J Ophthalmol. 2005 Oct;89(10):1298-301.</citation>
    <PMID>16170120</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Susanna R Jr, Clement C, Goldberg I, Hatanaka M. Applications of the water drinking test in glaucoma management. Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2017 Aug;45(6):625-631. doi: 10.1111/ceo.12925. Epub 2017 Mar 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28164419</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ishida K, Yamamoto T, Sugiyama K, Kitazawa Y. Disk hemorrhage is a significantly negative prognostic factor in normal-tension glaucoma. Am J Ophthalmol. 2000 Jun;129(6):707-14.</citation>
    <PMID>10926977</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Manitoba</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lisa Gould</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lisa Gould Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>normal tension glaucoma</keyword>
  <keyword>disc hemorrhages</keyword>
  <keyword>water drinking test</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Tension Glaucoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the paper or poster , after deidentification (text, tables, figures, and appendices) will be available</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Immediately upon publication and for 36 months afterwards</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

