<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03754140</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HREC/18/RPAH 621</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03754140</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intralesional Sclerosant for in Transit and Cutaneous Melanoma Metastases</brief_title>
  <acronym>INTRANS</acronym>
  <official_title>Intralesional Sclerosant for in Transit and Cutaneous Melanoma Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Melanoma Institute Australia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Melanoma Institute Australia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is currently an urgent need for low cost and well tolerated intralesional agents for&#xD;
      the management of in transit and cutaneous melanoma metastases that are unsuitable for, or&#xD;
      resistant to, other therapies. This pilot study will determine whether intralesional&#xD;
      injections of the sclerosant polidocanol into intransit and cutaneous melanoma lesions shows&#xD;
      promise for efficacy, safety and ease of use that will enable this inexpensive and widely&#xD;
      available agent to undergo further evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Many patients with metastatic melanoma have in transit and other cutaneous metastases.&#xD;
      Untreated, these lesions become eroded, haemorrhagic and symptomatic. When systemic therapy&#xD;
      is not warranted, has failed or is not tolerated for in transit disease, and when surgery is&#xD;
      not feasible or appropriate, other local treatments are needed. Current options include&#xD;
      isolated limb infusion for bulky limb disease, topical immunotherapy with contact sensitisers&#xD;
      and imiqiuimod for superficial, nonbulky disease or radiation therapy. Intralesional (IL)&#xD;
      agents such as Rose Bengal (PV-10, Provectus) and Talimogene laherparepvec (T-Vec, Amgen)&#xD;
      have been used for patients with limited numbers of cutaneous metastases with reported&#xD;
      overall response rates of 51% and 26% respectively. It is thought that these IL agents can&#xD;
      incite regional or even systemic anti-tumour immune responses, thus providing benefit beyond&#xD;
      the individual injected lesions. Use of PV-10, which is not an intrinsic immune modulator,&#xD;
      was associated with regression of untreated bystander lesions in 27% of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      T-Vec is not currently available as a subsidised product in Australia and PV-10 is not&#xD;
      currently accessible outside of dual-agent systemic/IL clinical trials. Intralesional&#xD;
      injection of the antimetabolites 5-fluorouracil and methotrexate has been used successfully&#xD;
      for the treatment of cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, but the efficacy of these agents in&#xD;
      melanoma is unknown. Importantly, the investigator's in transit melanoma patients usually&#xD;
      have multiple, often very numerous lesions, making IL injection with adequate volumes of&#xD;
      antimetabolites difficult without significant risk of systemic haematologic, hepatic and&#xD;
      renal side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hence there is currently an urgent need for tolerable, low cost and accessible intralesional&#xD;
      therapies for in transit and cutaneous melanoma metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of intralesional therapy with the&#xD;
      sclerosant polidocanol for treatment of in transit and cutaneously metastatic melanoma&#xD;
      unsuitable for other therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravascularly injected sclerosants have a long history of safe and effective use in the&#xD;
      treatment of varicose veins. Sclerosants have also been used intralesionally for the&#xD;
      treatment of cutaneous lesions such as squamous cell carcinoma, pyogenic granulomas, Kaposi&#xD;
      sarcoma and angiomas. They are inexpensive, readily accessible and can be easily administered&#xD;
      in the clinic to multiple metastases. By inciting cell death within melanoma metastases in&#xD;
      the skin, they may also incite anti-tumour immune responses in untreated bystander lesions,&#xD;
      as is observed with IL PV-10 therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open label, single arm pilot study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical efficacy of interlesional polidocanol injection assessed by the size of in transit melanoma metastases after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with a complete response (complete disappearance of treated lesions), partial response (a 25% or more reduction in size of treated lesions), stable disease (a 0 to 24% reduction in size of treated lesions) or disease progression (any increase in size of treated lesions)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment related adverse events using the CTCAE version 4 terms and grading.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bystander treatment effect on untreated intransit melanoma metastases</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with a complete response (complete disappearance of untreated lesions), partial response (a 25% or more reduction in size of untreated lesions), stable disease (a 0 to 24% reduction in size of untreated lesions) or disease progression (any increase in size of untreated lesions)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bystander treatment effect on the proportion of tumour infiltrating immune markers in treated and untreated melanoma lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion (%) of tumour-infiltrating immune markers: CD4, CD8 and FoxP3 T cell markers, CD20 (B cell), CD16 and CD56 Natural Killer (NK) cell markers, Ki67 marker of proliferation, CD31 (endothelial cells) and CD68 and CD163 (macrophages) detected at baseline and 1 week after intralesional injection by immunohistochemistry. The same analysis will be undertaken in a minimuim of one untreated lesion detected at baseline and at anytime between 1 and 8 weeks. Change in the proportion (%) of immune markers will be ,made within each lesion and between each lesion.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bystander treatment effect on tumour viabilty in treated and untreated melanoma lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of residual non-necrotic melanoma cells detected histolologcally in treated and untreated lesions one week after intralesional injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>In-Transit Metastasis of Cutaneous Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Polidocanol Injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Polidocanol (3%) 0.1ml intralesional injection per 10mm diameter lesion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Polidocanol Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Sclerotic agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Polidocanol Injection</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Aethoxysklerol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed in transit and/or cutaneous melanoma metastases unsuitable&#xD;
             for, or with progressive disease despite systemic, surgical, intra-arterial, topical&#xD;
             or radiation therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A minimum of 2 accessible lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periocular lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe renal impairment defined as an estimated glomerular filtration rate&#xD;
             &lt;20ml/min/1.73sqm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sever liver function abnormality defined as aspartate aminotransferase and / or&#xD;
             alanine aminotransferase &gt; 3 x upper limit of normal and / or bilirubin &gt; 1.5 x upper&#xD;
             limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known hypersensitivity to polidocanol or its exipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unavailble for the full study duration (of a 4 week screening period and 8&#xD;
             week treatment period) because of general frailty, geographical or social reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding female patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving topical or radiation therapy to the in transit and / or cutaneous&#xD;
             lesions within 4 weeks of planned start of study treatment (patients receiving current&#xD;
             systemic immunotherapy which is deemed appropriate to continue, despite progression of&#xD;
             disease in the skin, in order to reduce the likelihood of visceral metastases are&#xD;
             eligible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving sclerosants for other indications within 4 weeks of planned start&#xD;
             of study treatment or during study treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Diona Damian</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, Australia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Diona Damian</last_name>
    <phone>+612 9515 8331</phone>
    <email>diona.damian@health.nsw.gov.au</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Prince Alfred Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Camperdown</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2050</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diona Damian, MBBS</last_name>
      <phone>+612 9515 8295</phone>
      <email>Diona.Damian@health.nsw.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 22, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sclerosant</keyword>
  <keyword>Polidocanol</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Polidocanol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

