<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00218374</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NIDA-15463-1</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01-15463-1</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>DPMC</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00218374</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dextromethorphan, Gabapentin, and Oxycodone to Treat Opioid-Induced Hyperalgesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Hyperalgesia in Methadone Patients: Can it be Treated?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Individuals who reduce or stop use of opioid medications are at risk for developing&#xD;
      hyperalgesia, which is an increased sensitivity to pain. This study will compare the&#xD;
      effectiveness of dextromethorphan, gabapentin, and oxycodone at reducing hyperalgesia in&#xD;
      individuals addicted to opioids who are concurrently receiving methadone treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Opioid medications are frequently used for the treatment of moderate to severe pain; however,&#xD;
      individuals who use opioids have a high risk of becoming addicted. Opioid users who abruptly&#xD;
      stop using opioid drugs may experience withdrawal symptoms, including drug craving, sweating,&#xD;
      sleep disruption, nausea, irritability, and pain. Hyperalgesia, a severe and excessive&#xD;
      sensitivity to pain, is a serious condition that may also occur when opioid use is reduced or&#xD;
      discontinued. Opioid medications affect both the pain inhibitory and facilitatory systems,&#xD;
      meaning that while they are effective at treating pain in many individuals, they also have&#xD;
      the ability to intensify pain and cause hyperalgesia in some opioid users. Three medications,&#xD;
      dextromethorphan, gabapentin, and oxycodone, may alleviate the symptoms of hyperalgesia and&#xD;
      lessen an individual's sensitivity to pain. Further research is needed to confirm the&#xD;
      benefits of these medications for opioid addicts. The purpose of this study is to compare the&#xD;
      effectiveness of dextromethorphan, gabapentin, and oxycodone at reducing opioid-induced&#xD;
      hyperalgesia in methadone-maintained opioid addicts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will involve three separate experiments. Participants in Experiment 1 will be&#xD;
      randomly assigned to receive either dextromethorphan or placebo; in Experiment 2,&#xD;
      participants will be randomly assigned to receive either gabapentin or placebo; and in&#xD;
      Experiment 3, participants will be randomly assigned to receive either oxycodone or placebo.&#xD;
      Each experiment will last 5 weeks. All 3 experiments will begin with a screening session.&#xD;
      Potential participants will undergo a physical exam and an electrocardiogram. Blood and urine&#xD;
      will be collected for laboratory tests and drug screening. Each individual's medical and drug&#xD;
      history will be reviewed and psychological and opiate withdrawal symptoms will be assessed.&#xD;
      Individuals who complete the screening and meet all study requirements will be permitted to&#xD;
      continue in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be maintained on methadone throughout the study. Participants will also&#xD;
      receive either the study medication (dextromethorphan, gabapentin, or oxycodone) or placebo&#xD;
      four times per day beginning on Day 5. Study visits will take place once a week. At each&#xD;
      visit, medications for the previous week will be accounted for and medications for the&#xD;
      following week will be dispensed. Questionnaires and self-reports will be completed to assess&#xD;
      depression levels and drug use. Urine tests will be used to screen for the presence of drugs&#xD;
      and alcohol. During the study, participants will take part in four pain testing sessions to&#xD;
      measure pain threshold and tolerance; two sessions will take place during Week 1 and another&#xD;
      two sessions will occur during Week 5. The pain testing sessions will include a cold pressor&#xD;
      (CP) test and an electrical stimulation (ES) procedure. The CP test will involve placing an&#xD;
      arm in ice water for a short period of time; the ES procedure will involve stimulating muscle&#xD;
      nerve endings via electrodes placed on the skin. Immediately after the CP and ES sessions,&#xD;
      blood will be drawn for laboratory testing. Participants will again complete questionnaires&#xD;
      and self-reports, and urine samples will be collected. Gift cards will be offered as an&#xD;
      incentive for attending study visits and having negative drug tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain response (measured after each pain testing session on Days 1, 4, 36, and 39)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 week</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Hyperalgesia</condition>
  <condition>Opioid-Related Disorders</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gabapentin</intervention_name>
    <description>Gabapentin initiated up to a daily dose of 2400mg PO x 5 weeks</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be between the ages of 18 and 55 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets DSM-IV diagnostic criteria for opioid dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking a stable dose of methadone for 6 weeks prior to study entry and is compliant in&#xD;
             methadone maintenance treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is in good physical health or under a physician's care if a medical condition requires&#xD;
             ongoing treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known sensitivity to dextromethorphan, gabapentin, or oxycodone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently dependent on alcohol, benzodiazepine, or any drug (other than nicotine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently in an acutely psychotic, severely depressed state and in need of inpatient&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immediate suicide risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological or psychiatric illness (e.g., peripheral neuropathy, schizophrenia,&#xD;
             neuropathic pain, Raynaud's disease, or urticaria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute medical condition that would make study participation medically dangerous (e.g.,&#xD;
             acute hepatitis, unstable cardiovascular disease, liver disease, or kidney disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver enzyme values five times greater than normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently taking analgesic medication for a painful condition on a regular basis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or past history of high blood pressure, heart disease, or stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using a pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Margaret Compton, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, Los Angeles</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 16, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 22, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 12, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Margaret (Peggy) Compton</name_title>
    <organization>UCLA School of Nursing</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Opiate Addiction</keyword>
  <keyword>Opiate Dependence</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperalgesia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

