<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00215696</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GV-002.001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00215696</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Treat Patients Whose Chronic Angina Symptoms Are Not Relieved by Medication and Have an Area of the Heart That Cannot be Treated by Standard Therapies</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study Evaluating the Efficacy of BIOBYPASS® (ADGVVEGF121.10NH) Delivered by NOGA™-GUIDED/MYOSTAR™ Catheter in &quot;No Option&quot; Patients With Class II-IV Stable Angina</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GenVec</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GenVec</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to determine whether treatment with an experimental gene&#xD;
      therapy (BIOBYPASS®) will reduce angina in study participants by stimulating the growth of&#xD;
      new blood vessels. This will be measured by testing whether participants are able to exercise&#xD;
      longer without experiencing angina after treatment, as compared to before treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, this study will collect information about any side effects that might be&#xD;
      related to the treatment with the experimental therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2005</start_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in total exercise duration on exercise tolerance test (ETT, using the bicycle ergometry test protocol) at week 26.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of reversible perfusion defect size in SPECT perfusion study at week 26</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total exercise duration at weeks 12 and 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time-to-onset of 1mm ST depression on ETT at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak rate-pressure product and maximal workload (in METS) during ETT at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CCS class at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of angina attacks at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nitroglycerine consumption at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Results of Seattle angina questionnaire at weeks 12, 26, 52</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>129</enrollment>
  <condition>Moderate to Severe Angina Pectoris</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BioBypass®</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years and less than or equal to 80 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent obtained prior to any study dictated procedure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe angina (CCS Angina Class II-IV) despite optimal medical therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treated with optimal unchanged antianginal medical therapy for at least 2 months prior&#xD;
             to the first baseline ETT. Optimal medical therapy must include the following&#xD;
             medications (unless hemodynamic parameters or intolerance contraindicate their use):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nitroglycerine;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Antianginal medications: Long-acting nitrates, calcium-channel blockers,&#xD;
                  potassium channel opener and beta-blockers (Note: All participants are required&#xD;
                  to be on at least 2 of the 4 antianginal medications listed above);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet aggregation inhibitor (e.g., aspirin, ticlopidine, or clopidogrel)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ACE inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Statin (HMG-CoA Reductase Inhibitor)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant must have, within 3 months prior to randomization, documented coronary&#xD;
             angiographic evidence of significant 2- or 3- vessel disease, or equivalent disease in&#xD;
             one dominant artery, and at least one remaining larger coronary vessel from which new&#xD;
             collaterals/vessels could be supplied.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant who has undergone CABG or PCI within 6 months of entry must have&#xD;
             angiography performed within 1 month prior to entry, and at least 4 months after the&#xD;
             previous intervention to rule out early restenosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Candidates must not be eligible for any other re-vascularization procedures. The&#xD;
             participant and his coronary film must have been discussed with an independent cardiac&#xD;
             surgeon and must have been denied for CABG or PTCA. Participants who are marginal or&#xD;
             poor candidates for conventional revascularization will be considered eligible if the&#xD;
             risks of performing a CABG or PTCA procedure outweigh the potential benefit and/or&#xD;
             such a procedure is unlikely to offer a worthwhile clinical benefit. The criteria&#xD;
             defining such cases may include, but may not be limited to, the following examples:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diffuse or distal vessel disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic occlusions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unprotected left main stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Tortuous or severely angulated vessels&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severely calcified vessels&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Small vessels (&lt; 2.5mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Two baseline bicycle ergometry exercise tolerance tests (ETTs) performed meeting the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Able to exercise for a minimum duration of 2 minutes and no more than 8 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Exercise duration on the two ETTs must be within 15% of each other. (The second&#xD;
                  test will be used for the baseline value. In the event of excessive variability,&#xD;
                  a third test may be performed and the participant may be enrolled if exercise&#xD;
                  duration on the third test is within 15% of either prior test. In this case, the&#xD;
                  third test will be used as the baseline value.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ETTs must not be discontinued for any reason other than ETT Angina Level 3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Participant must NOT be informed of exercise restrictions required for&#xD;
                  entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant reversible myocardial ischemia on a single photon emission computer&#xD;
             tomography (SPECT). Judgment will be made by an independent core lab. The size of the&#xD;
             reversible defect must be &gt; 10 % of left ventricle.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ventricular wall thickness of the treatment zone &gt; 8mm as per baseline echocardiogram.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women. It is required that both men and women use condoms or&#xD;
             another barrier method of birth control for at least 8 weeks following administration&#xD;
             of BIOBYPASS® and some form of birth control for at least one year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant anemia (e.g. hematocrit &lt; 36% or hemoglobin &lt; 12 g/dL for men&#xD;
             and &lt; 11 g/dL for women), leukopenia (WBC&lt;3,000/µL), leukocytosis (WBC &gt; 12,000), or&#xD;
             thrombocytopenia (platelet count &lt; 100,000 billion/l);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal prothrombin or partial thromboplastin time or anticoagulant therapy that&#xD;
             cannot be withheld for treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant renal dysfunction (serum creatinine &gt; 1.6 mg/dL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatic dysfunction (AST/ALT must be within normal limits);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematuria, unless of known, non-malignant etiology (any unexplained hematuria would&#xD;
             require the candidate to be excluded);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;200 mmHg or diastolic blood&#xD;
             pressure &gt;110 mmHg) or significant hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions other than angina that will limit exercise test (e.g. severe peripheral&#xD;
             vascular disease, COPD);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ophthalmologic conditions pertinent to proliferative retinopathy or conditions that&#xD;
             preclude standard ophthalmologic examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cataract surgery within 6 months of trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vascular lesions of the anterior segment of the eye (infection or ulceration of&#xD;
                  the cornea, rubeotic glaucoma, etc);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vascular lesions of the posterior segment of the eye or proliferative retinopathy&#xD;
                  in diabetics, macular edema, s/p photocoagulation for macular edema or&#xD;
                  proliferative retinopathy; nondiabetics with central or branch retinal vascular&#xD;
                  occlusions, sickle cell retinopathy, ischemic retinopathy due to retinal venous&#xD;
                  stasis or carotid artery disease);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Choroidal new vessels associated with age-related macular degeneration, myopic&#xD;
                  degeneration, presumed ocular histoplasmosis syndrome, angioid streaks,&#xD;
                  pseudoxanthoma elasticum, or without ocular disease; and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Large elevated choroidal nevi, choroidal vascular tumors (choroidal hemangioma),&#xD;
                  or melanomas.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any acute illness within one week of the start of the study or any other illness&#xD;
             considered by the Investigator to significantly interfere with study outcome;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical evidence of active infection of any type, including adenovirus (evidenced by&#xD;
             a screening adenovirus neutralizing antibody titer of &gt; 1:50);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised status (in the investigator's opinion) or currently receiving&#xD;
             immunosuppressive therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 25% as measured by LV angiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congestive heart failure NYHA class III-IV;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Valvular heart disease requiring surgical intervention or hemodynamically significant&#xD;
             aortic valve disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (less than 6 weeks prior to screening) Acute Coronary Syndrome with increase in&#xD;
             CK-MB or Troponins/PCI/CABG/Stroke or TIA;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancy (except cured non-melanoma skin cancer) or suspicion of current&#xD;
             malignancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to the diluent used to suspend the virus;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other experimental medications within the last four weeks prior to the second baseline&#xD;
             ETT;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Revascularization procedure (percutaneous coronary intervention or coronary artery&#xD;
             bypass) within 4 months of Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have previously received VEGF or any other angiogenic agent or gene&#xD;
             therapy in the past, or who have participated in other investigational studies within&#xD;
             the last year if the endpoints are overlapping.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr. Jens Kastrup</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Heart Center, University hospital Rigshospitalet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiovascular Laboratory 2014, The Heart Center, University hospital Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Skejby Sygehus, Caridology Laboratory</name>
      <address>
        <city>Århus N</city>
        <zip>DK-8200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiac Catheterization Laboratories, Cardiology Department, Rabin Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petah</city>
        <state>Tikva</state>
        <zip>49100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 22, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 12, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 12, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 13, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Paul Fischer, PhD</name_title>
    <organization>GenVec</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Angina Pectoris</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

