<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00232609</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>02254, 0410155</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2R44HD039535-02A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00232609</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Development of the GameCycle Exercise System: Phase II</brief_title>
  <official_title>Development of the GameCycle Exercise System: Phase II</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research project is to further develop and test the effectiveness of a&#xD;
      novel exercise system for wheelchair users, the Game Cycle.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research project is to further develop and test the effectiveness of a&#xD;
      novel exercise system for wheelchair users, the GAMECycle. People in wheelchairs who have a&#xD;
      desire to exercise are faced with barriers with respect to access to exercise equipment and&#xD;
      to availability of exercise equipment that is specifically suitable for use with a&#xD;
      wheelchair. The GAMECycle exercise system removes these barriers and offers the wheelchair&#xD;
      user an entertaining, motivational environment in which to exercise. The long-term goal is to&#xD;
      improve the overall activity level of individuals who use wheelchairs as their primary means&#xD;
      of mobility and increase their general well being.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The GAMECycle Exercise System is a modified arm-ergometer that sits on a turnstile to allow&#xD;
      steering in much the same way as an arm-cycle. More specifically, it is a crank and pedal set&#xD;
      that is turned using the arms, similar to a bicycle that is turned with the feet. When using&#xD;
      the system, subjects will be seated in their own wheelchair in front of the system&#xD;
      comfortably positioned to be able to grasp the handles and use the arm crank. The GAMECycle&#xD;
      is designed to provide upper body aerobic exercise in an environment (computer game play)&#xD;
      that will help to make exercise more enjoyable by, among other things, distracting people&#xD;
      from some of the less pleasant aspects of exercising. Although upper-body exercise systems&#xD;
      for wheelchair users do exist, the GAMECycle is unique in its ability to combine&#xD;
      arm-ergometry with playing computer videogames. And, in contrast to wheelchair roller&#xD;
      systems, the arm-ergometry provided by the GAMECycle affords the user an exercise option that&#xD;
      uses a motion that differs significantly from the motion of wheelchair propulsion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This research consists of two phases: a Training Phase and an In Home Trial Phase. The&#xD;
      training phase will last a maximum of two hours and the In Home Phase will last 4 months.&#xD;
      Subjects who complete the Training Phase will be asked to participate in the In Home Trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training Phase The purpose of the training sessions are to determine the users ability to&#xD;
      reach and maintain target aerobic training zones during 15 minute exercise trials, teach new&#xD;
      users how to use the GAMECycle Exercise System, and to obtain feedback from new users&#xD;
      regarding perceived comfort, fit, and ease of use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A GAMECycle exercise system will be set up in participating local rehab and research&#xD;
      facilities. A clinician will ensure that the GAMECycle is adjusted to fit each user. The&#xD;
      amount of resistance from the arm-ergometer will be adjusted to a level that feels&#xD;
      comfortable during exercise. Heart rate and breathing rate will be monitored during a&#xD;
      15-minute exercise session. Subjects will rate their level of exertion every 2 minutes during&#xD;
      the 15-minute exercise phase and will be asked to complete a questionnaire about their&#xD;
      opinion of the GAMECycle System.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Home Phase This phase involves a 4-month trial period divided into 2 two-month sessions.&#xD;
      For two months, subjects will be asked to use the GAMECycle and for the other two months,&#xD;
      subjects will be asked to use an arm-ergometer. It will randomly be determined whether the&#xD;
      GAMECycle or the arm-ergometer is used first. Subjects will be required to record their&#xD;
      exercise sessions and will be followed by a member of the research team by telephone. In&#xD;
      addition, once a month for four months, a member of our research staff will visit each&#xD;
      participant with a portable metabolic cart and heart rate monitor in order to collect heart&#xD;
      rate date, metabolic date (VO2, VCO2), and ratings of perceived exertion using the Borg&#xD;
      scale. This data will be collected during exercise with or without game play, depending on&#xD;
      the condition of that session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physiologic and Metabolic activity (VO2, VCO2, HR)</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ratings of perceived exertion</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Questionnaire responses</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Wheelchair Users</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GameCycle Exercise System</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Use of a wheelchair as primary means of mobility (use a wheelchair &gt; 20 hours per&#xD;
             week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Between ages 18 and 50&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to use an arm-cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any history of cardiovascular or cardiopulmonary disease for the participant, or a&#xD;
             history of CVD in their family (e.g., parents, grandparents, and siblings) which will&#xD;
             be defined as death as a result of CVD prior to the age of 55.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. If a subject answers yes to any question on the PAR-Q.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rory A Cooper, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh and VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Human Engineering Research Laboratories</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15206</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.herlpitt.org</url>
    <description>Human Engineering Research Laboratories</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 30, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 4, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 18, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Rory Cooper, PhD</name_title>
    <organization>Human Engineering Research Laboratories</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Wheelchair</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular Disease</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

