<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00239135</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PEP005-004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00239135</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Determine the Maximum Tolerated Dose and Safety of PEP005 Topical Gel</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Dose Escalation, Cohort Study to Determine the Maximum Tolerated Dose and Safety of PEP005 Topical Gel When Applied on Day 1 and Day 2 to Actinic Keratoses on the Shoulders, Chest, Back or Arms Followed by a Post-Treatment Follow-up Period Lasting at Four Weeks</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peplin</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peplin</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) for PEP005 Topical Gel in patients with&#xD;
           actinic keratoses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate patients for clinical safety&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the systemic absorption of PEP005 Topical Gel&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Actinic keratoses (AK) is a common skin condition characterized by rough, scaly patches or&#xD;
      sores on the top layer of the skin which if left untreated can progress to skin cancer.&#xD;
      Current treatments can cause scarring and hypopigmentation, be inconvenient, or require long&#xD;
      treatment duration. Non-invasive alternative therapy for treatment of AK lesions is thus&#xD;
      being researched.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an open label, dose escalation, cohort study to determine the maximum tolerated dose&#xD;
      (MTD) of PEP005 Topical Gel, administered once daily for two consecutive days (90 ul gel&#xD;
      applied topically over a 3 x 3cm template surrounding a target lesion), to patients with&#xD;
      actinic keratoses (AK). The study will be conducted in one centre in the US. Three patients&#xD;
      will be entered initially at the lowest dose level (0.01%) with up to an additional three&#xD;
      patients to be entered in the event of a dose limiting toxicity (DLT) in the initial&#xD;
      patients. DLT are defined as 'severe' local skin reactions observed by the Investigator,&#xD;
      either prior to treatment on Day 2 ( following treatment on Day 1 ) or observed on Day 8&#xD;
      (following treatment on Day 2). Based on findings from phase I studies and the low systemic&#xD;
      absorption found in non-clinical toxicokinetic evaluations, no systemic toxicity is&#xD;
      anticipated.Once determined A total of 10 patients will be treated at the MTD in order to&#xD;
      confirm it's determination. Based on findings from the phase I study, the starting dose will&#xD;
      be 0.01% PEP005 Gel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives of the study are (1) evaluate the clinical efficiency of PEP005 Topical&#xD;
      Gel, when administered once daily for two consecutive days and (2) determine the systemic&#xD;
      absorption of PEP005 Topical Gel at the MTD . Hematologic and biochemical assessments will be&#xD;
      undertaken at the screening visit and at days 8 and 29 . Adverse events will be assessed at&#xD;
      every study visit. Clinical response to treatment will be assessed at Days 8, 15 and 29.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2005</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2005</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD)</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and clinical efficacy</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systemic absorption</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>34</enrollment>
  <condition>Keratosis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PEP005</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One AK lesion selected for treatment on the shoulders, chest, back or arms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Longest diameter of the selected lesion between 3mm and 15mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening laboratory values within the references ranges as defined by the laboratory&#xD;
             or &quot;out of range&quot; test results that are clinically acceptable to the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to follow study instructions and likely to complete all study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent has been obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written Authorization for the Use and Release of Health and Research Study Information&#xD;
             has been obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement from the patient to allow photographs of the selected lesion to be taken and&#xD;
             used as part of the study data package.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of child bearing potential (a female is considered to be of childbearing&#xD;
             potential unless she is post-menopausal, i.e no menses for at least 12 consecutive&#xD;
             months or is without a uterus)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Actinic Keratoses selected for treatment that are hypertrophic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Location of the selected actinic keratoses lesion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. within 5 cm of a scar&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. within 5 cm of any actinic keratosis lesion not selected for treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. within 5 cm of an incompletely healed wound&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. on the breast&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. within 5 cm of an area previously treated with surgical excision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of suspected basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma within 5 cm of&#xD;
             the selected treatment area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of known or suspected metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or evidence of skin conditions other than AK which would interfere with the&#xD;
             evaluation of the study medication (e.g eczema, unstable psoriasis, xeroderma&#xD;
             pigmentosa)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known sensitivity to any of the ingredients in the study medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A cosmetic or therapeutic procedure (e.g liquid nitrogen, curettage, dermabrasion,&#xD;
             medium or greater depth chemical peel, laser resurfacing) located within 10cm of the&#xD;
             actinic keratosis lesion selected for treatment during three months prior to study&#xD;
             entry or anticipated treatment within 10cm of the selected lesion during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within four weeks prior to study entry, a cosmetic or therapeutic procedure located&#xD;
             anywhere on the body&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within three months prior to the study entry, treatment with 5-flourouracil,&#xD;
             imiquimod, diclofenac, masoprocol, or photodynamic therapy for lesions located within&#xD;
             10cm of the actinic keratosis lesion selected for treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within four weeks prior to study entry, treatment with 5-flourouracil, imiquimod,&#xD;
             masoprocol, or photodynamic therapy for lesion located anywhere on the body&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with other immunomodulators (e.g vinblastine, podophyllin,&#xD;
             colhamin, camptothecin), cytotoxic drugs (e;g cyclophosphamide, azathioprine,&#xD;
             chlorambucil, nitrogen mustard, methotrexate), or interferon/interferon inducers&#xD;
             (other than imiquimod)within four weeks prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with psoralen plus UVA or use of UVB therapy within six months&#xD;
             prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require or desire excess or prolonged exposure to ultraviolet light(e.g&#xD;
             sunlight, tanning beds) during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications that suppress the immune system within four weeks prior study entry&#xD;
             (e.g cyclosporine, prednisone, methotrexate, alefacept, infliximab)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within four weeks prior to study entry, use of topical retinoids or light chemical&#xD;
             peels located within 10cm of the actinic keratosis lesion selected for treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of systemic retinoids (e.g isotretinoin, acitretin, bexarotene) within six months&#xD;
             prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within four weeks prior to study entry, use of acid containing products (e.g salicylic&#xD;
             acids or fruit acids such as alpha and beta hydroxy acids and glycolic acids). located&#xD;
             within 10 cm of the actinic keratosis lesion selected for treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated need to use acid containing products on the treatment area during the&#xD;
             study ( e.g salicylic acids or fruit acids, such as alpha and beta hydroxy acids and&#xD;
             glycolic acids)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent disease that supresses the immune system(e.g HIV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled systemic disease (e.g uncontrolled hypertension)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated need for surgery or hospitalization during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current evidence of chronic alcohol or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current enrollment in an investigational drug or device study or participation in such&#xD;
             a study within 30 days of entry into this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a condition or is in a situation which in the Investigator's opinion may&#xD;
             put the patient at significant risk, may confound the study results, or may interfere&#xD;
             significantly with the patients participation in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lawrence Anderson, MD, F.A.C.P</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Associates of Tyler</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tyler</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75703</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 14, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 25, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Actinic Keratosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Topical</keyword>
  <keyword>Maximum Tolerated Dose</keyword>
  <keyword>Solar Keratosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Sun Spots</keyword>
  <keyword>Dermatology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Keratosis, Actinic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Keratosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

