<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00232349</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TA1 28</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>GAL-EMR-4009</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00232349</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Galantamine to Treat Schizophrenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label Trial of Adjunctive Galantamine Maintenance Therapy to Treat Functional Impairments in Chronic Outpatients With Schizophrenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seattle Institute for Biomedical and Clinical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seattle Institute for Biomedical and Clinical Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study was to determine if treatment with adjunctive galantamine is&#xD;
      effective in the reduction of functional impairments in patients with schizophrenia and&#xD;
      schizoaffective disorder. It was hypothesized that adjunctive galantamine would yield&#xD;
      clinically significant improvements from baseline to end of study on a measure of quality of&#xD;
      life and a measure of independent living skills.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A majority of patients with schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder experience impairments&#xD;
      in social relations and employment. Many patients experience impairments in their ability to&#xD;
      live independently, requiring assistance in such activities as money management, shopping,&#xD;
      food preparation and hygiene. These impairments in functioning have been shown to be related&#xD;
      to cognitive deficits associated with the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Galantamine is a medication that has been approved by the FDA for the treatment of mild to&#xD;
      moderate Alzheimer's disease. Both animal and human models have shown that galantamine can&#xD;
      enhance learning and memory. Case reports and preliminary research have suggested that&#xD;
      galantamine is an effective adjunctive treatment for schizophrenia, improving both cognition&#xD;
      and negative symptoms. Improvements in functioning require that gains in cognition be&#xD;
      maintained long enough to allow for the acquisition and application of new skills and&#xD;
      behaviors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, this nine month, open label study assessed the efficacy of galantamine, dosed at 4-12&#xD;
      mg/twice a day, for the treatment of functional impairments in individuals, ages 18-60, with&#xD;
      schizophrenia and schizoaffective disorder. The primary outcome measures were changes from&#xD;
      baseline to end of study in scores on the Independent Living Scale (ILS) and the Quality of&#xD;
      Life Scale (QLS). Secondary outcome measures included assessments of symptoms, cognition,&#xD;
      side effects, and movement disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Twenty-one subjects signed informed consent and fourteen subjects were initiated on&#xD;
      medication. Six subjects completed the study. As per a priori plan, those subjects (n = 8)&#xD;
      who were treated with study medication for at least four months were included in the analyses&#xD;
      of treatment outcomes. Our findings regarding the efficacy of galantamine for functional&#xD;
      outcomes, including activities of daily living and quality of life, did not support our&#xD;
      hypothesis that long-term treatment with galantamine would yield improvements in these&#xD;
      domains in patients with schizophrenia spectrum disorders. In fact, in the current study, we&#xD;
      did not observe any anticipated improvements in cognition. In addition, we did not observe&#xD;
      any anticipated improvements in symptoms, specifically negative symptoms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study terminated due to no apparent benefit.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>February 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>score on a measure of quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>after 9 months treatment</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>score on a measure of independent living skills</measure>
    <time_frame>after 9 months treatment</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score on a measure of psychopathology</measure>
    <time_frame>after 9 months treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score on a measure of negative symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>after 9 months treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score on a neurocognitive battery</measure>
    <time_frame>after 9 months treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <condition>Psychotic Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects enrolled in study are in the intervention group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>galantamine</intervention_name>
    <description>open label galantamine, dosed at 4-12 mg/b.i.d., with a target dose of 12 mg/b.i.d.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Razadyne</other_name>
    <other_name>Reminyl</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-60&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed, written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment for schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder for 5 or more years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatrically stable as evidenced by no hospitalizations and no changes in&#xD;
             psychiatric medications (with the exception of dosage adjustments and the prescription&#xD;
             of adjunctive treatments for sleep disturbance or anxiety) within the prior 3 months,&#xD;
             and as confirmed by clinical interview during the screening phase&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total score &gt; 60 baseline on The Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Score &gt; 3 on at least one of the five subscales of the SANS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-Kraepelinian schizophrenia, as defined by the ability to independently provide for&#xD;
             at least one domain of basic needs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must be of non-child bearing potential or on appropriate contraceptive and not&#xD;
             breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must have a negative serum beta HCG at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical laboratory values within normal limits, as defined in study protocol, or&#xD;
             abnormalities considered not clinically significant by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kraepelinian schizophrenia, as defined by dependency on others for the provision of&#xD;
             all basic needs (including shopping, food preparation, household chores, and&#xD;
             transportation);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DSM-IV criteria for substance dependence (excluding nicotine and caffeine), as&#xD;
             determined by SCID and chart review, during the 90 days prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients judged by the investigator as being at significant risk of suicide, violent&#xD;
             behavior, or homicide;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent participation or participation within the prior 30 days in any study&#xD;
             involving investigational medications;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant or lactating;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer's disease and other dementias,&#xD;
             Parkinson's disease, Pick's disease, and Huntington's chorea;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of significant cerebrovascular event yielding a physical or neurological&#xD;
             deficit likely to confound the assessment of the subject's functioning;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of significant head trauma, defined as head trauma resulting in neurological&#xD;
             or cognitive sequelae;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known personal history of seizure disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known sensitivity to cholinesterase inhibitors, choline agonists, or similar agents;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are known to be HIV positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of clinically significant, active gastrointestinal, hepatic, pulmonary,&#xD;
             endocrine, renal, or cardiovascular system disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or clinically significant conditions affecting absorption, distribution or&#xD;
             metabolism of the study medication (e.g. inflammatory bowel disease or gastric or&#xD;
             duodenal ulcers);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant urinary outflow obstruction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with untreated thyroid disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Type I or Type II diabetes controlled by medication or diet who do not&#xD;
             have a HbA1c of &lt; 8.5%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known significant cardiac history such as myocardial infarction or&#xD;
             abnormal cardiac catheterization within the last 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable angina: angina or coronary artery disease requiring a change in medications&#xD;
             within the 3 months prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Decompensated congestive heart failure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe mitral or aortic valvular disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atrial fibrillation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than first degree atrioventricular block;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  QTc prolongation at screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bradycardia &lt;50 beats/min;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current treatment with clozapine, olanzapine, chlorpromazine, or thioridazine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of potent cytochrome P450 inhibitors or inducers within 14 days before the&#xD;
             Baseline Visit or during treatment, as listed in Appendix B of protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of potent anticholinergic medication, as listed in Appendix B;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of any disallowed concomitant medication, as listed in Appendix B; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinical finding that in the opinion of the investigator could potentially be&#xD;
             negatively affected by study participation or that could potentially affect study&#xD;
             participation is criterion for exclusion from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andre Tapp, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Puget Sound Health Care System, Tacoma and Seattle, WA and University of Washington, Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Seattle, WA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Puget Sound Health Care System, American Lake Division</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tacoma</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98493</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Allen TB, McEvoy JP. Galantamine for treatment-resistant schizophrenia. Am J Psychiatry. 2002 Jul;159(7):1244-5.</citation>
    <PMID>12091212</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 30, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 4, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 31, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Andre Tapp, M.D.</name_title>
    <organization>VA Puget Sound Health Care System</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
  <keyword>galantamine</keyword>
  <keyword>cholinesterase inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>cognition</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Galantamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

