<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00433056</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LOTTI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00433056</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long Term Treatment Interruptions</brief_title>
  <official_title>Strategic, Long Term, Immunologically Driven Treatment Interruptions in Patients on Effective HAART: A Controlled, Randomized Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>A.O. Ospedale Papa Giovanni XXIII</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>A.O. Ospedale Papa Giovanni XXIII</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      LOTTI study Centers&#xD;
&#xD;
      This a multicenter, multinational study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical phase: III&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to compare efficacy and safety of continuing a conventional HAART in&#xD;
      chronically infected HIV patients with a therapeutic strategy based on long term,&#xD;
      immunologically driven treatment interruptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the risk of developing viral resistance&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the effect of the two strategies on metabolic parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the possibility to steadily discontinue antiretroviral therapy in patients who&#xD;
           started it with baseline immunological values higher than those currently recommended by&#xD;
           international guidelines for HIV treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify predictive variables of the possibility to safely discontinue antiretroviral&#xD;
           therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the dynamic of CD4+ cell loss and HIV replication after treatment interruption&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of Patients: A total of 320 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Controlled, Randomized, Open study The study will last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomized in a ratio 1:1 to one of the two treatment arms Control group&#xD;
      continuing the ongoing therapy STI group performing long term CD4 guided structured treatment&#xD;
      interruptions In the STI arm patients will stay off therapy until their CD4 count will drop &lt;&#xD;
      350 cells/mcL (one measurement will be considered sufficient). At that time point patients&#xD;
      will resume the HAART regimen they were assuming before STI and will continue HAART until&#xD;
      they CD4 count will raise &gt; 600 cells/mcL (at least 2 consecutive measurements 2 months&#xD;
      apart) and their HIV-RNA will drop below the detection limit of 50 copies/ml (one measurement&#xD;
      will be considered sufficient). When both the CD4 count and the viral load will be within&#xD;
      these pre-set values they will stop therapy again. There is no limit to the number of&#xD;
      interruptions and re-start cycles during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
      End points:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary end-point for the evaluation of the main objective of the study will be clinical.&#xD;
      The primary outcome measure will be based on the occurrence of a clinical end-point defined&#xD;
      as: disease progression (occurrence of any AIDS defining event), death for any cause or the&#xD;
      occurrence of clinical events requiring hospital admission&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives of the study will be evaluated on the basis of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mean variation of blood cholesterol and triglycerides from baseline values.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Development of lipodystrophy or modification of a pre-existing lipodystrophy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time off therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Variation of CD4 counts and HIV-RNA levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Genotypic tests to be performed in the case of HIV-RNA &gt; 1000 copies/ml while on therapy&#xD;
           for at least 4 months or one month after each treatment interruption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is powered to evaluate equivalence between the two strategies under the assumption&#xD;
      that, in the control arm, the primary end-point would be observed in a proportion of subjects&#xD;
      &lt; 7% and that the same proportion in the STI arm would not exceed 10% with a maximum allowed&#xD;
      95%CI of 12%. 320 patients will be needed for alfa = 5% and 1-beta = 80%. The primary&#xD;
      analysis will be made according to the intention-to-treat approach and therefore no&#xD;
      correction for eventual drop outs is needed. In addition, a secondary per-protocol analysis&#xD;
      will be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the current regimens cannot eradicate HIV infection, persons living with HIV are doomed to&#xD;
      assume chronic therapies with often very demanding daily schedules. In the long run, this may&#xD;
      lead to reduced adherence to therapy, to incomplete suppression of viral replication and to&#xD;
      the emergence of resistant viruses that can vanish the patients' efforts. Furthermore with&#xD;
      continued exposure to antiretroviral drugs, patients have begun to experience new adverse&#xD;
      effects including body fat redistribution, dislipidemia, diabetes, insulin resistance,&#xD;
      osteopenia and the fear of unexpected complications such as cardiovascular diseases has&#xD;
      raised. A variety of strategies has emerged to try to help the long-term management of HAART.&#xD;
      Researchers have focused their attention on the development of simpler regimens. An&#xD;
      alternative approach involves various types of structured treatment interruptions (STI).&#xD;
      Several different roles have been claimed for STIs. They have been postulated to enhance&#xD;
      specific immune response and allow control of viral replication, in the absence of continuous&#xD;
      HAART, in seroconverters. In advanced treatment failures STIs has been suggested to favor the&#xD;
      overgrowth of wild-type virus in the peripheral circulation and thus facilitate the&#xD;
      &quot;disappearance&quot; of resistance mutations. In chronically infected patients without virologic&#xD;
      failure STIs have been explored to boost HIV specific immune responses and, more recently, to&#xD;
      reduce drug exposure, promote adherence and minimize drug-related morbidity .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Various strategies with fixed intervals for on and off periods, or with specific thresholds,&#xD;
      either immunologic or virologic, for re-initiation of therapy have been explored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, unanswered questions about STIs or even pulse therapy include the risk of exposing&#xD;
      patients to differential drug levels which may enhance selection of resistant mutants, the&#xD;
      effects of re-seeding of viral reservoirs, the real extent of the assumption that less drug&#xD;
      is associated with less toxicity or better adherence, and the overall outcome compared to&#xD;
      continuous HAART.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally STIs and pulse therapy may result strictly linked with questions raised by new&#xD;
      treatment recommendations: what to do with individuals who began therapy at a CD4 + cell&#xD;
      level above the currently recommended threshold, and how to manage those patients who, under&#xD;
      HAART, have gained a CD4 cell count far above this threshold.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will conduct a controlled, prospective and randomized trial on a cohort of chronically HIV&#xD;
      infected individuals on effective HAART to address most of these open questions. We will&#xD;
      apply an individualized pulse therapy strategy, driven by CD4 + cell count, and will compare&#xD;
      it with conventional continuous HAART.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective of the study is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To compare efficacy and safety of continuing a conventional HAART in chronically infected HIV&#xD;
      patients with a therapeutic strategy based on long term, immunologically driven treatment&#xD;
      interruptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the risk of developing viral resistance&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the effect of the two strategies on metabolic parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the possibility to steadily discontinue antiretroviral therapy in patients&#xD;
           that started it with baseline immunological values higher than those currently&#xD;
           recommended by international guidelines for HIV treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify predictive variables of the possibility to safely discontinue antiretroviral&#xD;
           therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To verify the dynamic of CD4 + loss and HIV replication after treatment interruption&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the study wants to enroll patients strictly reflecting the population of HIV infected&#xD;
      individuals, previous mono or dual therapies as well as the presence of co-morbidities such&#xD;
      as HBV and HCV co-infection do not constitute exclusion criteria, but will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multicenter, randomized, controlled, open, comparative study. The trial will have a&#xD;
      follow-up of 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be monitored according to the international and local guidelines for HIV&#xD;
      infection as far as timing and type of laboratory and clinical controls. Laboratory exams&#xD;
      will be decided locally and only a few key tests are required for the study. The timing of&#xD;
      laboratory evaluation will be 1 and 2 months after each treatment interruption and thereafter&#xD;
      every 2 months in the STI arm and every 4 months in the control group. All data will be&#xD;
      stored in a computerized data-base.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study arms and management of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomized in the ratio 1: 2 to one of the following treatment arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Continuing their ongoing HAART (control)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Long term treatment interruption (STI)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization will be accomplished centrally according to a pre-determined,&#xD;
      computer-generated random list.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the control group, patients will be allowed to change therapy for virological,&#xD;
      toxicological or personal reasons. All variation will be recorded. Patients changing therapy&#xD;
      will be still included in the ITT analysis, but will be considered failures in the AT&#xD;
      analysis. Patients stopping therapy, for any reason and not resuming it within 3 months will&#xD;
      be considered as failures for both the ITT and AT analysis In the STI arm, patients will stay&#xD;
      off therapy until their CD4 count drop &lt; 350 cells/mcL (one measurement will be considered&#xD;
      sufficient). At that time point patients will resume the HAART regimen they were assuming&#xD;
      before the STI period and will continue HAART until their CD4 count raises &gt; 600 cells/mcL&#xD;
      and their plasma HIV-RNA drops below the detection limit of 50 copies/ml (one measurement&#xD;
      will be considered sufficient). When both the CD4 count and the viral load will be within&#xD;
      these pre-set values they will stop therapy again. There is no limit to the number of&#xD;
      interruptions and re-start cycles during the study period 160 patients will be allocated in&#xD;
      the STI arm and 80 patients in the control arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End points and evaluation criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary end-point for the evaluation of the main objective of the study will be clinical:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measure will be based on the occurrence of a clinical end-point defined&#xD;
      as: disease progression (occurrence of any AIDS defining event), death for any cause or the&#xD;
      occurrence of clinical events requiring hospital admission&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives of the study will be evaluated on the basis of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mean variation of blood cholesterol and triglycerides from baseline values. Development&#xD;
           of lipodystrophy or modification of a pre-existing lipodystrophy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time off therapy, variation of CD4 counts and HIV-RNA levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Genotypic tests to be performed in the case of HIV-RNA &gt; 1000 copies/ml while on therapy&#xD;
           for at least 4 months or one month after each treatment interruption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment will be continued for 5 years under the study conditions. Patients completing the&#xD;
      study period and still responding to therapy will be kept on the same regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical evaluation of the study will be performed yearly. A first interim analysis will&#xD;
      be performed when the mean follow-up will reach 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory tests during the study period will be performed in he fasting state. The following&#xD;
      tests and procedures are required and will be recorded in the electronic data base. It is&#xD;
      also advised to perform on regular basis haemogram, renal function tests, blood glucose and&#xD;
      amylase. Other test could be performed according to local needs or particular situations&#xD;
      related to the specific management of single patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline (all patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) Informed consent and treatment randomization 2) Biochemical analysis: ALT, AST, total&#xD;
      cholesterol and HDL, triglycerides 3) CD4 count, CD8 count 4) Plasma HIV-RNA 5) Clinical&#xD;
      evaluation, anamnestic and demographic data: sex, age, risk factor for HIV infection, CDC&#xD;
      AIDS classification, time on ART, time on current HAART, previous antiretroviral drugs,&#xD;
      previous sub-optimal ARTs, current antiretroviral drugs, presence and grade of lipodystrophy,&#xD;
      time with HIV-RNA below detection, nadir CD4, CD4 at start of antiretroviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. month after each STI (only STI group) 1) CD4 count, CD8 count&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. months after each STI (only STI group) 1) Biochemical analysis: ALT, AST, cholesterol&#xD;
           (total and HDL), triglycerides 2) CD4 count, CD8 count 3) Plasma HIV-RNA, Genotype 4)&#xD;
           Clinical evaluation: disease progression, lipodystrophy assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every 2 months thereafter (STI group) or every 4 months from baseline (control group)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Biochemical analysis: ALT, AST, cholesterol (total and HDL), triglycerides&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. CD4 count, CD8 count&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Plasma HIV-RNA&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Clinical evaluation: disease progression, lipodystrophy assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional tests will be requested in specific cases:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. a second genotype after 4 months from the initiation of the STI period will be performed&#xD;
           in all patients showing a major mutation in the genotype performed 2 months after STI&#xD;
           start&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. a genotype will be performed in all patients either in the STI or in the control group&#xD;
           showing a viral load above 1000 copies/ml after a continuous treatment period (on drugs)&#xD;
           &gt; 4 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical considerations&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is powered to evaluate equivalence between the two strategies under the assumption&#xD;
      that, in the control arm, the primary end-point would be observed in a proportion of subjects&#xD;
      &lt; 7% and that the same proportion in the STI arm would not exceed 10% with a maximum allowed&#xD;
      95%CI of 12%. According to the model published in Controlled Clinical Trials 1982; 3:&#xD;
      345-353,320 patients will be needed for alfa = 5% and 1-beta = 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary analysis will be made according to the intention-to-treat approach and therefore&#xD;
      no correction for eventual drop outs is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, a secondary per-protocol analysis will be performed. Chi-square or Fisher's&#xD;
      exact test that will be used to analyze all categorical variables. Time to treatment failure&#xD;
      will be estimated using Kaplan-Meier product-limit estimates (that will be presented&#xD;
      graphically). The log-rank test will be used to assess the difference between the survival&#xD;
      curves for each arm, while ANOVA test and Student's t test will be used for continuous&#xD;
      variables unless the variables will not be normally distributed, in which case the&#xD;
      Kruskal-Wallis and Mann-Whitney U tests will be used. Logistic regression analysis (forward&#xD;
      stepwise model) will be used to evaluate the relationship between variables and outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All tests will be two-sided and a P value inferior to 0.05 will be regarded as significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The analysis of data will be performed by the proposing Study Center with the SPSS&#xD;
      statistical software package for Windows, version 13.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a spontaneous study. It is proposed that all drugs will be dispensed according to&#xD;
      standard procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data use&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be used for scientific porpoises only. The analysis will be performed yearly and&#xD;
      the results will be disclosed to the major participating groups for discussion and comments.&#xD;
      The type and timing of publication of data will be agreed among the participants to the&#xD;
      study. The authorship of each presentation will be agreed among participants. It is&#xD;
      foreseeable that no more than 10 authors will be included for each publication. The number of&#xD;
      authors for each group will be proportional to the number of patients included at the site.&#xD;
      All participants will be acknowledged as members of the study group. The principal&#xD;
      investigator at each site will be responsible for indicating the researchers to include as&#xD;
      authors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2004</start_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary outcome will be clinical response: Death, ADE, pathology requiring hospital admission</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean variation of blood cholesterol and triglycerides from baseline values. Development of lipodystrophy or modification of a pre-existing lipodystrophy</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time off therapy, variation of CD4 counts and HIV-RNA levels</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Genotypic tests to be performed in the case of HIV-RNA &gt; 1000 copies/ml while on therapy for at least 4 months or one month after each treatment interruption.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">320</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>AIDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>STI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>stable HAART, Any registered regimen containing NRTIs (AZT or D4T or 3TC or TDF or DDI), NNRTIs (EFV or NVP) or PIs (RTV-boosted ATV; IDV; LPV, fosAPV, SQV; unboosted ATV or NFV)is allowed according to international guidelines</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>STI</intervention_name>
    <description>CD4 guided treatment interruption</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>stable HAART</intervention_name>
    <description>continuous therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 17 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent signed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Effective ongoing treatment (HIV-RNA &lt; 50 copies/ml). Treatment must be based on any&#xD;
             triple drug therapy. Patients must be on the same steady therapy for at least 3&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current CD4 cell count above 600 cells/mcL and nadir of CD4 cell count &gt; 200 cells/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Childbearing or breastfeeding. Women of childbearing potential will be asked to adopt&#xD;
             effective contraceptive methods or behaviors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any ongoing grade 4 (WHO) AE or laboratory abnormality with the exclusion of&#xD;
             cholesterol, triglycerides for which a grade 3 (AHA) level will be considered an&#xD;
             exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous diagnosis of AIDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with HBV coinfection on active anti-HIV treatment with either lamivudine&#xD;
             and/or tenofovir&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Franco Maggiolo, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ospedali Riuniti, Bergamo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedali Riuniti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bergamo</city>
        <state>BG</state>
        <zip>24128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 24, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 24, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 25, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>STI</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>CD4</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV-RNA</keyword>
  <keyword>HAART</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

