<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04313296</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Blake-ParlinTOMTEC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04313296</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediction and Maintenance of Sinus Rhythm Among Atrial Fibrillation Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prediction and Maintenance of Sinus Rhythm Among Atrial Fibrillation Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Crystal Blake-Parlin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>MaineHealth</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MaineHealth</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common heart rhythm disorder seen in clinical practice,&#xD;
      with an estimated 2.7-6.1 million people in the U.S. affected by the disorder [1]. Previous&#xD;
      studies have demonstrated that left atrial volume is a predictive measure of incident atrial&#xD;
      fibrillation [2]. This study aims to add to the literature by investigating predictive&#xD;
      measures of left atrial global longitudinal strain (LA GLS) that would be suggestive of&#xD;
      maintenance of normal sinus rhythm post cardioversion. If the investigators could gain&#xD;
      insight on the connection between LA GLS and cardioversion among patients with atrial&#xD;
      fibrillation, the investigators could potentially help the clinical management of patients&#xD;
      pre/post cardioversion, and potentially change poor outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Atrial fibrillation (AF) is a heart rhythm disorder in which the normal beating in the upper&#xD;
      chambers of the heart is irregular, leading to poor blood flow to the lower chambers. Risk&#xD;
      factors include older age, high blood pressure, obesity, European ancestry, diabetes, heart&#xD;
      failure, ischemic heart disease, hyperthyroidism, chronic kidney disease, heavy alcohol use,&#xD;
      and enlarged heart chambers on the left side [3]. AF increases a person's risk for stroke and&#xD;
      contributes to an estimated 130,000 deaths each year [1]. Treatment generally includes&#xD;
      medication, surgery, and/or healthy lifestyle changes [1]. Electrical cardioversion, in which&#xD;
      the patient must undergo sedation or general anesthesia, is also used to convert patients&#xD;
      with persistent AF to normal sinus rhythm. Electrical cardioversion has been associated with&#xD;
      a high initial success rate of 68-98% [4], but long-term maintenance of sinus rhythm has&#xD;
      proved challenging [5]. Due to the potential risks incurred to the patient, it is important&#xD;
      to understand which patients are good candidates for cardioversion therapy. A review article&#xD;
      describes that duration of AF, sex, age, weight smoking status, number of shocks at&#xD;
      cardioversion, post-ablation procedure, medications, hypertension, diabetes, Chronic&#xD;
      Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), obstructive sleep apnea, renal impairment,&#xD;
      hyperthyroidism, coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, left systolic&#xD;
      dysfunction, left diastolic dysfunction, left ventricular hypertrophy, valvular heart&#xD;
      disease, and left atrial size have each been found to be associated with maintenance of sinus&#xD;
      rhythm [6].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Echocardiography has been increasing used in understanding the cardiac structure and risk of&#xD;
      stroke among patients with AF, with left atrial size, left ventricular wall thickness, and&#xD;
      left ventricular dysfunction recognized as independent predictors of AF [7]. Increasing&#xD;
      evidence supports that the left atrial strain measurements can be a predictor of outcomes&#xD;
      among AF patients, including stroke and AF recurrence after catheter ablation [8], [9]. The&#xD;
      investigators aim to further explore left atrial strain measurements, including left atrial&#xD;
      global longitudinal strain (LA GLS), as predictors of maintenance of normal sinus rhythm&#xD;
      post- cardioversion. It is anticipated that a lower LA GLS will predict AF recurrence. To do&#xD;
      this, the investigators will study patients with AF at Pen Bay Medical Center who have&#xD;
      undergone cardioversion, measuring their LA GLS pre-cardioversion, and assess maintenance of&#xD;
      sinus rhythm 6 months post-cardioversion. It is anticipated that this study will confirm LA&#xD;
      GLS as a marker for maintenance of sinus rhythm post-cardioversion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a retrospective and prospective cohort study of patients with atrial fibrillation (AF) identified at Pen Bay Medical Center (PBMC). Patients will be identified for inclusion in the study based on a previous documented diagnosis of AF, have a documented echocardiogram, and have undergone electrical cardioversion, with a study enrollment goal of 150 patients.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between left atrial global longitudinal strain and the maintenance of sinus rhythm after cardioversion</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient data will derive from existing electronic medical record (EPIC) data for PBMC patients from January 1, 2017 to November 8, 2018.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients identified at PBMC with a documented diagnosis of AF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients identified at PBMC with a documented diagnosis of AF (at any point in time) and who have undergone any cardioversion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Unique measurement (AutoSTRAIN) by a commercial software program (TOMTEC-ARENA)</intervention_name>
    <description>The historic echocardiograms from patients who meet the study inclusion criteria will be uploaded into this software, which was newly acquired by the PBMC Cardiology Department. MaineHealth Information Services are currently working with study staff to assure appropriate security compliance within the network. LA GLS has not been routinely collected previously from echocardiograms performed at PBMC because of a lack of such technology.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients identified at PBMC with a documented diagnosis of AF</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients identified at PBMC with a documented diagnosis of AF (at any point in time)&#xD;
             and who have undergone any cardioversion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patient would also need to have had an echocardiogram within six months&#xD;
                  pre-cardioversion (performed for any reason) with a well visualized atrial roof&#xD;
                  in order to perform the measurements accurately using the TOMTEC-ARENA software.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients with a mitral regurgitation greater than moderate (effective regurgitant&#xD;
             orifice &gt;= .2 mm2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with post-surgical valve repair or replacement, if the procedure was&#xD;
                  done with a thoracotomy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any patient how has had any cardiac surgery requiring a thoracotomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Crystal Blake-Parlin</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Pen Bay Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Caroline Knight, BSN</last_name>
    <phone>207-301-8959</phone>
    <email>cknight@pbmc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Crystal Blake-Parlin</last_name>
    <phone>207-301-8460</phone>
    <email>cblakeparl@wcgh.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pen Bay Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rockport</city>
        <state>Maine</state>
        <zip>04856</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Caroline Knight, BSN</last_name>
      <phone>207-301-8959</phone>
      <email>cknight@pbmc.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>MaineHealth</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Crystal Blake-Parlin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Program Supervisor-Lead Cardiac Ultrasound Sonographer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

