<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04311463</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>212969</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04311463</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bioequivalence Study of Paroxetine and PAXIL Under Fasting Conditions in Healthy Mexican Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Oral Single-dose, Randomized, Balanced, Open-label, Two-sequence, Two-treatment, Two-period, Crossover Bioequivalence Study of Paroxetine Tablets 20 mg of GlaxoSmithKline Pharmaceuticals S.A, With That of PAXIL (Paroxetine) Tablets 20 mg of GlaxoSmithKline México S.A. de C.V., in Healthy Adult Male and Female Subjects Under Fasting Conditions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will be conducted to evaluate and compare the single oral dose bioavailability of&#xD;
      Paroxetine manufactured by GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Pharmaceuticals S.A. for GlaxoSmithKline&#xD;
      México, S.A. de C.V. with that of PAXIL® (Paroxetine) of GlaxoSmithKline, México, S.A. de&#xD;
      C.V. in healthy, adult, male and female participants under fasting conditions. Maximum 38&#xD;
      participants will be randomized and dosed. The expected duration of this study will be 12&#xD;
      days including 7 days of washout period in-between each dosing. PAXIL is a registered&#xD;
      trademark of GSK group of companies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A single-dose, randomized, balanced, open-label, two-sequence, two-treatment, two-period, crossover bioequivalence study under fasting condition.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>This is an open-label study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed concentration (Cmax) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration-time curve from time zero to the last measurable concentration (AUC [0-t]) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of the maximum measured concentration (Tmax) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The area under the concentration versus time curve from time zero to infinity (AUC [0-inf]) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage AUC extrapolated (AUC_% Extrap) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (Kel) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Kel is estimated via linear regression of time versus (vs). logarithm (log) concentration. This parameter will be calculated using at least three or more non-zero plasma concentration values</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life (t1/2) of Paroxetine</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected for the concentrations of Paroxetine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events (AEs) and serious adverse events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 days</time_frame>
    <description>All AEs and SAEs will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormal medical examination and vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with abnormal medical examination and vital signs will be analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paroxetine hydrochloride followed by PAXIL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PAXIL followed by paroxetine hydrochloride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paroxetine hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Paroxetine hydrochloride will be administered.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PAXIL followed by paroxetine hydrochloride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Paroxetine hydrochloride followed by PAXIL</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PAXIL (Paroxetine hydrochloride )</intervention_name>
    <description>PAXIL will be administered.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PAXIL followed by paroxetine hydrochloride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Paroxetine hydrochloride followed by PAXIL</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy adult male and female participants aged between 18 and 55 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is a light smoker (someone who smokes 9 or less cigarettes per day) or&#xD;
             non- or an ex-smoker (someone who completely stopped smoking for at least 6 months&#xD;
             before day 1 of this study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a weight greater than or equal to (&gt;=)50.00 kilograms (kg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a body mass index (BMI) &gt;=18.5 kilograms per meter square (kg/m^2) and less than&#xD;
             or equal to (&lt;=)27.0 kg/m^2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Found healthy according to the clinical laboratory results and physical examination&#xD;
             (performed within 90 days prior to the dosing on period -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a normal 12 lead electrocardiogram (ECG) and vital signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have laboratory test results within the laboratory's stated normal range; if not&#xD;
             within this range, they must lack of no clinical significance as judged by the&#xD;
             principal investigator (PI) or responsible physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to avoid sexual contact or use an acceptable contraceptive method during the&#xD;
             study including the washout period (for females). In case of male participants, they&#xD;
             should avoid sexual contact or use a latex or synthetic condom each time they have sex&#xD;
             with a woman while taking Paroxetine and during 7 days after the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If study participant is a female and is of child bearing potential, practicing an&#xD;
             acceptable method of birth control for the duration of the study as judged by the&#xD;
             investigators, like combined short acting (estrogen and progestogen containing)&#xD;
             hormonal contraception for example (e.g.) oral, intravaginal, and progestogen-only&#xD;
             hormonal contraception e.g. oral, intrauterine device (IUD), intrauterine&#xD;
             hormone-releasing system (IUS), condoms, foams, jellies and diaphragm or abstinence or&#xD;
             if study participant is a female and is postmenopausal for at-least 1 year or is&#xD;
             surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy&#xD;
             has been performed on the study participant).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a negative test for active Coronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19), within 72 hours&#xD;
             prior to the first period check-in. The testing should be done using a molecular (Real&#xD;
             time-Polymerase Chain Reaction [RT-PCR]) approved by the country regulatory&#xD;
             authorities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is able to communicate effectively and voluntarily agreed to participate&#xD;
             in this study by signing written informed consent after being informed sufficiently&#xD;
             about study aspects like objectives, study procedures, characteristics of the&#xD;
             investigational drug, expected adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant willing to adhere to protocol requirements as described in informed&#xD;
             consent (written) approved by research ethics committee/research committee (REC/RC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If participants age is less than 18 or older than 55 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any history of allergy or hypersensitivity to Paroxetine or derivatives to any of&#xD;
             its metabolites/derivatives or related drugs or excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a positive test result for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBs Ag) or hepatitis C&#xD;
             virus antibody (HCV Ab) or human immune deficiency virus (HIV) antibodies (types 1 and&#xD;
             2) or venereal disease research laboratory (VDRL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with symptoms suggestive of active COVID-19 infection (that is, fever,&#xD;
             cough, respiratory difficulties) within 14 days of inpatient admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with known COVID-19 positive contact (meaning if the participant has been&#xD;
             living, providing care, being within 1.5 meters for at least 15 min or having exposure&#xD;
             to respiratory secretions with/to a person who has COVID-19) within the past 14 days&#xD;
             prior to the first period check-in. Study drug is contraindicated for medical reasons&#xD;
             to the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any history or presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, seizures, endocrine, dermatological, neurological or psychiatric&#xD;
             disease or disorder (e.g. participants with uncontrolled hypertension,&#xD;
             pheochromocytoma, carcinoid, thyrotoxicosis, bipolar depression, schizoaffective&#xD;
             disorder and acute confusional states).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of significant gastrointestinal, hepatic or kidney disease, or surgery or any&#xD;
             other conditions known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or&#xD;
             excretion of drugs or known to potentiate or predispose to undesired effects or&#xD;
             participants with a history of gastrointestinal disorder or surgery which may affect&#xD;
             the absorption of investigational drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of alcohol abuse or drug abuse during the last 1 year prior to period&#xD;
             -1 dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of smoking &gt;=10 cigarettes per day during the last 6 months prior to&#xD;
             period -1 dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have history or presence of cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any history of gastrointestinal ulcers/intestinal bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have history of difficulty for donating blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have clinically significant abnormal laboratory tests results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a systolic blood pressure less than (&lt;)90 or greater than (&gt;)140 millimeters of&#xD;
             mercury (mmHg) or diastolic blood pressure is &lt;60 or &gt;90 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a pulse rate &lt;60 beats/minute or &gt;100 beats/minute (lower range of pulse range&#xD;
             will be accepted up to 45 beats/minute in case of athlete).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have used any prescribed medication during the last 14 days preceding the first&#xD;
             dosing, or use over-the-counter (OTC), medicinal or herbal products during the last 7&#xD;
             days or use medicinal enzyme inhibitors / inducers during last 30 days preceding the&#xD;
             first dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have participated in a drug research study or donated blood within the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a positive result for drugs of abuse test (cannabinoids&#xD;
             [marijuana/tetrahydrocannabinol-(THC)], cocaine, opiates/morphine, amphetamine,&#xD;
             methamphetamine and benzodiazepines] performed during screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant, who is currently breast feeding or a who is pregnant or who is&#xD;
             likely to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant has a positive pregnancy test results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness or inability to comply with the instructions on the lifestyle.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the PI considers, for any reason, that the volunteer is not a suitable candidate to&#xD;
             receive the study drug.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monterrey</city>
        <state>Nuevo León</state>
        <zip>66260</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anxiety Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>Bioequivalence study</keyword>
  <keyword>Paroxetine hydrochloride</keyword>
  <keyword>PAXIL</keyword>
  <keyword>Fasting condition</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paroxetine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD for this study will be made available via the Clinical Study Data Request site.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>IPD will be made available within 6 months of publishing the results of the primary endpoints, key secondary endpoints and safety data of the study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access is provided after a research proposal is submitted and has received approval from the Independent Review Panel and after a Data Sharing Agreement is in place. Access is provided for an initial period of 12 months but an extension can be granted, when justified, for up to another 12 months.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://clinicalstudydatarequest.com</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

