<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04490213</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018/212-31</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04490213</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Scarring At Donor Sites After Split-Thickness Skin Graft.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Scarring At Donor Sites After Split-Thickness Skin Graft: A Prospective, Longitudinal, Randomised Trial; The Observer's View</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Linkoeping</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Linkoeping</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study was to investigate if previous findings on the association between&#xD;
      dressing treatments and subjective opinion on final donor site scar outcome using the patient&#xD;
      scale of POSAS could be confirmed objectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Scar outcome measurements were assessed by a blinded observer using POSAS and the device:&#xD;
      Cutometer dual MPA 580 (Courage and Khazaka Electronic GmbH, Cologne, Germany) to measure the&#xD;
      viscoelasticity of the skin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is the third and last part of a clinical project concerning the treatment of split&#xD;
      thickness skin graft donor sites. In the first part the Investigators completed a randomised&#xD;
      clinical trial (RCT) in which donor sites were randomly assigned to treatment with either&#xD;
      hydrofibre covered with film, non-adhesive polyurethane foam, or porcine xenograft. Results&#xD;
      from the first study indicated that donor sites treated with hydrofibre and porcine xenograft&#xD;
      healed significantly faster than those treated with polyurethane foam. As the hydrofibre was&#xD;
      the most comfortable, easy to use, and cost-effective it was implemented as the standard of&#xD;
      care for donor sites at the specific centre.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the initial RCT, patients treated with polyurethane foam showed significantly longer&#xD;
      healing times than the other treatment groups. As longer healing time has been shown to be a&#xD;
      predictor for pathological donor site scarring it was hypothesised that this group would be&#xD;
      the most unsatisfied with their scars, if they had any donor site scar at all eight years&#xD;
      after their skin graft. In the second part of the project the long-term scar outcomes of the&#xD;
      donor sites included in the RCT was investigated. Study participants were asked to evaluate&#xD;
      their scars using the &quot;Patients part&quot; of the Patient and Observer Scar Scale (POSAS). After&#xD;
      analysing the data collected in the second part, it was concluded that the fast and moist&#xD;
      healing seen with hydrofibre seemed to result in significantly more satisfied patients - and&#xD;
      members of the polyurethane foam group, as hypothesised, were significantly more unsatisfied&#xD;
      with their donor site scars. The Investigators also found that the dressing associated with&#xD;
      the fastest wound healing (the porcine xenograft) also had the poorest long-term outcome for&#xD;
      scarring, according to the patients' opinion. This contradicts what is claimed to be the&#xD;
      relation between duration of healing and donor site scarring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this last, third study, the aim was to investigate if the previous findings could be&#xD;
      confirmed by an evaluation done by a blinded observer using POSAS. Donor sites were also&#xD;
      evaluated for firmness and elasticity using the device; Cutometer dual MPA 580 (Courage and&#xD;
      Khazaka Electronic GmbH, Cologne, Germany), which is described in the Method section.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 15, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>donor sites scar outcome according to a blinded observer</measure>
    <time_frame>within 9 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>evaluated with the scar scale Patient and Observer Scar Assesment Scale (POSAS). The scale contains six items that are scored numerically and when added, constitutes the &quot;Total Score&quot; of the Patient or the Observer Scale. Each of the six items on both scales has a 10-point range (1 - 10), with 10 indicating the worst imaginable scar or sensation. The lowest score, &quot;1&quot; corresponds to the normal skin.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>donor sites scar outcome according to a cutometer</measure>
    <time_frame>within 9 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of elasticity and firmness with cutometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">17</enrollment>
  <condition>Donor Site Complication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hydrofibre, Aquacel</arm_group_label>
    <description>Study participants were previously treated on their donor sites with these CE-marked dressing products (RCT study published in 2014) and are now compared regarding scar outcome at the donor sites</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>polyurethane foam, Allevyn</arm_group_label>
    <description>Study participants were previolsuy treated on their donor sites with these CE-marked dressing products (RCT study published in 2014) and are now compared regarding scar outcome at the donor sites</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>porcine xenograft, Mediskin</arm_group_label>
    <description>Study participants were previolsuy treated on their donor sites with these CE-marked dressing products (RCT study published in 2014) and are now compared regarding scar outcome at the donor sites</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Allevyn, Aquacel and Tegaderm, Mediskin</intervention_name>
    <description>Wound dressing tested earlier on donor sites, in this study scar outcome between the 3 dressing groups are compared.</description>
    <arm_group_label>hydrofibre, Aquacel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>polyurethane foam, Allevyn</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>porcine xenograft, Mediskin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>polyurethan foam, hydrofibre, film, porcone xenograft</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Of the 27 participants in the second part of the study, two had died, six (with a total of&#xD;
        8 donor sites) chose not to participate and two did not answer our letter. The remaining 17&#xD;
        were included in the Observer follow up. Of the 17 participants, five came from the&#xD;
        hydrofibre group, six from the polyurethane foam, and six from porcine xenograft group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participation in part I (RCT) and part II of the project&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        No former participation in the project&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Burn Centre at Linköping University Hospital,</name>
      <address>
        <city>Linköping</city>
        <zip>58185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 26, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital, Linkoeping</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Folke Sjoberg</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cicatrix</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carboxymethylcellulose Sodium</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

