<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04494334</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19SM5398</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>239911</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04494334</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Development of Airway Absorption Sampling Methods</brief_title>
  <acronym>FIBRO-SAM</acronym>
  <official_title>Development of Airway Absorption Sampling Methods for Biomarker Assessment in Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF) Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Imperial College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will measure airway inflammation in probable idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF)&#xD;
      and sarcoidosis as well as in healthy volunteers. This can help understand the molecular&#xD;
      basis of these diseases, why these diseases happen, and what makes patients develop lung&#xD;
      fibrosis. These insights should one day help to monitor patients and aid in their diagnosis&#xD;
      and treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      IPF is a progressive disease caused by irreversible scarring of the lung, and disease&#xD;
      trajectory is not easily predicted based on clinical measurements. Biomarkers reflective of&#xD;
      molecular pathways involved in IPF may help inform patient trajectory, but have been&#xD;
      difficult to identify in circulation due to the disease manifesting in the lung. The study&#xD;
      team will measure biomarkers from Probable IPF patients, sarcoidosis patients, and healthy&#xD;
      volunteers using novel sampling methods involving absorption of upper and lower airway&#xD;
      fluids. These novel sampling methods may enable less invasive and potentially more sensitive&#xD;
      methods to detect disease activity and will be performed in IPF and sarcoidosis patients&#xD;
      during a routine bronchoscopy procedure. The study team will compare the levels of biomarkers&#xD;
      that have been shown to be predictive of disease course in airway fluids of probable IPF&#xD;
      patients versus sarcoidosis and healthy controls. This study may help understand the&#xD;
      molecular basis of IPF, and improve the understanding of diagnosis and treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of the of biomarker/mediator surfactant protein D (SPD) in bronchial Lining fluid in IPF and sarcoidosis patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline Bronchoscopy visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of bronchial lining fluid levels of biomarker/mediator surfactant protein D (SPD), in patients with IPF and sarcoidosis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of the biomarker/mediator CCL18 in bronchial Lining fluid in IPF and sarcoidosis patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline Bronchoscopy visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of bronchial lining fluid levels of biomarker/mediator CCL18 in patients with IPF and sarcoidosis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of the biomarker/mediator CXCL13 in bronchial Lining fluid in IPF and sarcoidosis patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline Bronchoscopy visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of bronchial lining fluid levels of biomarker/mediator CXCL13 in patients with IPF and sarcoidosis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of the of biomarker/mediator periostin in bronchial Lining fluid in IPF and sarcoidosis patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline Bronchoscopy visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of bronchial lining fluid levels of biomarker/mediator periostin in patients with IPF and sarcoidosis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of Periostin in nasosorption samples within and across the 3 groups of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of airways levels of biomarker/mediator periostin between patients with IPF and sarcoidosis and health volunteers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of surfactant protein (SPD) in nasosorption samples within and across the 3 groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of airways levels of biomarker/mediator surfactant protein D (SPD) between patients with IPF and sarcoidosis and health volunteers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of CCL18 in nasosorption samples within and across the 3 groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of airways levels of biomarker/mediator CCL18 between patients with IPF and sarcoidosis and health volunteers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of CXCL13 in nasosorption samples within and across the 3 groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparisons will be made of airways levels of biomarker/mediator CXCL13 between patients with IPF and sarcoidosis and health volunteers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of periostin in blood within and across the 3 groups of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be made of periostin levels in blood with nasosorption and bronchosorption levels across the 3 participant groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of surfactant protein D (SPD in blood within and across the 3 groups of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be made of surfactant protein D (SPD levels in blood with nasosorption and bronchosorption levels across the 3 participant groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of CCL18 in blood within and across the 3 groups of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be made of CCL18 levels in blood with nasosorption and bronchosorption levels across the 3 participant groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of CXCL13 in blood within and across the 3 groups of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be made of CXCL13 levels in blood with nasosorption and bronchosorption levels across the 3 participant groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</condition>
  <condition>Sarcoidosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <description>These will be age matched healthy volunteers (n=15) who will not undergo bronchoscopy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with probable IPF, who will be having bronchoscopy as part of their clinical diagnostic work up</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sarcoidosis,</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with sarcoidosis who will be having bronchoscopy as part of their clinical diagnostic work up</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bronchoscopy for Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis and Sarcoidosis</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood samples and Nasosorption sampling</description>
    <arm_group_label>Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sarcoidosis,</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients diagnosed with probable IPF and Sarcoidosis will be included. Patients with&#xD;
        probable IPF and Sarcoidosis will be selected from clinic lists for patients undergoing&#xD;
        bronchoscopy as part of their clinical assessment, and they will be invited to participate&#xD;
        in this study that involves additional sampling for clinical research purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Probable IPF patients must have Usual Interstitial Pneumonitis (UIP) on CT scan and will be&#xD;
        sub classified by gas transfer (DLco corrected for haemoglobin as detailed below;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild (DLco&gt;60)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate (DLco 40-60)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe (DLco&lt;40)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy volunteers (age/sex matched, non-smoking, without a clinical history of atopy).&#xD;
&#xD;
        The patient populations will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF), n=30&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sarcoidosis patients, n=15&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy Volunteers n=15&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion Criteria for Probable Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult male or female patients aged 40 to 85 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing age should not be pregnant, planning to get pregnant or&#xD;
             breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Command of the English language to be able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probable IPF requiring bronchoscopy to confirm the diagnosis, agreed within the local&#xD;
             multi-disciplinary team (MDT).,according to the American Thoracic Society/European&#xD;
             Respiratory Society/Japanese Respiratory Society/ American Latin Thoracic Association&#xD;
             (ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT) guidelines (2018) (3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IPF disease diagnosis within the past 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Usual Interstitial Pneumonia (UIP) on HRCT scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent lung function criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Forced vital capacity (FVC) &gt;40% of predicted value.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Carbon monoxide diffusing lung capacity (DLco) corrected for haemoglobin &gt;30% of&#xD;
                  predicted value&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Sarcoidosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult male or female patients aged 18 years and over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing age should not be pregnant, planning to get pregnant or&#xD;
             breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical symptoms, CT scan and biopsy diagnosis of sarcoidosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with lung parenchymal disease and pulmonary stage II or more&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent lung function criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FVC&gt;50% predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  DLCO &gt;40% predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Healthy Volunteers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 40 to 85 years, age and sex to match the group with IPF&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy subjects without any diseases that may cause inflammation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing age should not be pregnant, planning to get pregnant or&#xD;
             breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently non-smokers: see exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:Exclusion Criteria for probable IPF and Sarcoidosis Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        Respiratory Conditions other than IPF or sarcoidosis:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of occupational lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug-induced lung disease or hypersensitivity pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lung and systemic autoimmune disease including connective tissue disease. Patients&#xD;
             with an auto-immune profile considered diagnostic for a specific connective tissue&#xD;
             disease will be excluded, even in the absence of systemic symptoms. Non-specific rises&#xD;
             in auto antibodies e.g. rheumatoid factor; anti-nuclear antibody etc. will not be used&#xD;
             to exclude individuals from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asbestosis or other asbestos related disease (pleural plaques, mesothelioma, asbestos&#xD;
             pleural effusions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Granulomatous lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary artery hypertension (PAH) requiring a specific treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Predominant chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) with forced expiratory volume&#xD;
             in 1 second /forced vital capacity (FEV1/FVC) &lt;0.70.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active tuberculosis or incompletely treated latent tuberculosis&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Upper respiratory tract infections in the past 6 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Systemic Conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of vasculitis, autoimmune or connective tissue disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or chronic viral hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant diseases (other than IPF or sarcoidosis) that may alter&#xD;
             respiratory biomarkers: including other respiratory, gastrointestinal, endocrine,&#xD;
             haematological, cardiovascular, genitourinary, skin or neurological diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent or ongoing malignant diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant nasal anatomical defects preventing nasal sampling: including hypertrophy&#xD;
             of turbinates, major septum deviation, nasal polyposis or recurrent sinusitis and&#xD;
             nasal mucosal defects&#xD;
&#xD;
        Bronchoscopy Contraindications&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any contra-indication to bronchoscopy as set out in British Thoracic Society guidelines&#xD;
        (34)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
        A detailed smoking history will be taken from all participants: to include total pack&#xD;
        years, smoking in the past year, and smoking in the past 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The history will include cigarettes, pipe smoking, cigars, vaping, and shisha. Any form of&#xD;
        smoking is not permitted within 2 weeks of bronchoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5.4.2 Exclusion Criteria for Healthy Volunteers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current inflammatory/ immunological conditions. Any clinically significant diseases&#xD;
             that may alter respiratory biomarkers: including respiratory, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             endocrine, haematological, cardiovascular, genitourinary, skin or neurological&#xD;
             diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent or ongoing malignant diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant nasal anatomical defects preventing nasal sampling: including hypertrophy&#xD;
             of turbinates, major septum deviation, nasal polyposis or recurrent sinusitis and&#xD;
             nasal mucosal defects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Upper respiratory tract infections in the past 6 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cigarette smoking:&#xD;
&#xD;
        no cigarettes in the last 2 weeks not more than 10 cigarettes in the past year &lt;10 year&#xD;
        lifetime pack history of smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Melissa Wickremasinghe</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Physician</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melissa Wickremasinghe</last_name>
    <phone>02033121344</phone>
    <email>melissa.wickremasinghe@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Trevor Hansel</last_name>
    <phone>00442033125733</phone>
    <email>t.hansel@imperial.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sarcoidosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>June 8, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/34/NCT04494334/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

