<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04497740</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GO20529</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04497740</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Follow-up Results of Newborns With Tracheostomy</brief_title>
  <acronym>FRONWT</acronym>
  <official_title>Retrospective Evaluation of Follow-up Results of Newborns Who Underwent Tracheostomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hacettepe University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hacettepe University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The chances of survival in premature babies, especially in babies born under 28 weeks, have&#xD;
      increased in recent years, and comorbidities also increase. Bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD),&#xD;
      one of the premature problems, is one of them. After a while, babies with heavy BPD are&#xD;
      discharged with the support of a home-type mechanical ventilator by opening a tracheostomy.&#xD;
      Tracheostomy procedure is performed by specialist doctors of otolaryngology under general&#xD;
      anesthesia in the operating room conditions in newborns. Complications of this procedure such&#xD;
      as bleeding, skin necrosis, decanulation, trachea laceration and infection in the early&#xD;
      period can be seen. In the long term, in addition to complications such as formation of&#xD;
      tracheal granulation tissue, ulceration, laceration due to the procedure, babies with&#xD;
      tracheostomy may develop nutrition and speech problems and neurodevelopmental problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the literature, there is no comprehensive clinical follow-up study involving early and&#xD;
      late clinical results related to newborns undergoing tracheostomy. In this study, early and&#xD;
      late follow-up results (indications, anthropometric measurements, mechanical ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygen deposition times, complications, tracheostomy closure times, tracheostomy closure&#xD;
      times, neurodevelopmental patients in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit of Hacettepe&#xD;
      University Ihsan Dogramaci Children's Hospital. results, accompanying other comorbidities,&#xD;
      etc.).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      With the advances in science and technology in recent years, the rate of survival of&#xD;
      high-risk newborns has increased in neonatal intensive care units. Some of these babies are&#xD;
      left in the neonatal intensive care unit for a long time, and because of the need for&#xD;
      respiratory support, tracheostomy is opened and discharged with home mechanical ventilator&#xD;
      devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Especially babies with severe BPD cannot be extubated and they may be exposed to trauma of&#xD;
      long-term intubation. Subglottic stenosis is the most common result of this trauma. Some of&#xD;
      the babies with severe BPD are discharged by the otolaryngology specialist doctor before&#xD;
      discharge, to prevent both long-term intubation complications, airway obstruction or tracheal&#xD;
      stenosis and adaptation to the home mechanical ventilator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to babies with BPD, tracheostomy is opened to babies in the early period due to&#xD;
      various developmental tracheal anomalies in our unit. Some of these are congenital tracheal&#xD;
      stenosis, congenital laryngeal atresia, laryngeal web.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the following process, the growth of the baby, the development of the lungs and auxiliary&#xD;
      respiratory muscles and the need for mechanical ventilator support are eliminated and the&#xD;
      patient can wean from the ventilator support. In addition, the tracheostomy procedure secures&#xD;
      the patient's airway and allows it to be fed easily by mouth and the comfort of the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When the tracheostomy requirement of the patient disappears (mechanical ventilator, when&#xD;
      oxygen is not needed), tracheostomy closure can be performed to ensure the patient has normal&#xD;
      larynx functions (sounding, speech, airway protection reflexes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the literature, there is no comprehensive clinical follow-up study involving early and&#xD;
      late clinical results related to newborns undergoing tracheostomy. In this study, early and&#xD;
      late follow-up results (indications, anthropometric measurements, mechanical ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygen deposition times, complications, tracheostomy closure times, tracheostomy closure&#xD;
      times, neurodevelopmental patients in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit of Hacettepe&#xD;
      University Ihsan Dogramaci Children's Hospital results, accompanying other comorbidities,&#xD;
      etc.). This study is planned as a retrospective study. Participants planned to determine the&#xD;
      results of the study whether these babies should be careful in the follow-up and to take&#xD;
      precautions in order to lead a better and healthier life, and what participants can do in&#xD;
      order to provide these babies and their families with better health care support.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>follow up after tracheostomy</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Follow-up of patients who have been in our NICU for the last fifteen years and discharged with tracheostomy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>evaluation of tracheostomy opening indications</measure>
    <time_frame>15 years</time_frame>
    <description>indications of tracheostomy in the last fifteen years in our unit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Premature</condition>
  <condition>Tracheostomy Complication</condition>
  <condition>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        These are the babies who stayed in Hacettepe University Ihsan Dogramaci Children's Hospital&#xD;
        Neonatal Intensive Care Unit between 01.01.2005-31.12.2019, underwent tracheostomy&#xD;
        procedure and followed up at risky neonatal outpatient clinic.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  These are the babies who stayed in Hacettepe University Ihsan Dogramaci Children's&#xD;
             Hospital Neonatal Intensive Care Unit between 01.01.2005-31.12.2019, underwent&#xD;
             tracheostomy procedure and followed up at risky neonatal outpatient clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newborns whose file and follow-up information required for the study are not available&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hasan T Celik, Ass Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+905305925584</phone>
    <email>htcelik@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hacettepe University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30396419/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hacettepe University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>H. Tolga Çelik</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>June 10, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/40/NCT04497740/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

