<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04494633</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>271330</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04494633</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Summative Assessment of the BurntOut 3D Simulation With Medical Students</brief_title>
  <official_title>Summative Assessment of the BurntOut 3D Simulation With Medical Students</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clinical Tools, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clinical Tools, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Burnout is a common problem for medical students and is associated with stress-related health&#xD;
      problems and also potentially affects the quality of care delivered to their patients. Among&#xD;
      the health problems commonly associated with burnout are substance use problems, and alcohol&#xD;
      is the substance most often misused. The purpose of the evaluation is to document whether an&#xD;
      educational intervention delivered via a 3D online simulation experience prevents or improves&#xD;
      the primary endpoint of burnout and the secondary endpoints of burnout-related factors in&#xD;
      medical students. The investigators will also will evaluate student satisfaction with the&#xD;
      intervention to determine if it meets our standard of success. The hypothesis is that the&#xD;
      intervention will improve the primary clinical endpoint of burnout from pre-intervention to&#xD;
      post-intervention as measured by the Maslach Burnout Inventory, a validated inventory that is&#xD;
      widely used to measure burnout. The related factors that will be measured as secondary&#xD;
      clinical endpoints include quality of life, substance use (alcohol and drugs), depression,&#xD;
      and resilience. Due to evidence that these endpoints are linked to burnout, the investigators&#xD;
      also hypothesize that the measures will improve pre- to post-intervention. Satisfaction of&#xD;
      the target audience after completing the simulation intervention will also be evaluated. The&#xD;
      evaluation will be prior to and after use of the simulation by medical student participants,&#xD;
      using a pre-/post intervention wait-list crossover design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will use a pre-/post-intervention design with wait-list controls who also&#xD;
      will receive the intervention. The investigators will recruit and enroll 80 medical students&#xD;
      who are in pre-clinical years of medical school. The number of participants selected is based&#xD;
      on a power analysis of the design and experience of low dropout rate with this target&#xD;
      audience; to reach a medium effect size the investigators plan for a final sample size of 68&#xD;
      medical students. During the intervention phase of the study, students will 1) Complete the&#xD;
      simulation experience: 6 to 8 tailored scenarios and resilience-building activities (taking&#xD;
      around 2 hours over a period of around 4 weeks); and 2) Complete pre-/post- assessments (each&#xD;
      taking around 1 hour) plus a follow-up survey after 3 months. The investigators will screen&#xD;
      for and exclude students with severe depression and suicidality. The primary clinical&#xD;
      endpoint will be burnout as measured by the Maslach Burnout Inventory. Secondary endpoints&#xD;
      will be measured via the following assessments: Medical Student Quality of Life, PHQ2/PHQ9 to&#xD;
      screen for depression, CD-RISC 2 for resiliency, AUDIT-C/AUDIT for alcohol use disorder and&#xD;
      two drug question screening for drug use, and CSQ8 for satisfaction plus questions adapted&#xD;
      from the Game User Experience Satisfaction survey and Intrinsic Motivation Inventory to&#xD;
      further describe the experience. After 4 weeks, the control and experimental (intervention)&#xD;
      groups will cross over to the opposite status and control participants will engage in the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Users will report decreased levels of burn out, as measured on the Maslach Burnout Inventory. This scale uses 22 items to assess emotional exhaustion, depersonalization, and measure the sense of personal accomplishment. Higher scores indicate higher, and thus more problematic, levels of burnout. There are 3 scales:&#xD;
Emotional exhaustion, scores from 0-54 with higher scores indicating more exhaustion;&#xD;
Depersonalization, scores from 0-30, with higher scores indicating more depersonalization;&#xD;
Personal achievement, scores from 0-48, with lower scores indicating a worse outcome of less feeling of personal achievement.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol misuse</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Users will have decrease scores on the Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test, AUDIT-C, after the intervention. This instrument is a screening tool to identify users who are hazardous drinkers or who have active alcohol use disorder.&#xD;
Minimum value: 0, Maximum value 12. High scores indicate better outcomes.&#xD;
A score of over 4 for men, and over 3 for women is considered a positive screen for alcohol misuse. Higher scores suggest a higher likelihood that alcohol use is negatively impacting the person's health and safety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will complete the 2 item Patient Health Questionaire, PHQ-2.&#xD;
The PHQ-2 is a two-item screen where respondents indicate how often the respondent has experienced depressed mood and anhedonia over the prior two weeks.&#xD;
Minimum value: 0, Maximum value 6. High scores indicate worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in this area will be measured via the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale - a 2 item scale.&#xD;
Minimum value: 0, Maximum value 8. Low scores indicate worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Drug use</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Substance use in the past 3 months will be measured via the National Institute for Drug Abuse-Modified Alcohol, Smoking and Substance Involvement Screening Test (3 items).&#xD;
Minimum 0, Maximum value 390 High scores indicate worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Happiness; Exhaustion</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Users will report better Quality of Life after using the intervention for 3 months than at baseline.&#xD;
The Medical Student Quality of Life Questionnaire with Nine Items, MSQoL9. The MSQofL is a linear self-assessment analog scale. Users rate their overall quality of life focused on the two domains of exhaustion and general happiness.&#xD;
Minimum value: 0, Maximum value 10. High scores indicate better outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Burnout, Student</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol; Harmful Use</condition>
  <condition>Quality of Life</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Resilience</condition>
  <condition>Drug Use</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete the pre-assessments, use the intervention, complete the assessments, wait 4 weeks, and complete the assessment a 3/final time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wait Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete the pre-assessments, wait, complete the assessments, use the intervention, complete the assessment a 3/final time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clinical Encounters Medical School VR Simulation</intervention_name>
    <description>A VR based simulation related to coping with the stresses of medical school and burnout.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wait Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  US Medical students in years 1-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has access to a computer with Internet access&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A score of less than 20 points on the PHQ9 before enrollment (indicating severe&#xD;
             depression)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Answer of &quot;NO&quot; to the PHQ9 question &quot;being better off dead&quot; or considering self-harm&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mary P Metcalf, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinical Tools, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mary Metcalf, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>9199608118</phone>
    <email>billing@clinicaltools.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Karen Rossie</last_name>
    <phone>9199608118</phone>
    <email>admin@clinicaltools.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Tools, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27516</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Metcalf, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>919-960-8118</phone>
      <email>billing@clinicaltools.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Karen Rossie, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>9199608118</phone>
      <email>admin@clinicaltools.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bradley Tanner, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

