<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04495452</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300004738</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04495452</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Precision Medicine in Anesthesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Precision Medicine in Anesthesia: Genetic Component in Opioid-induced Respiratory Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to look at how often a decrease in the rate of breathing occurs after&#xD;
      being given a routinely used intravenous (IV) pain medication. This pain medication&#xD;
      (Fentanyl) is given in the research procedure room by the anesthesiologist. In addition to&#xD;
      relieving pain, in some patients it has been observed that this medication may decrease the&#xD;
      rate of breathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different pieces of one's genetic makeup (also known as genes) can affect how well this&#xD;
      medication relieves pain. The investigators do not know if these same genes influence how&#xD;
      large the effect of the medication has on breathing rate. The purpose of this study is to&#xD;
      determine if the presence or alteration of these same genes may be associated with a decrease&#xD;
      in rate of breathing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Opioids are key analgesic drugs. Unfortunately, they have a high potential for abuse with&#xD;
      potentially lethal consequences, more specifically death due to respiratory suppression. In&#xD;
      both Canada and the US, the number of deaths from opioid overdose continues to rise at an&#xD;
      alarming rate, far exceeding fatalities from motor vehicle accidents in Canada and becoming&#xD;
      the number one cause of unintentional injury-related death in the US. In light of the opioid&#xD;
      epidemic and CDC-scrutiny of opioid use, determining genetic profiles susceptible to&#xD;
      respiratory depression could prove useful in further tailoring the treatment of pain both in&#xD;
      the perioperative setting and in the chronic pain management setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the proposed study is to evaluate for a genetic component of opioid-induced&#xD;
      respiratory depression. Our overall study hypothesis is that genetic variation influences&#xD;
      opioid-induced respiratory depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of the study is to correlate an intravenous opioid bolus and genetic&#xD;
      variations of opioid-related target genes. Secondary aims or outcomes are the determination&#xD;
      of general variation in respiratory responses in response to a single intravenous fentanyl&#xD;
      bolus. Other observed effects are age and gender related differences, the effect of a single&#xD;
      fentanyl bolus on alertness, the incidence of emesis and opioid effects on micturition as&#xD;
      determined by the modified Aldrete discharge criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on existing work on genetic determinants of opioid receptor effects, we propose to&#xD;
      correlate clinical parameters of respiratory depression (proportional reduction in&#xD;
      respiratory minute ventilation) with the expression of single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs)&#xD;
      of genes related to opioid-induced analgesia. We propose to identify a subset of participants&#xD;
      with the most significant respiratory depression and contrast those with participants that&#xD;
      exhibit no respiratory effects. The blood samples from these two groups will be used to&#xD;
      compare genetic variances of genes related to opioid-induced analgesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a collaborative project between the clinical physicians and basic scientists in&#xD;
      an effort to better characterize opioid-induced respiratory depression. We believe this work&#xD;
      will be valuable as a means to prevent and treat opioid toxicity and guide development of&#xD;
      safer approaches to opioid therapy and drug development.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of administration of study medication to 10 minutes after study medication administration</time_frame>
    <description>A decrease in breathing frequency as quantified by respiratory rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minute Ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of administration of study medication to 10 minutes after study medication administration</time_frame>
    <description>A decrease in breathing as quantified by minute ventilation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occlusion Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of administration of study medication to 10 minutes after study medication administration</time_frame>
    <description>A measure of respiratory depression as quantified by occlusion pressure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>We will be enrolling 200 participants, this will provide a large enough sampling to assure there are at least 25 patients with significant respiratory depression and 25 with insignificant respiratory depression.&#xD;
The genetic data from participants with the most respiratory depression defined as having a 20-40% decrease from initial respiratory parameters will be compared with genetic data from participants with the least respiratory depression defined as having no change or less than 10% decrease from initial respiratory parameters.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fentanyl Drug Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be given a standardized dose of fentanyl 2.5 mcg/kg estimated ideal body weight (males: ideal body weight = 50 kg + 2.3 kg for each inch over 5 feet. Females: Ideal body weight = 45.5 kg + 2.3 kg for each inch over 5 feet).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      A blood sample (about 10 mL) will be collected either during the IV line insertion or after&#xD;
      fentanyl administration during the recovery period&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study will involve adult human volunteers, representative of the greater Alabama&#xD;
        population.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  older than 19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to follow the study instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that could affect study procedures or potentially put the&#xD;
             subject at risk, in the opinion of the investigators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age less than 18 or older than 40&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  obesity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sleep apnea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pulmonary problems such as moderate or severe bronchial asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic analgesic medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of surgery for which details are unavailable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to fentanyl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  positive urine test for illicit drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  female participants will be scheduled for a urine pregnancy test on the day of the&#xD;
             procedure, prior to receiving study medication, only subjects with negative tests will&#xD;
             continue&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alethia Sellers, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adam Sturdivant, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>205-934-4042</phone>
    <email>Adamsturdivant@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ayesha Bryant, MD, MSPH</last_name>
    <phone>205-934-4969</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alethia Sellers</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

