<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04492631</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P1940120</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04492631</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety of an Oral Probiotic in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A 4-Week Study to Evaluate the Safety of a Probiotic Water Containing Streptococcus Salivarius DB-B5 in Healthy Volunteer Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dose Biosystems Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dose Biosystems Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety of an oral probiotic in healthy&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The oral cavity houses one of the most diverse microbiota in the human body. There are nearly&#xD;
      800 unique oral bacterial species identified with more species expected to be added with&#xD;
      further sampling and identification. As with microbiota of other sites in the human body, a&#xD;
      balanced oral microbiota is essential to maintaining the health of the human host.&#xD;
      Streptococcus salivarius is a pioneer species that colonizes the human oral cavity from&#xD;
      birth, and remains a predominant member of the commensal microbiota throughout life. This&#xD;
      randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study is conducted to investigate the safety and&#xD;
      tolerability of a Streptococcus salivarius DB-B5 strain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 21, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 21, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reports of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Reports of adverse events will be collected and compared between the probiotic and placebo groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in gastrointestinal symptoms measured using the Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Gastrointestinal tolerability to the test products will be assessed using the Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS). The GSRS is composed of 15 items covering 5 dimensions: Reflux, Abdominal pain, Indigestion, Diarrhea and Constipation. The GSRS has a seven-point graded Likert-type scale where 1 represents absence of troublesome symptoms and 7 represents very troublesome symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of abnormal blood laboratory test results</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood samples will be collected at baseline and end-of-study visits to assess for changes in hematology parameters (complete blood count including differentials and platelets).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of abnormal clinical chemistry parameters test results</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood samples will be collected at baseline and end-of-study visits to assess for changes in clinical chemistry parameters (basic metabolic panel, hepatic function panel).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of abnormal urinalysis test results</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Urine samples will be collected at baseline and end-of-study visits to assess for changes in standard urinalysis parameters (specific gravity, pH, ketones, glucose, blood, bilirubin, and leukocyte esterase).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Adults</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Powdered probiotic with a carrier.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Carrier only.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Streptococcus salivarius DB-B5</intervention_name>
    <description>Sachets containing Streptococcus salivarius DB-B5 will be dissolved in water and consumed by the participants (n=30) once daily for 4 weeks. The participants will consume 10 billion colony forming units (CFU) per day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Sachets containing a placebo (probiotic carrier) will be dissolved in water and consumed by the participants (n=30) once daily for 4 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are adults, 18 to 65 years of age and in good general health and good oral health (no&#xD;
             active or uncontrolled diseases or conditions);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have a body mass index (BMI) range of 18.5 - 35 kg/m^2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have no known food allergies or intolerances;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have normal or acceptable to the Investigator vital signs (blood pressure, heart rate,&#xD;
             respiratory rate, temperature) at screening and Day -1 and normal laboratory values&#xD;
             and physical exam findings at screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Agree not to make any major changes to their diet during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Read and sign the Research Subject Information and Consent Form;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Are willing to use the assigned products according to instructions, attend scheduled&#xD;
             appointments, and complete the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Are males and females who agree to use medically acceptable contraception&#xD;
             (oral/implant/injectable/transdermal contraceptives, intrauterine device, condom with&#xD;
             spermicide, diaphragm with spermicide, abstinence, partner's vasectomy, tubal&#xD;
             ligation; abstinence or vasectomies are acceptable if the female subject agrees to&#xD;
             implement two of the other acceptable methods of birth control if her&#xD;
             lifestyle/partner changes) for the duration of the study and 30 days after study&#xD;
             completion and attest to having used it for three months prior to screening, if of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. If subject is a female of child-bearing potential, agrees to submit to a urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test (UPT) at screening, Day -1 and at the end of study / early termination&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have self-reported history of active or chronic dental or medical disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are prone to gas, bloating, or diarrhea;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have received antibiotic treatment in the three months prior to Day 1 or are unwilling&#xD;
             to refrain from antibiotic use during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Used probiotic supplements or consumed probiotic rich foods such as yogurt or kefir&#xD;
             within 30 days prior to Day 1 or are unwilling to refrain from the use of probiotic&#xD;
             supplements or probiotic rich foods for the duration of the study, even if they are&#xD;
             for non-oral health reasons (e.g., vaginal or gut health probiotics);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Are pregnant, planning to become pregnant during the study period, or are&#xD;
             breastfeeding a child;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Self-reported current users of tobacco products, vaping products, cannabis, and/or&#xD;
             nicotine replacement therapy (gums, lozenges, sprays, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Frequent users of alcohol, defined as consumption of 21 units or more of alcoholic&#xD;
             beverage per week (21 units = 6 L of beer, 2.5 L of wine, or 500 mL of spirits);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Used over-the-counter (OTC) laxatives or any other medications, supplements, or&#xD;
             products that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could influence the endpoints in&#xD;
             this study within 30 days prior to Day 1 or are unwilling to refrain from the use of&#xD;
             these products for the duration of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Have chronic or acute illness such as heart disease, diabetes, cancer, autoimmune&#xD;
             conditions, or history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator, could impact the outcome of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Have any other condition or situation that may increase the risk associated with study&#xD;
             participation or may interfere with the study results, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Are unwilling or unable to provide informed consent and follow study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have participated in any clinical study within the 30 days prior to Day 1;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Are clinical site personnel or relative or partner of clinical site personnel.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Casser, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>TKL Research, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>TKL Research, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fair Lawn</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07410</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

