<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04494516</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00237243</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04494516</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Qualitative Understanding of Community TB Services Pre and Post the CHIP-TB Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Qualitative Study to Optimize a Community-Based Pediatric TB/HIV Prevention Intervention and Implementation Strategy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UNITAID</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aurum Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KNCV Tuberculosis Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This qualitative study is designed to elicit the perspectives of relevant stakeholders to&#xD;
      adapt a community-based TB/HIV intervention aimed on providing home-based TB prevention&#xD;
      treatment (TPT) initiation for child TB contacts, to design its implementation strategy and,&#xD;
      post intervention, to assess lessons learned for future scale up. Participants will include&#xD;
      policy makers and health system managers, nurse and physician providers, community health&#xD;
      team members, and child caregivers of TB-exposed children. Stakeholders will be asked to&#xD;
      participate in two interviews, one prior to the cluster randomized trial assessing this&#xD;
      intervention and one after the cluster randomized trial. Trained interviewers will conduct&#xD;
      1-hour semi-structured in-depth interviews that will be audio-recorded, translated and&#xD;
      transcribed for thematic analysis using a priori and emergent domains of interest.&#xD;
      Free-listing, ranking exercises and cultural consensus will be used to identify&#xD;
      context-specific intervention adaptations and implementation strategies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis (TB) remains a top 10 cause of child mortality in sub-Saharan Africa.&#xD;
      Short-course combination TB preventive therapy (TPT) regimens are highly effective with high&#xD;
      completion rates and therefore hold promise to reduce the 1 million pediatric TB patients and&#xD;
      233,000 child TB deaths annually. TPT effectiveness requires improvement in access to&#xD;
      pediatric TB preventive care. The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates only 23% of the&#xD;
      1.3 million TB-exposed children under 5 years old initiated TPT in 2017. The investigators'&#xD;
      previous data suggest 50-75% of TB-exposed children under 5 years old fail to be either&#xD;
      identified or linked to TB preventive care. Children under 5 years are at exceptionally high&#xD;
      risk of TB disease due to not only immature immune systems, but also HIV infection and HIV&#xD;
      exposure. Guidelines have long recommended TPT for children under 5 years, but have recently&#xD;
      been expanded to children under 15 years. Developing and testing innovative health care&#xD;
      delivery models to accompany new WHO-endorsed short-course combination TPT regimens is&#xD;
      essential to reduce TB-associated global child morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Integrated community case management (iCCM) is a cost-effective intervention that increases&#xD;
      child survival by bringing curative therapies to at risk children in the community. Recently,&#xD;
      algorithms for screening pediatric patients with household exposure to TB have been&#xD;
      simplified to include symptom screening only, eliminating costly laboratory and radiographic&#xD;
      evaluations that are barriers to treatment and do not improve sensitivity and specificity of&#xD;
      the assessment. The CHIP-TB Trial plans to assess whether integrated community-based&#xD;
      pediatric TB/HIV prevention services is feasible, acceptable and effective in increasing TPT&#xD;
      uptake among child TB contacts under 15 years in a cluster-randomized trial in South Africa&#xD;
      and Ethiopia, two high-burden, resource-limited settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nested within this larger trial, the investigators will use qualitative research to (1)&#xD;
      describe the social context in which the community health teams perform the team's duties,&#xD;
      (2) make context-specific adaptations to the intervention to maximize its effectiveness, (3)&#xD;
      define a context-specific implementation strategy and evaluation plan, and (4) learn&#xD;
      important lessons for the future scale up and dissemination of the community-based&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will conduct 10-15 paired semi-structured individual in-depth interviews&#xD;
      (IDI) for each of the four key stakeholder groups: (1) caregivers of TB-exposed children, (2)&#xD;
      community health team members, (3) clinic-based nurse and clinic or hospital-based physician&#xD;
      providers, and (4) health system managers and policy makers, for a total of ~120 IDIs (~60 in&#xD;
      South Africa and ~60 in Ethiopia) both pre and post trial. Before the intervention the&#xD;
      investigators will conduct a one-hour interview that will explore the inner setting of the&#xD;
      community health team's environment from each stakeholder perspective and will develop and&#xD;
      decide upon key intervention adaptations and implementation strategies for the&#xD;
      community-based TB/HIV prevention program that will be assessed with a one-year&#xD;
      cluster-randomized trial. Upon trial completion, the investigators will conduct another 10-15&#xD;
      semi-structured IDIs with each stakeholder group in each country (total ~120 IDIs) to&#xD;
      identify key facilitators and barriers to the implementation. Thematic content analysis with&#xD;
      an inductive approach will be used to analyze transcripts for both a priori and emergent&#xD;
      domains of interest. A coding scheme will be adapted from Consolidated Framework for&#xD;
      Implementation Research (CFIR) constructs. Free listing, ranking, and cultural consensus will&#xD;
      be used to identify intervention adaptations and implementation strategies that are context&#xD;
      specific. The investigators will use Smith's Saliency Index to analyze the free listed data,&#xD;
      mean rank order to assess ranking exercises, and the Eigenvalue to evaluate consensus across&#xD;
      groups all using the ANTHROPAC ® 4.0 software.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of intervention adaptations as assessed by an in-depth interview</measure>
    <time_frame>Within six months prior to CHIP-TB trial initiation</time_frame>
    <description>In-depth, semi-structured interviews will explore perceptions of context-specific adaptations to the community-based TB prevention intervention needed for success.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of implementation strategies as assessed by an in-depth interview</measure>
    <time_frame>Within six months prior to CHIP-TB trial initiation</time_frame>
    <description>In-depth, semi-structured interviews will explore perceptions of context-specific implementation strategies for the community-based TB prevention intervention needed for success.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of the social context of the community-based health teams as assessed by an in-depth interview</measure>
    <time_frame>Within six months prior to CHIP-TB trial initiation</time_frame>
    <description>In-depth, semi-structured interviews will explore the social context and inner setting of the community health teams.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of the lessons learned as assessed by an in-depth interview</measure>
    <time_frame>Within four months after CHIP-TB Trial completion</time_frame>
    <description>In-depth, semi-structured interviews will explore lessons learned for the future scale up and dissemination of the community-based TB prevention intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis Infection</condition>
  <condition>Tuberculosis Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-trial</arm_group_label>
    <description>This cohort of participants will be recruited preceding evaluation of the community-based pediatric TB prevention intervention (CHIP-TB; NCT04369326) to assist with design of the intervention and implementation strategy. Participants will include four stakeholder groups including: (1) policy makers, program managers, (2) nurse and physician clinicians, (3) community health team members, and (4) caregivers of child contacts from both South African and Ethiopian sites.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post-trial</arm_group_label>
    <description>This cohort of participants will be recruited after evaluation of the community-based pediatric TB prevention intervention (CHIP-TB; NCT04369326) to assist with future scale up and dissemination of the intervention. Participants will include four stakeholder groups including: (1) policy makers, program managers, (2) nurse and physician clinicians, (3) community health team members, and (4) caregivers of child contacts from both South African and Ethiopian sites.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will include key stakeholders from the target communities in South&#xD;
        Africa (Ekurhuleni, Gauteng Province) and Ethiopia (East Shewa Zone of the Oromia regional&#xD;
        state), including caregivers of TB-exposed children, community health teams including&#xD;
        nurses and community health workers, clinic-based nurse and clinic/hospital-based physician&#xD;
        providers, program managers and policy makers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Interview 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult caregiver (18 years of age or older) of a child (&lt;15 years of age) who was&#xD;
             exposed to TB in the last two years where at least one child was evaluated for and&#xD;
             offered either TB preventive therapy or TB treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Community health team members from one of the Ethiopian or South African clinics in&#xD;
             which the CHIP-TB trial will be conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TB nurse from one of the 16 Ethiopian or South African clinics in which the study will&#xD;
             be conducted&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pediatrician or medical officer working in pediatrics at the relevant Ethiopian or&#xD;
             South African District Hospital who sees outpatient pediatric consultations including&#xD;
             TB-exposed children&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Program manager or policy maker in the relevant Ethiopian or South African district or&#xD;
             provincial office who manages TB, PMTCT, and/or other pediatric programming&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Interview 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any adult caregivers, community health team members, TB nurses, medical officers or&#xD;
             pediatricians, program managers or policy makers who are unable or unwilling to&#xD;
             provide informed consent for both the interview and audio-recording&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for Interview 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any community health team members, TB nurses, medical officers or pediatricians,&#xD;
             program managers or policy makers who participated in the program for at least 3&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any adult caregiver whose child participated in the community-based TB prevention&#xD;
             program&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Interview 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any adult caregivers, community health team members, TB nurses, medical officers or&#xD;
             pediatricians, program managers or policy makers who are unable or unwilling to&#xD;
             provide informed consent for both the interview and audio-recording&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicole Salazar-Austin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nicole Salazar-Austin, MD</last_name>
    <phone>410-614-3917</phone>
    <email>nsalaza1@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KNCV Tuberculosis Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Addis Ababa</city>
        <country>Ethiopia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ahmed Bedru</last_name>
      <phone>251 911 405 405</phone>
      <email>ahmed.bedru@kncvtbc.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Aurum Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Salome Charalambous</last_name>
      <phone>+27 010 590 1300</phone>
      <email>SCharalambous@auruminstitute.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ethiopia</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Latent Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

