<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04492592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17182</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04492592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>JUS Media? Programme: A Food-Focused Media Literacy Intervention for Americanized Adolescents and Mothers Globally</brief_title>
  <official_title>The J(Amaican and) U(Nited) S(Tates) Media? Programme: A Food-Focused Media Literacy Intervention for Americanized Adolescents and Mothers Globally</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of The West Indies</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The J(amaican and) U(nited) S(tates) Media? Programme is a culturally-tailored food-focused&#xD;
      media literacy preventive intervention designed to promote healthier eating habits among&#xD;
      remotely acculturating early adolescents and their mothers in Jamaica (i.e., they have&#xD;
      internalized American culture) and are exposed to U.S. food advertising. The JUS Media?&#xD;
      Programme consists of a 2-session face:face weekend workshop for adolescent-mother pairs&#xD;
      supplemented by 8 weeks of SMS/text messages to reinforce workshop themes. Adolescents and&#xD;
      their mothers learn critical thinking skills to combat the unhealthy food messages they&#xD;
      encounter in food advertising, particularly advertising on U.S. cable TV. The efficacy of the&#xD;
      JUS Media? Programme was evaluated with a small experimental study utilizing a randomized&#xD;
      controlled trial design among adolescents and mothers in Jamaica.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Western diet is common in the United States and has a lot of salt, sugar, and fat. Modern&#xD;
      globalization has shifted eating habits in many countries toward this unhealthy Western diet.&#xD;
      For example, U.S. cable TV in other countries promotes this Western diet through&#xD;
      advertisements for junk foods and sugary drinks. This is a major concern because experimental&#xD;
      research studies show that seeing food advertising while watching TV leads to eating more&#xD;
      food afterwards. Research studies also show that people who watch a lot of TV tend to think&#xD;
      that junk food is not that harmful.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers now believe that some people living outside the U.S. are drawn to the U.S.&#xD;
      culture and lifestyle and can become &quot;Americanized&quot; through a process called remote&#xD;
      acculturation. These Americanized people in other countries such as Jamaica are mostly&#xD;
      teenagers, but sometimes also adults. Americanized people outside the United States are even&#xD;
      more likely to adopt the unhealthy Western diet even though they have never lived in the&#xD;
      United States. In research the investigators did before getting this grant, they showed that&#xD;
      Americanized youth and mothers in Jamaica watched more hours of U.S. cable daily and also ate&#xD;
      more unhealthy food. This led them to develop a new healthy eating education program for&#xD;
      Americanized families in Jamaica that highlighted the role of U.S. media - the &quot;J(amaican)&#xD;
      U(nited) S(tates) Media? Programme&quot;. The JUS Media? Programme teaches young people and&#xD;
      mothers to question the health messages in food advertising on U.S. cable TV so that they can&#xD;
      be smarter and healthier consumers. For example, the JUS Media? Programme covers the&#xD;
      recommended food guidelines in Jamaica and teaches adolescents and their mothers the&#xD;
      principles of media literacy, such as to think about &quot;who is the source of this message?&quot;&#xD;
      &quot;what do they want you to do?&quot; and &quot;what information is missing?&quot;. Finally, the JUS Media?&#xD;
      Programme teaches participants to use these media literacy principles to challenge unhealthy&#xD;
      food advertisements by creating smart, funny parody versions called subvertisements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project,the investigators evaluated how well the JUS Media? Programme worked for 7th&#xD;
      graders and their mothers in Jamaica. About 30 adolescents and their mothers got a 2-session&#xD;
      workshop, another 30 families got the workshop and text messages, and another 30 families did&#xD;
      not get any part of the program.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 10, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants were not told what arm of the intervention they were in (i.e., they were not told if they were receiving the intervention or not).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Dietary Intake Using a 24-Hour Recall Method</measure>
    <time_frame>4 measurement points: baseline, 4 weeks, 6 weeks, 17-20 weeks (study ended at this final timepoint).</time_frame>
    <description>24-Hour Recall. Each participant reported detailed information on all foods and beverages consumed in the previous 24 hours via structured interviews with open-ended responses over the phone, and reported dietary intake was coded into coded for the presence (1) or absence (0) of fruits, raw vegetables, cooked vegetables, fats/oils, and sugary foods/beverages (aligning with the major national food groups of the population studied).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CHANGE IN STAGE OF CHANGE TOWARDS HEALTHY EATING</measure>
    <time_frame>4 measurement points: baseline, 4 weeks, 6 weeks, 17-20 weeks (study ended at this final timepoint).</time_frame>
    <description>A stages of change measure of healthy eating (Wright et al., 2015) was adapted to measure participants' adherence to 5 additional food-based dietary guidelines of the Jamaica Ministry of Health. Participants reported their adherence to each dietary guideline using a 1-6 likert type scale ranging from 1 &quot;precontemplation stage (No, and I do not intend to [insert wording from guideline]...in the next 6 months&quot; to 6 &quot;total abstinence (I do not consume...[insert wording from guideline).&quot; Higher scores on this scale represent being closer to one's healthy eating goal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CHANGE IN FOOD-FOCUSED MEDIA LITERACY</measure>
    <time_frame>4 measurement points: baseline, 4 weeks, 6 weeks, 17-20 weeks (study ended at this final timepoint).</time_frame>
    <description>Food-focused media literacy was measured with a 14-item scale (Powell &amp; Gross, 2018). Participants responded on a 4-point likert type scale ranging from 1 (strongly disagree) to 4 (strongly agree). Higher scores on this scale represent higher food-focused media literacy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">184</enrollment>
  <condition>Nutrition Poor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Workshop Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2 session weekend face:face workshop for adolescent-mother pairs</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Workshop + SMS/Texting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2 session weekend face:face workshop for adolescent-mother pairs followed by 8 weeks of supplementary text messages (NOTE: there was no 'SMS/texting-only' arm of this study)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention provided.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Workshop</intervention_name>
    <description>Workshop</description>
    <arm_group_label>Workshop + SMS/Texting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SMS/Texting</intervention_name>
    <description>SMS/Texting</description>
    <arm_group_label>Workshop + SMS/Texting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Workshop Only</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • 7th grader enrolled in the participating schools and present at school on the days of&#xD;
        recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for each adolescent or mother seeking to enroll:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother/student was not born in Jamaica&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother/student is not a Jamaican citizen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother/student is a citizen (including dual citizen) of the United States&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother/student has not lived in Jamaica for the past 15 years (mother) or 8 years&#xD;
             (student)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother and student do not live together&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother has been primary guardian for &lt;5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  study screening scores show no U.S. TV usage or no affinity for the U.S. culture, and&#xD;
             very low junk food consumption&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 15, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Minnesota</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gail Marcia Ferguson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

