<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03379662</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EC_AUT_001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03379662</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Evaluation of Low Level Laser Light Therapy for Autistic Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Randomized Evaluation of the Effect of the Erchonia® HLS Laser Device on Children and Adolescents With Autistic Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Erchonia Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Erchonia Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether the Erchonia HLS Laser is effective in the&#xD;
      treatment of irritability associated with autistic disorder in children and adolescents aged&#xD;
      five (5) to seventeen (17) years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a range of complex neurodevelopment disorders characterized&#xD;
      by behavioral, developmental, cognitive and psychological deficits that include social&#xD;
      impairment, communication and language difficulties, hyperactivity, irritability, obsessive&#xD;
      interests and restricted, and repetitive behaviors. Autistic disorder, sometimes called&#xD;
      autism or classical ASD, is the most severe form of ASD. ASD occurs in all ethnic and&#xD;
      socioeconomic groups and affects every age group, with symptoms appearing before age 3. The&#xD;
      Centers for Disease Control (CDC) estimates that 1 out of 88 children age 8 will have an ASD,&#xD;
      with males four times more likely to have an ASD than females.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no cure for ASD and no single best treatment for all individuals with autistic&#xD;
      disorder. The majority of diagnosed cases of autism are idiopathic with an enigmatic&#xD;
      pathogenesis, and as a result, therapeutic approaches have focused on mitigating specific&#xD;
      symptoms rather than treating disease etiologies. The current standard treatment approach is&#xD;
      a team approach to customize an individual highly structured, specialized program or&#xD;
      treatment plan including medications, therapies and behavioral interventions targeted toward&#xD;
      improving the individual's specific symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cause of ASD is not clearly understood, but it is believed that both genetics and&#xD;
      environment likely play a role. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) studies have demonstrated&#xD;
      increased brain volume and head circumference during early developmental childhood,&#xD;
      suggesting that autistic brains experience a period a rapid overgrowth which hampers further&#xD;
      development during later developmental stages. Morphological aberrations have been observed&#xD;
      in the hippocampus, anterior cingulate cortex, prefrontal cortex, amygdala, and cerebellum.&#xD;
      Another consistent observation has also been the reduction in cerebellar vermis volume, which&#xD;
      helps to explain specific behavioral patterns in children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Molecular analysis of postmortem brain tissue has revealed reduced Purkinje cell numbers,&#xD;
      which helps to explain aberrant locomotive activity and level presser function. Another&#xD;
      finding has been impaired neuronal connectivity within the cerebellum, amygdala, anterior&#xD;
      cingulate cortex, and dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. As a consequence, synapse structure and&#xD;
      function has demonstrated impairment in postmortem evaluations. Dendritic spines of&#xD;
      glutamatergic neurons in autistic patients have shown morphological alterations and&#xD;
      suppressed density, which, in turn, results in diminished synaptic transmissions. Nascent&#xD;
      spines have been reported in frontal, temporal, and parietal cortices of autistic patients,&#xD;
      and have a negative correlation with cognitive abilities in autism. Other neurological&#xD;
      aberrations include signaling through metabotropic glutamate receptor (mGluR) and&#xD;
      ƴ-aminobutyric acid (GABA)ergic system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The elusive pathophysiology of autism provides a marked challenge for health care providers.&#xD;
      One promising technology is low-level laser therapy (LLLT). LLLT uses photonic energy to&#xD;
      modulate the behavior and function of cells by stimulating molecular entities capable of&#xD;
      absorbing discrete wavelengths. or instance, cytochrome c oxidase (CCO), a terminal enzyme of&#xD;
      the respiratory change, contains a tetrapyrrole prosthetic group that has been shown to&#xD;
      absorb 635nm. Photon-induced activation of CCO increases cell bioenergetics, which, in turn,&#xD;
      activates intra-cellular secondary signaling cascades that in turn affect growth factor&#xD;
      synthesis, cell proliferation, cytokine production, and expression of specific transcription&#xD;
      factors. Studies have reported increased adenosine triphosphate (ATP) synthesis along with&#xD;
      activation of the intracellular redox state following the production of reactive oxygen&#xD;
      species (ROS). As an essential bio-catalyst, ATP lowers the activation for pivotal&#xD;
      biochemical reactions within cells. Concerning neurons, laser irradiation has been shown to&#xD;
      promote the recovery of injured peripheral nerves and the spinal cord. Moreover, studies have&#xD;
      revealed that excitable cells like neurons can be directly stimulated by light, enhancing the&#xD;
      action potential of the cell increasing the release of neurotransmitters such as glutamate&#xD;
      and acetylcholine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical outcomes with LLLT trials include nerve regeneration, increased neurotransmitter&#xD;
      release, growth factor synthesis, and neovascularization to name a few. It follows that&#xD;
      positioning of the laser along impaired regions of an autistic brain could elicit a positive&#xD;
      therapeutic outcome in a safe and non-invasive manner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 2, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 28, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 28, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Change From Baseline to Study Endpoint in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability &amp; Agitation Subscale Score.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 4 weeks (Study Endpoint)</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome measure in this study is defined as the mean change from baseline to 4 weeks of intervention (study endpoint), in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability Subscale score. The ABC Irritability Subscale contains 15 items relating to aggression, self-injury, tantrums, agitation and unstable mood in individuals with developmental disorders. Each item is rated from 0 (not at all a problem) to 3 (the problem is severe in degree). The individual scores are summed for a total score from 0 to 45, with higher scores indicating greater severity. A negative (-) change indicates a decrease in symptom severity and is positive for improvement. A positive (+) change indicates an increase in symptom severity and is negative for improvement. Study success is established as the detection of a minimum mean difference of -8.5 points between test and placebo groups in the change in ABC Irritability Subscale score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Autistic Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Erchonia HLS Laser</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Laser</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Placebo Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erchonia HLS Laser</intervention_name>
    <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser emits a 640 nm (nanometer) wavelength with a tolerance of ±10 nm from each of two 7.5 mw (milliwatt) laser diodes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Erchonia HLS Laser</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Laser</intervention_name>
    <description>The Placebo Laser emit the same visible light output as the active HLS Laser but without therapeutic effect.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Laser</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female child or adolescent aged 5 to 17 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th Edition, Text&#xD;
             Revision criteria (DSM-IV-TR) for autistic disorder within the past 2 years, as&#xD;
             diagnosed by a trained, qualified medical professional such as a pediatric&#xD;
             neurologist, child psychiatrist or developmental pediatrician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis is confirmed by Autism Diagnostic Interview (ADI-R)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrates 'irritable' behaviors such as tantrums, aggression, self-injurious&#xD;
             behavior, or a combination of such behaviors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability Subscale score is &gt;=18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical Global Impressions - Severity (CGI-S) scale score is &gt;=4 (moderately ill)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current therapeutic/intervention plan for treating autistic disorder has been&#xD;
             consistent/ stable over at least the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caregiver agrees, and it is possible for, the subject to abstain from partaking in new&#xD;
             treatments to treat autistic disorder symptoms during the course of study&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of child-bearing age are willing and able to use acceptable means of&#xD;
             contraception throughout study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary or concurrent diagnosis of another disorder or other identifiable genetic&#xD;
             condition associated with the autism spectrum scale or with mental retardation,&#xD;
             including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pervasive Developmental Disorder-Not Otherwise Specified (PDD-NOS); Asperger's Disorder;&#xD;
        Rett's Disorder; Fragile-X Syndrome; Childhood Disintegrative Disorder; Down Syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seizure disorders (active), cerebrovascular disease or brain trauma as etiology of&#xD;
             autistic behavior&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of, and treatment for, bipolar disorder, psychosis, schizophrenia,&#xD;
             or major depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of a psychotropic drug deemed effective for the treatment of aggression,&#xD;
             tantrums or self-injurious behavior&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known neurological disease, such as encephalitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant sensory or motor impairment such as cerebral palsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of epilepsy that is currently treated with anti-convulsant medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous significant head trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hearing loss requiring use of assistive devices such as hearing aids or cochlear&#xD;
             implant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant visual impairment that cannot be adequately corrected with lenses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented mental age younger than 18 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV and other autoimmune disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active cancer or treatment for cancer within last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable cardiac disease, such as a recent cardiac arrhythmias (including atrial&#xD;
             fibrillation, ventricular fibrillation and irregular atrial-ventricular conduction&#xD;
             time), or recent congestive heart failure, or recent myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous surgical interventions to the head/neck area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sensitivity to, or contraindication for, light therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is presently pregnant or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a research study within the past 30 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Calixto Machado, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute for Brain and Rehabilitation Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nazareth</city>
        <zip>16470</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 15, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 15, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 20, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>January 26, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">May 27, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Autism</keyword>
  <keyword>Autistic Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Autistic Spectrum Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Irritability</keyword>
  <keyword>laser</keyword>
  <keyword>light therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan, and Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 31, 2013</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/62/NCT03379662/Prot_SAP_ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Erchonia HLS Laser</title>
          <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Erchonia HLS Laser: The Erchonia HLS Laser emits a 640 nm (nanometer) wavelength with a tolerance of ±10 nm from each of two 7.5 mw (milliwatt) laser diodes.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Placebo Laser</title>
          <description>The Placebo Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Placebo Laser: The Placebo Laser emit the same visible light output as the active HLS Laser but without therapeutic effect.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="21"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="19"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="21"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="19"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Erchonia HLS Laser</title>
          <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Erchonia HLS Laser: The Erchonia HLS Laser emits a 640 nm (nanometer) wavelength with a tolerance of ±10 nm from each of two 7.5 mw (milliwatt) laser diodes.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Placebo Laser</title>
          <description>The Placebo Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Placebo Laser: The Placebo Laser emit the same visible light output as the active HLS Laser but without therapeutic effect.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="21"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="19"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="40"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="8.24" spread="3.02"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="8.37" spread="3.15"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="8.29" spread="3.07"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="16"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="14"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="30"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="8"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="20"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="12"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="16"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Cuba</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="19"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="40"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Baseline Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability Score</title>
          <description>The ABC Irritability Subscale includes questions about aggression, self-injury, tantrums, agitation and unstable mood on a scale of 0 to 45, with higher scores indicating greater severity. Data from studies of developmentally disabled children indicated that a score of 18 is 1.3 to 1.5 SD above the population means, depending on the age and sex of the child.</description>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="30.52" spread="15.71"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="29.58" spread="28.89"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="30.04" spread="22.65"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Mean Change From Baseline to Study Endpoint in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability &amp; Agitation Subscale Score.</title>
        <description>Primary outcome measure in this study is defined as the mean change from baseline to 4 weeks of intervention (study endpoint), in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability Subscale score. The ABC Irritability Subscale contains 15 items relating to aggression, self-injury, tantrums, agitation and unstable mood in individuals with developmental disorders. Each item is rated from 0 (not at all a problem) to 3 (the problem is severe in degree). The individual scores are summed for a total score from 0 to 45, with higher scores indicating greater severity. A negative (-) change indicates a decrease in symptom severity and is positive for improvement. A positive (+) change indicates an increase in symptom severity and is negative for improvement. Study success is established as the detection of a minimum mean difference of -8.5 points between test and placebo groups in the change in ABC Irritability Subscale score.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline and 4 weeks (Study Endpoint)</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Erchonia HLS Laser</title>
            <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Erchonia HLS Laser: The Erchonia HLS Laser emits a 640 nm (nanometer) wavelength with a tolerance of ±10 nm from each of two 7.5 mw (milliwatt) laser diodes.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Placebo Laser</title>
            <description>The Placebo Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Placebo Laser: The Placebo Laser emit the same visible light output as the active HLS Laser but without therapeutic effect.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Mean Change From Baseline to Study Endpoint in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability &amp; Agitation Subscale Score.</title>
          <description>Primary outcome measure in this study is defined as the mean change from baseline to 4 weeks of intervention (study endpoint), in the Aberrant Behavior Checklist (ABC) Irritability Subscale score. The ABC Irritability Subscale contains 15 items relating to aggression, self-injury, tantrums, agitation and unstable mood in individuals with developmental disorders. Each item is rated from 0 (not at all a problem) to 3 (the problem is severe in degree). The individual scores are summed for a total score from 0 to 45, with higher scores indicating greater severity. A negative (-) change indicates a decrease in symptom severity and is positive for improvement. A positive (+) change indicates an increase in symptom severity and is negative for improvement. Study success is established as the detection of a minimum mean difference of -8.5 points between test and placebo groups in the change in ABC Irritability Subscale score.</description>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="21"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="19"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="-14.81" spread="6.40"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0.37" spread="1.38"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Erchonia HLS Laser</title>
          <description>The Erchonia HLS Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Erchonia HLS Laser: The Erchonia HLS Laser emits a 640 nm (nanometer) wavelength with a tolerance of ±10 nm from each of two 7.5 mw (milliwatt) laser diodes.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Placebo Laser</title>
          <description>The Placebo Laser is administered 8 times across 4 weeks for 5 minutes each time to the skull at the base of the brain and temporal areas.&#xD;
Placebo Laser: The Placebo Laser emit the same visible light output as the active HLS Laser but without therapeutic effect.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="19"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="19"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="19"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Elvira Cawthon</name_or_title>
      <organization>Regulatory Insight, Inc.</organization>
      <phone>6154475150</phone>
      <email>elvira@reginsight.com</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

