<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03370276</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCC-19178</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03370276</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cetuximab &amp; Nivolumab in Patients With Recurrent/Metastatic Head &amp; Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Study of Concurrent Cetuximab and Nivolumab in Patients With Recurrent and/or Metastatic Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>James and Esther King Biomedical Research Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eli Lilly and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find out if the combination of two established anti-cancer&#xD;
      therapies are beneficial in participants with Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma (HNSCC).&#xD;
      Specifically, investigators want to determine if the combination of Cetuximab and nivolumab&#xD;
      can help people with advanced cases of HNSCC. Both cetuximab and nivolumab have been used&#xD;
      separately to treat HNSCC and are Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved in this type of&#xD;
      cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PHASE I: Participants will be enrolled sequentially and treated at Dose Level 1, or Dose&#xD;
      Level -1, every 2 weeks for 12 cycles or until discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each cycle is 4 weeks. Cetuximab is given alone in lead-in period at Day -14 before Cycle 1&#xD;
      only. In all subsequent doses starting Cycle 1 Day 1, nivolumab and cetuximab will be given&#xD;
      concurrently. Dose limiting toxicity (DLT) assessment will be performed during Cycle 1 and&#xD;
      will start with the initiation of the combination of cetuximab and nivolumab (4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
      PHASE II: Once the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or the recommended phase II dose of cetuximab&#xD;
      is determined in Phase I, accrual to the phase II will begin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      FOLLOW-UP: Participants will be followed for 2 years from End of Treatment. The imaging&#xD;
      studies will be performed every 8 weeks (2 cycles) of the treatments during Cycle 1-6 and&#xD;
      then every 12 weeks during Cycle 7-12 as per standard of care. Patient will be followed by&#xD;
      treating physicians as per standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 4, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I: Maximum Tolerated Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD).. The target Dose Limiting Toxicity (DLT) rate is &lt;25%. The MTD will be defined as the dose of cetuximab and nivolumab in which &lt;1 of 3 patients experience a DLT or &lt;2 of 6 patients experience a DLT with the next higher dose having at least 2 patients experiencing a DLT. The MTD is the highest dose at which at most 1 of 6 patients has a DLT. This study will utilize the Cancer Therapy Evaluation Program CTCAE version 4.1 for toxicity and event reporting. Dose-limiting toxicities will be observed until patients have completed Cycle 1 (4 weeks).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Overall Survival (OS) Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>One year overall survival rate of concurrent cetuximab and nivolumab in patients with recurrent and/or metastatic HNSCC. OS: The length of time from the start of treatment until death by any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Complete Response (CR): The disappearance of all measurable lesions. Partial Response (PR): At least a 30% decrease in the sum of the longest diameters of measureable lesions, taking as reference the baseline sum longest diameter. Progressive Disease (PD): At least a 20% increase in the sum of the longest diameters of target lesions, taking as reference the smallest sum longest diameter recorded since the baseline measurements, or the appearance of one or more new lesion(s). Stable Disease (SD): Neither sufficient shrinkage to qualify for partial response nor sufficient increase to qualify for progressive disease. To be assigned a status of stable disease, measurements must have met the stable disease criteria at least once after study entry at a minimum interval of 6 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Progressive Disease (PD): At least a 20% increase in the sum of the longest diameters of target lesions, taking as reference the smallest sum longest diameter recorded since the baseline measurements, or the appearance of one or more new lesion(s).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of Study Treatment Related Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post protocol treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Related adverse events according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) V4.1. An adverse event (AE) is defined as any untoward medical occurrence, including an exacerbation of a pre-existing condition, in a patient in a clinical investigation who received a pharmaceutical product.&#xD;
A serious adverse event (SAE) is defined as any AE that results in death, is immediately life-threatening, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, requires or prolongs patient hospitalization, is a congenital anomaly/birth defect, or is to be deemed serious for any other reason if it is an important medical event when based on appropriate medical judgement that may jeopardize the patient and may require medical or surgical intervention to prevent one of the other outcomes listed in the above definitions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">95</enrollment>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Oropharynx</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Larynx</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Oral Cavity</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Hypopharynx</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Paranasal Sinus</condition>
  <condition>Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Head and Neck Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab and dose escalation of Cetuximab.&#xD;
Dose Level 1:&#xD;
Lead-in Day -14 before Cycle 1 only: Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab - none. Cycle 1 Day 1 and all subsequent doses every 2 weeks (Q2W): Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab 240 mg.&#xD;
Dose Level -1:&#xD;
Lead-in Day -14 before Cycle 1 only: Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab - none. Cycle 1 Day 1 and all subsequent doses every 2 weeks (Q2W): Cetuximab 250 mg/m^2; Nivolumab 240 mg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab and dose escalation of Cetuximab.&#xD;
Dose Level 1:&#xD;
Lead-in Day -14 before Cycle 1 only: Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab - none. Cycle 1 Day 1 and all subsequent doses every 2 weeks (Q2W): Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab 240 mg.&#xD;
Dose Level -1:&#xD;
Lead-in Day -14 before Cycle 1 only: Cetuximab 500 mg/m^2; Nivolumab - none. Cycle 1 Day 1 and all subsequent doses every 2 weeks (Q2W): Cetuximab 250 mg/m^2; Nivolumab 240 mg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab and Cetuximab at recommended Phase II dose (RP2D).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab and Cetuximab at recommended Phase II dose (RP2D).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Nivolumab intravenously (IV) at 240 mg as outlined in the treatment arms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cetuximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Cetuximab intravenously (IV) at 500 mg/m^2 or 250 mg/m^2 as outlined in the treatment arms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Affiliate Sites Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II - Moffitt Site Only</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Erbitux</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have histologically or cytologically confirmed squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma of oral cavity, oropharynx, paranasal sinuses, nasal cavity, hypopharynx, or&#xD;
             larynx. Squamous cell carcinoma of unknown primary in cervical lymph node can be&#xD;
             included only if p16 status is positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have recurrent or metastatic HNSCC stage III/IV that is not amenable to local&#xD;
             therapy with curative intent (surgery or radiation therapy with or without&#xD;
             chemotherapy).Patients with persistent disease following radiation therapy&#xD;
             administered with a chemotherapy sensitizer may also be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have progressed on at least one prior line of chemotherapy, targeted therapy,&#xD;
             palliative radiation, and/or biological therapy regimen for their recurrent and/or&#xD;
             metastatic HNSCC. However, if patients are likely to be intolerant to standard&#xD;
             first-line systemic chemotherapy, the patients are eligible to enroll to this study as&#xD;
             the first-line therapy. Additionally, patients with persistent disease or&#xD;
             platinum-refractory recurrent disease may enroll in this study as a first-line&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must NOT have any systemic therapy for recurrent and/or metastatic disease except if&#xD;
             given as a part of a multimodality treatment (i.e. re-irradiation and systemic therapy&#xD;
             for curable intent of locally recurrent disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be accurately&#xD;
             measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded) as outlined in&#xD;
             RECIST version 1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of greater than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have normal organ function: Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1,500/μL; Hemoglobin &gt; 9&#xD;
             g/dL; Platelets &gt; 100,000/μL; Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL X institutional upper limits&#xD;
             of normal (ULN); AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) &lt; 3 X institutional ULN (or 5.0 X the ULN in&#xD;
             the setting of liver metastasis); Serum creatinine of ≤ 1.5 X ULN or creatinine&#xD;
             clearance &gt; 40 mL/minute (using Cockcroft/Gault formula): Female creatinine clearance&#xD;
             = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 0.8572 x serum creatinine in mg/ dL; Male&#xD;
             creatinine clearance = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 1.0072 x serum creatinine&#xD;
             in mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants, if sexually active, must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or using&#xD;
             effective contraception (hormonal or barrier methods). Female participants of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior&#xD;
             to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have experienced grade 3 or above skin toxicity from prior Epidermal growth factor&#xD;
             receptor (EGFR) inhibiting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have experienced grade 3 or above toxicity from prior anti-PD1 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have p16 negative squamous cell carcinoma of unknown primary in cervical lymph node.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with primary nasopharynx or salivary gland cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy, biological therapy or definitive radiation within&#xD;
             4 weeks of the study enrollment or those who have not recovered from adverse events to&#xD;
             ≤ Grade 1 due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had undergone any major surgery within 4 weeks of study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had undergone any palliative radiation within 2 weeks of study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have had other investigational agents within 4 weeks or 5 half-lives, whichever is&#xD;
             shorter, of the study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have known leptomeningeal metastases or untreated or symptomatic brain metastases.&#xD;
             Treated, asymptomatic brain metastasis can be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, autoimmune disease requiring systemic steroids, symptomatic congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric&#xD;
             illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a condition requiring systemic treatment with either corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg&#xD;
             daily prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications within 14 days of&#xD;
             study drug administration. Inhaled or topical steroids and adrenal replacement doses &gt;&#xD;
             10 mg daily prednisone equivalents are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have clinically relevant coronary artery disease or history of myocardial infarction&#xD;
             in the last 12 months or high risk of uncontrolled arrhythmia or uncontrolled cardiac&#xD;
             insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have uncontrolled or poorly controlled hypertension (&gt;180 mmHg systolic or &gt; 130 mmHg&#xD;
             diastolic) at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with a combination of cetuximab and a PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitor. Prior&#xD;
             treatment with cetuximab or a PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitor is allowed as long as not&#xD;
             previously given in combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition similar to those of cetuximab and/or nivolumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active HIV, Hep B, or Hep C infection. If not clinically indicated, the patients&#xD;
             do not need to be tested.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christine H. Chung, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://moffitt.org/clinical-trials-research/</url>
    <description>Moffitt Cancer Center Clinical Trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 7, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 12, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

