<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00351689</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1030740</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00351689</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Placebo-controlled Assessment of the Effect of a Food Supplement on Skin Protection After Exposure to UV Radiation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Placebo-controlled Assessment of the Effect of a Food Supplement on Skin Protection After Exposure to UV Radiation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>L'Oreal</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nestlé</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>L'Oreal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A probiotic bacterial strain was tested in a randomized, double blind , placebo controlled&#xD;
      clinical trial with 54 healthy male volunteers. Half the volunteers received the dietary&#xD;
      supplement the other half placebo during 6 weeks prior to exposure to solar-simulated UV&#xD;
      irradition (2x1,5MED). Blister roofs and skin biopsies were recovered 1, 4 and 10 days after&#xD;
      UV exposure from unirradiated and irradiated skin and used for immunohistochemical analysis&#xD;
      and mixed epidermal cell lymphocyte reaction&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Langerhans cells (LC), the dendritic cells (DC) from epidermis, constitute the first line of&#xD;
      immune defense against environmental attacks. Under steady state conditions, LC turnover is&#xD;
      very low. The LCs reside in the epidermis in an immature state and can be distinguished from&#xD;
      other epidermal cells by their surface expression of HLA-DR, CD1a and langerin. Upon&#xD;
      stimulation by inflammatory mediators LCs are activated and acquire CCR7 expression, the&#xD;
      chemokine receptor for CCL21 that mediates their migration to lymph nodes. Moreover,&#xD;
      activated LCs display a mature phenotype characterized by increased expression of&#xD;
      co-stimulatory molecules and acquisition of maturation markers that facilitate their&#xD;
      interaction with T-cells and aid in the elicitation of the immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It has long been known that, in addition to being carcinogenic via DNA damage and mutations,&#xD;
      solar UV radiation induces local and systemic immune suppression which represents a major&#xD;
      risk for skin cancer induction and progression in sun-exposed areas. The process is mostly&#xD;
      related to direct LC damage through induction of apoptosis and impairment of&#xD;
      antigen-presenting function. Moreover, UV radiation elicits an inflammatory response and&#xD;
      subsequent recruitment of immune cells, including CD36+ monocytic cells. These cells colonize&#xD;
      the epidermis in the days following UV exposure and are the major source of immunosuppressive&#xD;
      cytokines such as IL-10. All these mechanisms ultimately lead to impaired cell-mediated&#xD;
      reactions and establishment of immune tolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutritional intervention, particularly with dietary antioxidants and vitamins, has been&#xD;
      proposed to protect against UV-induced skin damage and to a certain extent skin cancer&#xD;
      occurrence. In recent years, there has been an increasing interest for probiotics, defined as&#xD;
      live microorganisms which, when consumed in adequate amounts, confer a health benefit upon&#xD;
      the host. Particular focus has been on species of lactic acid bacteria including Lactobacilli&#xD;
      and Bifidobacteria that are part of the natural human intestinal microbiota. Indeed, it is&#xD;
      well documented that the endogenous intestinal microbiota plays a crucial role in immune&#xD;
      maturation, gut integrity and defense against pathogens. Recently, it has been shown that&#xD;
      some probiotic bacteria possess the ability to modulate the immune system at both the local&#xD;
      and systemic levels and thereby improve immune defense mechanisms and/or down-regulate immune&#xD;
      disorders such as intestinal inflammations or allergies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Probiotic used as the dietary supplement, was isolated from healthy adult microbiota and&#xD;
      was shown to have a strong anti-pathogenic activity against a wide range of entero-pathogens.&#xD;
      Furthermore, a pre-clinical study demonstrated that it can maintain the epidermal LC density.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Here, we analyzed, in a randomized double blind, placebo controlled, clinical trial, whether&#xD;
      this dietary supplement could also modulate the cutaneous immune homeostasis after&#xD;
      solar-simulated UV exposure in humans.For this purpose, we analyzed whether this dietary&#xD;
      supplement could interfere with LC allostimulatory function and activation/maturation&#xD;
      phenotypic status of skin DC, after solar-simulated UV irradiation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date>July 2004</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of food supplement effect on the functions of epidermal cells after UV radiation exposure.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative analysis (activation and/or maturation status) of cutaneous Langerhans cells and macrophages and analysis of their location and Evaluation of the erythema, pigmentation after UV exposure, Evaluation of safety.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>50</enrollment>
  <condition>Photobiology</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dietary supplement</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy subject&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gender: male.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: greater than 20 years and less than 40 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phototype: II or III.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject having freely given his informed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cooperative subject, aware of the necessity for and duration of the controls,&#xD;
             suggesting complete compliance with the protocol set up by Laboratoire DERMSCAN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with Social Security coverage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A priori, a low fermented milk product consumer (less than 125 g/d) who, during the&#xD;
             study, agrees not to eat fermented milk products containing live bacteria (yogurt,&#xD;
             cream cheese, fermented dairy products, unpasteurized cheese, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject deprived of freedom by a court or administrative order.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor or major protected by law.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject residing in a health or social care establishment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient in an emergency setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject presenting with skin disease on the test zones.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject presenting with a stable or progressive serious disease (investigator's&#xD;
             assessment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject allergic to one of the constituents of the test products or to xylocaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with a history of allergy to solar or UV radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immoderate use of alcohol (more than 2 glasses of wine daily or more than 1 glass of&#xD;
             spirits daily).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immoderate smoker (more than 6 cigarettes/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject exposed to the sun or UV radiation in the last 3 months (facial exposure was&#xD;
             authorized with use of a total-block sunscreen and sunglasses).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with cardiovascular or circulatory disease history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with a history of skin cancer, malignant melanoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with a history of intestinal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antibiotic, corticosteroid, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory or immunosuppressant&#xD;
             intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Strenuous sports (&gt; 5 hours per week) or naturism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject having taken a course of mineral supplements or vitamins in the 3 months&#xD;
             preceding study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vegetarian or vegan diet.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>AUDREY GUENICHE, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>L'Oreal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>TIMO BUETLER, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Nestlé</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermscan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon Villeurbane</city>
        <zip>69 603</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 13, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 2, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 2, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 3, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Probiotic bacteria</keyword>
  <keyword>cutaneous immune homeostasis</keyword>
  <keyword>UV radiation</keyword>
  <keyword>dietary supplement</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

