<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00359034</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H06-70016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00359034</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fetal Aortic Pulsewave Velocity: A Novel Doppler Ultrasound Method of Measuring the Biophysical Properties of the Fetal Aorta</brief_title>
  <official_title>Fetal Aortic Pulsewave Velocity: A Novel Doppler Ultrasound Method of Measuring the Biophysical Properties of the Fetal Aorta</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We are interested in determining if we can measure the blood flow in the descending aorta&#xD;
      (large blood vessel in the abdomen) of healthy fetuses and fetuses with growth restriction.&#xD;
      An increasing number of adult diseases (e.g. heart and blood vessel disease) are recognized&#xD;
      as potentially associated with fetal growth and development.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulse wave velocity (PWV) is a measure of blood flow in blood vessels. This is routinely&#xD;
      measured in adults, and has recently been studied in children. The purpose of our study is to&#xD;
      see if we can develop a simple ultrasound method to measure the PWV in fetuses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to see if we can consistently measure the blood flow patterns in&#xD;
      the fetal descending aorta (large blood vessel in the abdomen) of 20 healthy fetuses and 20&#xD;
      growth restricted fetuses using standard ultrasound techniques.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prospective subjects will be recruited through:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Recruitment posters placed in the DAP department at BCWH. A contact number for the&#xD;
           research nurse will be included on the recruitment poster for interested subjects to&#xD;
           contact.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The antepartum inpatient unit at BCWH. Prospective subjects will be identified by the&#xD;
           charge nurse as those patients satisfying the inclusion and exclusion criteria.&#xD;
           Potential subjects will be asked by the charge nurse if they are interested in meeting a&#xD;
           study investigator or research nurse for more information.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The same subject can participate twice in the study, once before 28 weeks and once after&#xD;
           28 weeks, as long as 3 weeks have passed between the study periods. All subjects&#xD;
           participating before 28 weeks will be asked during the consent process if they are&#xD;
           interested in participating a second time. Subjects in agreement will be contacted by&#xD;
           the study nurse by phone to arrange a second appointment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject Involvement Measuring the PWV requires placing 3 electrocardiography (ECG) leads over&#xD;
      the maternal abdomen in various positions to detect the fetal ECG signal. We have established&#xD;
      that the fetal ECG signal can be detected as a small deflection in the maternal ECG tracing.&#xD;
      The fetal ECG signal will allow us to correlate the blood flow wave form in the descending&#xD;
      aorta to the fetal cardiac cycle. The onset of the blood flow waveform will be assessed at&#xD;
      two points (A and B) along the descending aorta using standard pulsed Doppler ultrasound&#xD;
      techniques. Point A will be the aortic isthmus and Point B will be at or beyond the level of&#xD;
      the renal arteries. Measurements will be obtained in the following sequence: 1) time required&#xD;
      for waveform to travel from Point A to Point B; 2) distance (mm) between Point A and Point B;&#xD;
      3) fetal heart rate using M-mode. The time it takes for the waveform to travel the measured&#xD;
      distance between points A and B, will allow us to calculate the PWV in that portion of the&#xD;
      fetal aorta. This sequence of measurements will be repeated three times in each fetus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subjects will be asked to drink 500 cc of water prior to arrival to appointment to&#xD;
           ensure adequate hydration (which can affect amniotic fluid volume).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Subjects will be asked to void prior to entering study room.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Subjects will placed in the left lateral decubitus supine position&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Subjects will rest for 15 minutes prior to the start of the ultrasound examination. At&#xD;
           this time, consents will be reviewed again, and the demographic information recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. ECG electrodes will applied to the maternal abdomen&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Fetal biometry, AFI and umbilical artery Dopplers will be performed (if not done within&#xD;
           past 48 hours).&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. PWV will be determined at three times, within 10 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The demographic and pregnancy information collected will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. maternal age&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. gestational age at the time of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. obstetrical history (gravida, term, preterm, abortus, living)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. maternal smoking history&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. amniotic fluid volume&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. estimated fetal weight and/or growth parameter percentiles&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following information will be collected and recorded during the study ultrasound:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. time required to obtain the PWV measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. the calculated PWV&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. maternal blood pressure and pulse&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. fetal presentation&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. fetal heart rate&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. presence or absence of fetal activity or breathing during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. AFI and UA Doppler waveforms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Could not resolve technical difficulties&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>May 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Singleton pregnancy between 20-36 weeks GA presenting at British Columbia Women's Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study Group N:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Singleton pregnancy between 20 weeks 0 days and 36 weeks 0 days Normal obstetrical&#xD;
        ultrasound in DAP at BCWH between 20-36 weeks GA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study Group IUGR:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Singleton pregnancy between 20 weeks 0 days and 36 weeks 0 days Obstetrical ultrasound in&#xD;
        DAP at BCWH between 20-36 weeks GA demonstrating IUGR (abdominal circumference AC &lt;10%) and&#xD;
        one of: a)oligohydramnios (amniotic fluid index (AFI) &lt;5%) or b)abnormal umbilical artery&#xD;
        (UA) Dopplers (absent or reversed end-diastolic flow)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study Group N:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Gestational age &lt;20 weeks or ≥36 weeks Multiple pregnancy Any known or suspected fetal&#xD;
        structural anomaly (including cardiac) Chromosomal abnormalities (on amniocentesis or CVS)&#xD;
        Abnormalities in fetal growth (AC &lt;10%; AC &gt;90%) Abnormalities in amniotic fluid volume&#xD;
        (AFI &lt;5% or &gt;95%) Maternal hypertensive disorder (during or prior to pregnancy) Illicit&#xD;
        drug use during pregnancy (cocaine, heroin, methamphetamine) Maternal medical history of&#xD;
        any chronic illness requiring medication (eg lupus, asthma, etc.) Abnormal maternal serum&#xD;
        triple screen (AFP ≥2.5MoM, hCG &gt;3.0 MoM)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study Group IUGR:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Gestational age &lt;20 weeks or ≥36 weeks Multiple pregnancy Any known or suspected fetal&#xD;
        structural anomaly (including cardiac) Chromosomal abnormalities (on amniocentesis or CVS)&#xD;
        Normal fetal growth with AC ≥10% Illicit drug use during pregnancy (cocaine, heroin,&#xD;
        methamphetamine)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tracy Pressey, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 31, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 1, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 6, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Doppler ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>pulsewave velocity</keyword>
  <keyword>intrauterine growth restriction</keyword>
  <keyword>Fetal Pulsewave Velocity</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

