<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00758316</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>149/2008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00758316</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Prospective, Randomized Controlled Trial for a Rapid Pleurodesis Protocol for the Management of Pleural Effusions</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Randomized Controlled Trial for a Rapid Pleurodesis Protocol for the Management of Pleural Effusions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Singapore General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Singapore General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malignant pleural effusions form a significant proportion of respiratory and oncology&#xD;
      work-load. The efficacy of thoracoscopic talc poudrage which is the current standard of care&#xD;
      is limited by lung entrapment which prevents lung re-expansion. Thoracoscopy patients also&#xD;
      have significant hospital length of stay because chest tube drainage must continue until the&#xD;
      pleural space is dry to effect successful pleurodesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternative management strategies such as tunnelled pleural catheters (bedside&#xD;
      ultrasound-guided) enable outpatient management of pleural effusions but have limited&#xD;
      pleurodesis rates and do not offer any chance of getting pleural biopsies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A prospective randomized controlled trial with two arms i.e. thoracoscopic poudrage alone&#xD;
      (standard care) versus combined thoracoscopic poudrage and tunnelled pleural catheters. The&#xD;
      tunnelled catheters will be inserted at the time of thoracoscopy in the endoscopy centre&#xD;
      under ultrasound guidance. The trial is aimed to be completed within 3 years. Primary&#xD;
      end-points will be pleurodesis success. The secondary end-points are hospital length-of-stay,&#xD;
      complication rates, analgesia requirements, pain scores and quality-of-life scores. Based on&#xD;
      power calculations, we aim to recruit 120 patients in each arm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Malignant effusions are the 2nd commonest cause of exudative effusions and 75% are due to&#xD;
      lung, breast and lymphoma primaries. It is estimated that effusions take up about 20% of&#xD;
      pulmonologists' work. About 15% of lung cancers have effusions at presentation and 50% will&#xD;
      develop effusions during the course of the illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current standard care of a symptomatic malignant effusion is to perform medical&#xD;
      thoracoscopy and talc poudrage pleurodesis to prevent recurrence. Reported pleurodesis&#xD;
      success with this technique is about 78%. However, this success rate is limited by the&#xD;
      presence of lung entrapment that prevents lung re-expansion and effective pleurodesis. Lung&#xD;
      entrapment occurs when there is a visceral pleural tumour peel encasing the lungs or when&#xD;
      endobronchial tumour causes lung/lobar collapse. Thoracoscopic pleurodesis also results in&#xD;
      significant hospital length of stay as chest tubes must stay in situ until the pleural space&#xD;
      is dry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is also established data on the use of outpatient tunnelled pleural catheters in&#xD;
      malignant effusions. Besides providing effective drainage in cases with entrapped lungs,&#xD;
      these catheters also result in spontaneous pleurodesis in 42 to 70% of cases. The attraction&#xD;
      of the catheters is that it enables early discharge of patients who already have a terminal&#xD;
      illness and an extremely poor prognosis (Prognosis is usually about 3-8 months depending on&#xD;
      the primary) However, the pleural catheters do not allow biopsies to be taken from the pleura&#xD;
      and the pleurodesis rate is both lower and slower than with talc poudrage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project hopes to capitalize on the strengths of both methods ie. talc poudrage via&#xD;
      thoracoscopy and indwelling pleural catheters, to increase the success of pleurodesis and to&#xD;
      decrease hospital stay. Indwelling catheters may improve the success data by draining&#xD;
      effusions associated with entrapped lungs that do not usually achieve pleurodesis with talc&#xD;
      poudrage alone. These catheters can be left in patients on a long term basis i.e. &gt; 6 months.&#xD;
      The attraction of the PleurxTM tunnelled catheter system is the low risk of infections, air&#xD;
      leaks (because of a one-way valve) and slippage.4-5 This type of study involving combining&#xD;
      both modalities has never been reported in the literature. There is no such trial registered&#xD;
      under clinicaltrials.gov. Pilot data (&lt;20 patients) has been previously presented at the&#xD;
      American College of Chest Physicians Conference 2006 from Harvard University with promising&#xD;
      results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current data from our thoracoscopy service in SGH (Jan 2004 to June 2007), shows that our&#xD;
      pleurodesis success rate is 78.2%. However, complete success was achieved in 38.1%.7 This&#xD;
      data is in keeping with the reported literature and the failures/incomplete successes are&#xD;
      attributed to lung entrapment.3 Our data for hospital length of stay is 9.0 ± 4.0 (range 4 to&#xD;
      21) days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesized that by combining thoracoscopic talc poudrage with tunnelled catheters, the&#xD;
      pleurodesis success rate could be improved by 15% to 93%, complete success to &gt;75 % and&#xD;
      hospital length of stay approximately halved to 5 days or less. To test this hypothesis, we&#xD;
      want to conduct a prospective, randomized controlled trial comparing thoracoscopic talc&#xD;
      poudrage (standard care) to combined talc poudrage with tunnelled pleural catheters.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who meet inclusion/exclusion criteria will be screened by investigators and trial&#xD;
      coordinators. After informed consent has been taken, patients will be randomized to either of&#xD;
      the study arms. Randomization will be done through a computer generated random list. Baseline&#xD;
      data and quality of life scores will be computed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will then undergo standard medical thoracoscopy in the endoscopy center including&#xD;
      the use of moderate sedation, prophylactic antibiotics for 1 week and 20F chest tube&#xD;
      insertion at the end of the procedure. The standard of 4-6 g of sterilized talc will be used&#xD;
      for talc poudrage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the combined procedure group, a PleurxTM tunnelled catheter will be inserted under&#xD;
      ultrasound guidance. As this procedure will be done concurrently with thoracoscopy, there is&#xD;
      no estimated increase in endoscopy time. If either group of patients is found to have no&#xD;
      gross evidence of malignancy at the time of thoracoscopy (ie. empyemas or tuberculous&#xD;
      pleurisy), then they will be withdrawn from the study and notified appropriately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in the standard therapy arm will emerge from the procedure with a chest tube while&#xD;
      the intervention arm will have both a chest tube and a tunnelled catheter. In the standard&#xD;
      therapy arm, the chest tube will be removed when there is no further air leak and when&#xD;
      drainage drops to ≤ 150 ml/day. After chest tube removal, the patient is fit for discharge.&#xD;
      In the intervention arm, the chest tube is removed when air leak stops. There will be no need&#xD;
      to wait for fluid drainage to decrease and theoretically, the patient can go home on day 3 or&#xD;
      4 with the tunnelled pleural catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in the thoracoscopy only arm will be reviewed at 1 week in the outpatient clinic by&#xD;
      the investigators for suture removal and then again at 1 month for evaluation of radiological&#xD;
      success. This is the current standard practice. Quality of life assessment will be also done&#xD;
      at the one month visit by the trial coordinator. Subsequent follow-ups will be with medical&#xD;
      oncology as per standard practice including visits at about 3 months, 6 months and 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concurrent chemotherapy and radiotherapy will be allowed as per current standard of care.&#xD;
      Concurrent therapy is unlikely to impact our results because non-small cell lung cancers&#xD;
      which form the majority of our referrals have poor pleural effusion response to treatment.&#xD;
      This is the basis of why pleurodesis is the current standard of care. Chemosensitive tumours&#xD;
      like small cell lung cancers, ovarian cancers and lymphomas are seldom referred for symptom&#xD;
      management of pleural effusions unless they are refractory to chemotherapy. Again, these&#xD;
      patients will not be affected by concurrent 2nd/3rd line therapy. The small group of patients&#xD;
      who may be affected by simultaneous oncological management are those who have a first time&#xD;
      diagnosis of a chemosensitive tumour like small cell lung cancer or those with a sensitive&#xD;
      adenocarcinoma who are managed with Epidermal Growth Factor Tyrosine-kinase (EGRF)&#xD;
      inhibitors. These patients comprise &lt;5% of our referrals and will have to analyzed separately&#xD;
      in subsets to determine their impact on our data. In our pilot review of SGH thoracoscopy&#xD;
      data, these cases formed a tiny proportion (1-2 cases) which prevented any meaningful pilot&#xD;
      study analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients in the intervention combined treatment arm will be reviewed at outpatient clinic&#xD;
      either the next day or within 48 hours. They will undergo drainage via the tunnelled&#xD;
      catheter. If drainage is less than 150 ml, the PleurxTM catheter will be removed. Otherwise,&#xD;
      the patient will be recalled over the next 24-48 hours till such drainage is achieved. If&#xD;
      drainage persists for greater than 5 visits, then these patients will be deemed to have an&#xD;
      entrapped lung and will need long term pleural catheterization. Subsequent management will be&#xD;
      billed to the patient as part of their usual care. In the rare occurrence of a blocked&#xD;
      pleural catheter, a fibrinolytic flush (using streptokinase or alteplase) will be used. This&#xD;
      will be done using established protocols for management of blocked catheters.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary end points will be pleurodesis/pleural catheter success. Complete success is&#xD;
      defined in the literature to be no or minimal re-accumulation of pleural fluid at 30 days.&#xD;
      Partial success is defined as partial (≤ 50%) re-accumulation of fluid with some resolution&#xD;
      of symptoms and the absence of any further therapeutic interventions at 30 days. If any of&#xD;
      these conditions are not met then the procedure is deemed to be a failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints are&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Hospital length of stay. This will be determined primarily by the primary attending&#xD;
           physician based on the patient's medical condition. Patients will be considered&#xD;
           'pleurodesis fit for discharge' the day the chest tube is removed. The chest tube will&#xD;
           be removed in the absence of pleural space infection or air-leak (i.e. complications) if&#xD;
           the effusion drainage drops to ≤ 150 ml/day and if there is lung re-expansion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Complication rates for infections, bleeding, air-leaks/pneumothorax, tumor seeding of&#xD;
           the track&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Pain scores&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Analgesia/sedation requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Talc dose required&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Quality of life analysis using St George's respiratory questionnaire (pre and post),&#xD;
           Borg's scale, ECOG and Karnofsky score.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Re-admission and repeat procedure rates for complications related to pleurodesis or&#xD;
           re-accumulation of fluid. We aim to track the patients for 1 year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary end points will be pleurodesis/pleural catheter success.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complication rate/analgesia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Talc dose</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Pleural Effusions</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Thoracoscopy with pleurodesis Patients will then undergo standard medical thoracoscopy in the endoscopy center including the use of moderate sedation, prophylactic antibiotics for 1 week and 20F chest tube insertion at the end of the procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combined thoracoscopy with pleurodesis and pleurx catheter. In the combined procedure group, a PleurxTM tunnelled catheter will be inserted under ultrasound guidance. As this procedure will be done concurrently with thoracoscopy, there is no estimated increase in endoscopy time.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thoracoscopy and Pleurx</intervention_name>
    <description>Talc poudrage and tunneled pleural catheter</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pleuroscopy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thoracoscopy</intervention_name>
    <description>Talc poudrage</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pleuroscopy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients aged ≥ 18 with suspected or known symptomatic malignant pleural effusions&#xD;
             (i.e. age &gt;60 or smoking history &gt; 20 pack years or moderate effusion &gt;1/3 hemithorax)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability and willingness to sign informed consent. See Annex 1 for patient information&#xD;
             sheet and informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Absence of contraindications to thoracoscopy and tunnelled pleural catheters&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willingness to comply with follow-up i.e. outpatient follow-up at 1 week and at 1&#xD;
             month for standard intervention; and additional every other day drainage in the&#xD;
             intervention group (up to 5 times).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Uncorrected coagulopathy with platelet count ≤ 60 and INR ≥ 1.5.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Uncontrolled coughing because of risk of lung puncture and air leaks&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Severe hypoxemia with a PaO2/FiO2 ratio ≤ 200 or hypercapnia with a PaCO2 ≥ 60 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unstable cardiovascular status ie. hemodynamic instability requiring&#xD;
             inotropes/vasopressors, recent myocardial infarction &lt; 5 days or uncontrolled&#xD;
             arrythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Uncontrolled psychiatric disorders or absence of a significant caregiver both of which&#xD;
             will contraindicate sending the patient home with a tunnelled catheter&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Previous thoracic surgery/intervention to the affected hemothorax which may have&#xD;
             obliterated the pleural space&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Local skin infections that prevent long term catheter placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Morbid obesity which will increase risks associated with moderate sedation in the&#xD;
             endoscopy centre&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Multi-loculated effusions that will not benefit from drainage&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Suspected pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Devanand Anantham, FCCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Singapore General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sinagpore General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169608</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shaw P, Agarwal R. Pleurodesis for malignant pleural effusions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;(1):CD002916. Review. Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;11:CD002916.</citation>
    <PMID>14973997</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dresler CM, Olak J, Herndon JE 2nd, Richards WG, Scalzetti E, Fleishman SB, Kernstine KH, Demmy T, Jablons DM, Kohman L, Daniel TM, Haasler GB, Sugarbaker DJ; Cooperative Groups Cancer and Leukemia Group B; Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group; North Central Cooperative Oncology Group; Radiation Therapy Oncology Group. Phase III intergroup study of talc poudrage vs talc slurry sclerosis for malignant pleural effusion. Chest. 2005 Mar;127(3):909-15.</citation>
    <PMID>15764775</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tremblay A, Michaud G. Single-center experience with 250 tunnelled pleural catheter insertions for malignant pleural effusion. Chest. 2006 Feb;129(2):362-368. doi: 10.1378/chest.129.2.362.</citation>
    <PMID>16478853</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tremblay A, Mason C, Michaud G. Use of tunnelled catheters for malignant pleural effusions in patients fit for pleurodesis. Eur Respir J. 2007 Oct;30(4):759-62. Epub 2007 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>17567670</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 25, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 9, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 9, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Malignant</keyword>
  <keyword>Pleural</keyword>
  <keyword>Effusions</keyword>
  <keyword>Thoracoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Catheter</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pleural Effusion, Malignant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pleural Effusion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

