<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00756158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200712085R</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00756158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Molecular Studies on the Candidate Genes of Dopaminergic and Noradrenergic Systems in ADHD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Molecular Studies on the Candidate Genes of Dopaminergic and Noradrenergic Systems in Attention-deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Science Council, Taiwan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ultimate goal of this study is to find specific polymorphism of candidate genes&#xD;
      associated with endophenotypes and/or phenomenological phenotypes of ADHD. We propose to&#xD;
      replicate the analysis of the candidate genes identified by previous genetic studies on ADHD&#xD;
      using the candidate gene association study design (family-based case control study using&#xD;
      parental controls) to validate the findings from other research groups. These results will&#xD;
      lead our team: (1) to resolve controversies over inconsistent findings in previous genetic&#xD;
      studies and contribute to the literature on the validity of ASD using clinical and genetic&#xD;
      data; (2) to study the pathogenetic process of abnormal genes in abnormal neuropsychological&#xD;
      and neurobiological functions of ADHD; (3) to delineate the nature and the effect of&#xD;
      gene-gene interaction in the etiology of ADHD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), characterized by inattention, hyperactivity&#xD;
      and impulsivity, is an early onset, highly heritable, clinically heterogeneous, long-term&#xD;
      impairing disorder with tremendous impact on individuals, families, and societies. It affects&#xD;
      5-10% of school-aged children worldwide (7.5% in Taiwan) and 2-4% of adults.&#xD;
      Neuropsychological deficits related to executive functions, state regulation, and delay&#xD;
      aversion show heritability, replicated association with ADHD, and familial-genetic overlap&#xD;
      with ADHD, are suitable for biomarkers for ADHD. Despite the abundance of molecular genetic&#xD;
      studies on ADHD, the genetic etiologies of ADHD have been non-conclusive, and there is&#xD;
      limited information about the expressions, neuropsychological deficits, and genetic variants&#xD;
      for ADHD in Chinese population. This present study, a family-based parental control&#xD;
      association study, aims to identify the genetic markers of dopaminergic and noradrenergic&#xD;
      systems for ADHD using the dichotomous categorization of affected and non-affected,&#xD;
      quantitative phenotypes (symptom dimension and severity of ADHD) and endophenotype&#xD;
      (neuropsychological measures) as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. to determine the components of ADHD and neuropsychological deficits with the greatest&#xD;
           familial recurrence risks;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. to replicate studies with positive genetic findings from literature by performing&#xD;
           candidate gene analysis such as DRD4, DRD2, DRD5, DAT1, DBH, ADRA2C, ADRA1C, and SLC6A2;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. to identify the potential genetic variants using haplotype tagSNPs for the following&#xD;
           candidate genes, MAO-A and ADRA2A and any updated genetic findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to a sample of 200 ADHD families (200 probands, 400 parents, and 150 siblings)&#xD;
      being recruited in a parallel study (NSC96-2628-B-002-069 -MY3), we will recruit another 100&#xD;
      probands with ADHD, aged 7-18, and their parents (n = 200) and siblings (n= 75) in this&#xD;
      project. The phenotype measures include (1) interviews for psychopathology (K-SADS-E) and&#xD;
      social functioning (SAICA), (2) self-administered questionnaires to measures ADHD symptoms&#xD;
      (SNAP-IV and Adult ADHD rating scale) and comorbid conditions (ASRI and CBCL), and (3)&#xD;
      Neuropsychological tests: WISC-III, CPT, CANTAB, and Time Perception Tasks. The DNA will be&#xD;
      collected and analyzed. The transmission/disequilibrium test (TDT) and quantitative TDT will&#xD;
      be used in data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We anticipate the establishment of clinical, neuropsychological, and genetic database of 300&#xD;
      ADHD families (200 in NSC96-2628-B-002-069-MY3 and 100 in this project), completion of the&#xD;
      screening of several candidate genes, and identification of potential genetic variants for&#xD;
      ADHD, and determination of their association with ADHD diagnosis and symptoms and its&#xD;
      endophenotype in a Taiwanese sample. The long-term objectives are to identify the behavioral&#xD;
      phenotypes and endophenotypes that are close to the biological expression of genes underlying&#xD;
      ADHD. The findings of different approaches to identify the genetic etiologies for ADHD in&#xD;
      this pilot study should help us to determine the most promising approach for future molecular&#xD;
      genetic and pharmacogenetic study on ADHD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Family-Based</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The subjects will receive blood withdrawal. The blood sample will be used for establishing&#xD;
      lymphoblastoid cell lines, which will be used for molecular genetic experiments&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The sample will consist of 100 probands with ADHD, aged 7-18. Their biological parents (n =&#xD;
        200) and siblings (estimated number = 75) born to the same biological parents will be&#xD;
        recruited as the parent controls and sibling controls, respectively, for the family-based&#xD;
        case control study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inclusion criteria for the proband subjects are&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  That subjects have a clinical diagnosis of ADHD, or Hyperkinetic Disorder defined by&#xD;
             the DSM-IV and ICD-10, respectively, which was made by a full-time board-certificated&#xD;
             child psychiatrist at the first visit and following visits;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Their ages range from 7 to 18 when we conduct the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects have at least one biological parent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both parents are Han Chinese;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects and their biological parents (and siblings if any) consent to participate in&#xD;
             this study for complete phenotype assessments and blood withdraw or saliva collection&#xD;
             for genetic study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The proband subjects will be excluded from the study if they currently meet criteria&#xD;
             or have a history of the following condition as defined by DSM-IV:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Schizophrenia,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Schizoaffective Disorder,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Organic Psychosis, or Pervasive Developmental Disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moreover, the subjects will also be excluded from the study if they completely cannot&#xD;
             cooperate with blood withdrawal, collection of saliva, or buccal swabs.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chi-Yung Shang, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dept of Psychiatry, National Taiwan University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 18, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 19, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>dopaminergic</keyword>
  <keyword>noradrenergic</keyword>
  <keyword>endophenotype</keyword>
  <keyword>molecular genetics</keyword>
  <keyword>candidate gene</keyword>
  <keyword>Family-based Association study</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

