<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04351386</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019-A01476-51</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04351386</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Validation Study of the Watch HWA09 and Its Softwares ECG-SW1 and PPG-SW1 for the Detection of Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
  <acronym>WEFA</acronym>
  <official_title>Validation Study of the Watch HWA09 and Its Softwares ECG-SW1 and PPG-SW1 for the Detection of Atrial Fibrillation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Withings</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Withings</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed clinical study aims to validate the diagnostic performance, compared to a&#xD;
      reference ECG, of the ECG-SW1 software and the PPG-SW1 software integrated into the HWA09&#xD;
      watch developed by Withings for the automatic identification of atrial fibrillation (AF).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HWA09 is a wrist-worn watch that enables to record a single-lead ECG similar to the standard&#xD;
      lead I configuration, and a photoplethysmogram (PPG).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective :&#xD;
&#xD;
      To validate the diagnostic performance of the ECG-SW1 software integrated into the HWA09&#xD;
      watch for the automatic identification of atrial fibrillation (AF) compared to a simultaneous&#xD;
      12-lead ECG (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;gold standard&quot; or &quot;reference method&quot;).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The algorithm classifies the watch signals into four categories: normal sinus rhythm (RSN),&#xD;
      AF, arrhythmia other than AF, or non-interpretable. The latter category includes signals of&#xD;
      insufficient quality to be interpreted with confidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This classification will be compared to the diagnosis made by three independent, blinded&#xD;
      cardiologists based on a 12-lead ECG. The final diagnosis retained will be decided by&#xD;
      majority with adjudication by a consensus of 3 to 6 cardiologists. The sensitivity and&#xD;
      specificity of the device will then be estimated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first secondary objective is to validate the diagnostic performance, compared to a&#xD;
      simultaneous 12-lead ECG, of the PPG-SW1 software integrated in the HWA09 watch for the&#xD;
      automatic identification of atrial fibrillation (AF) from the photoplethysmography (PPG)&#xD;
      signal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three independent blinded cardiologists will issue a diagnosis based on the ECG recording of&#xD;
      the HWA09 watch. The final diagnosis retained will be decided by majority with adjudication&#xD;
      by a consensus of 3 to 6 cardiologists. Sensitivity and specificity will be calculated in&#xD;
      relation to the reference ECG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Second secondary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the quality of the single-channel strips measured with the HWA09 watch, as&#xD;
      follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Three independent cardiologists, having neither performed the data collection nor read&#xD;
           the reference ECG, will independently make a diagnosis based on the HWA09 single-channel&#xD;
           strips, blinded to the diagnosis made from the reference ECG. The ECG traces from the&#xD;
           watch will be exported in PDF format from the Withings Health Mate application and the&#xD;
           final diagnosis will be made by majority with adjudication by a consensus of 3 to 6&#xD;
           cardiologists. The final diagnosis will be compared to the diagnosis made by the&#xD;
           cardiologists who read the reference ECG. Sensitivity and specificity will then be&#xD;
           calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The visibility and polarity of ECG waves (i.e. P waves, QRS complex and T waves) will be&#xD;
           determined by cardiologists for the single-channel strips recorded with HWA09 and for&#xD;
           the lead I of the reference 12-lead ECG. For each of the waves, the agreement on their&#xD;
           visibility and polarity (if visible) between the HWA09 and the reference ECG will be&#xD;
           calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The durations of the major intervals of an ECG (i.e., QT interval, QRS complex, and PR&#xD;
           interval) will be determined by the cardiologists for the single-channel strips recorded&#xD;
           with HWA09 and for the lead I of the reference 12-lead ECG. For each interval (QT, QRS,&#xD;
           PR), the difference of duration between the signals from the watch and the reference ECG&#xD;
           will be calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The heart rate will first be determined by cardiologists from each signal of lead I&#xD;
           (recorded by the HWA09 watch and the reference ECG) that has been diagnosed as NSR. The&#xD;
           difference between the heart rate of the watch and the reference will be calculated. In&#xD;
           a second step, the heart rate recorded by the HWA09 watch will be calculated by the&#xD;
           Withings software. The difference between the heart rate calculated by the Withings&#xD;
           software (from the signal of the watch) and the heart rate determined by the&#xD;
           cardiologists (from the lead I of the reference ECG) will also be calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sponsor will ensure that no cardiologist makes a diagnosis on both a signal from the&#xD;
      HWA09 watch and the reference ECG fomr the same patient. The sponsor will centralize&#xD;
      diagnostics on the HWA09 and reference ECG signals and perform agreement calculations on the&#xD;
      associated pairs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 7, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 7, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the automatic classification in AF by ECG-SW1 of HWA09 single-lead ECG against reference 12-lead ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix AF vs 'non-AF'</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the automatic classification in NSR by ECG-SW1 of HWA09 single-lead ECG against reference 12-lead ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix NSR vs 'non-NSR'</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the automatic classification in AF by PPG-SW1 of the HWA09 PPG against reference 12-lead ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix AF vs 'non-AF'</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the automatic classification in NSR by PPG-SW1 of the HWA09 PPG against reference 12-lead ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix NSR vs 'non-NSR'</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the cardiologists' classification in AF from the HWA09 ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix AF vs 'non-AF'</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of the cardiologists' classification in SR from the HWA09 ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity from the 2x2 confusion matrix NSR vs 'non-NSR'</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the visibility of P-waves of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the positivity of P-waves of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the visibility of QRS-complexes of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the positivity of QRS-complexes of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the visibility of T-waves of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the positivity of T-waves of single-lead ECG from HWA09</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>(true positives + true negatives)/(sample size) from the 2x2 confusion matrix</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>RMSE between cardiologist's estimate of heart rate from the HWA09 single-lead ECG and the lead I reference ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Root Mean Squared Error</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>RMSE between cardiologist's estimate of heart rate from the HWA09 single-lead ECG and the heart rate calculated by ECG-SW1</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Root Mean Squared Error</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">283</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <condition>Arrythmia, Cardiac</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Atrial Fibrillation (AF)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with AF during reference ECG</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Normal Sinus Rhythm (NSR)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with NSR during reference ECG</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Other Arrythmia</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with an arrhythmia other than AF during the reference ECG</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AF Detection</intervention_name>
    <description>Recording PPG and single-lead ECG signals with the Withings HWA09 and ECG signal for the reference 12-lead ECG</description>
    <arm_group_label>Atrial Fibrillation (AF)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Normal Sinus Rhythm (NSR)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Other Arrythmia</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Every eligible patient doing a medical examination at the investigation center will be&#xD;
        asked to take part in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals over 18yo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who expressed their non-opposition to take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals affiliated to a social security system or eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable individuals according to the regulation in force :&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant, parturient or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Individuals deprived of liberty by a court, medical or administrative order&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Individuals under 18yo&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Individuals legally protected or unable to express their non-opposition to take&#xD;
                  part in&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Individuals unaffiliated to or not beneficiary of a social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Individuals who fit in multiple categories above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals having refused to take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals linguistically or mentally unable to express their non-opposition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals physically unable to wear a watch&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with an electrical pacing by a pacemaker&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David CAMPO</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Withings</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Julien NAHUM</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Cardiologique du Nord</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Cœur Paris Centre Turin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile-de-France</state>
        <zip>75008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Europeen Georges Pompidou</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile-de-France</state>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Cardiologique du Nord</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Denis</city>
        <state>Ile-de-France</state>
        <zip>93200</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
  <keyword>Arrythmia, Cardiac</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Wearable Electronic Device</keyword>
  <keyword>Watch</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrocardiography</keyword>
  <keyword>ECG</keyword>
  <keyword>Photoplethysmography</keyword>
  <keyword>PPG</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual patient data (IPD) are considered as confidential in this study. After the end the final quality control, the database will be frozen and all the IPD will be archived .</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

