<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00787358</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OC-018</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00787358</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Proof-of-Concept Study Investigating the Safety and Efficacy of ZT-031 on Hip Fracture Healing in Men and Postmenopausal Women</brief_title>
  <acronym>SHIFT</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo Controlled Proof-of-Concept Study Investigating the Safety and Efficacy of ZT-031 on Hip Fracture Healing in Men and Postmenopausal Women With Intertrochanteric Fracture of the Hip</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zelos Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zelos Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to test if an experimental drug called ZT-031 can help&#xD;
      men over 30 years or post-menopausal women over 55 years of age with certain types of hip&#xD;
      fracture to heal better or faster following surgery and to determine if ZT-031 is safe for&#xD;
      patients with fractures. To be allowed in the study you have to have a type of hip fracture&#xD;
      that requires surgery that is being studied (intertrochanteric fracture). You must also&#xD;
      otherwise be in good health, with no serious diseases such as cancer, neurologic disease,&#xD;
      other bone disease, liver, heart or kidney disease. You must be able to inject yourself every&#xD;
      day with the study medication using an injection pen, like that used for insulin injections.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Change in company direction&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>December 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compression hip screw (CHS) migration: the difference in the tip apex distance (TAD) post-operatively to that at Visit 7/Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Screw barrel impaction distance</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Screw cut-out and/or other hardware failure</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of fracture non-union</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for surgical revision with or without hardware removal</measure>
    <time_frame>16 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Fracture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ZT-031</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ZT-031</intervention_name>
    <description>80 ul subcutaneous injection per day</description>
    <arm_group_label>ZT-031</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>80 ul daily subcutaneous injection of vehicle only</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are required to meet all of the following criteria for inclusion in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed Institutional Review Board (IRB)/Research Ethics Board (REB)-approved informed&#xD;
             consent form (ICF).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Sustained an unstable low energy intertrochanteric (Evans Type II or higher) hip&#xD;
             fracture within 7 days prior to planned surgery date. Low energy is defined as a&#xD;
             fracture that occurs spontaneously or from a fall from a stationary height of ≤ 1&#xD;
             meter (3 feet) or missing one to three steps.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women ≥ 55 years of age and men ≥ 30 years of age of any race. If female, subjects&#xD;
             must be post-menopausal for at least 5 years and weigh ≥ 110 lbs or 50 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects who are expected to undergo or have recently undergone (within two weeks)&#xD;
             open or closed repair of the fracture requiring a CHS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. By history, the subject was at least household ambulatory prior to hip fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Serum calcium level within the normal range when corrected for albumin. Corrected&#xD;
             calcium (mg/dL) = Serum Ca (mg/dL) + 0.8 x (4.0 - albumin [g/dL])&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Able and willing to comply with all protocol procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Cognitive, visual, auditory and physical abilities adequate to undertake assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Availability of a care partner to administer injections or demonstrated ability to&#xD;
             self-administer injections. Subjects planning to self-administer study drug will need&#xD;
             to show that they will be capable of accurately self-injecting study drug in rotating&#xD;
             quadrants of the abdomen, in the opinion of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Clinically acceptable medical history and physical examination, according to the&#xD;
             judgment of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Laboratory results within normal ranges or, if abnormal, considered by the&#xD;
             Investigator as not clinically significant for the well-being of the subject or for&#xD;
             the purpose of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             The following additional criteria are required for randomization and dosing with&#xD;
             ZT-031 or placebo to occur:&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The most recent value for 25-hydroxy Vitamin D (25OHD) must be at or above the lower&#xD;
             limit of normal (LLN) for the laboratory reference range of the testing method used&#xD;
             for determination of 25OHD. NOTE: Randomization should be delayed until it is known&#xD;
             that 25OHD is ≥ LLN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The most recent value for intact PTH must be ≤ ULN for the laboratory reference range.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Randomization and dosing must occur within 2 weeks post-op. Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who meet any of the following conditions are excluded from this clinical study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous fracture(s) or bone or joint surgery in the currently fractured site&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Intertrochanteric fracture with reverse obliquity&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pathologic fracture: A fracture occurring at a site of metabolic bone disease (other&#xD;
             than osteoporosis) or a benign or malignant tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of a concurrent disease known to affect bone metabolism other than&#xD;
             post-menopausal osteoporosis, including but not limited to hyperparathyroidism,&#xD;
             hyperthyroidism, osteogenesis imperfecta, abnormalities of serum calcium, Paget's&#xD;
             disease, or osteomalacia&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any significant neurologic disease including but not limited to any dementing illness&#xD;
             or other neurodegenerative disease, cerebrovascular disease, epilepsy or undiagnosed&#xD;
             syncope&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Unstable or clinically significant cardiovascular disease resulting in:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hemodynamic instability manifested as hypotension unresponsive to intravenous&#xD;
                  fluids&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Uncontrolled hypertension requiring administration of parenteral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Renal disease, defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Creatinine level of &gt;2.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Urolithiasis or nephrolithiasis in the last 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hepatic disease or insufficiency, defined by liver function tests (ALT, AST or GGT) &gt;&#xD;
             3 times the ULN or bilirubin &gt; 34 mmol/L or 2.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Currently receiving treatment for cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of external beam radiation to the skeleton or a radiation therapy implant&#xD;
             device&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Presence of substance abuse, including alcohol, within 1 year of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Current or previous use of any PTH compound, including ZT-031&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Use of any investigational compound within 4 weeks of Screening, or within 5&#xD;
             half-lives of compound, whichever is longer&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Use of any bone substitutes, osteobiologics or any fracture healing drug.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>J. Edward Puzas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 7, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 3, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 3, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 4, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Dr. David S. Krause, Chief Medical Officer</name_title>
    <organization>Zelos Therapeutics</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
  <keyword>intertrochanteric</keyword>
  <keyword>hip fracture</keyword>
  <keyword>compression hip screw</keyword>
  <keyword>surgical fixation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

