<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02485639</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14-0059</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>HHSN272201400004C</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02485639</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Analysis of Bone Marrow and Blood B Cell Immune Responses to Influenza Vaccination</brief_title>
  <official_title>Analysis of Bone Marrow and Blood B Cell Immune Responses to Influenza Vaccination</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase IV open label and single arm study enrolling up to 55 healthy males and&#xD;
      non-pregnant females in a single site, 18-49 years old, inclusive. The study is designed to&#xD;
      assess the humoral response to influenza vaccination and the longevity of humoral immunity to&#xD;
      influenza vaccination in healthy adults. The study duration is up to 4 years. After 1 year,&#xD;
      subjects will be offered the opportunity to participate in the study for up to 3 consecutive&#xD;
      years provided eligibility criteria is met each year. Subjects who elect to continue in the&#xD;
      study after first year of participation will be rescreened to verify continued eligibility&#xD;
      and re-consented prior to subsequent participation. The primary study objective is to&#xD;
      investigate the longevity of humoral immunity to influenza virus in humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note: Due to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, all non-essential research was&#xD;
      halted in mid-March 2020. New enrollments were placed on hold for this study. Follow-up&#xD;
      visits were also halted, which impacted the timing of participants' subsequent follow-up&#xD;
      visits. Participant visits for Day 7 and Day 14 were not impacted. For this study, there are&#xD;
      participants whose Day 28 and Day 90 visits were impacted by the temporary halting of&#xD;
      non-essential research studies. As such, a request is submitted to extend the missed visit&#xD;
      windows for the Day 28 and Day 90 visits for a maximum of up to 180 days, to ensure that&#xD;
      ample time is available to bring participants back for their missed visits. Enrollment for&#xD;
      this study ended on March 31, 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase IV open label and single arm study enrolling up to 55 healthy males and&#xD;
      non-pregnant females in a single site, 18-49 years old, inclusive. The study is designed to&#xD;
      assess the humoral response to influenza vaccination and the longevity of humoral immunity to&#xD;
      influenza vaccination in healthy adults. The laboratory technique will characterize&#xD;
      persistence and clonotype of antigen specific B-cells and plasmablasts in blood and bone&#xD;
      marrow. Enrolled subjects will receive licensed seasonal inactivated influenza vaccine&#xD;
      (administered as a part of the study). The vaccine will be administered according to the&#xD;
      package insert, and study participants will donate serial samples of blood and bone marrow&#xD;
      aspirate for immunology monitoring. Safety will be assessed from the time of study enrollment&#xD;
      through the last study visit, via monitoring of vital signs, change in health status, and&#xD;
      targeted physical exam with safety labs prior to each bone marrow aspirate procedure.&#xD;
      Repeated measurements of humoral immunity will be obtained at 7 days, 14 days, 28 days, 90&#xD;
      days and at one year post vaccination to assess the magnitude, clonal diversity and&#xD;
      persistence of B-cell responses to influenza vaccination. The study duration is up to 4&#xD;
      years. After 1 year, subjects will be offered the opportunity to participate in the study for&#xD;
      up to 3 consecutive years provided eligibility criteria is met each year. Subjects who elect&#xD;
      to continue in the study after first year of participation will be rescreened to verify&#xD;
      continued eligibility and re-consented prior to subsequent participation. Re-enrolling&#xD;
      subjects will receive new subject identifiers and will count towards the total enrollment&#xD;
      number for subsequent years of participation. A separate subject record will be maintained&#xD;
      each year a subject re-enrolls in the study. Enrollment for the next year will begin with the&#xD;
      availability of the seasonal flu vaccine. For subjects who elect to re-enroll in the study,&#xD;
      the Day 365 visit (+/- 3 month window) would also be the Day 0 visit for the subsequent year.&#xD;
      The primary study objective is to investigate the longevity of humoral immunity to influenza&#xD;
      virus in humans. The secondary study objective is the longitudinal tracking of&#xD;
      vaccine-induced B cell responses with special emphasis on broadly neutralizing HA&#xD;
      stem-reactive responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note: Due to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, all non-essential research was&#xD;
      halted in mid-March 2020. New enrollments were placed on hold for this study. Follow-up&#xD;
      visits were also halted, which impacted the timing of participants' subsequent follow-up&#xD;
      visits. Participant visits for Day 7 and Day 14 were not impacted. For this study, there are&#xD;
      participants whose Day 28 and Day 90 visits were impacted by the temporary halting of&#xD;
      non-essential research studies. As such, a request is submitted to extend the missed visit&#xD;
      windows for the Day 28 and Day 90 visits for a maximum of up to 180 days, to ensure that&#xD;
      ample time is available to bring participants back for their missed visits. Enrollment for&#xD;
      this study ended on March 31, 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 23, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of influenza-specific antibody secreting cells (ASC) present in the blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of influenza-specific antibody secreting cells (ASC) present in the bone marrow</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 through 365</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of influenza-specific memory B cells present in the blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 through 365</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of seroconverting subjects who maintain a hemagglutination inhibition (HAI) titer &gt; / = 1:40</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 365</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects achieving seroconversion to each of the 3 strains in the vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 180</time_frame>
    <description>Seroconversion defined as having a pre-vaccination hemagglutination inhibition (HAI) titer &lt; 1:40 against a particular strain and a day 28 post-vaccination titer &gt; / = 1:40 against the same strain</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of hemagglutinin stem reactive responses to influenza vaccine among blood plasmablasts</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of hemagglutinin stem reactive responses to influenza vaccine among the bone marrow plasma cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 365</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Influenza</condition>
  <condition>Influenza Immunisation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All study participants will receive licensed inactivated influenza vaccine intramuscularly on Day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Influenza Virus Vaccine Inactivated</intervention_name>
    <description>A synthetic vaccine consisting of three inactivated influenza viruses: two different influenza type A strains and one influenza type B strain. Trivalent influenza vaccine is formulated annually, based on influenza strains projected to be prevalent in the upcoming flu season. All participants will receive vaccine IM on day 1.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or non-pregnant female subjects between 18 and 49 years of age (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects capable of providing written informed consent prior to initiation of any&#xD;
             study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects able to understand and comply with planned study procedures and be available&#xD;
             for all study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Safety labs:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White blood cell count (WBC), within reference range of lower limit of normal of&#xD;
                  4,000 per microliter (uL), and upper limit of normal of 10,000 per microliter&#xD;
                  (uL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin, within reference range of lower limit of normal of 11.4 grams per&#xD;
                  deciliter (gm/dL) and upper limit of normal of 16.1 grams per deciliter (gm/dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematocrit, within reference range of lower limit of normal of 33.3 percent and&#xD;
                  an upper limit of normal of 46.5 percent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet Count, within reference range of lower limit of normal of 150,000 per&#xD;
                  microliter (uL) and upper limit of normal of 400,000 per microliter (uL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prothrombin Time (PT/INR), PT below or equal to the upper limit of normal of 13.1&#xD;
                  seconds; International Normalized Ratio (INR) within normal reference range of&#xD;
                  less than 1.5 (normal range for non-anti-coagulated patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine within reference range of lower limit of normal of 0.4 milligrams per&#xD;
                  deciliter (mg / dL) and upper limit of normal of 1.2 milligrams per deciliter (mg&#xD;
                  / dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Potassium, within reference range of lower limit of normal of 3.6 millimolar (mM)&#xD;
                  and upper limit of normal of 5.1 millimolar (mM).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Heart rate &gt; / = 55 to &lt; / = 100 per minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Systolic blood pressure &gt; / = 90 to &lt; / = 150 millimeters of mercury (mmHg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Diastolic blood pressure &lt; 90 millimeters of mercury (mmHg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Oral temperature &lt; 100 degrees Fahrenheit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Respirations even, unlabored, and &gt; 10 / minute to &lt; 20 / minute.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female subjects of child bearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             at the screening visit, enrollment visit and prior to subsequent bone marrow aspirate&#xD;
             procedures. Female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to practice&#xD;
             abstinence, use a barrier method of birth control, or use an U.S. Food and Drug&#xD;
             Administration (FDA) approved form of birth control.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who have not received seasonal flu vaccine for the current year (September -&#xD;
             June).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. If female, active pregnancy or breast-feeding or plans to become pregnant during study&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject report of having any medical disease or condition that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             site principal investigator or appropriate sub-investigator, is a contraindication to&#xD;
             study participation. This includes any acute or chronic medical disease or condition,&#xD;
             defined as persisting 3 months (defined as 90 days) or longer, that would place the&#xD;
             subject at an unacceptable risk of injury, render the subject unable to meet the&#xD;
             requirements of the protocol, or may interfere with the evaluation of responses or the&#xD;
             subject's successful completion of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject report of taking anticoagulants, or long-term (greater than 14 days) systemic&#xD;
             steroids or other immunosuppressive medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject report of known allergy to lidocaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject report of known hypersensitivity or allergy to eggs, egg or chicken protein,&#xD;
             report of allergy to components of the study vaccine or other components of the study&#xD;
             vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject report of known latex allergy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject report of a history of severe reactions following previous immunization with&#xD;
             licensed or unlicensed influenza virus vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject report of a history of Guillain-Barre syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who believe they cannot tolerate the bone marrow aspirations without&#xD;
             sedation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects with an active infection or that have an acute illness within 72 hours prior&#xD;
             to study vaccination. Subject having had an acute illness which is nearly resolved&#xD;
             with only minor residual symptoms remaining is allowable if, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             site principal investigator or appropriate sub-investigator, the residual symptoms&#xD;
             will not interfere with the ability to assess safety parameters as required by the&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who are participating in another clinical trial involving the use of&#xD;
             investigational agents or vaccines.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory Clinic - Winship Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322-1059</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 17, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 11, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 25, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 30, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HA-specific plasmablasts</keyword>
  <keyword>humoral immunity</keyword>
  <keyword>influenza</keyword>
  <keyword>memory B cells</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

