<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04344470</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200077</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-N-0077</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04344470</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Volition: Behavioral Analysis and EEG/ERP Analysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study of Volition: Behavioral Analysis and EEG/ERP Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      'Free will' can be defined as the belief that people have control over their thoughts and&#xD;
      movements. The topic of free will is controversial and is still being debated. Science has&#xD;
      only partial answers to questions about free will, so researchers want to learn more about&#xD;
      it. They want to assess the role of consciousness when intentions are present with behavior.&#xD;
      This could help to explain the causal role of consciousness in movement or decisions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn more about free will.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy, right-handed adults ages 25-45&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with medical history, physical exam, and neurological exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 1 study visit. It will last up to 4 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will sit in a comfortable chair in front of a screen. They will perform some or&#xD;
      all of the following tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visual Task. Participants will watch different stimuli on the screen and answer simple&#xD;
      questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electroencephalography (EEG). An EEG records the electrical activity of the brain ('brain&#xD;
      waves'). For the EEG, small electrodes are put on the scalp with an electrode cap. A gel is&#xD;
      placed in the space between the electrodes and the scalp. Participants' brain waves will be&#xD;
      recorded, including while they decide whether to move their thumb.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Choice/Reaction Time Task. Participants will watch different stimuli on the screen and react&#xD;
      to them by moving their wrist. During this task, they will wear an EEG cap on their head and&#xD;
      electrodes on their arms and wrists.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electromyography. Small electrodes will be attached to participants' skin. Their muscle&#xD;
      activity will be recorded while they decide whether to move their wrist and during the&#xD;
      movement itself....&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main focus of this protocol will be to try to identify the quale of free will, its&#xD;
      electrophysiological correlates, and to determine whether this quale plays a causative role&#xD;
      in movement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will be doing a series of experiments. In the first experiments, we want to explore the&#xD;
      behavioral response of normal subjects when they move after a visual stimulus that can be&#xD;
      seen or unseen. We want to study behavior in different conditions with movement triggered by&#xD;
      stimuli seen and not seen. Furthermore, we want to analyze the EEG related to those stimuli&#xD;
      to explore sensory and motor processing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reaction time and accuracies of the responses to different stimuli in different conditions&#xD;
      will be identified as well as the subjects subjective experiences. EEG ERP shapes and&#xD;
      microstates patterns will also be investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 50 healthy volunteers of both genders between the ages of 25-45, fluent in English and&#xD;
      right-handed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total study is expected to last 48 months, with each individual expected to participate&#xD;
      in a single 4-hour outpatient visit at the NIH Clinical Center, but there can be multiple&#xD;
      visits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Experiment1: Identification of the best characteristics that allow us to create a backward masking effect of the second stimulus on the first one.</measure>
    <time_frame>throughout</time_frame>
    <description>We will develop a methodological approach to create the best backward masking effect. We will ask the subjects what they saw, to prove the effectiveness of the backward masking.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Experiment 2: Reaction time and accuracies of the responses to different stimuli (symbols, faces, objects, etc.) in different conditions (with and without masking)</measure>
    <time_frame>throughout</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will move to the first stimulus even if unseen. We want to study subjects behavior in different conditions (simple reaction task, choice reaction task, with and without masking) with different stimuli (symbols, faces, objects, etc.). Furthermore, we want to analyze the EEG (classic ERP, microstates, etc.) related to those stimuli. EEG will be also analyzed to study the nature and strength of the visual pathway for movement and the pathway for visual perception at rest.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Experiment 1: Identification of the EEG characteristic or ERP shape related to different stimuli and the brain region origin.</measure>
    <time_frame>throughout</time_frame>
    <description>We will create a template of the shape of the ERP and the characteristics of EEG related to different stimuli to be identified in the second sub-study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Normal Physiology</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy Volunteers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EMG</intervention_name>
    <description>EMG will be recorded from two electrodes placed on both extensor carpi radialis (ECR) muscles</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EEG</intervention_name>
    <description>EEG electrodes will be positioned according to 10-20 International System, with every impedance kept under 5 kOhm. EEG data will be amplified, filtered (DC-100 Hz), digitized at 1000 Hz, and stored on a computer for offline analysis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 25-45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Right-handed (tested by the Edinburg handedness inventory).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to comply with all study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fluent in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illegal drug use within the past 6 months based on history alone. The intent is to&#xD;
             exclude those with drug use that may affect study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported consumption of &gt;14 alcoholic drinks/week for a man and &gt;7 alcoholic&#xD;
             drinks/week for a woman.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal findings on neurological examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of current brain tumor, stroke, head trauma with loss of consciousness,&#xD;
             epilepsy, or seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current episode of major depression or any major psychiatric illness.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Hallett, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antonio I Triggiani, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-9526</phone>
    <email>antonio.triggiani@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-N-0077.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 12, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

