<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04344795</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TPST-1495-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04344795</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase 1a/1b Study of TPST-1495 as a Single Agent and in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Subjects With Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1a/1b Open Label Dose-escalation and Expansion Study of TPST-1495 as a Single Agent and in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Subjects With Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tempest Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tempest Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a first-in-human Phase 1a/1b, multicenter, open-label, dose-escalation, dose and&#xD;
      schedule optimization, and expansion study of TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination&#xD;
      with pembrolizumab to determine its maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and or recommended Phase 2&#xD;
      dose (RP2D), safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics and preliminary&#xD;
      anti-tumor activity in subjects with advanced solid tumors. Subjects with all histologic&#xD;
      types of solid tumors are eligible for the escalation and dose-finding portions of the study.&#xD;
      However, the preferred tumor types for enrollment are colorectal cancer (CRC), non-small cell&#xD;
      lung cancer (NSCLC), squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN), urothelial cancer,&#xD;
      endometrial cancer, and gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) or gastric adenocarcinoma. Enrollment&#xD;
      in the expansion cohorts is limited to the following tumor types: endometrial, SCCHN, CRC,&#xD;
      and a basket cohort in subjects selected for an activating mutation in PIK3Ca.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a first-in-human Phase 1a/1b, multicenter, open-label, dose-escalation, dose and&#xD;
      schedule optimization, and expansion study of TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination&#xD;
      with pembrolizumab to determine its MTD, safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics (PD),&#xD;
      pharmacodynamics (PK) and preliminary anti-tumor activity in subjects with advanced solid&#xD;
      tumors. Subjects with all histologic types of solid tumors are eligible for the study.&#xD;
      However, the preferred tumor types for enrollment are colorectal cancer (CRC), non-small cell&#xD;
      lung cancer (NSCLC), squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN), urothelial cancer,&#xD;
      endometrial cancer, and gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) or gastric adenocarcinoma. Tumor&#xD;
      prostaglandin production and downstream signaling in both tumor cells and other cell types,&#xD;
      including immune suppressive cell population in the tumor microenvironment, is thought to be&#xD;
      a principal driver of progression in each of these selected malignancies. To be eligible,&#xD;
      subjects must have no remaining standard therapy known to confer clinical benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is composed of 3 stages. The Dose-Escalation stage will determine the MTD of&#xD;
      single-agent TPST-1495 administered twice a day (BID). The Schedule and Dose Optimization&#xD;
      stage will evaluate alternative TPST-1495 single-agent administration schedules and determine&#xD;
      an RP2D for the selected schedule. This arm will also evaluate TPST-1495 in combination with&#xD;
      pembrolizumab. The Expansion stage will evaluate the activity of TPST-1495 as a single agent&#xD;
      and in combination with pembrolizumab at the selected schedule and dose in disease-specific&#xD;
      cohorts and in a basket cohort in subjects selected for an activating mutation in PIK3Ca.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>open-label dose escalation, schedule and dose optimization, and dose expansion</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of maximum tolerated dose and/or recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) and optimum dose schedule for TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination with pembrolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of maximum tolerated dose and/or recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) and optimum dose schedule for TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination with pembrolizumab based on dose limiting toxicities</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events and serious adverse events as assessed by NCI-CTCAE v.5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of treatment-emergent adverse events and serious adverse events for TPST-1495</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacokinetics: maximum serum concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum serum concentration (Cmax) of TPST-1495</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacokinetics: area under the serum concentration-time curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the serum concentration-time curve (AUC) of TPST-1495</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacokinetics: Clearance (CL)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clearance (CL) of TPST-1495</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess pharmacokinetics: terminal elimination half-life (t 1/2)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half-life (t 1/2) of TPST-1495</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) using RECIST version 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Preliminary efficacy of TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination with pembrolizumab as assessed by overall response rate (ORR) using RECIST version 1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Preliminary efficacy of TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination with pembrolizumab as assessed by progression free survival (PFS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to treatment termination visit, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Preliminary efficacy of TPST-1495 as a single agent and in combination with pembrolizumab as assessed by duration of response (DoR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">175</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</condition>
  <condition>Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastroesophageal Junction Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Gastric Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Solid Tumors With PIK3Ca Mutation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive escalating doses of TPST-1495 administered orally twice daily until maximum tolerated dose is reached or until disease progression</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose and schedule optimization</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive alternative TPST-1495 administration schedules until RP2D for the selected schedule is determined or until disease progression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive selected dose regimen from dose and schedule optimization stage until disease progression</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose and schedule optimization</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive alternative TPST-1495 administration schedules in combination with pembrolizumab until RP2D for the selected schedule is determined or until disease progression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive selected dose regimen from dose and schedule optimization stage until disease progression</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TPST-1495 twice daily</intervention_name>
    <description>TPST-1495 administered orally twice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose escalation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TPST-1495 once daily or on intermittent schedule</intervention_name>
    <description>TPST-1495 administered orally once daily or on intermittent schedule</description>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose and schedule optimization</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose and schedule optimization</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 monotherapy dose expansion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab dosed per label recommendations</description>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose and schedule optimization</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TPST-1495 in combination with pembrolizumab dose expansion</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Subjects must meet all the following inclusion criteria to be eligible:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must have a histologically-confirmed malignancy that is metastatic or&#xD;
             unresectable for which there is no remaining standard therapy known to confer clinical&#xD;
             benefit. While all solid tumor types are eligible for the dose-escalation and&#xD;
             dose-finding portions of the study, there is a preference to enroll patients with&#xD;
             colorectal cancer, squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck, urothelial cancer,&#xD;
             endometrial cancer, NSCLC, and gastric or gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
             The expansion cohorts are limited to the following tumor types: endometrial, SCCHN,&#xD;
             CRC, and tumors with an activating mutation in PIK3Ca.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects must have a tumor that is at least 1 cm in a single dimension and is&#xD;
             radiographically apparent on CT or MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0 or 1 at treatment&#xD;
             initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Life expectancy estimated to be ≥ 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Adequate organ and marrow function (subjects must not have received transfusions or&#xD;
             growth factor support within 1 month prior to first dose of investigational product)&#xD;
             as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Albumin ≥ 3.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × institutional upper limit of normal (ULN); for subjects with&#xD;
                  documented/suspected Gilbert's disease, bilirubin should be ≤ 2 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 × ULN; for&#xD;
                  subjects with liver metastases, AST or ALT ≤ 5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ 1.5×ULN OR calculated creatinine clearance (CrCl) ≥ 60 mL/min for&#xD;
                  subjects with creatinine levels &gt; 1.5× ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who meet any of the following exclusion criteria will not be eligible to receive&#xD;
        investigational product:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Concurrent enrollment in another clinical study, unless it is an observational (non&#xD;
             interventional) clinical study, a specimen-collection study or the follow-up period of&#xD;
             an interventional study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received more than 4 doses of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs or COX-2 inhibitors&#xD;
             within 2 weeks prior to study treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of allergy or hypersensitivity, GI bleed, or ulceration secondary to&#xD;
             nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs or COX-2 inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of GI ulcer within 1 year of treatment initiation or history of untreated&#xD;
             helicobacter pylori infection. Subjects with history of treated helicobacter pylori&#xD;
             infection with confirmation of eradication are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of diverticulitis or any GI bleed within 2 years of treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of any anticancer therapy within the following windows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Small molecule tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI) therapy (including&#xD;
                  investigational) within 2 weeks or 5 half-lives prior to treatment initiation,&#xD;
                  whichever is longer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any type of anti-cancer antibody or cytotoxic chemotherapy within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
                  to treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation therapy for bone metastasis within 2 weeks, any other external&#xD;
                  radiation therapy within 4 weeks before treatment initiation. Patients with&#xD;
                  clinically relevant ongoing complications from prior radiation therapy are not&#xD;
                  eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other investigational therapy within 2 weeks or 5 half-lives prior to dosing,&#xD;
                  whichever is longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with active or untreated central nervous system (CNS) metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. New York Heart Association Classification II, III or IV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Baseline QTcF &gt; 470 milliseconds&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Receipt of live attenuated vaccines within 30 days prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             investigational product. (Killed virus or other non-live vaccines are allowed&#xD;
             (including most seasonal influenza vaccines, streptococcus pneumonia vaccines, and&#xD;
             newly approved COVID-19 vaccines).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Active autoimmune disease or inflammatory disorders including inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease (e.g., ulcerative colitis or Crohn's disease) requiring systemic treatment&#xD;
             (i.e., with use of disease modifying agents, systemic corticosteroids or&#xD;
             immunosuppressive drug) within 2 years prior to treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, active Hepatitis B (HBV), or&#xD;
             hepatitis C (HCV). Active HBV is defined as a known positive HBsAg result. Active HCV&#xD;
             is defined by a known positive HCV antibody result and known quantitative HCV RNA&#xD;
             results greater than the lower limits of detection of the assay. Patients receiving&#xD;
             antiviral therapy for Hepatitis B or C also are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness, including but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, serious chronic gastrointestinal conditions&#xD;
             associated with diarrhea, or psychiatric illness/social situations including a history&#xD;
             of substance abuse that would limit compliance with study requirement, substantially&#xD;
             increase risk of incurring AEs or compromise the ability of the patient to give&#xD;
             written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects who are receiving anti-coagulant therapy or who are considered to be at&#xD;
             increased risk of bleeding (i.e bleeding disorder or coagulopathy).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samuel Whiting, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Tempest Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tempest Clinical Trial Support</last_name>
    <phone>415-798-8589</phone>
    <phone_ext>122</phone_ext>
    <email>1495-Inquiries@tempesttx.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan Rogel Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brandy Slusser</last_name>
      <phone>734-936-9499</phone>
      <email>slusserb@med.umich.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>START Midwest</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49546</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yvette Cole</last_name>
      <phone>616-389-1652</phone>
      <email>yvette.cole@startmidwest.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carolina BioOncology Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Huntersville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28078</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sophia Jean-Francois, BS</last_name>
      <phone>980-441-1149</phone>
      <email>sjean-francois@carolinabiooncology.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SCRI-OK Stephenson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura Deaver</last_name>
      <phone>405-271-8001</phone>
      <phone_ext>30488</phone_ext>
      <email>Laura-Deaver@ouhsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sarah Brodeur</last_name>
      <phone>412-623-2944</phone>
      <email>brodeurs@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennessee Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Referrals</last_name>
      <email>DDUreferrals@sarahcannon.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Texas Accelerated Research Therapeutics (START)</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Edwin F Blanco-Cepeda, BSN, RN</last_name>
      <phone>210-593-2547</phone>
      <email>Edwin.BlancoCepeda@startsa.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>TPST-1495</keyword>
  <keyword>EP2 antagonist</keyword>
  <keyword>EP4 antagonist</keyword>
  <keyword>prostaglandin E2 (PGE2)</keyword>
  <keyword>pembrolizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>PIK3Ca mutation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

