<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05016440</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Lisinopril-Renal Protection</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05016440</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lisinopril for Renal Protection in Postpartum Preeclamptic Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>Lisinopril To Reduce Microalbuminuria In Postpartum Preeclamptic Women. A Role For Renal Protection?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eastern Virginia Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eastern Virginia Medical School</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There may be a role for Lisinopril in improving renal protection in post-partum women who had&#xD;
      preeclampsia during pregnancy. The aim of this study is to determine whether routine&#xD;
      initiation of Lisinopril after delivery, in women who had preeclampsia while they were&#xD;
      pregnant, can control high blood pressure and improve kidney function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is being done to determine the effects (good or bad) of Lisinopril (high blood&#xD;
      pressure medication) in controlling high blood pressure and improving kidney function for&#xD;
      women after delivery who had preeclampsia while they were pregnant .Preeclampsia is a&#xD;
      condition that can occur during pregnancy, up to 6 weeks post partum, where the mother's&#xD;
      blood pressure is high and protein is present in the urine. This can be dangerous for both&#xD;
      the mother and fetus. Although the blood pressure usually returns to normal after delivery,&#xD;
      elevated pressures may continue. Normally medication is given when you continue to have high&#xD;
      blood pressure after delivery. High blood pressure can cause damage to the kidneys.&#xD;
      Lisinopril is a medication that can be used to treat high blood pressure after delivery.&#xD;
      Lisinopril offers kidney protection in patients diagnosed with diabetes. We currently do not&#xD;
      know if lisinopril can offer the same kidney protection in women diagnosed with preeclampsia.&#xD;
      Considering that 10% of all pregnant women develop preeclampsia, the number of women who may&#xD;
      eventually develop end stage kidney disease is relatively large and any relatively safe and&#xD;
      easy means to prevent this disease would be beneficial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Albumin Excretion Rate in mg/mmol</measure>
    <time_frame>Change is being assessed within 24 hours of delivery and 6-8 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Prior to discharge from the hospital, either during the woman's labor progress or immediately post delivery, a catheterized urine specimen will be obtained and sent to the lab for an Albumin-Creatinine Ratio (ACR) by a nurse. Following discharge, the woman will be seen 6-8 weeks postpartum for her routine postpartum visit. If the woman reports vaginal spotting or bleeding a straight catheter urine specimen will be obtained, otherwise a clean catch specimen may be obtained, and sent for lab assessment of Albumin-Creatinine Ratio (ACR). This collection of a urine specimen is standard of care for our pregnant and postpartum patients. Prior to hospital discharge, she will also be instructed to collect a 24 hour urine specimen collection, the day before her 6-8 week postpartum visit and bring it with her to this visit. When analyzed, this second 24 hour urine specimen will be assessed for both albumin concentration and albumin/creatinine ratio (Albumin Excretion Rate).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Microalbuminuria</condition>
  <condition>Preeclampsia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lisinopril</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>10mg Lisinopril tablets</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sugar pill</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>sugar pill</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lisinopril</intervention_name>
    <description>10mg Lisinopril daily for 6-8 weeks postpartum</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lisinopril</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sugar pill</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women 18 to 50 yrs of age with mild or severe preeclampsia diagnosed using criteria&#xD;
             (listed below) set forth by the American College of Obstetrics and Gynecology (ACOG)&#xD;
             Criteria. (Note; women who become eclamptic will be included in the study.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood Pressure of 140 mmHg systolic or greater or 90 mmHg diastolic or higher&#xD;
                  that occurs after 20 weeks' gestational age in a woman with previously normal&#xD;
                  blood pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Proteinuria defined as 0.3 g protein or higher in a 24 hour urine specimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Preeclampsia was considered severe when any of the following were present:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Blood pressure of 160 mmHg systolic of higher or 110 mg Hg diastolic or&#xD;
                       higher on two occasions at least 6 hours apart while the patient is on bed&#xD;
                       rest&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Proteinuria of 5 grams of higher in a 24-hour urine specimen of 3+ or&#xD;
                       greater on two random urine samples collected at least 4 hours apart&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Oliguria of less than 500cc in 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
                    4. Cerebral of visual disturbances&#xD;
&#xD;
                    5. Pulmonary edema or cyanosis&#xD;
&#xD;
                    6. Epigastric or right upper quadrant pain&#xD;
&#xD;
                    7. Impaired liver function, thrombocytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
                    8. Fetal growth restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior hypersensitivity (allergic reaction) to Lisinopril or ACE Inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pre-gestational chronic hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pre-gestational diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Rheumatologic disorders (i.e., systemic lupus erythematosus, scleroderma)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple gestations for present pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who declined birth control postpartum&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient who has been on an Ace-inhibitor within 6 months prior to pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac problems like; Aortic stenosis or Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe kidney disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Taking any of the prohibited medications listed in section VI&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prisoners will not be included in the study due to difficulty in tracking their&#xD;
                  pregnancy care being provided at the prison centers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James Hill, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Eastern Virginia Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eastern Virginia Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23507</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lisinopril</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

