<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05011890</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LCCC 2050</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>25210</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05011890</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remote Monitoring of Lung Cancer Patient-Reported Outcomes Using Moovcare®</brief_title>
  <acronym>LC-PRO</acronym>
  <official_title>Feasibility and Acceptability of Remote Monitoring of Lung Cancer Patient-Reported Outcomes Using Moovcare®</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sivan Innovation Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to demonstrate how Moovcare®, a mobile medical application, can&#xD;
      be used to monitor Patient-Reported Outcomes (PROs) related to cancer treatment, cancer&#xD;
      complications, and cancer relapse in patients with lung cancer. PROs are symptoms directly&#xD;
      reported by patients through the completion of a survey. Up to 300 patients undergoing&#xD;
      treatment and/or surveillance for new or existing diagnoses of lung cancer at the University&#xD;
      of North Carolina's Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center will be prospectively enrolled to&#xD;
      the use of the mobile medical application Moovcare® for two years. Moovcare® is not FDA&#xD;
      approved, and its role in improving clinical care is being studied through this research.&#xD;
      Moovcare® automatically delivers electronic patient reported outcome (ePRO) surveys on common&#xD;
      symptoms experienced by lung cancer patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single site nonrandomized feasibility study of approximately 300 participants on&#xD;
      treatment and/or surveillance for new or existing diagnoses of lung cancer who will be&#xD;
      assigned to a single-arm involving monitoring of their patient-reported outcomes using a&#xD;
      mobile medical application. The study procedures include monitoring of patient symptoms using&#xD;
      automated weekly PRO surveys delivered by Moovcare® and assessment of outcomes including&#xD;
      quality of life at baseline and at monthly intervals, as well as patient satisfaction at 6&#xD;
      months and 1 year. Other clinical outcomes including health care utilization, recurrence, and&#xD;
      survival will be assessed. The clinical care team will receive an alert if the PRO survey&#xD;
      suggests increased or worsening symptoms.The care team will follow their usual protocols for&#xD;
      the management of symptoms. The patient clinical information will also be abstracted from the&#xD;
      medical record to assess clinical outcomes. The provider's satisfaction survey will be&#xD;
      assessed via surveys.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a single site nonrandomized feasibility study of approximately 300 participants on treatment and/or surveillance for new or existing diagnoses of lung cancer who will be assigned to a single arm involving monitoring of their patient-reported outcomes using a mobile medical application. The study population will include patients with a diagnosis of clinical-stage I-IV lung cancer undergoing outpatient treatment or surveillance at UNC. Patients will be recruited from the Multidisciplinary Thoracic Oncology Program (MTOP) clinics at the University of North Carolina over 10-12 months and undergo ePRO monitoring for 2 years or until criteria for coming off study are met, whichever comes first.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of self-reporting symptoms by lung cancer patients using Moovcare®</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Average percentage of e-PRO surveys completed per patient by 6 months or coming off study per protocol if sooner.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline at 6 months and 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>≥75% of patients report having open/honest communication with care team</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Provider satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>≥75% of providers would recommend use of Moovcare</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>CT scan evidence of survival as confirmed by the treating clinician</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>CT scan evidence of recurrence as confirmed by the treating clinician</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health care utilization (Emergency Department)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with emergency department visits</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health care utilization (hospitalization)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with hospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life (QLQ-C30)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>EORTC QLQC30 is a validated instrument to assess quality of life and is composed of multi-item scales and single-item measures. Possible scores ranges from 0 to 100; a higher score represents a higher (&quot;better&quot;) level of functioning, or a higher (&quot;worse&quot;) level of symptoms.&#xD;
Change = (6 months score - Baseline) and (1 year score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life (QLQ-LC13)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>EORTC QLQ-LC13 is a validated instrument to assess quality of life and is composed of one multi-item scale. Possible scores ranges from 0 to 100; a higher score represents an increasing symptom level.&#xD;
Change = (6 months score - Baseline) and (1 year score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Neoplasms, Lung</condition>
  <condition>Neoplasms, Pulmonary</condition>
  <condition>Pulmonary Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pulmonary Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Cancer of Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single-arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be assigned to the single-arm involving weekly monitoring of their patient-reported outcomes using Moovcare®.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Moovcare® use</intervention_name>
    <description>Moovcare® performs symptom monitoring by automatically delivering ePRO surveys on common symptoms experienced by lung cancer patients. Results are stored in a secure web-based portal for provider review. Providers will manage ePRO responses through a combination of reports graphically displaying responses over time and e-mail alerts about concerning levels or combinations of symptoms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single-arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stage I-IV lung cancer undergoing outpatient treatment and/or surveillance/monitoring&#xD;
             at UNC.&#xD;
&#xD;
             This will include stage I and II patients who have completed lung resection and/or are&#xD;
             undergoing radiation, stage II and III patients receiving neoadjuvant, adjuvant, or&#xD;
             definitive chemotherapy, stage IV patients undergoing active therapy or monitoring,&#xD;
             and patients undergoing surveillance for treated or untreated stage I-III lung cancer.&#xD;
             The study team will request the patient stage from the managing clinician. Patients&#xD;
             can be enrolled at any point in their lung cancer treatment trajectory (i.e., not just&#xD;
             at the initiation of first-line treatment) after a diagnosis of lung cancer has been&#xD;
             assigned by the treating clinician. This may include patients assigned a diagnosis of&#xD;
             lung cancer without a tissue diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ECOG Performance Status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Speaks and understands English&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Reliable access to the internet and email (by participant or caregiver who can assist&#xD;
             the participant with surveys)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Access to a mobile phone (participant or caregiver who can assist participant with&#xD;
             surveys)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Dementia, altered mental status, or any psychiatric condition that would prohibit the&#xD;
             understanding or rendering of informed consent or completing study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current participation in other PRO monitoring trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Inability to read and speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Current incarceration&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gita Mody, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sachita Shrestha, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>(919) 966-4320</phone>
    <email>sachita_shrestha@med.unc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Bri Castrogivanni</last_name>
    <phone>(919) 966-3036</phone>
    <email>brianna_castrogivanni@med.unc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center at University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gita Mody, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>919-966-3381</phone>
      <email>gita_mody@med.unc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sachita Shrestha, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>(919) 966-4320</phone>
      <email>sachita_shrestha@med.unc.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://unclineberger.org/patientcare/clinical-trials/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Patient Reported Outcome</keyword>
  <keyword>Feasibility</keyword>
  <keyword>Acceptability</keyword>
  <keyword>Moovcare®</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No plans as of now to make IPD available to other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

