<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05017909</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IARPACI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05017909</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Different Education Techniques on the Acquisition of the Mothering Role</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Education Given to Primipara Pregnancy With Two Different Methods (Face-To-Face/ Web-Based) in the Last Trimester on Their Acquisition of the Mothering Role</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hasan Kalyoncu University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hasan Kalyoncu University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The research consists of two stages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First Stage: It is the development of the scale for gaining the role of motherhood in&#xD;
      primiparas according to the scale development stages. In order to define the subject and&#xD;
      determine the scope, the content analysis will be determined by interviewing the sample group&#xD;
      that will not be included in the pilot application and the final scale application and the&#xD;
      primipara people with similar characteristics. As a result, the item pool will form the basis&#xD;
      together with the literature. An item pool related to gaining the role of motherhood will be&#xD;
      created, the opinions of experts will be taken to evaluate the scope and appearance validity&#xD;
      of the scale, and adjustments will be made in the item pool according to expert opinions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to determine the validity and reliability of the scale, half of the participants&#xD;
      will be tested-retested. The internal consistency reliability of the scale will be determined&#xD;
      by the Cronbach Alpha reliability coefficient. In addition, Edinburgh Postpartum Depression&#xD;
      Scale (EDDS) and Mother-Infant Attachment Scale (MIAS), which are similar scales, will be&#xD;
      used in the scale development phase for the validity of the scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Second stage: The training consisting of 3 modules is planned. MODULE: Mother Module MODULE:&#xD;
      Infant Module MODULE: Breastfeeding Module&#xD;
&#xD;
      At this stage of the study, pregnant women who meet the sampling criteria will be divided&#xD;
      into groups. The determination of the groups will be according to the Randomized numbers&#xD;
      table. Pregnant women who will enter the web-based training group (Experimental group 1),&#xD;
      Face-to-face training group (Experimental group 2) and the control group will be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The personal information form containing the socio-demographic data and the final scale&#xD;
      developed to gain the role of motherhood in primiparas will be applied to the participants&#xD;
      who volunteered to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Initiative: A web-based and face-to-face training program will be planned and&#xD;
      implemented as separate groups for the sampled participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-Test Application of the Final Scale: The final scale, which was developed to gain the&#xD;
      role of motherhood in primiparas, will be administered to the participants in the sample&#xD;
      group as a post-test on the 40th day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By analyzing the data obtained, the effectiveness of the scale and the difference between the&#xD;
      pre-test scores of the participant group after the training program will be examined.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The research was planned methodologically and experimentally. A motherhood role acquisition&#xD;
      scale will be developed as a methodological study, and web-based and face-to-face training&#xD;
      will be given experimentally. The effect of the training given on the acquisition of the role&#xD;
      of mother will be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research will be conducted between September 2021 and September 2022.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Universe and Sample of the Research; the population of the research will be all&#xD;
      primiparous pregnant women who meet the criteria for participation in the study and volunteer&#xD;
      to participate in the study in two different Family Health Centers (FHC) affiliated to&#xD;
      Gaziantep Provincial Health Directorate and Private Dr. Tuncay Yüce Gynecology and Obstetrics&#xD;
      Clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample of the first stage of the research; determined by the number of items in the&#xD;
      scale. When we examine the literature, it is seen that there will be 5-10 times as many&#xD;
      participants as the number of items, and the sample size should be at least 50 in the data&#xD;
      for which factor analysis will be applied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample of the second phase of the research; With G-Power, it was determined that there&#xD;
      were 42 people in the experimental 1 group, 42 in the experimental 2 group, and 42 in the&#xD;
      control group at 80% power, 5% error and 95% confidence interval. Data collection will take&#xD;
      place between September 2021 and May 2022.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Location and Characteristics of the Research; The research will be carried out between&#xD;
      December 2021 and May 2022 with primiparous pregnant women in two different Family Health&#xD;
      Centers (ASM) affiliated to Gaziantep Provincial Health Directorate and Private Dr. Tuncay&#xD;
      Yüce Gynecology and Obstetrics Clinic. There are 10 Family Medicine units in total in two&#xD;
      centers, and there are baby care rooms and breastfeeding rooms where training can be provided&#xD;
      for pregnant women in Family Health Centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Application of Research&#xD;
&#xD;
      Under the guidance of the literature, an item pool will be created and the content validity&#xD;
      of the scale will be determined by taking the opinions of field experts. Care will be taken&#xD;
      to ensure that the sample size is at least 5 times the number of items. After the approval of&#xD;
      the ethics committee, the written consent of the primiparous pregnant women who volunteered&#xD;
      to participate will be obtained and they will be asked to respond to the data collection&#xD;
      tool. The data obtained will be analyzed, and the final form will be created by selecting&#xD;
      items with high reliability according to the results obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the last form, the sample size will be calculated according to the minimum sample size&#xD;
      formula to represent the population. The final form will be applied after obtaining written&#xD;
      permission from the participants who volunteered to participate in the research. The obtained&#xD;
      data will be analyzed and interpreted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental group 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study will be explained to the pregnant women in the experimental group 1,&#xD;
      and those who accepted to participate in the study and who met the criteria of the study&#xD;
      would have to fill in the personal information form prepared by the researcher as a pre-test&#xD;
      form, which includes socio-demographic data, and the scale developed to gain the role of&#xD;
      motherhood. Afterwards, a 3-week training will be applied on the created web page, and the&#xD;
      scale developed to give mothers the role of motherhood as a post-test will be applied in the&#xD;
      first 40 days following the birth of expectant mothers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental group 2&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study was explained to the pregnant women in the experimental group 2, and&#xD;
      those who accepted to participate in the study and who met the criteria of the study would be&#xD;
      asked to fill in the personal information form prepared by the researcher, containing the&#xD;
      socio-demographic data as a pre-test form, and the scale developed to gain the role of&#xD;
      motherhood in Primiparas. Then, a 3-week face-to-face training will be applied, and the scale&#xD;
      developed to give mothers the role of motherhood as a post-test will be applied to mothers in&#xD;
      the first 40 days following their birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control group&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study will be explained to the pregnant women in the control group, and&#xD;
      those who agree to participate in the study and who meet the criteria of the study will be&#xD;
      asked to fill in the personal information form containing their socio-demographic data as a&#xD;
      pre-test form prepared by the researcher, and the scale developed to gain the role of&#xD;
      motherhood in Primiparas. The pregnant women in the control group will not be trained, and&#xD;
      the scale developed to give mothers the role of motherhood will be applied as a post-test in&#xD;
      the first 40 days following their birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Educational subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
      The training consists of 3 modules.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. MODULE: Mother Module&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. MODULE: Baby Module&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. MODULE: Breastfeeding Module&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Tools&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data during the scale development phase will be collected using the &quot;Draft Scale for&#xD;
      Acquiring the Role of Motherhood&quot; form determined in the item pool, the data collection form&#xD;
      developed by the researcher, and the Edinburgh Postpartum Depression Scale (EDDS) and the&#xD;
      Mother-Infant Attachment Scale (MIAS). The data in the second stage will be collected using&#xD;
      the &quot;Scale for Acquiring the Role of Motherhood &quot; and the data collection form developed by&#xD;
      the researcher.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of education on the role of motherhood</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>As a result of our research, a motherhood role acquisition scale will be developed. This developed scale will be applied to pregnant women in the last trimester. By providing web-based or face-to-face training, it will be determined which training method has a positive or negative effect on gaining the role of motherhood.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Gaining the Role of Motherhood in Primipara Pregnancy (Focus)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3-week web-based education group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3-week face to face education group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Uneducated group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Face to face education</intervention_name>
    <description>Face to face education techniques on the acquisition of the mothering Role</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Web based education</intervention_name>
    <description>web based education techniques on the acquisition of the mothering Role</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No education</intervention_name>
    <description>Control group will not be educated</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a primiparous pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the last trimester of pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least primary school graduate,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read and understand Turkish,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use the internet actively and regularly access the website and receive training,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have any physical, mental or social problems that may prevent participation in&#xD;
             face-to-face or web-based education and pregnant women who accepted the study will be&#xD;
             included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women who cannot access the website,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any congenital defect in their baby,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experience mother-baby separation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Want to leave the research before the end of the research will not be included in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Feride Yiğit</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hasan KU</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>İmren Arpacı</last_name>
    <phone>+905395576147</phone>
    <email>imren2746@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Feride Yiğit</last_name>
    <phone>+905365848966</phone>
    <email>ferideyigit@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hasan Kalyoncu University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Imren ARPACI</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PHD Student</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Primipara Pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Role of Motherhood</keyword>
  <keyword>Web-Based Education</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

