<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05012371</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0400</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-07429</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-0400</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05012371</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lenvatinib With Everolimus Versus Cabozantinib for Second-Line or Third-Line Treatment of Metastatic Renal Cell Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Lenvatinib Plus Everolimus Versus Cabozantinib in Patients With Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma That Progressed on A PD-1/PD-L1 Checkpoint Inhibitor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial compares the effects of lenvatinib given in combination with everolimus&#xD;
      to the effects of cabozantinib given alone in treating patients with renal cell cancer (RCC)&#xD;
      that has spread to other parts of the body (metastatic) and that got worse on a previous&#xD;
      PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor. Lenvatinib, everolimus, and cabozantinib may stop the growth&#xD;
      of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare the efficacy of lenvatinib plus everolimus versus cabozantinib in patients with&#xD;
      mRCC who developed progressive disease after 1-2 lines of therapy, including a PD-1/PD-L1&#xD;
      checkpoint inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare tumor responses to lenvatinib plus everolimus versus cabozantinib in patients&#xD;
      with mRCC who developed progressive disease after 1-2 lines of therapy, including a&#xD;
      PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To compare health-related quality of life (HRQoL) and safety of lenvatinib plus&#xD;
      everolimus versus cabozantinib in patients with mRCC who developed progressive disease after&#xD;
      1-2 lines of therapy, including a PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To compare overall survival (OS) with lenvatinib plus everolimus versus cabozantinib in&#xD;
      patients with mRCC who developed progressive disease after 1-2 lines of therapy, including a&#xD;
      PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess whether alterations to c-MET, VEGF, mTOR, and FGFR are associated with response&#xD;
      to therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM A: Patients receive lenvatinib orally (PO) once daily (QD) and everolimus PO QD. Cycles&#xD;
      repeat every 30 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM B: Patients receive cabozantinib PO QD. Cycles repeat every 30 days in the absence of&#xD;
      disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 25, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 25, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from start of study drug until disease progression defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To be compared between lenvatinib + everolimus versus cabozantinib. Monitored using Bayesian optimal phase 2 (BOP2) design with time-to-event endpoint.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is defined as complete response (CR) plus partial response (PR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as CR + PR + stable disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-Related Quality of Life (HRQoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated using standardized questionnaires, including Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Kidney Symptom Index 19 (FKSI-19), Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS)-10, Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D), Social Provisions Scale, and the Finding Meaning in Cancer Scale (FMCS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of grade 3 or 4 adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Defined by the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Start of study drug to death due to any cause, assessed up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>OS is compared between lenvatinib + everolimus versus cabozantinib in patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma who developed progressive disease after 1-2 lines of therapy, including a PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Clear Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Clear Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Renal Cell Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Renal Cell Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (lenvatinib, everolimus)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive lenvatinib PO QD and everolimus PO QD. Cycles repeat every 30 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (cabozantinib)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive cabozantinib PO QD. Cycles repeat every 30 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabozantinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (cabozantinib)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Everolimus</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (lenvatinib, everolimus)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>42-O-(2-Hydroxy)ethyl Rapamycin</other_name>
    <other_name>Afinitor</other_name>
    <other_name>Certican</other_name>
    <other_name>RAD 001</other_name>
    <other_name>RAD001</other_name>
    <other_name>Votubia</other_name>
    <other_name>Zortress</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenvatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (lenvatinib, everolimus)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>E7080</other_name>
    <other_name>ER-203492-00</other_name>
    <other_name>Multi-Kinase Inhibitor E7080</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A (lenvatinib, everolimus)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B (cabozantinib)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic/advanced clear cell&#xD;
             renal cell cancer (RCC), or RCC with a clear cell component, who have received 1 or 2&#xD;
             prior lines of treatment in the advanced or metastatic setting, and the most recent&#xD;
             treatment must include a PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There must be evidence of progression on or after treatment (at any point after&#xD;
             completing prior therapy) with a PD-1/PD-L1-containing regimen as the last treatment&#xD;
             received within 6 months of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have at least one measurable site of disease, defined as a lesion that&#xD;
             can be accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded)&#xD;
             and measures &gt;= 15 mm with conventional techniques or &gt;= 10 mm with more sensitive&#xD;
             techniques such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or spiral computed tomography (CT)&#xD;
             scan. If the patient has had previous radiation to the marker lesion(s), there must be&#xD;
             evidence of progression since the radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status &gt;= 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL (treatment/transfusion allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,000/microliter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 75,000/microliter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 mg/dL (for patients with Gilbert's disease, total bilirubin&#xD;
             should be =&lt; 3 mg/dL [=&lt; 51.3 micromoles/L])&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotrasferase (AST)(serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase [SGOT]) or&#xD;
             alanine aminotransferase (ALT)(serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT]) =&lt; 2.5 x&#xD;
             institutional upper limit of normal (ULN), except in known hepatic metastasis, wherein&#xD;
             may be =&lt; 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (as long as patient does not require dialysis); if&#xD;
             creatinine is not &lt; 1.5 x ULN, then calculate by Cockcroft-Gault methods or local&#xD;
             institutional standard and creatinine clearance must be &gt;= 30 mL/kg/1.73 m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  International normalized ratio (INR) and partial thromboplastin time (PTT) =&lt; 1.5 x&#xD;
             ULN prior to study entry. Therapeutic anticoagulation is permitted if: on a stable&#xD;
             dose of low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) for &gt; 2 weeks (14 days) at the time of&#xD;
             enrollment or on a direct oral anticoagulant (DOAC) for &gt; 2 weeks at time of&#xD;
             enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential (not postmenopausal for at least 12 months&#xD;
             and not surgically sterile) must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             (minimum sensitivity 25 international units/L or equivalent units of human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin [HCG]) before study entry. Pregnancy test must be repeated if performed &gt;&#xD;
             14 days before starting study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women must not be breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of major psychiatric illness must be judged (by the treating&#xD;
             physician) able to fully understand the investigational nature of the study and the&#xD;
             risks associated with the therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with treated/stable brain metastases are allowed on protocol if they had&#xD;
             brain metastases that received central nervous system (CNS)-directed therapy, such as&#xD;
             surgery or treatment with radiosurgery or gamma knife, without recurrence or edema for&#xD;
             1 month (4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt of lenvatinib, a c-MET inhibitor, such as cabozantinib or sitravatinib,&#xD;
             or an mTOR inhibitor, such as everolimus or temsirolimus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have any other malignancies within the past 3 years except for in&#xD;
             situ carcinoma of any site, adequately treated (without recurrence post-resection or&#xD;
             post- radiotherapy) carcinoma of the cervix or basal or squamous cell carcinomas of&#xD;
             the skin, or active non-threatening second malignancy that would not, in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion, potentially interfere with the patient's ability to&#xD;
             participate and/or complete this trial. Examples include but are not limited to:&#xD;
             urothelial cancer grade Ta/T1 or adenocarcinoma of the prostate treated with active&#xD;
             surveillance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently receiving anticancer therapies or who have received anticancer&#xD;
             therapies within 2 weeks (14 days) from enrollment into this study (including&#xD;
             chemotherapy and targeted therapy) are excluded. Also, patients who have completed&#xD;
             palliative radiation therapy more than 14 days prior to the first dose of lenvatinib&#xD;
             plus everolimus or cabozantinib are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had a major surgery or significant traumatic injury (injury requiring &gt;&#xD;
             28 days to heal) within 28 days of start of study drug, patients who have not&#xD;
             recovered from the side effects of any major surgery (defined as requiring general&#xD;
             anesthesia), or patients that are expected to require major surgery during the course&#xD;
             of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or documented inflammatory bowel disease (e.g., Crohn's disease, ulcerative&#xD;
             colitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromising conditions, as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known acute or chronic human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection with CD4+ T&#xD;
                  cell count &lt; 350 cells/microliter. Patients with a history of an acquired&#xD;
                  immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)-defining infection can be included if their CD4+&#xD;
                  T cell count &gt; 350 cells/microliter and have not had an AIDS-defining infection&#xD;
                  within prior 12 months. If patients are on antiretroviral therapy (ART), it must&#xD;
                  be started at least 4 weeks prior to trial enrollment and the HIV viral load&#xD;
                  should be &lt; 400 copies/mL. Medication interactions with ART should be screened&#xD;
                  prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History or allogeneic transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 28 days before the&#xD;
                  first dose of study treatment, with the exception of topical, ocular, intranasal,&#xD;
                  and inhaled corticosteroids, or systemic corticosteroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any underlying medical condition, which in the opinion of the investigator, will make&#xD;
             the administration of study drug hazardous or obscure the interpretation of adverse&#xD;
             events, such as a condition associated with frequent diarrhea, uncontrolled nausea,&#xD;
             vomiting, malabsorption syndrome or small bowel resection that may significantly alter&#xD;
             the absorption of lenvatinib, everolimus, or cabozantinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving any concomitant systemic therapy for renal cell cancer are&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not be scheduled to receive another experimental drug while on this&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have any severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions or other&#xD;
             conditions that could affect their participation in the study such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic congestive heart failure of New York Heart Association class III or&#xD;
                  IV&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina pectoris, symptomatic congestive heart failure, myocardial&#xD;
                  infarction within 6 months of start of study drug, serious uncontrolled cardiac&#xD;
                  arrhythmia, or any other clinically significant cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severely impaired lung function as defined as oxygen saturation that is 88% or&#xD;
                  less at rest on room air&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled diabetes as defined by a hemoglobin A1C &gt;= 8%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic fungal, bacterial, viral, or other infection that is not controlled&#xD;
                  (defined as exhibiting ongoing signs/symptoms related to the infection and&#xD;
                  without improvement) despite appropriate antibiotics or other treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Liver disease, such as cirrhosis or chronic active hepatitis as defined here. For&#xD;
                  hepatitis B virus (HBV), a positive test using HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) test.&#xD;
                  For hepatitis C virus (HCV), patients with a positive HCV antibody test and HCV&#xD;
                  ribonucleic acid (RNA) positive are excluded. If a patient is receiving HCV&#xD;
                  curative treatment, they must complete therapy and have HCV RNA below level of&#xD;
                  detection. For patients with a history of HCV infection, they are eligible if&#xD;
                  they have completed curative therapy and have HCV viral load below the level of&#xD;
                  detection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled blood pressure (systolic blood pressure &gt; 140 mmHg or diastolic&#xD;
                  blood pressure &gt; 90 mmHg) in spite of optimized regimen of antihypertensive&#xD;
                  medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects having &gt; 1+ proteinuria on urine dipstick testing unless a spot urine&#xD;
                  protein to creatinine ratio is =&lt; 1 mg/mg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have history of other diseases, metabolic dysfunction, physical&#xD;
             examination finding, or clinical laboratory finding giving reasonable suspicion of a&#xD;
             disease or condition that contraindicates the use of lenvatinib, everolimus, or&#xD;
             cabozantinib or that might affect the interpretation of the results of the study or&#xD;
             render the subject at high risk from treatment complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding or thrombotic disorders or subjects at risk for severe hemorrhage. The degree&#xD;
             of tumor invasion/infiltration of blood vessels should be considered because of the&#xD;
             risk of severe hemorrhage associated with tumor shrinkage/necrosis following&#xD;
             lenvatinib treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patients who cannot be compliant with the appointments required in this protocol&#xD;
             must not be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe hypersensitivity (&gt;= grade 3) to lenvatinib and/or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 40%.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nizar M Tannir</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nizar M. Tannir</last_name>
      <phone>713-563-7265</phone>
      <email>ntannir@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nizar M. Tannir</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lenvatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

