<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05016960</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D3721-P</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05016960</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sleep-SMART for Veterans</brief_title>
  <acronym>Sleep-SMART</acronym>
  <official_title>Sleep-SMART for Veterans With MCI and Insomnia: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia (CBT-I) is the first-line treatment for chronic&#xD;
      insomnia. However, cognitive impairments may limit progress in CBT-I for older Veterans with&#xD;
      Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI). This study will develop and pilot test Sleep-SMART (Sleep&#xD;
      Symptom Management and Rehabilitation Therapy), an adapted CBT-I treatment that incorporates&#xD;
      Cognitive Symptom Management and Rehabilitation Therapy (CogSMART) principles with a goal of&#xD;
      improving sleep treatment and rehabilitation outcomes for Veterans with co-occurring MCI and&#xD;
      insomnia. The innovation of this study centers on enhancing CBT-I by providing supportive&#xD;
      cognitive strategies designed to improve treatment adherence, learning, and acceptability.&#xD;
      The investigators anticipate that by improving sleep it can concurrently improve daily&#xD;
      functioning, increase quality of life, prevent or reduce late-life disability, and mitigate&#xD;
      long-term cognitive decline in this Veteran population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Mild cognitive impairment (MCI) is an important public health concern for aging Veterans due&#xD;
      to the increased risk for progression to dementia and increased mortality. Insomnia is common&#xD;
      in MCI (occurring in up to 60% of patients) and increases risk for dementia, disability, and&#xD;
      poor quality of life. Rates of MCI and insomnia are higher among Veterans than civilians,&#xD;
      thus aging Veterans with MCI and comorbid insomnia represent a particularly high-risk&#xD;
      population. The gold standard treatment for insomnia, Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for&#xD;
      Insomnia (CBT-I), is a multi-component behavioral intervention. However, cognitive&#xD;
      impairments experienced by individuals with MCI may limit the rate of progress in CBT-I. The&#xD;
      use of memory support strategies can improve patient recall of therapeutic information,&#xD;
      enhance treatment adherence, and improve treatment outcomes. Cognitive Symptom Management and&#xD;
      Rehabilitation Therapy (CogSMART) provides compensatory strategies to improve learning,&#xD;
      memory, attention, and executive functioning. CogSMART has been shown to improve cognition,&#xD;
      functional capacity, neurobehavioral symptoms, and quality of life in diverse Veteran&#xD;
      populations with cognitive impairment. Incorporating supportive CogSMART cognitive strategies&#xD;
      into CBT-I has the potential to improve treatment learning, adherence, and outcomes for this&#xD;
      Veteran population. This RR&amp;D SPiRE research project will assist us in developing and&#xD;
      evaluating Sleep-SMART (Sleep Symptom Management and Rehabilitation Therapy), an innovative&#xD;
      user-informed approach for treatment of insomnia in Veterans with MCI. Sleep-SMART is&#xD;
      intended to provide the core components of CBT-I along with training in compensatory&#xD;
      cognitive strategies from CogSMART to enhance intervention adherence and learning. Provision&#xD;
      of this supportive cognitive training will assist Veterans with cognitive impairments in&#xD;
      maintaining compliance with the CBT-I regimen, thereby leading to faster and more complete&#xD;
      treatment benefits. The principle aims for the investigation include: 1) developing the&#xD;
      Sleep-SMART intervention and treatment manual; 2) assessing the feasibility and acceptability&#xD;
      of Sleep-SMART in Veterans with MCI and insomnia; and 3) exploring the effects of Sleep-SMART&#xD;
      on rehabilitation outcomes, quality of life, sleep, and cognitive functioning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 4, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The investigators will develop and pilot test a modified CBT-I treatment that incorporates technology, user-centered design principles, and CogSMART strategies to improve sleep and rehabilitation outcomes for Veterans with co-occurring insomnia and MCI. The investigators will assess the feasibility and acceptability of Sleep-SMART (Sleep Symptom Management and Rehabilitation Therapy), which will seamlessly incorporate select CogSMART cognitive strategies within a standard 6-session 50-minute CBT-I treatment protocol. Sleep-SMART will focus on enhancing CBT-I by providing supportive cognitive strategies designed to boost treatment learning and adherence.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of Intervention Measure (FIM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Rating scale assessing intervention feasibility; minimum score is 4, maximum score is 20; higher scores indicating better/higher levels of feasibility.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Client Satisfaction Questionnaire (CSQ-8)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale to assess level of client satisfaction for the intervention. Scores range from 8-32, higher score indicates higher satisfaction.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Telehealth Usability Questionnaire (TUQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Scale to assess the usability of telehealth to deliver the intervention. Responses are interpreted qualitatively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Rating scale assessing intervention acceptability; scores range from 4-20 with higher scores indicating higher levels of acceptability.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Appropriateness Measure (IAM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Rating scale assessing intervention appropriateness; scores range from 4-20 with higher scores indicating higher levels of appropriateness.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WHO Disability Assessment Schedule 2.0 (WHODAS 2.0)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale assessing Subjective level of disability. Scores range from 0-100, where 0 = no disability; 100 = full disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Independent Living Skills Survey (ILSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale assessing independent living skills; standardized scores ranging from 20 to 39 suggest maximum (full-time) supervision for daily living, scores from 40 to 49 suggest moderate supervision, and scores from 50 to 63 suggest minimum supervision, or independent living.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life Inventory (QOLI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale assessing quality of life. Higher scores indicating better quality of life/satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life in Neurological Disorders (Neuro-QOL) cognition scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scales assessing subjective cognitive complaints and subjective everyday functioning. Each response option is assigned a value (e.g., 1=Not at all). To find the total raw score, sum the values of the response to each question. For example, for an 8-item form that includes items with 5 response options ranging from 1 to 5, the lowest possible raw score is 8 (8 x 1) ; the highest possible raw score is 40 (8 x 5). Conversion tables are used to translate the total raw score into an IRT-based T score for each participant. A higher Neuro-QoL T-score represents more of the concept being measured - higher scores indicate worse functioning for the cognition scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Everyday Cognition Scale (ECoG)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Collateral measure of cognitive and everyday functioning. Is a 39 item questionnaire used to measure a patient's cognitive function and aid in the detection and diagnosis of dementia and other neurodegenerative diseases that are associated with aging. The final score is an average of the individual scores for each item answered out of the 39 items in the questionnaire and ranges from 1 to 4.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insomnia Severity Index (ISI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before the intervention, weekly during the intervention, and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale assessing perceived insomnia severity; scores range from 0-28 with higher scores indicating more severe insomnia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale assessing sleep quality over a 1-month interval. Scoring of the answers is based on a 0 to 3 scale, whereby 3 reflects the negative extreme on the Likert Scale. A global sum of &quot;5&quot;or greater indicates a &quot;poor&quot; sleeper</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hopkins Verbal Learning Test-Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Performance based measure of verbal list learning and memory. Higher scores indicate better performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Visuospatial Memory Test-Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Performance based measure of Visual design learning and memory. Scores are based on individual performance. Higher scores indicate better performance/memory.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale-IV (WAIS-IV) Digit Span</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Performance based measure of auditory attention; raw scores range from 0-48 with higher scores indicating better performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Delis-Kaplan Executive Function System (D-KEFS) Trail Making Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Performance based measures of attention, processing speed, and executive function. Scores are based on the time (number of seconds) to complete the task for the trail making test. Raw scores are converted to age-based scaled scores with higher scaled scores indicating better performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Delis-Kaplan Executive Function System (D-KEFS) Verbal Fluency Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately before and immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Performance based measures of executive function. Scores are based on the number of words generated for the verbal fluency task. Raw scores are converted to age-based scaled scores with higher scaled scores indicating better performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">31</enrollment>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <condition>Mild Cognitive Impairment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sleep-SMART</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sleep-SMART intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sleep-SMART</intervention_name>
    <description>Sleep-SMART will be a treatment for insomnia that will follow the standard 6 session 50-minute CBT-I format and will deliver CBT-I treatment along with training in select CogSMART strategies to enhance intervention learning and adherence. It will be delivered via video-based telehealth.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sleep-SMART</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Veterans ages 60 or older who are competent to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chart diagnosis of MCI based on previously published criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DSM-5 diagnosis of insomnia and an Insomnia Severity Index (ISI) score &gt;7 at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand, speak, and read English with acceptable visual and auditory&#xD;
             acuity&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sleep disorders other than insomnia as determined by medical chart review and clinical&#xD;
             interview&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of a neurological disorder, dementia, or moderate to severe TBI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Auditory, visual, or other impairments that would prevent ability to use video&#xD;
             teleconferencing or participate in assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Schizophrenia, psychotic disorder, bipolar disorder, and/or current substance use&#xD;
             disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suicidality more than &quot;low risk&quot; as assessed by the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating&#xD;
             Scale&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erin Almklov, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA San Diego Healthcare System, San Diego, CA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Erin Almklov, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(858) 855-8585</phone>
    <phone_ext>2345</phone_ext>
    <email>erin.almklov@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Henry J Orff, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(858) 642-6492</phone>
    <email>Henry.Orff@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA San Diego Healthcare System, San Diego, CA</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92161</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gerhard H Schulteis, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>858-642-3657</phone>
      <email>gerhard.schulteis@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>James Pittman, PhD MSW</last_name>
      <phone>(858) 552-8585</phone>
      <phone_ext>7787</phone_ext>
      <email>james.pittman@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erin Almklov, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Mild Cognitive Impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Veterans</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavioral Sleep treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>CBT for Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>CogSMART</keyword>
  <keyword>Feasibility</keyword>
  <keyword>Acceptability</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

