<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05017727</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>298164</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05017727</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Closed-loop Oxygen Control in Ventilated Infants Born at or Near Term</brief_title>
  <official_title>Does Closed-loop Automated Oxygen Control During Mechanical Ventilation Reduce Hypoxic Events? A Randomised Controlled Crossover Study in Ventilated Infants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>King's College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ventilated neonates frequently require supplementary oxygen to allow for adequate oxygen&#xD;
      delivery to the tissues and normal cell metabolism. Oxygen treatment should be monitored&#xD;
      carefully as both excessive and inadequate dosing can have detrimental effects for the&#xD;
      infants. Hypoxia (giving too little oxygen) increases mortality and later disability whereas&#xD;
      hyperoxia (giving too much oxygen) increases the risk of complications such as retinopathy of&#xD;
      prematurity and lung disease. Although very preterm and low birth weight infants represent&#xD;
      the majority of ventilated neonates, more mature infants may also require mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation at birth and provision of supplementary oxygen. Therefore, they may suffer from&#xD;
      complications related to hypoxia or hyperoxia. Hence, their oxygen saturation levels and the&#xD;
      amount of the inspired oxygen concentration provided should be continuously monitored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oxygen control is traditionally monitored and adjusted manually by the nurse looking after&#xD;
      the infant. Closed-loop automated oxygen control (CLAC) is a more recent approach that&#xD;
      involves the use of a computer software incorporated into the ventilator. The software uses&#xD;
      an algorithm that automatically adjusts the amount of inspired oxygen to maintain oxygen&#xD;
      saturation levels in a target range. Evidence suggests that CLAC increases the time spent in&#xD;
      the desired oxygen target range, decreases the duration of hypoxia and hyperoxia and reduces&#xD;
      the number of manual adjustments required by clinical staff. However previous studies have&#xD;
      been limited to very small infants. With this study the investigators aim to evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of CLAC in ventilated infants born at 34 weeks gestation and beyond. The&#xD;
      achievement of oxygen saturation targets and the number of manual adjustments required will&#xD;
      be compared between periods of CLAC and manual control in a cohort of patients that has not&#xD;
      been included in previous studies and could also benefit from the intervention. The&#xD;
      investigators will also evaluate if CLAC reduces investigations performed to ventilated&#xD;
      babies(blood gases, X-rays).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This will be a randomised controlled crossover study. The investigators aim to recruit a&#xD;
      minimum of 31 ventilated infants born at 34 weeks completed gestation and above and admitted&#xD;
      to the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit at King's College Hospital over one year. Participants&#xD;
      will undergo two monitoring periods each lasting 12 hours (8:00am-20:00pm): one with standard&#xD;
      manually controlled oxygen and one with closed-loop automated oxygen control. Randomisation&#xD;
      will be used to determine whether the first period will be manual or closed-loop automated&#xD;
      oxygen control. The two monitoring periods will take place on two consecutive days to allow&#xD;
      for clinical conditions to remain as stable as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Infants with known congenital cyanotic heart disease will be excluded from the study as well&#xD;
      as those undergoing surgery or any planned procedures during the monitoring period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed written consent will be requested from the parents or legal guardians of the infants&#xD;
      and the attending Neonatal Consultant will be requested to verbally assent to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation of eligible infants whose parents consent to the study will be performed using&#xD;
      an online randomisation generator to determine whether the first monitoring period will be&#xD;
      manual adjustment or closed-loop automated oxygen control (&quot;intervention&quot; period).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be ventilated using SLE6000 ventilators. Ventilation settings will be manually&#xD;
      adjusted by the clinical team as per unit's protocol. During the intervention period, in&#xD;
      addition to standard care, infants will be also connected to the OxyGenie closed-loop oxygen&#xD;
      saturation monitoring software (SLE). This software uses oxygen saturations from the SpO2&#xD;
      probe attached to the neonate, fed into an algorithm, to automatically adjust the percentage&#xD;
      of inspired oxygen to maintain oxygen saturations within the target range. Manual adjustments&#xD;
      including the percentage of FiO2 will be allowed at any point during the study including the&#xD;
      period of automated oxygen control if deemed appropriate by the clinical team. Oxygen&#xD;
      saturation levels and automatic adjustments to the inspired oxygen concentration will be&#xD;
      captured by the ventilator software. Manual adjustments will be recorded during both&#xD;
      monitoring periods. In addition to data collected from the ventilator, medical notes will be&#xD;
      reviewed to determine any adverse events or clinical interventions to participants during the&#xD;
      study. The number of blood gas samples taken and chest radiographs performed during each&#xD;
      monitoring period will also be recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The decrease in the percentage of time spent in extremes of hypoxia</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>That will be assessed by evaluating the infant's respiratory status.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The increase in the percentage of time spent within target oxygen saturation ranges (94-98%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>This will be assessed by evaluating the infant's respiratory status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The reduction in the number of manual adjustments required to the inspired oxygen concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>That will be assessed by reviewing the infant's medical records</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The reduction in the number of blood gases and chest radiographs</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>That will be assessed by reviewing the infant's medical records</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">31</enrollment>
  <condition>Pre-Term</condition>
  <condition>Respiratory Disease</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Closed-loop automated oxygen control with Oxygenie Auto-O2 software (SLE6000)</intervention_name>
    <description>The 'Oxygenie' is a closed loop automated oxygen control system that has been incorporated into a software module for the SLE6000 infant ventilators. This software control system allows targeting SpO2 values by controlling FiO2.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This will be a randomised controlled crossover study. We aim to recruit a minimum of 31&#xD;
        ventilated infants born at 34 weeks completed gestation and above and admitted to the&#xD;
        Neonatal Intensive Care Unit at our hospital over one year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants born at 34 weeks completed gestation and above requiring mechanical&#xD;
             ventilation and admitted to King's NICU&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any gender, ethnicity or other comorbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm infants less than 34 weeks gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants with cyanotic congenital heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants undergoing planned procedures or surgery during the monitoring period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants on high frequency oscillatory ventilation (HFOV)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>34 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anne Greenough, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King's College Hospital/ King's College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ourania Kaltsogianni, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>(+44)02032999000</phone>
    <phone_ext>38495</phone_ext>
    <email>ourania.kaltsogianni@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Theodore Dassios, Consultant Neonatologist</last_name>
    <email>theodore.dassios@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE5 0BD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ourania Kaltsogianni</last_name>
      <email>ourania.kaltsogianni@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Consortium on Safe Labor, Hibbard JU, Wilkins I, Sun L, Gregory K, Haberman S, Hoffman M, Kominiarek MA, Reddy U, Bailit J, Branch DW, Burkman R, Gonzalez Quintero VH, Hatjis CG, Landy H, Ramirez M, VanVeldhuisen P, Troendle J, Zhang J. Respiratory morbidity in late preterm births. JAMA. 2010 Jul 28;304(4):419-25. doi: 10.1001/jama.2010.1015.</citation>
    <PMID>20664042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Colin AA, McEvoy C, Castile RG. Respiratory morbidity and lung function in preterm infants of 32 to 36 weeks' gestational age. Pediatrics. 2010 Jul;126(1):115-28. doi: 10.1542/peds.2009-1381. Epub 2010 Jun 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20530073</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pike KC, Lucas JS. Respiratory consequences of late preterm birth. Paediatr Respir Rev. 2015 Jun;16(3):182-8. doi: 10.1016/j.prrv.2014.12.001. Epub 2014 Dec 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25554628</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clark RH. The epidemiology of respiratory failure in neonates born at an estimated gestational age of 34 weeks or more. J Perinatol. 2005 Apr;25(4):251-7.</citation>
    <PMID>15605071</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gouyon JB, Ribakovsky C, Ferdynus C, Quantin C, Sagot P, Gouyon B; Burgundy Perinatal Network. Severe respiratory disorders in term neonates. Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol. 2008 Jan;22(1):22-30. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-3016.2007.00875.x.</citation>
    <PMID>18173781</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ramadan G, Paul N, Morton M, Peacock JL, Greenough A. Outcome of ventilated infants born at term without major congenital abnormalities. Eur J Pediatr. 2012 Feb;171(2):331-6. doi: 10.1007/s00431-011-1549-8. Epub 2011 Aug 11.</citation>
    <PMID>21833494</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Angus DC, Linde-Zwirble WT, Clermont G, Griffin MF, Clark RH. Epidemiology of neonatal respiratory failure in the United States: projections from California and New York. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2001 Oct 1;164(7):1154-60.</citation>
    <PMID>11673202</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Walsh BK, Smallwood CD. Pediatric Oxygen Therapy: A Review and Update. Respir Care. 2017 Jun;62(6):645-661. doi: 10.4187/respcare.05245. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28546370</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baba L, McGrath JM. Oxygen free radicals: effects in the newborn period. Adv Neonatal Care. 2008 Oct;8(5):256-64. doi: 10.1097/01.ANC.0000338015.25911.8a.</citation>
    <PMID>18827514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Askie LM, Henderson-Smart DJ, Irwig L, Simpson JM. Oxygen-saturation targets and outcomes in extremely preterm infants. N Engl J Med. 2003 Sep 4;349(10):959-67.</citation>
    <PMID>12954744</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Supplemental Therapeutic Oxygen for Prethreshold Retinopathy Of Prematurity (STOP-ROP), a randomized, controlled trial. I: primary outcomes. Pediatrics. 2000 Feb;105(2):295-310.</citation>
    <PMID>10654946</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>BOOST-II Australia and United Kingdom Collaborative Groups, Tarnow-Mordi W, Stenson B, Kirby A, Juszczak E, Donoghoe M, Deshpande S, Morley C, King A, Doyle LW, Fleck BW, Davis PG, Halliday HL, Hague W, Cairns P, Darlow BA, Fielder AR, Gebski V, Marlow N, Simmer K, Tin W, Ghadge A, Williams C, Keech A, Wardle SP, Kecskes Z, Kluckow M, Gole G, Evans N, Malcolm G, Luig M, Wright I, Stack J, Tan K, Pritchard M, Gray PH, Morris S, Headley B, Dargaville P, Simes RJ, Brocklehurst P. Outcomes of Two Trials of Oxygen-Saturation Targets in Preterm Infants. N Engl J Med. 2016 Feb 25;374(8):749-60. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1514212. Epub 2016 Feb 10.</citation>
    <PMID>26863265</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saugstad OD, Aune D. In search of the optimal oxygen saturation for extremely low birth weight infants: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neonatology. 2011;100(1):1-8. doi: 10.1159/000322001. Epub 2010 Dec 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21150224</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williams LZJ, McNamara D, Alsweiler JM. Intermittent Hypoxemia in Infants Born Late Preterm: A Prospective Cohort Observational Study. J Pediatr. 2019 Jan;204:89-95.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2018.08.048. Epub 2018 Oct 1.</citation>
    <PMID>30287066</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lakshminrusimha S, Konduri GG, Steinhorn RH. Considerations in the management of hypoxemic respiratory failure and persistent pulmonary hypertension in term and late preterm neonates. J Perinatol. 2016 Jun;36 Suppl 2:S12-9. doi: 10.1038/jp.2016.44. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27225960</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Askie LM, Darlow BA, Finer N, Schmidt B, Stenson B, Tarnow-Mordi W, Davis PG, Carlo WA, Brocklehurst P, Davies LC, Das A, Rich W, Gantz MG, Roberts RS, Whyte RK, Costantini L, Poets C, Asztalos E, Battin M, Halliday HL, Marlow N, Tin W, King A, Juszczak E, Morley CJ, Doyle LW, Gebski V, Hunter KE, Simes RJ; Neonatal Oxygenation Prospective Meta-analysis (NeOProM) Collaboration. Association Between Oxygen Saturation Targeting and Death or Disability in Extremely Preterm Infants in the Neonatal Oxygenation Prospective Meta-analysis Collaboration. JAMA. 2018 Jun 5;319(21):2190-2201. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.5725. Erratum in: JAMA. 2018 Jul 17;320(3):308.</citation>
    <PMID>29872859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hagadorn JI, Furey AM, Nghiem TH, Schmid CH, Phelps DL, Pillers DA, Cole CH; AVIOx Study Group. Achieved versus intended pulse oximeter saturation in infants born less than 28 weeks' gestation: the AVIOx study. Pediatrics. 2006 Oct;118(4):1574-82.</citation>
    <PMID>17015549</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sink DW, Hope SA, Hagadorn JI. Nurse:patient ratio and achievement of oxygen saturation goals in premature infants. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2011 Mar;96(2):F93-8. doi: 10.1136/adc.2009.178616. Epub 2010 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>21037284</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dargaville PA, Sadeghi Fathabadi O, Plottier GK, Lim K, Wheeler KI, Jayakar R, Gale TJ. Development and preclinical testing of an adaptive algorithm for automated control of inspired oxygen in the preterm infant. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2017 Jan;102(1):F31-F36. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2016-310650. Epub 2016 Sep 15.</citation>
    <PMID>27634820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dani C. Automated control of inspired oxygen (FiO(2) ) in preterm infants: Literature review. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2019 Mar;54(3):358-363. doi: 10.1002/ppul.24238. Epub 2019 Jan 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30632296</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sturrock S, Ambulkar H, Williams EE, Sweeney S, Bednarczuk NF, Dassios T, Greenough A. A randomised crossover trial of closed loop automated oxygen control in preterm, ventilated infants. Acta Paediatr. 2021 Mar;110(3):833-837. doi: 10.1111/apa.15585. Epub 2020 Oct 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32969040</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sturrock S, Williams E, Dassios T, Greenough A. Closed loop automated oxygen control in neonates-A review. Acta Paediatr. 2020 May;109(5):914-922. doi: 10.1111/apa.15089. Epub 2019 Nov 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31715041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury O, Wedderburn CJ, Lee S, Hannam S, Greenough A. Respiratory support practices in infants born at term in the United Kingdom. Eur J Pediatr. 2012 Nov;171(11):1633-8. doi: 10.1007/s00431-012-1784-7. Epub 2012 Jul 22.</citation>
    <PMID>22821075</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhat P, Chowdhury O, Shetty S, Hannam S, Rafferty GF, Peacock J, Greenough A. Volume-targeted versus pressure-limited ventilation in infants born at or near term. Eur J Pediatr. 2016 Jan;175(1):89-95. doi: 10.1007/s00431-015-2596-3. Epub 2015 Aug 4.</citation>
    <PMID>26239663</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury O, Greenough A. Neonatal ventilatory techniques - which are best for infants born at term? Arch Med Sci. 2011 Jun;7(3):381-7. doi: 10.5114/aoms.2011.23400. Epub 2011 Jul 11.</citation>
    <PMID>22295020</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury O, Rafferty GF, Lee S, Hannam S, Milner AD, Greenough A. Volume-targeted ventilation in infants born at or near term. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2012 Jul;97(4):F264-6. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2011-301041. Epub 2011 Dec 22.</citation>
    <PMID>22194469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reynolds PR, Miller TL, Volakis LI, Holland N, Dungan GC, Roehr CC, Ives K. Randomised cross-over study of automated oxygen control for preterm infants receiving nasal high flow. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2019 Jul;104(4):F366-F371. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2018-315342. Epub 2018 Nov 21.</citation>
    <PMID>30464005</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiration Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

