<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05014087</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2000030659</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05014087</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Digoxin In Treatment of Alcohol Associated Hepatitis</brief_title>
  <acronym>DIGIT-AlcHep</acronym>
  <official_title>Digoxin In Treatment of Alcohol Associated Hepatitis (DIGIT-AlcHep)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prospective, single center, open label, randomized controlled trial to determine the&#xD;
      feasibility of conducting a future study with respect to patient recruitment, digoxin&#xD;
      administration and dose adjustment. The study intervention will be intravenous digoxin&#xD;
      (renal-based dosing for maximum of 28 days) versus no digoxin in an open-label 1:1 randomized&#xD;
      allocation of patients with severe acute alcohol associated hepatitis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe alcohol associated hepatitis is a condition of acute on chronic immune liver&#xD;
      dysfunction that is associated with high mortality, necessitating a search for drugs that may&#xD;
      prove safe and efficacious in treating this disease. Pre-clinical studies suggest that&#xD;
      digoxin, which is currently used for treating cardiac conditions, is also effective in&#xD;
      improving alcohol-associated liver injury. To date, there have been no clinical studies of&#xD;
      digoxin use in patients with alcohol associated hepatitis. The primary objective of this&#xD;
      study of digoxin versus no digoxin in patients with severe alcohol associated hepatitis is to&#xD;
      assess the feasibility of conducting a large randomized trial to detect efficacy with respect&#xD;
      to patient recruitment, digoxin administration and dose adjustment in patients hospitalized&#xD;
      with severe alcohol associated hepatitis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, single center, open label, randomized 1:1 controlled trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ability to recruit 4 patients a month.</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of subjects recruited per month will be summarized to assess the study's primary recruitment feasibility objective.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Practicality of daily digoxin measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>90% of patients have digoxin checked levels within the pre-specified time window</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of digoxin dosing in a timely manner.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>90% of patients receive every scheduled dose of the drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of digoxin dose adjustments in renal insufficiency.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>90% of necessary dose adjustments were made appropriately in response to digoxin levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality at 7, 14, 28, 90 days</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>The mortality rates at different time points in the digoxin group and in the control group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of ECG abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The number and proportion of patients in the digoxin and control groups with ECG changes compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver - Lille Score)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of Lille score. The model is based on: Age, Albumin, Bilirubin (initial), Bilirubin (day 7), Creatinine, PT. Survival probability at 6 months is defined by a cutoff of 0.45: 6-month survival probability of patients with a Lille model above 0.45 is about 25% contrary to patients with a Lille model below this cutoff (85% survival).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver) with Model for End-stage Liver Disease (MELD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of Model for End-stage Liver Disease (MELD) score, a number that ranges from 6 (least sick) to 40 (most sick) based on blood tests. The lab tests used to determine the MELD score are creatinine, bilirubin, sodium and international normalized ratio (INR).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver Enzyme: Bilirubin)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of the liver enzyme bilirubin</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver Enzyme: Alkaline Phosphatase [ALP])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of liver enzymes (alkaline phosphatase [ALP])</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver Enzyme: Aspartate Aminotransferase [AST])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of liver enzymes (aspartate aminotransferase [AST])</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ dysfunction (Liver Enzyme: Alanine Aminotransferase [ALT])</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in liver-related function will be determined through assessment of liver enzymes (alanine aminotransferase [ALT])</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ Dysfunction (Multi-Organ) with Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Dysfunction in other organs will be assessed using Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) score which is calculated based on a person's liver function, kidney function, nervous system, coagulation, circulation, and respiratory status. The score ranges from 0 (least sick) to 24 (most sick).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Organ Dysfunction (Multi-Organ) with the Multi-Organ Dysfunction Score (MODS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Dysfunction in other organs will be assessed using Multi-organ dysfunction score (MODS), calculated based on a person's liver function, kidney function, nervous system, coagulation, circulation, and respiratory status. The score ranges from 0 (least sick) to 24 (most sick).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Development of new or recurrent renal failure.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Creatinine rise ≥ 0.5 mg/dL or ≥ 20% from baseline or requiring renal replacement therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Racial and ethnic diversity in subject recruitment and retention.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Race and ethnicity of enrolled subjects and subjects who completed the study will be summarized using count and proportion to assess the study's objective of enrolling and retaining at least 10% Black and at least 10% Hispanic participants to study completion (90-days follow-up)follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Alcoholic Hepatitis</condition>
  <condition>Chemical and Drug Induced Liver Injury</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol-Induced Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Steatohepatitis Caused by Ingestible Alcohol</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Digoxin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the digoxin arm, the intervention to be administered will be intravenous digoxin dosed by weight and by renal function using an adaption of the established FDA nomogram. Participants randomized to digoxin will receive an intravenous digoxin loading dose administered in 3 doses over 24 hours starting on Day 1. Digoxin levels will be monitored daily throughout the participant's hospital stay, to a maximum of 28 days. Digoxin will be discontinued at the time discharge if before 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: No Digoxin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the no digoxin arm, no study drug or placebo will be administered.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intravenous digoxin</intervention_name>
    <description>Loading dose: the total loading dose of digoxin will be determined using the Loading nomogram. The FDA-recommended total IV digoxin loading dose range is 8 to 12 mcg/kg. The lowest recommended dose of 8 mcg/kg was used in constructing the digoxin Loading nomogram that will be used in this trial.&#xD;
Maintenance dose: the maintenance dose will be started approximately 24 hours after initiation of digoxin loading. The post-loading digoxin trough will be reviewed prior to starting maintenance dosing.&#xD;
Subjects on P-gp inhibitors or spironolactone, will have an additional digoxin level performed 12-hours after any dose adjustment. Once digoxin levels are stable, 24-hour blood draws will be performed.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: Digoxin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lanoxin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosis of alcohol associated hepatitis based on clinical criteria or histologic&#xD;
             evidence&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Clinical criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Onset of jaundice (bilirubin &gt;3 mg/dL) within the prior 8 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Regular alcohol use &gt; 6 months, with intake of &gt; 40 g/day (&gt;280 g/week) for&#xD;
                       women; and &gt; 60 g/day (&gt;420 g/week) for men&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  AST &gt; 50 IU/l&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  AST: ALT &gt; 1.5 and both values &lt; 400 IU/l&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Histological evidence of alcohol associated hepatitis*&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. MDF 32 to 60 or MELD 20 to 30 on Day 0 of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Started on steroid treatment for acute alcohol associated hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Age between 21 and 65 years, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability of patient, legally authorized representative or next-of-kin to provide&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy or intolerance to digoxin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically active C. diff infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for COVID-19 within 14 days prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute hepatitis E, Cytomegalovirus, Epstein Barr Virus, Herpes Simplex Virus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other liver diseases including hepatitis B (positive HBsAg or HBV DNA),&#xD;
             hepatitis C (positive HCV RNA), autoimmune hepatitis, Wilson disease, genetic&#xD;
             hemochromatosis, alpha1-antitrypsin deficiency, strong suspicion for Drug Induced&#xD;
             Liver Injury (DILI), or other etiologies seen on liver imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV infection (positive HIV RNA or on treatment for HIV infection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure defined by GFR &lt;30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refractory ascites, defined as having more than 4 paracenteses in the preceding 8&#xD;
             weeks despite diuretic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior exposure to experimental therapies or other clinical trial in last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current acute or chronic pancreatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active gastrointestinal bleeding unless resolved for &gt;48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experiencing withdrawal seizures or considered at high risk for alcohol withdrawal&#xD;
             seizures or delirium tremens&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart rate less than 60 bpm at screening visit or at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiomyopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe aortic valve disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of Accessory arterio-ventricular pathway (eg Wolf-Parkinson-White syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete heart block or second degree arterio-ventricular block without pacemaker or&#xD;
             implantable cardiac device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following within the previous 6 months: myocardial infarction, percutaneous&#xD;
             intervention, pacemaker/implantable cardiac device implantation, cardiac surgery or&#xD;
             stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of the following medications: Antiarrthymics (amiodarone, dofetilide,&#xD;
             sotalol, dronedarone), Parathyroid hormone analog (teriparatide), Thyroid supplement&#xD;
             (thyroid), Sympathomimetics or ionotropic drugs (epinephrine, norepinephrine,&#xD;
             dopamine, dobutamine, milrinone), Neuromuscular blocking agents (succinylcholine),&#xD;
             Calcium supplement, Ivabradine, Disulfiram&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bubu Banini, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University, Department of Internal Medicine, Section of Digestive Diseases, Yale School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bubu Banini, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>203-737-6063</phone>
    <email>bubu.banini@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Johnson Oladuja</last_name>
    <phone>2674673792</phone>
    <email>johnson.oladuja@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale New Haven Hospital, Yale School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bubu Banini, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>203-737-6063</phone>
      <email>bubu.banini@yale.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bubu Banini, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wajahat Mehal, MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Simona Jakab, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Maddrey WC, Boitnott JK, Bedine MS, Weber FL Jr, Mezey E, White RI Jr. Corticosteroid therapy of alcoholic hepatitis. Gastroenterology. 1978 Aug;75(2):193-9.</citation>
    <PMID>352788</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sahlman P, Nissinen M, Pukkala E, Färkkilä M. Incidence, survival and cause-specific mortality in alcoholic liver disease: a population-based cohort study. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2016 Aug;51(8):961-6. doi: 10.3109/00365521.2016.1157889. Epub 2016 May 16.</citation>
    <PMID>27181618</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thursz MR, Richardson P, Allison M, Austin A, Bowers M, Day CP, Downs N, Gleeson D, MacGilchrist A, Grant A, Hood S, Masson S, McCune A, Mellor J, O'Grady J, Patch D, Ratcliffe I, Roderick P, Stanton L, Vergis N, Wright M, Ryder S, Forrest EH; STOPAH Trial. Prednisolone or pentoxifylline for alcoholic hepatitis. N Engl J Med. 2015 Apr 23;372(17):1619-28. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1412278.</citation>
    <PMID>25901427</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scalese MJ, Salvatore DJ. Role of Digoxin in Atrial Fibrillation. J Pharm Pract. 2017 Aug;30(4):434-440. doi: 10.1177/0897190016642361. Epub 2016 Apr 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27067743</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ouyang X, Han SN, Zhang JY, Dioletis E, Nemeth BT, Pacher P, Feng D, Bataller R, Cabezas J, Stärkel P, Caballeria J, Pongratz RL, Cai SY, Schnabl B, Hoque R, Chen Y, Yang WH, Garcia-Martinez I, Wang FS, Gao B, Torok NJ, Kibbey RG, Mehal WZ. Digoxin Suppresses Pyruvate Kinase M2-Promoted HIF-1α Transactivation in Steatohepatitis. Cell Metab. 2018 Feb 6;27(2):339-350.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2018.01.007. Erratum in: Cell Metab. 2018 May 1;27(5):1156.</citation>
    <PMID>29414684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arteel GE, Iimuro Y, Yin M, Raleigh JA, Thurman RG. Chronic enteral ethanol treatment causes hypoxia in rat liver tissue in vivo. Hepatology. 1997 Apr;25(4):920-6.</citation>
    <PMID>9096598</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee YS, Kim JW, Osborne O, Oh DY, Sasik R, Schenk S, Chen A, Chung H, Murphy A, Watkins SM, Quehenberger O, Johnson RS, Olefsky JM. Increased adipocyte O2 consumption triggers HIF-1α, causing inflammation and insulin resistance in obesity. Cell. 2014 Jun 5;157(6):1339-1352. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2014.05.012.</citation>
    <PMID>24906151</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nath B, Levin I, Csak T, Petrasek J, Mueller C, Kodys K, Catalano D, Mandrekar P, Szabo G. Hepatocyte-specific hypoxia-inducible factor-1α is a determinant of lipid accumulation and liver injury in alcohol-induced steatosis in mice. Hepatology. 2011 May;53(5):1526-37. doi: 10.1002/hep.24256.</citation>
    <PMID>21520168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Palmer BF, Clegg DJ. Ascent to altitude as a weight loss method: the good and bad of hypoxia inducible factor activation. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2014 Feb;22(2):311-7. doi: 10.1002/oby.20499. Epub 2013 Oct 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23625659</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Semenza GL. Hypoxia-inducible factors in physiology and medicine. Cell. 2012 Feb 3;148(3):399-408. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2012.01.021. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22304911</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hollman A. Drugs for atrial fibrillation. Digoxin comes from Digitalis lanata. BMJ. 1996 Apr 6;312(7035):912.</citation>
    <PMID>8611904</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Digoxin FDA insert. . [cited 2021 3/15/2021]</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>(CDC)., C.f.D.C.a.P. Alcohol and Public Health: Alcohol-Related Disease Impact (ARDI). Annual Average for United States 2011-2015 Alcohol-Attributable Deaths Due to Excessive Alcohol Use, All Ages. [cited 2021 3/20/2021]</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>(NIH)., N.I.o.H. Alcohol Facts and Statistics. [cited 2021 3/20/2021]</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rathore SS, Curtis JP, Wang Y, Bristow MR, Krumholz HM. Association of serum digoxin concentration and outcomes in patients with heart failure. JAMA. 2003 Feb 19;289(7):871-8.</citation>
    <PMID>12588271</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ouyang AJ, Lv YN, Zhong HL, Wen JH, Wei XH, Peng HW, Zhou J, Liu LL. Meta-analysis of digoxin use and risk of mortality in patients with atrial fibrillation. Am J Cardiol. 2015 Apr 1;115(7):901-6. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2015.01.013. Epub 2015 Jan 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25660972</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dasgupta A. Endogenous and exogenous digoxin-like immunoreactive substances: impact on therapeutic drug monitoring of digoxin. Am J Clin Pathol. 2002 Jul;118(1):132-40. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12109847</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yang SS, Hughes RD, Williams R. Digoxin-like immunoreactive substances in severe acute liver disease due to viral hepatitis and paracetamol overdose. Hepatology. 1988 Jan-Feb;8(1):93-7.</citation>
    <PMID>2828215</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosenkranz B, Frölich JC. Falsely elevated digoxin concentrations in patients with liver disease. Ther Drug Monit. 1985;7(2):202-6.</citation>
    <PMID>4024214</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nikou GC, Vyssoulis GP, Venetikou MS, Karga HI, Karoutsos KA, Toutouzas PK. Digoxin-like substance(s) interfere(s) with serum estimations of the drug in cirrhotic patients. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1989 Aug;11(4):430-3.</citation>
    <PMID>2547866</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Digoxin conversion calculator.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Shea RS, Dasarathy S, McCullough AJ; Practice Guideline Committee of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases; Practice Parameters Committee of the American College of Gastroenterology. Alcoholic liver disease. Hepatology. 2010 Jan;51(1):307-28. doi: 10.1002/hep.23258. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20034030</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bode C, Bode JC. Effect of alcohol consumption on the gut. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2003 Aug;17(4):575-92. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12828956</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trial of Anakinra (Plus Zinc) or Prednisone in Patients With Severe Alcohol associated Hepatitis (AlcHepNet). [cited 2021 03/29]</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>R Core Team. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing 2020</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Yale University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bubu Banini, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Internal Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acute alcoholic hepatitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Digoxin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Alcoholic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chemical and Drug Induced Liver Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol-Induced Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Digoxin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

