<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05018052</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Stop-Covid/1/2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05018052</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Early and Late Complications of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Characteristics and Predictors of Early and Late Cardiovascular Complications of Covid-19 Patients - the PoLoCOV-Study (Polish LONG-COVID Cardiovascular Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Michal Chudzik</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Saint Family Hospital Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a serious respiratory disease that results from&#xD;
      infection with a newly discovered coronavirus (SARS-COV-2). Unfortunately, COVID-19 is not&#xD;
      only a short-term infection. Patients (pts) recovering from SARS-COV2 infection complain of&#xD;
      persisting symptoms including: fatigue, diffuse myalgia and weakness, which may lead to&#xD;
      chronic fatigue syndrome and as well as many other complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The vast majority of COVID-19 patients remaining in isolation/quarantine, due to the mild&#xD;
      course of the disease, do not require hospitalization. In this group of patients, the course&#xD;
      of COVID-19 is very different - from asymptomatic patients to very severe and long lasting&#xD;
      symptoms also with a decrease in saturation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are many studies describing the course and complications of patients hospitalized due&#xD;
      to COVID-19. There is little published data on how non-hospitalized patients get sick and&#xD;
      what are the early and late complications of SARS-CoV-2 infection. In addition, many patients&#xD;
      remain ill even many months after COVID-19, entering what is known as LONG-COVID.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the STOP-COVID Registry was established. The purpose of the Registry is to assess&#xD;
      the course of COVID-19 infection, early and late cardiovascular complications of COVID-19 in&#xD;
      patients with and without hospitalization. In addition, the purpose of the STOP-COVID&#xD;
      Registry is to assess the incidence of LONG-COVID with all other complications and to&#xD;
      identify predictive factors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The following patients are included in the Registry: Patients 18 years and older diagnosed&#xD;
      with COVID-19, in accordance with the current guidelines of the Ministry of Health of Poland,&#xD;
      after full recovery (resolution of clinical symptoms, minimum 14 days after last symptoms).&#xD;
      The Registry includes patients with and without hospitalization .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approval from the Bioethics Committee of Lodz Regional Medical Chamber to conduct the&#xD;
      Registry was obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Registry was held at the: Saint Family Hospital Medical Center, Lodz, Poland Patient&#xD;
      information, course of the disease, post-COVID-19 complaints, comorbidities and current&#xD;
      treatment were collected at visit &quot;0&quot; within 4-8 weeks after the end of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subsequently, patients were ordered the following tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  12-lead ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  24-hour Holter ECG monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  24-hour Holter blood pressure monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Echocardiographic of the Heart assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biochemical tests: Lipid Profile (total cholesterol, LDL fraction, HDL, triglycerides),&#xD;
           glucose or glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) level, D-dimers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with indications, the following were additionally performed: MRI of the heart,&#xD;
      Angio CT of pulmonary vessels, Angio CT of coronary vessels or other diagnostic tests.&#xD;
      Depending on the indications of the pts, they were referred for other tests and specialist&#xD;
      consultations. All pts were diagnosed and treated in accordance with the current&#xD;
      recommendations of the European Cardiology Society (ESC) and Polish Cardiac Society (PCS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If any abnormalities were found, patients were treated in accordance with the current ESC&#xD;
      guidelines. In the event of complications after COVID-19, each patient will be treated in&#xD;
      accordance with current guidelines and recommendations, in accordance with current medical&#xD;
      knowledge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a period of 3 months after COVID-19, new symptoms that appeared after COVID-19,&#xD;
      remained and/or worsened after COVID-19 were assessed at the follow-up visit, based on the&#xD;
      patient's interview. If such symptoms occurred, patients were classified as LONG-COVID.&#xD;
      Symptoms that may have resulted from the severity of the underlying condition were not&#xD;
      classified as LONG-COVID.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with LONG-COVID, after excluding complications/contraindications, will be referred&#xD;
      to the post-COVID rehabilitation program. This program covers a comprehensive range of&#xD;
      rehabilitation with dietary and psychological consultations. Patients referred to the&#xD;
      rehabilitation program will constitute the REHA-STOP-COVID group. The rehabilitation program&#xD;
      will last 6 weeks. At the beginning and at the end of the program, each patient will have&#xD;
      fitness assessment performed with the following tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  oxygen saturation assessment performed with a pulse oximeter;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  physical capacity assessment with 6 minute walking test (6MWT)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dyspnea assessment with modified 0-10 Borg scale&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fatigue assessment with Modified Fatigue Impact Scale (MFIS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Muscle Strength Assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  lower extremity function and mobility with Short Physical Performance Battery test&#xD;
           (SPPB)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Annual reassessment of all patients is planned for 5 years after COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the control visits, patients will be ordered the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical evaluation with health assessment, comorbidities and symptoms that may be due&#xD;
           to a history of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  12-lead ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  24-hour Holter ECG monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  24-hour Holter blood pressure monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Echocardiographic of the Heart assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biochemical tests: Lipid Profile (total cholesterol, LDL fraction, HDL, triglycerides),&#xD;
           glucose or glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, a questionnaire will be completed by the patient with an assessment of his/her&#xD;
      health, weight, height, BMI, risk factors for cardiovascular diseases (smoking, alcohol&#xD;
      abuse), physical activity, all medications that the patient takes, whether the patient was&#xD;
      re-infected with SARS-CoV in the past years (date) , whether the patient was vaccinated (with&#xD;
      full vaccination date).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each patient from the STOP-COVID program, in the event of deterioration of health and / or&#xD;
      the appearance of new ailments, may be referred for the consultation to the Saint Family&#xD;
      Hospital Medical Center by a GP and/or another specialist during the whole period of the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the entire study period, the following will be registered in the medical database:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Any new medical event assessed by 2 doctors as a complication after COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Any hospitalization related to complications of COVID-19 as well as any other reason&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Each severity has already been diseases diagnosed and treated, with information whether&#xD;
           it required correction / modification of the current treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Any newly diagnosed diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Any abnormalities in the results of diagnostic examinations, laboratory tests and&#xD;
           consultations&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 29, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Early and Late COVID-19 cardio-vascular complications</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Early and Late COVID-19 cardio-vascular complications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictors of Long-Covid Cardio-Vascular complications</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Predictors of Long-Covid Cardio-Vascular complications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SCORE - algorithm to help to predict the highest risk of Long-Covid complications</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>SCORE - algorithm to help to predict the highest risk of Long-Covid complications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detailed patients' characteristics and differences in those with and without Long-Covid complications</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Detailed patients' characteristics and differences in those with and without Long-Covid</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Definition and characteristics of the early and Late COVID-19 complications</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Definition and characteristics of the early and Late COVID-19 complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of complications and Long-Covid depending on the severity of the course of COVID-19 COVID-19, comorbidities</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of complications and Long-Covid depending on the severity of the course of COVID</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1900</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>LONG-COVID</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients 18 years and older diagnosed with COVID-19, after full recovery (resolution of&#xD;
        clinical symptoms, minimum 14 days after last symptoms), with and without hospitalization .&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients after COVID-19, 18 years and older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical Center, Saint Family Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Łódź</city>
        <zip>90-302</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.stop-covid.pl</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Saint Family Hospital Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michal Chudzik</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Doctor, Cardiologist, Medical Director Ambulatory Clinic</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid complications</keyword>
  <keyword>Long-Covid</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Fatigue Syndrome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

