<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05018585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DIAGNODE-3 (D/P3/21/7)</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-002731-32</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05018585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diamyd Administered Into Lymph Nodes in Individuals Recently Diagnosed With Type 1 Diabetes, Carrying the HLA DR3-DQ2 Haplotype</brief_title>
  <acronym>DIAGNODE-3</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase III, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Multicenter Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Diamyd® to Preserve Endogenous Beta Cell Function in Adolescents and Adults With Recently Diagnosed Type 1 Diabetes, Carrying the Genetic HLA DR3-DQ2 Haplotype</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Diamyd Medical AB</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Diamyd Medical AB</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of DIAGNODE-3 is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of three intranodal&#xD;
      injections of 4 μg of Diamyd compared to placebo, along with oral Vitamin D supplementation,&#xD;
      to preserve endogenous beta cell function and influence glycemic parameters in adolescent and&#xD;
      adults recently diagnosed with T1D carrying the HLA DR3-DQ2 haplotype.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is a 2-arm, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, clinical&#xD;
      trial. Patients will have the HLA genotyping performed at the first Screening visit (Visit&#xD;
      1A). If the results indicate the patient is carrying the HLA DR3-DQ2 haplotype, then the&#xD;
      patient will attend the second Screening visit (Visit 1B) to perform the remaining screening&#xD;
      procedures. Eligible patients will receive injections of Diamyd/placebo into an inguinal&#xD;
      lymph gland at three occasions, with one month intervals along with oral Vitamin D&#xD;
      supplementation. All patients will continue to receive intensive insulin treatment from their&#xD;
      personal physicians during the whole study period. Patients will be followed in a blinded&#xD;
      manner for a total of 24 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is a 2-arm, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, clinical trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in stimulated C-peptide during a MMTT</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline to Month 24 in C-peptide AUCmean 0-120 min during a 2 hour MMTT.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean difference in change from baseline to Month 24 in HbA1c (mmol/mol)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in time in glycemic target range 3.9 to 10 mmol/L (70 to 180 mg/dL) between baseline and Month 24.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in time in glycemic target range 3.9 to 10 mmol/L (70 to 180 mg/dL) [evaluated from continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) data] between baseline and Month 24.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with insulin dose-adjusted HbA1c ≤9 at Month 24.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with insulin dose-adjusted HbA1c (IDDA1C) ≤9 at Month 24.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes per patient of severe hypoglycemia between baseline and Month 24.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of episodes per patient of severe hypoglycemia between baseline and Month 24.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes per patient of diabetic ketoacidosis between baseline and Month 24.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of episodes per patient of diabetic ketoacidosis between baseline and Month 24</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">330</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Autoimmune Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Immune System Disease</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Juvenile Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Endocrine System Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Insulin Dependent Diabetes Mellitus 1</condition>
  <condition>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Disease</condition>
  <condition>Autoimmune Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diamyd</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be assigned to receive i) three (3) intralymphatic injections with 4µg Diamyd (rhGAD) on Days 0, 30, and 60 and; ii) oral vitamin D 2000 IU/daily for 4 months (from Day -30 through Day 90)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be assigned to receive i) three (3) intralymphatic injections of Placebo for Diamyd (rhGAD) on Days 0, 30, and 60 and; ii) oral vitamin D 2000 IU/daily for 4 months (from Day -30 through Day 90)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant human glutamic acid decarboxylase (rhGAD65) formulated in Alhydrogel®</intervention_name>
    <description>Recombinant human glutamic acid decarboxylase (rhGAD65) formulated in Alhydrogel®</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diamyd</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Diamyd</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colecalciferol 2000 IU</intervention_name>
    <description>Colecalciferol (vitamin D3) 2000 IU (equivalent to 50 microgram vitamin D3).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diamyd</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Divisun 2000 IU</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo for recombinant human glutamic acid decarboxylase (rhGAD65) formulated in Alhydrogel®</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo for Diamyd, Alhydrogel® only</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients are eligible to be included in this study only if all of the following criteria&#xD;
        apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Must be capable of providing written, signed, and dated informed consent; and for&#xD;
             patients who are minors, age-appropriate assent (performed according to local&#xD;
             regulations) and parent/caregiver consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males and females aged ≥12 and &lt;29 years old at the time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosed with T1D (according to the American Diabetes Association [ADA]&#xD;
             classification) ≤6 months at the time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Possess the HLA DR3-DQ2 haplotype (all patients will be tested; prior genetic testing&#xD;
             results will not be accepted).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Fasting C-peptide ≥0.12 nmol/L (≥0.36 ng/mL) on at least one occasion (maximum two&#xD;
             tests on different days during the Screening period).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Possess detectable circulating GAD65 antibodies (lowest level of detection defined by&#xD;
             the method used by the central laboratory).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Possess HbA1c levels between 35 to 80 mmol/mol (5.4 to 9.5%) on at least one occasion&#xD;
             prior to randomization (maximum one additional test within one month from Visit 1B).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Be on a stable insulin dose or insulin dosing regimen for one month prior to inclusion&#xD;
             with limited fluctuation of daily insulin requirement based on investigator's&#xD;
             assessment. For example, if the average insulin dose/kg/24h over a 7-day period&#xD;
             compared to the previous 7-day period does not vary more than approximately 15% and/or&#xD;
             if the daily insulin dose does not vary more than 0.1 U/kg/24h, the dose can be&#xD;
             considered stable. Individuals that are diagnosed with T1D according to the ADA&#xD;
             classification but are not taking insulin are eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. i. Females of childbearing potential (FOCBP) must agree to avoid pregnancy and have a&#xD;
             negative pregnancy test performed at the required study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        FOCBP must agree to use highly effective contraception, during treatment and, until 90 days&#xD;
        after the last administration of study medication. Birth control methods, which may be&#xD;
        considered as highly effective (e.g., a failure rate of less than 1% per year when used&#xD;
        consistently and correctly) include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Combined (estrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception associated with&#xD;
             inhibition of ovulation:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Oral.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intravaginal.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Transdermal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Oral.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Injectable.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Implantable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intrauterine device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intrauterine hormone-releasing system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilateral tubal occlusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vasectomized partner (vasectomized partner is a highly effective birth control method&#xD;
             provided that partner is the sole sexual partner of the FOCBP trial patient and that&#xD;
             the vasectomized partner has received medical assessment of the surgical success).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexual abstinence (sexual abstinence is considered a highly effective method only if&#xD;
             defined as refraining from heterosexual intercourse during the entire period of risk&#xD;
             associated with the study drugs. The reliability of sexual abstinence needs to be&#xD;
             evaluated in relation to the duration of the clinical trial and the preferred and&#xD;
             usual lifestyle of the patient).&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. ii. Male patients must agree to remain abstinent from heterosexual sex during&#xD;
             treatment and for 90 days after treatment or, if sexually active, to use two effective&#xD;
             methods of birth control (e.g., male uses a condom and female uses contraception)&#xD;
             during and for 90 days after treatment. Acceptable male contraception is as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Condom (male).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vasectomy. The agreement to remain abstinent or use two effective methods of birth&#xD;
             control will be clearly defined in the informed consent; the patient or legally&#xD;
             authorized representatives (e.g., parents, caregivers, or legal guardians) must sign&#xD;
             this specific section.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are not eligible to be included in this study if any of the following&#xD;
             criteria apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Participation in any other trial aimed to influence beta cell function from time&#xD;
                  of diagnosis of T1D.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Treatment with any oral or non-insulin injectable anti-diabetic medication within&#xD;
                  3 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. History of maturity-onset diabetes of the young (MODY).&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Pancreatic surgery, chronic pancreatitis, or other pancreatic disorders that&#xD;
                  could result in decreased beta cell capacity (e.g., pancreatogenous diabetes).&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. History of DKA or severe hypoglycemia requiring hospitalization within one month&#xD;
                  before Screening, or severe episodes of hypoglycemia requiring third party&#xD;
                  assistance within one month before Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Signs or symptoms suggesting very poorly controlled diabetes e.g., ongoing weight&#xD;
                  loss, polyuria or polydipsia.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Hematologic condition that would make HbA1c uninterpretable including:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Hemoglobinopathy, with the exception of sickle cell trait or thalassemia&#xD;
                       minor; or chronic or recurrent hemolysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Donation of blood or blood products to a blood bank, blood transfusion or&#xD;
                       participation in a clinical study requiring withdrawal of &gt;400 mL of blood&#xD;
                       during the 8 weeks prior to the Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Significant iron deficiency anemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    4. Heart malformations or vaso-occlusive crisis (VOC) leading to increased&#xD;
                       turnover of erythrocytes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Treatment with marketed or over-the-counter Vitamin D at the time of Screening&#xD;
                  and unwilling to abstain from such medication during the 120 days when the&#xD;
                  patient will be supplemented with the study-provided Vitamin D. A patient&#xD;
                  currently taking Vitamin D at the time of Screening must be willing to switch to&#xD;
                  the study-provided Vitamin D treatment and to administer it per the study&#xD;
                  requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Any clinically significant history of an acute reaction to a vaccine or its&#xD;
                  constituents (e.g., Alhydrogel).&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Treatment with any (live or inactive) vaccine, including influenza vaccine and&#xD;
                  Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccine, within 4 weeks prior to planned&#xD;
                  first study dose of study drug; or planned treatment with any vaccine up to 4&#xD;
                  weeks after the last injection with study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Any acute or chronic skin infection or condition that would preclude&#xD;
                  intralymphatic injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Recent (past 12 months) or current treatment with immunosuppressant therapy,&#xD;
                  including chronic use of glucocorticoid therapy. Inhaled, topical, and intranasal&#xD;
                  steroid use is acceptable. Short courses (e.g., ≤5 days) of oral or&#xD;
                  intra-articular injections of steroids will be permitted on trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Continuous/chronic treatment with prescribed or over-the-counter&#xD;
                  anti-inflammatory therapies. Short-term use (e.g., &lt;7 days) is permissible, for&#xD;
                  example to treat a headache or in connection with a fever.&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Known or suspected acute infection, including COVID-19 or influenza, at the time&#xD;
                  of Screening or within 2 weeks prior to Screening. After confirmed recent&#xD;
                  COVID-19 infection, a negative polymerase chain reaction test will be required&#xD;
                  before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. A history of epilepsy, head trauma or cerebrovascular accident, or clinical&#xD;
                  features of continuous motor unit activity in proximal muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B or hepatitis C&#xD;
                  infection. Patients with previous hepatitis C infection that is now cured may be&#xD;
                  eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Any clinically significant concomitant medical condition, including but not&#xD;
                  limited to other autoimmune diseases, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
                  hematological, immune, renal including a history of renal transplantation,&#xD;
                  neurological (including Batten disease), significant diabetes complication, any&#xD;
                  underlying conditions or receiving treatments that could affect red blood cell&#xD;
                  turnover or other diseases that in the opinion of the investigator would&#xD;
                  interfere with trial participation or procedures. Celiac disease with adequate&#xD;
                  diet before diagnosis or discovered by increased autoantibodies at Screening will&#xD;
                  be permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
              18. History of significant hepatic disease or Screening alanine aminotransferase&#xD;
                  (ALT) &gt;2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) 3 x&#xD;
                  ULN and/or total bilirubin &gt;2 x ULN. Patients with documented Gilbert syndrome&#xD;
                  and total bilirubin level ≥2 x ULN due to unconjugated hyperbilirubinemia,&#xD;
                  without other hepatic impairment, are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
              19. Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) calculated by Chronic Kidney Disease&#xD;
                  Epidemiology Collaboration (CKD-Epi) for those &gt;18 years old, and by the Schwartz&#xD;
                  equation for those 12 to 18 years old, &lt;90 mL/min per 1.73 m or rapidly&#xD;
                  progressing renal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
              20. Patients with hypothyroidism or hyperthyroidism must be on stable treatment for&#xD;
                  at least 3 months prior to Screening (with normal free thyroxine [T4] levels if&#xD;
                  hypothyroid).&#xD;
&#xD;
              21. Any clinically significant abnormal findings during Screening, and any other&#xD;
                  medical condition(s) or laboratory findings that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
                  investigator, might jeopardize the patient's safety or ability to complete the&#xD;
                  trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
              22. History of malignancy not in remission within the last 5 years other than&#xD;
                  adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or cervical carcinoma&#xD;
                  in situ.&#xD;
&#xD;
              23. Patients with any mental condition rendering him/her unable to understand the&#xD;
                  nature, scope and possible consequences of the trial, and/or evidence of poor&#xD;
                  compliance with medical instructions at Screening or showing non-compliance&#xD;
                  during the Run-In Period.&#xD;
&#xD;
              24. A history of alcohol or drug abuse or dependence within the past 12 months based&#xD;
                  on DSM IV criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
              25. Current or previous participation in a trial of Diamyd.&#xD;
&#xD;
              26. Participation in a clinical trial involving administration of an investigational&#xD;
                  drug in the past 3 months or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) prior to first&#xD;
                  dosing of study drug or during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
              27. Females who are breastfeeding, pregnant or plan to become pregnant during the&#xD;
                  trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
              28. Patients who in the opinion of the investigator will not be able to follow&#xD;
                  instructions and/or follow the study procedures or patients that are unwilling or&#xD;
                  unable to comply with the provisions of this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
              29. An employee or immediate family member of an employee of Diamyd Medical AB.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>28 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Johnny Ludvigsson, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Crown Princess Victoria Children´s Hospital and Linköping University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Director of Clinical Development</last_name>
    <phone>+46 (0) 8 661 00 26</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials@diamyd.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabete Mellitus</keyword>
  <keyword>residual beta cell function</keyword>
  <keyword>HLA DR3-DQ2</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</keyword>
  <keyword>Autoimmune Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Metabolic Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Autoimmune Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune System Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Insulin Dependent Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>rhGAD65</keyword>
  <keyword>GAD65</keyword>
  <keyword>GAD-alum</keyword>
  <keyword>residual c-peptide</keyword>
  <keyword>T1D</keyword>
  <keyword>recent-onset T1D</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>HLA</keyword>
  <keyword>Diamyd</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immune System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aluminum Hydroxide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

