<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05012813</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00023183</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-08489</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>STUDY00023183</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05012813</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Virtual Reality Greenspace and Humidified Forest Oils on Immune System Recovery in Stage I-III Breast or Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Feasibility of Substitution of Virtual Reality Greenspace and Volatile Organic Compound Humidification to Simulate the Forest Experience Effects on Immune System Recovery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oregon Health and Science University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial studies the feasibility of simulating forest immersion via virtual&#xD;
      reality, paired with humidified wood or fragrant oils, in improving immune cells, like&#xD;
      natural killer cells, number and activity, and their downstream proteins, perforin and&#xD;
      granulysin in patients with stage I-III breast or prostate cancer who completed chemo- and/or&#xD;
      radiation therapy. The knowledge gained from this study may help cancer patients who have&#xD;
      compromised immune systems and who also cannot participate in outdoor activities like&#xD;
      exercise or forest walks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine the feasibility of using virtual reality (VR) paired with humidified phytoncides&#xD;
      to simulate the forest greenspace immersion (simulated forest immersion therapy [SFIT]) in&#xD;
      cancer patients with solid tumor who have completed surgery, chemo- and radiation therapy as&#xD;
      an alternate method of access to the natural forest greenspace.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine the feasibility of collecting and analyzing immune system measures while&#xD;
      deploying the simulated forest immersion therapy with forest oils (SFIT), as well as&#xD;
      measuring natural killer (NK) cell number and activity, and perforin and granulysin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients participate in SFIT, using VR pictures of forest and greenspace, and humidified wood&#xD;
      and fragrance oils, over 1 hour. Patients also undergo blood sample collection at baseline&#xD;
      and on day 3 or 4 and participate in interviews at baseline and post-treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Virtual reality paired with humidified phytoncides to simulate the forest greenspace immersion (SFIT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline/Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility analysis will include qualitative interview data blinded by participant, CRC/research assistant and principal investigator. Qualitative interview questions include ease of use/deployment of VR and humidified forest oils by the CRC/research assistant and PI, the ability of the participants to tolerate SFIT. The responses will be coded, themed and summarized will be used to determine the feasibility of intervention deployment and creation of a standardized procedure for future research. To determine dose drop off between the start of SFIT and the end of SFIT of the humidified phytoncides a t-test with an alpha level of 0.05 will be used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Collecting and analyzing immune system measures while deploying the simulated forest immersion therapy with forest oils</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and at day 3 or 4</time_frame>
    <description>Will measure natural killer (NK) cell number and activity, and perforin and granulysin. NK cell number (NK CD3-/CD56+/) and activity (NK CD3-/CD56+/CD69+) will be tested with Flow Cytology. Perforin and granulysin will be tested by ELISA. Will use a t-test to determine the differences between these 4 variables collected at baseline and a Day 3-4. An alpha level of 0.05 will be set. Alternate analysis, the change NK cell number and activity will be determined from the mean of the standard range.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage I Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage II Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IIA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IIB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage III Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IIIA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IIIB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Anatomic Stage IIIC Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage I Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage II Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IIA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IIB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage III Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IIIA Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IIIB Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Prognostic Stage IIIC Breast Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage I Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage II Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIA Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIB Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIC Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Prostate Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Supportive care (SFIT, biospecimen, interview)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients participate in SFIT, using VR pictures of forest and greenspace, and humidified wood and fragrance oils, over 1 hour. Patients also undergo blood sample collection at baseline and on day 3 or 4 and participate in interviews at baseline and post-treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aromatherapy with Essential Oils and Virtual Reality</intervention_name>
    <description>Participate in SFIT this is one intervention with Virtual Reality (VR) and aroma therapy with essential Forest oils</description>
    <arm_group_label>Supportive care (SFIT, biospecimen, interview)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Aromatherapy with Essential Oils</other_name>
    <other_name>Virtual Reality</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapeutic Interventions</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapeutic Method</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapeutic Procedure</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapeutic Technique</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years. Both men and women and members of all races and ethnic groups will be&#xD;
             included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have histologically or cytologically confirmed hormone receptor&#xD;
             positive (HR+) HER2 negative (-) breast cancer or prostate cancer (hormone therapy&#xD;
             excepted) who are in Stage I-III with no evidence of metastasis using the Cancer&#xD;
             Therapy Evaluation Program (CTEP) Simplified Disease Classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria for solid tumors: Participants must have measurable disease, defined as at&#xD;
             least one lesion that can be accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest&#xD;
             diameter to be recorded for non-nodal lesions and short axis for nodal lesions) as &gt;=&#xD;
             20 mm with conventional techniques or as &gt;= 10 mm with spiral computed tomography (CT)&#xD;
             scan, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), or calipers by clinical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have no history of autoimmune disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they have asthma. Rationale: forest oils may be a possible trigger for asthma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they have a known allergy to citrus peel or pine forests. Rationale: forest oils&#xD;
             may cause contact dermatitis and coughing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they are unable to detect common odors from commercial fragrances. Rationale,&#xD;
             forest oils are humidified as an aroma to be inhaled in the simulate the forest&#xD;
             greenspace immersion (SFIT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they have known metastases should be excluded from this clinical study. Rationale,&#xD;
             because of their poor prognosis rather than being in early stages of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Febrile illness/infection within previous two weeks. Rationale, immune biomarkers will&#xD;
             reflect previous febrile illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current tobacco or tobacco use within 1 hour of start of SFIT. Rationale: forest oils&#xD;
             may cause contact dermatitis and coughing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior autoimmune disease, are on immune-modulating therapies (endocrine therapy&#xD;
             allowed). Rationale, because of their poor prognosis rather than being in early stages&#xD;
             of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had surgery or invasive procedure in the past two months. Rationale, because of their&#xD;
             poor prognosis rather than being in early stages of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to complete study requisites&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amy M Ross, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy M. Ross, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>503-494-2123</phone>
      <email>rossam@ohsu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amy M. Ross, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amy M. Ross Ph.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

