<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05013255</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2103254164</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05013255</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pioglitazone Therapy Targeting Fatigue in Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pioglitazone Therapy Targeting Fatigue in Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>West Virginia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>West Virginia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this project is to evaluate the therapeutic potential of pioglitazone (PIO) to&#xD;
      target underlying mechanisms that promote muscle fatigue in patients with breast cancer. This&#xD;
      represents an off-label use of this compound, both in terms of the patient population and the&#xD;
      clinical phenotype targeted. The central research hypothesis of this study is that daily&#xD;
      pioglitazone will restore transcriptional downregulation of pathways within skeletal that&#xD;
      promote fatigue.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fatigue is commonly reported in cancer patients, but is not treated due to the absence of&#xD;
      viable therapies. At the time of diagnosis, prior to treatment, nearly all breast cancer&#xD;
      patients have some degree of muscle dysfunction resulting in fatigue that ranges from mild to&#xD;
      debilitating and may worsen with chemotherapy, radiation, and/or surgery. A significant gap&#xD;
      in knowledge exists with respect to targetable mechanisms to alleviate fatigue in patients&#xD;
      with cancer. The goal of this project is to evaluate the therapeutic potential of&#xD;
      pioglitazone (PIO) to target underlying mechanisms that promote muscle fatigue in patients&#xD;
      with breast cancer. This represents an off-label use of this compound, both in terms of the&#xD;
      patient population and the clinical phenotype targeted. The central research hypothesis of&#xD;
      this study is that daily pioglitazone will restore transcriptional downregulation of pathways&#xD;
      within skeletal that promote fatigue. The investigators believe this trial will provide the&#xD;
      clinical data on optimal PIO dose to affect muscle gene expression in patients with breast&#xD;
      cancer. This data will be used to support a larger clinical trial in patients with and&#xD;
      without breast cancer to determine PIO therapy effects on muscle fatigue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pioglitazone is an FDA-approved drug that is used to treat insulin resistance in patients&#xD;
      with diabetes by targeting PPARγ activity, although this drug also affects mitochondrial&#xD;
      function through PPARγ regulation. Therefore, the investigators will test the central&#xD;
      research hypothesis that daily pioglitazone will restore transcriptional downregulation of&#xD;
      pathways within skeletal that promote fatigue. Specific Aim 1 will determine the molecular&#xD;
      signature within skeletal muscle in response to low dose and high dose pioglitazone therapy.&#xD;
      It is predicted that daily pioglitazone therapy will reverse the breast cancer-associated&#xD;
      downregulation of mitochondrial and metabolic genes in skeletal muscle. Specific Aim 2 will&#xD;
      determine the effects of low dose and high dose pioglitazone therapy on perceptions of&#xD;
      fatigue. It is predicted that daily pioglitazone therapy will improve patient reported&#xD;
      perceptions of fatigue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a Phase 2B Trial to determine the lowest effective dose of pioglitazone for affecting&#xD;
      skeletal muscle gene expression in breast cancer patients without diabetes (dose-finding&#xD;
      study). At the time of registration, subjects will be randomized to either the low dose (15mg&#xD;
      PIO; n=10) or the high dose (30mg PIO; n=10) group, or a no-drug control group (n=10). Drug&#xD;
      therapy will last for 2 weeks, leading into a scheduled mastectomy. Subjects will be provided&#xD;
      with a 2 week supply of PIO on Study Day 1 to be taken orally once per day. Following surgery&#xD;
      and muscle biopsy collection subjects will be followed for adverse events, fatigue and body&#xD;
      composition for 30 days through their first post-op visit. The total study duration will be&#xD;
      6-weeks (2 weeks of drug treatment + 4 weeks until follow-up visit).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Gene Expression</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>evaluate the ability of daily pioglitazone therapy to attenuate the transcriptional downregulation of a gene network within skeletal muscle that is integral to mitochondrial bioenergetics, with PPARγ central to this network. The outcome measure will be RNA-Sequencing and gene expression analysis from muscle biopsies obtained from subjects following either low dose or high dose pioglitazone therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the fatigue in subjects with breast cancer that are being treated with pioglitazone, as measured by the FACT-F questionnaire. 5 point Likert-type scale where 0= Not at all, 1= A little bit, 2= Somewhat, 3= Quite a bit, 4= Very much.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Monitor body weight for loss or gains in subjects receiving low dose and high dose pioglitazone for 2 weeks prior to a scheduled mastectomy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Muscle Fatigue</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pioglitazone 15mg Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be given PIO 15mg once daily, based on the randomization lists prepared by the WVUCI Biostatistics Core. This is a 1:1:1 randomization (10 in each group) without any planned stratification.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pioglitazone 30mg Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be given PIO 30mg once daily, based on the randomization lists prepared by the WVUCI Biostatistics Core. This is a 1:1:1 randomization (10 in each group) without any planned stratification.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be assigned to a no drug control group based on the randomization lists prepared by the WVUCI Biostatistics Core. This is a 1:1:1 randomization (10 in each group) without any planned stratification.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pioglitazone 15mg</intervention_name>
    <description>PIO 15mg orally once daily for 2 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pioglitazone 15mg Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Actos</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pioglitazone 30 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>PIO 30mg orally once daily for 2 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pioglitazone 30mg Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Actos</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have histologically or cytologically confirmed luminal (ER+/PR+&#xD;
             Her2/neu-) Breast Cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have received no prior therapies besides chemotherapy in the neoadjuvant&#xD;
             setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject must have a planned surgical (mastectomy) date within 2 weeks of starting&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  5 Subjects must have normal organ as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin within normal institutional limits (or &gt;10?)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fasting Blood Glucose within normal institutional limits&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum Creatinine within normal institutional limits&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Liver Function (AST and ALT, Alk phosphatase, Total Bilirubin) within normal&#xD;
                  limits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject does not have a prior diagnosis of diabetes or currently taking any&#xD;
             medications to lower blood glucose levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written&#xD;
             informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior diagnosis of Congestive Heart Failure (CHF), Bladder cancer, osteoporosis,&#xD;
             bariatric surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects receiving any other investigational agents or known agents to have a major&#xD;
             interaction with PIO to include clopidogrel, gatifloxacin, gemfibrozil, leflunomide,&#xD;
             lomitapide, lumateperone, mipomersen, pexideartinib and teriflunomide, insulin,&#xD;
             Lyrica, Synthroid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to Pioglitazone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing&#xD;
             or active infection, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, active alcoholism&#xD;
             or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding are excluded from this study because Pioglitazone has the&#xD;
             potential for teratogenic or abortifacient effects. Because there is an unknown, but&#xD;
             potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the&#xD;
             mother with PIO, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with&#xD;
             PIO. These potential risks may also apply to other agents used in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristin H Lupinacci, DO</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>West Virginia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kristin Lupinacci, DO</last_name>
    <phone>3042931022</phone>
    <email>kristin.lupinacci@hsc.wvu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Emidio Pistilli, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>304-293-0291</phone>
    <email>epistilli2@hsc.wvu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West Virginia University Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Morgantown</city>
        <state>West Virginia</state>
        <zip>26506</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristin Lupinacci, DO</last_name>
      <phone>304-293-1022</phone>
      <email>kristin.lupinacci@hsc.wvu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>West Virginia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kristin Lupinacci</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pioglitazone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

