<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05018598</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLI-05993AB1-06</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05018598</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Step-up to Medium Strength Triple Therapy vs High Strength ICS/LABA in Adult Asthmatics Uncontrolled on Medium Strength ICS/LABA</brief_title>
  <acronym>MiSTIC</acronym>
  <official_title>A 26 Week, Randomized, Double Blind, Multinational, Multicenter, Active Controlled, 2-arm Parallel Group Trial Comparing CHF 5993 100/6/12.5 μg pMDI (Fixed Combination of Extrafine Formulation of Beclometasone Dipropionate Plus Formoterol Fumarate Plus Glycopyrronium Bromide) to CHF 1535 22/6 μg pMDI (Fixed Combination of Extrafine Formulation of Beclometasone Dipropionate Plus Formoterol Fumarate) in Subjects With Asthma Uncontrolled on Medium Doses of Inhaled Corticosteroids in Combination With Long-Acting β2-Agonists</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chiesi Farmaceutici S.p.A.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chiesi Farmaceutici S.p.A.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this phase IV Study is to demonstrate the efficacy of CHF5993 (BDP/FF/GB&#xD;
      100/6/12.5 pMDI) on uncontrolled asthma subjects, compared to CHF1535 (BDP/FF 200/6 pMDI)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects exhibiting no Airflow Obstruction on average over 26 weeks of treatment in the study sub-population with Airflow Obstruction status at screening</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 26 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects exhibiting on average Airflow Obstruction negative (AO-) status over 26 weeks of treatment in the study sub-population with Airflow Obstruction positive (AO+) status at screening. A subject is defined as AO+ at screening if post-bronchodilator (salbutamol) FEV1/FVC ratio is &lt; 0.7. A subject is defined as AO- during the treatment period if the mean of their 3 hour post-dose FEV1/FVC ratio collected during the treatment period is ≥ 0.7</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in pre-dose FEV1 at Week 26</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 26 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1400</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHF5993</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2 inhalations BID, Daily dose is 400/24/50 μg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHF1535</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>2 inhalations BID, Daily dose is 800/24 μg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Administration via pressurized metered dose inhaler (pMDI)</intervention_name>
    <description>Either CHF5993 or CHF1535</description>
    <arm_group_label>CHF1535</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CHF5993</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Informed consent: Subject's written informed consent obtained prior to any study&#xD;
             related procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Gender and age: Male or female subjects aged ≥ 18 and ≤ 75 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of asthma: A documented diagnosis of permanent asthma for at least 1 year&#xD;
             according to GINA recommendations (Box 1-2, GINA report 2021), and with diagnosis&#xD;
             before the subject's age of 40 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Stable asthma therapy: a stable treatment with medium dose of Inhaled corticosteroids&#xD;
             (ICS) (extrafine BDP daily dose &gt; 200 and ≤400 µg or estimated clinically comparable&#xD;
             dose, as described in GINA 2021 box 3-6) plus a long-acting ß2-agonist (LABA)&#xD;
             (formoterol 24 µg or salmeterol 100 µg or vilanterol 25 µg or other approved dose of&#xD;
             LABA as clinically comparable to the others) for at least 4 weeks prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Lung function: A pre bronchodilator FEV1 &lt; 80% of the predicted normal value, after&#xD;
             appropriate washout from bronchodilators, at the screening and randomization visits;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Reversibility of bronchoconstriction: A demonstrated increase in FEV1 &gt; 12% and &gt; 200&#xD;
             mL over baseline within 30 minutes after inhaling 400 µg of salbutamol pMDI (based on&#xD;
             ATS/ERS guidelines);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. A Post-bronchodilator FEV1/FVC ratio ≥ 0.5 within 30 minutes after inhaling 400 µg of&#xD;
             salbutamol pMDI at screening (based on ATS/ERS guidelines);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Poor Asthma control: Evidence of poorly controlled or uncontrolled asthma as based on&#xD;
             an Asthma Control Questionnaire© (ACQ-7) score ≥ 1.5 at screening and at&#xD;
             randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of exacerbations: A documented history of one or more asthma exacerbations&#xD;
             requiring treatment with systemic corticosteroids or emergency department visit or&#xD;
             inpatient hospitalization in the last 3 years prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. A cooperative attitude and ability:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  to correctly use the pMDI inhalers;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  to perform all trial related procedures including technically acceptable&#xD;
                  pulmonary function tests;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  to correctly use the e-Diary/e-Peak flow meter and home-spirometry device.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Female subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Woman of Childbearing Potential (WOCBP) fulfilling one of the following criteria:&#xD;
             i. WOCBP with fertile male partners: they and/or their partner must be willing to use&#xD;
             a highly effective birth control method from the signature of the informed consent and&#xD;
             until the follow-up call or ii. WOCBP with non-fertile male partners (contraception is&#xD;
             not required in this case).&#xD;
&#xD;
        or b. Female patient of non-childbearing potential defined as physiologically incapable of&#xD;
        becoming pregnant (i.e. post-menopausal or permanently sterile. Tubal ligation or partial&#xD;
        surgical interventions are not acceptable. If indicated, as per investigator's request,&#xD;
        post-menopausal status may be confirmed by follicle-stimulating hormone levels (according&#xD;
        to local laboratory ranges).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or lactating woman where pregnancy is defined as the state of a female after&#xD;
             conception and until termination of the gestation, confirmed by a positive pregnancy&#xD;
             test (serum pregnancy test to be performed at screening visit and urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             to be performed prior to randomization);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Run-in compliance to study drug and e-Diary completion &lt; 50% at randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of &quot;at risk&quot; asthma: History of near fatal asthma or of a past hospitalization&#xD;
             for asthma in intensive care unit which, in the judgement of the Investigator, may&#xD;
             place the subject at undue risk;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Recent exacerbation: hospitalization, emergency room admission or use of systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids for an asthma exacerbation in the 4 weeks prior to screening visit or&#xD;
             during the run-in period;&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Subjects experiencing an exacerbation during the run-in period may be&#xD;
             re-screened once, at least 4 weeks after recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Non-permanent asthma: exercise-induced, seasonal asthma (as the only asthma-related&#xD;
             diagnosis) not requiring daily asthma control medicine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects using systemic corticosteroid medication in the 4 weeks or slow release&#xD;
             corticosteroids in the 12 weeks, prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Asthma requiring use of biologics: Subjects receiving asthma treatment with an&#xD;
             injectable biologic drug such as monoclonal antibodies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Respiratory disorders other than asthma: Subjects with known respiratory disorders&#xD;
             other than asthma. This can include but is not limited to: diagnosis of COPD as&#xD;
             defined by the current guidelines (e.g. GOLD Report), known α1-antitrypsine&#xD;
             deficiency, active tuberculosis, bronchiectasis, sarcoidosis, lung fibrosis, pulmonary&#xD;
             hypertension and interstitial lung disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Lung cancer or history of lung cancer: Subjects with an active diagnosis of lung&#xD;
             cancer or a history of lung cancer;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Lung resection: Subjects with a history of lung volume resection;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Respiratory tract infection: Subjects with respiratory tract infection within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to screening or during the run-in period; Note: Subjects experiencing a&#xD;
             respiratory tract infection during the run-in period may be re-screened once, at least&#xD;
             4 weeks after recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Smoking status: Current smoker or ex-smoker with a smoking history of ≥ 10 pack-years&#xD;
             (pack-years = the number of cigarette packs per day times the number of years). Ex-&#xD;
             smokers must have stopped smoking for ≥1 year (≥ 6 months for e-cigarettes).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Cancer or history of cancer (other than lung): Subjects with active cancer or a&#xD;
             history of cancer with less than 5 years disease free survival time (whether or not&#xD;
             there is evidence of local recurrence or metastases). Localized carcinoma (e.g. basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma, in situ carcinoma of the cervix adequately treated, …) is acceptable;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Cardiovascular diseases: Subjects who have clinically significant (CS) cardiovascular&#xD;
             condition according to Investigator's judgement, such as but not limited to:&#xD;
             congestive heart failure (NYHA class IV), unstable or acute ischemic heart disease in&#xD;
             the last year prior to screening, history of sustained and non-sustained cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmias diagnosed in the last 6 months prior to screening (sustained meant lasting&#xD;
             more than 30 seconds or ending only with external action, or led to hemodynamic&#xD;
             collapse; non-sustained meant &gt; 3 beats &lt; 30 seconds, and or ending spontaneously, and&#xD;
             or asymptomatic), high degree impulse conduction blocks (&gt; 2nd degree atrioventricular&#xD;
             block type 2),persistent, long standing or paroxysmal atrial fibrillation (AF); Note:&#xD;
             Subjects with permanent AF (for at least 6 months prior screening) with a resting&#xD;
             ventricular rate &lt; 100/min, controlled with a rate control strategy (i.e. selective β&#xD;
             blocker, calcium channel blocker, pacemaker placement, digoxin or ablation therapy)&#xD;
             can be considered for enrolment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. ECG criteria: Any abnormal and clinically significant 12-lead ECG that in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion would affect efficacy or safety evaluation or place the&#xD;
             subjects at risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. ECG QTcF: Male subjects with a Fridericia's corrected QT interval (QTcF) &gt;450 msec and&#xD;
             female subjects with a QTcF &gt;470 msec at screening are not eligible (not applicable&#xD;
             for subjects with permanent atrial fibrillation and for subjects with pacemaker);&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subjects with a medical history or current diagnosis of narrow angle glaucoma,&#xD;
             symptomatic prostatic hypertrophy, urinary retention bladder neck obstruction that, in&#xD;
             the opinion of the Investigator, would prevent use of anticholinergic agents; Note:&#xD;
             Benign prostatic hyperplasia subjects who are stable under treatment can be considered&#xD;
             for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. CNS disorders: Subjects with a history of symptoms or significant neurological disease&#xD;
             such as but not limited to transient ischemic attack (TIA), stroke, seizure disorder&#xD;
             or behavioral disturbances according to the investigator's opinion;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Other medical conditions: Subjects with other severe acute or chronic medical or&#xD;
             malignancy or psychiatric condition or clinically significant laboratory abnormalities&#xD;
             indicating a significant or unstable concomitant disease, that might in the judgment&#xD;
             of the Investigator, place the subject at undue risk or potentially compromise the&#xD;
             results or interpretation of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Other concurrent diseases: Subjects with historical or current evidence of&#xD;
             uncontrolled concurrent disease such as but not limited to hyperthyroidism, diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus or other endocrine disease; hematological disease; autoimmune disorders (e.g.&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, ), gastrointestinal disorders (e..; poorly controlled peptic&#xD;
             ulcer, GERD), significant renal and hepatic impairment or other disease or condition&#xD;
             that might, in the judgement of the investigator, place the subject at undue risk or&#xD;
             potentially compromise the results or interpretation of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Liver diseases: Subjects with severe hepatitis, chronic active hepatitis or evidence&#xD;
             of uncontrolled chronic liver disease according to the investigator's opinion;&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Vaccination: Subjects who receive a vaccination within 2 weeks prior to screening or&#xD;
             during the run-in;&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subjects mentally or legally incapacitated, or subjects accommodated in an&#xD;
             establishment as a result of an official or judicial order;&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Contra-indications to IMPs: Contra-indications to IMPs constitute an exclusion&#xD;
             criterion. For warnings, eligibility will be judged by the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Alcohol/drug abuse: Subjects with a history of alcohol or drug abuse within two years&#xD;
             prior to the start of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Hypersensitivity: Subjects with known intolerance/hypersensitivity or contraindication&#xD;
             to treatment with ß2-agonists, ICS, anticholinergics or propellant gases/excipients.&#xD;
             For warnings/precaution for use, eligibility will be judged by the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Surgery: Subjects with major surgery in the 3 months prior to screening visit or&#xD;
             planned surgery during the trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Subjects treated with non-potassium sparing diuretics (unless administered as a fixed&#xD;
             dose combination [FDC] with a potassium conserving drug or changed to potassium&#xD;
             sparing before the screening), nonselective beta blocking drugs, quinidine, quinidine&#xD;
             like anti-arrhythmics, or any medication with a corrected QT interval (QTc)&#xD;
             prolongation potential or a history of QTc prolongation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Subjects treated with monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs) and tricyclic&#xD;
             anti-depressants;&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Subjects receiving any therapy that could interfere with the study drugs according to&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion;&#xD;
&#xD;
         31. Participation to investigational trial: Subjects who have received an investigational&#xD;
             drug within 2 months or six half-lives (whichever is greater) prior to screening&#xD;
             visit, or have been previously randomized in this trial, or are currently&#xD;
             participating in another clinical trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
         32. Documented COVID-19 diagnosis or its complication which has not resolved within 14&#xD;
             days prior to screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chiesi Clinical Trial Info</last_name>
    <phone>+39 0521 2791</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials_info@chiesi.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

