<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05015855</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-13268</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05015855</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing Two Models of PrEP Delivery in OBGYN Clinics</brief_title>
  <official_title>Testing Two Service Models of PrEP Delivery in OBGYN Clinics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Montefiore Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>New York State Psychiatric Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Montefiore Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The HIV Center for Clinical and Behavioral Studies, the Albert Einstein College of Medicine&#xD;
      and the Alliance for Positive Change will test two healthcare models that integrate PrEP into&#xD;
      OBGYN services. Model 1 is OBGYN-PrEP with 4 parts: (1) prioritize PrEP; (2) train providers&#xD;
      in PrEP and intervention; (3) identify PrEP-appropriate women through a risk screen; and (4)&#xD;
      monitor progress and fidelity to protocol. Model 2 is NP-PC PrEP in which PrEP provider&#xD;
      burden is shifted to a Nurse Practitioner (NP) who will use a sex-positive approach to&#xD;
      deliver PrEP services via telemedicine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Albert Einstein College of Medicine (Einstein), the HIV Center for Clinical and&#xD;
      Behavioral Studies (HIV Center), the Montefiore Medical Center Department of Obstetrics and&#xD;
      Gynecology (OBGYN, Implementing Partner) and the Alliance for Positive Change (Alliance,&#xD;
      Implementing and Community Partner) will compare two healthcare models that integrate PrEP&#xD;
      into OBGYN services. Both models are acceptable standards of care and represent&#xD;
      evidence-based approaches to the provision of care. This study is the first example of&#xD;
      comparing these interventions in a head-to-head, comparative-effectiveness model. Both groups&#xD;
      will benefit from maintained access, enhanced assessment with the PrEP screening tool, and&#xD;
      physicians will all receive an evidence-based PrEP education seminar with supporting&#xD;
      materials and ongoing access to education and resources. MODEL 1, OBGYN-PrEP is based on&#xD;
      PC4PrEP (R01MH107297) that has four steps: announce the policy that PrEP counseling is the&#xD;
      responsibility of OBGYN providers to address the &quot;purview paradox&quot;; train providers to manage&#xD;
      patients on PrEP; use a screening tool to identify women appropriate for PrEP; and&#xD;
      implementation coaching to monitor and encourage PrEP counseling. The goal is that PrEP be&#xD;
      provided by a trusted provider with whom the patient has an ongoing relationship. In MODEL 2,&#xD;
      NP-PC PrEP, all the same provisions and practices present in Model 1 will be present however,&#xD;
      a telehealth opportunity with a Nurse Practitioner (NP) will be provided. A skilled and&#xD;
      PrEP-trained NP will deliver PrEP services via telemedicine visits&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 16, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Uptake of PrEP</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>We will compare the patients in the NP-PC PrEP and OBGYN-PrEP arms on number of PrEP prescriptions written per 100 patients. The proportion of prescriptions written for PrEP eligible patients will be compared between the two groups (NP-PC vs OBGYN) via chi-square test.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability will be assessed through qualitative in-depth interviews (IDIs) with OBGYN providers and PCs at Alliance at the end of the interventions to identify factors that facilitate or hinder the implementation of the intervention and to assess its acceptability. We will also conduct IDIs with 10 patients in each intervention arm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Hiv</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OBGYN-PrEP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>OBGYN-PrEP has 4 parts: (1) prioritize PrEP; (2) train providers in PrEP and intervention; (3) identify PrEP-appropriate women through a risk screen; and (4) monitor progress and fidelity to protocol.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NP-PC PrEP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NP-PC PrEP incorporates the standard of care and practices in OBGYN-PrEP but enhances access to additional skilled providers, as the PrEP provider burden is shifted to a Nurse Practitioner (NP) who will use a sexpositive approach to deliver PrEP services via telemedicine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NP-PC PrEP</intervention_name>
    <description>All participating providers will be provided standard education around PrEP and HIV prevention, but half of the providers will be randomized to also partner with a nurse practitioner who will provide additional consultation to patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NP-PC PrEP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OBGYN-PrEP</intervention_name>
    <description>OBGYN-PrEP is based on PC4PrEP (R01MH107297) that has four steps: announce the policy that PrEP counseling is the responsibility of OBGYN providers to address the &quot;purview paradox&quot;; train providers to manage patients on PrEP; use a screening tool to identify women appropriate for PrEP; and implementation coaching to monitor and encourage PrEP counseling</description>
    <arm_group_label>OBGYN-PrEP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥18 years of age Female (biological female at birth) Ability to speak and read English&#xD;
             or Spanish Patient at Montefiore Medical Center, Eastchester Professional Center&#xD;
             (EPC). No gross evidence of cognitive impairment precluding consent and participation&#xD;
             Willing to have interview digitally recorded&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt;18 years of age Not a female (biological female at birth)- We have excluded&#xD;
             transgender women because their sexual and reproductive health issues and PrEP use&#xD;
             differ from those of biological females. Does not speak English or Spanish Not a&#xD;
             patient at Montefiore Medical Center, Eastchester Professional Center (EPC). Gross&#xD;
             evidence of cognitive impairment precluding consent and participation Not willing to&#xD;
             have interview digitally recorded&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jessica Atrio, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10461</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>PrEP</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

