<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05017571</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000235</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000235-CH</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05017571</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Colchicine to Suppress Inflammation and Improve Insulin Resistance in Adults and Adolescents With Obesity</brief_title>
  <official_title>COLSIO Trial: Phase II Randomized, Controlled Trial of Colchicine to Suppress Inflammation and Improve Insulin Resistance in Adults and Adolescents With Obesity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      About 40 percent of adults and 20 percent of adolescents in the U.S. have a body mass index&#xD;
      over 30 kg/m2. Being overweight may lead to a state of low-level inflammation. This may cause&#xD;
      health problems. Researchers want to see if an anti-inflammatory medicine can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn if colchicine can improve metabolism in people who have high body weight, increased&#xD;
      inflammation, and high insulin in the blood but who have not yet developed high blood sugar.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People aged 12 and older with high body weight who may have increased inflammation and high&#xD;
      insulin in the blood. Healthy adult volunteers are also needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fasting blood tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electrocardiogram&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dual energy x-ray absorptiometry (They will lie on a table while a camera passes over their&#xD;
      body.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stool sample and 24-hour food diary (optional)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 3 study visits and 3 phone check-ins. At visits, they will repeat some&#xD;
      screening tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy volunteers will have the baseline visit only. They will not get the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the baseline visit, participants will have an Oral Glucose Tolerance Test (OGTT). For&#xD;
      this, they will drink a sweet liquid and then give blood samples. They will get a 12-week&#xD;
      supply of the study drug or placebo to take daily by mouth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have study visits 6 weeks and 12 weeks after they started taking the study&#xD;
      drug. At the 12-week visit, they will repeat the OGTT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last for 3 (Omega) to 4 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Obesity affects more than 40% of the adult U.S. population plus approximately 20% of&#xD;
      adolescents and is a major risk factor for the development of type 2 diabetes and&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease. Mouse models and human data suggest that obesity-induced chronic&#xD;
      inflammation is one mechanism promoting obesity-associated comorbid conditions. In obesity,&#xD;
      innate immunity is activated when circulating molecules such as fatty acids and cholesterol&#xD;
      crystals bind to nucleotide-binding oligomerization (NOD)-like receptor family, pyrin domain&#xD;
      containing 3 (NLRP3) receptors. The resultant inflammatory cascade leads to insulin&#xD;
      resistance and decreased pancreatic beta-cell reserve. It has been proposed that the&#xD;
      suppression of this chronic low-level inflammatory state may impede the onset of diabetes and&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent studies have shown colchicine, a potent microtubule inhibitor that is approved for use&#xD;
      in the treatment of gout and some rare inflammatory conditions in adults and children,&#xD;
      disrupts intracellular NLRP3 inflammasome assembly. As there are limited medical therapies&#xD;
      proven effective to improve obesity-related metabolic dysregulation, we propose to determine&#xD;
      the efficacy of colchicine 0.6 mg versus placebo once daily in non-diabetic adults and&#xD;
      adolescents with obesity, insulin resistance, and inflammation (elevated high-sensitivity&#xD;
      C-reactive protein concentrations). From among up to 500 individuals screened, we will&#xD;
      conduct a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial of colchicine in up to 200&#xD;
      adults. We will also obtain pilot data from 40 adolescents studied in the same randomized&#xD;
      fashion. This study will determine the effects of colchicine on insulin resistance and beta&#xD;
      cell reserve in adults with obesity and allow determination of the sample size needed to&#xD;
      conduct an adequately powered study of the effects of colchicine in adolescents. An&#xD;
      Evaluation-Only control group of up to 50 adults who do not meet entry criteria for the&#xD;
      randomized clinical trial will also be studied with baseline tests only.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 8, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Homeostatic model assessment of insulin resistance (HOMA-IR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>HOMA-IR is calculated from fasting (f) insulin (I) and glucose (G): Gf (in mg/dL) x If in ( (Micro)IU/mL/ 405).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in fasting serum insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting serum insulin</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in fasting serum glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting serum glucose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in High-Sensitivity C-Reactive Protein</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>High-Sensitivity C-Reactive Protein</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Matsuda Index</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>(10^4/([Gf x 18] x If x [mean GOSTTx18] x mean I-OSTT)0.5), where Gf is fasting glucose, If is fasting insulin, and I-OSTT is mean insulin from oral sugar tolerance test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Insulin Resistance</condition>
  <condition>Inflammation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults no obesity, insulin resistance, or inflammation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults without obesity, insulin resistance or inflammation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults with obesity, but no insulin resistance/inflammation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults with obesity, but without insulin resistance or inflammation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine - Adolescents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adolescents given Colchicine 0.6 mg per day (1 capsule per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine - Adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults given Colchicine 0.6 mg per day (1 capsule per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo - Adolescents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adolescents given Placebo (1 capsule per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo - Adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults given Placebo (1 capsule per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colchicine</intervention_name>
    <description>Colchicine 1 capsule (0.6 mg) per day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine - Adolescents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine - Adults</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo 1 capsule per day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo - Adolescents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo - Adults</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All races/ethnicities and people of all genders are eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants who will be randomized to colchicine or placebo must meet all of the following&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Good general health. In general subjects should take no medications. The use of&#xD;
             over-the-counter and prescription medications will be reviewed on a case-by-case&#xD;
             basis; depending on the medication, subjects who have continued to take prescription&#xD;
             medication or have stopped taking an exclusionary medication for at least 3 months&#xD;
             prior to study entry may be still eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age &gt;= 18y for adults; age 12y to &lt;18y for adolescents&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Obesity BMI &gt;= 30 kg/m2 (adults) or BMI &gt;= 95th percentile for age and sex per Centers&#xD;
             for Disease Control Standards (adolescents)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Weight &lt;= 450 lbs (204.5 kg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For females of reproductive potential: use of highly effective contraception for at&#xD;
             least 1 month prior to screening and agreement to use such a method during study&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. HOMA-IR &gt;= 2.6 mg/L, calculated as fasting glucose (in mg/dL) x insulin in&#xD;
             (microIU/mL/ 405). Our goal is to enroll participants who have pre-existing insulin&#xD;
             resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. hsCRP &gt;= 2.0 mg/L. We aim to recruit participants with increased baseline level of&#xD;
             inflammation. Individuals with hsCRP above 2.0 mg/L have been shown to have an&#xD;
             increased risk for cardiovascular events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willing to be randomized (willing and able to give consent/assent as required for&#xD;
             randomized study).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants who will be evaluated but are not eligible for randomization (Evaluation Only&#xD;
        Arm) must meet all of the following Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Good general health. In general subjects should take no medications. The use of&#xD;
             over-the-counter and prescription medications will be reviewed on a case-by-case&#xD;
             basis; depending on the medication, subjects who have continued to take prescription&#xD;
             medication or have stopped taking an exclusionary medication for at least 3 months&#xD;
             prior to study entry may still be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age &gt;= 18y&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. BMI &gt;= 18 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Weight &lt;= 450 lbs (204.5 kg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For females of reproductive potential: use of highly effective contraception for at&#xD;
             least 1 month prior to screening and agreement to use such a method during study&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing and able to provide consent for Evaluation-Only study&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All individuals meeting any of the exclusion criteria at screening or baseline will be&#xD;
        excluded from study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for subject randomized to colchicine or placebo:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals with significant medical comorbidities (e.g. NYHA Class III or IV heart&#xD;
             failure, or CKD Stage 3b or worse (eGFR &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73 m2), or American Society of&#xD;
             Anesthesiologists Physical Status Class 3 or above) or other serious disorders at the&#xD;
             discretion of the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. HbA1c &gt; 7.0%&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Type 2 diabetes mellitus, as determined by either having:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. clear clinical diagnosis of diabetes, such as a patient in a hyperglycemic crisis&#xD;
                  or classic symptoms of hyperglycemia and a random plasma glucose &gt;= 200 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. two of the following three:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. fasting plasma glucose &gt;= 126 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Hemoglobin A1c &gt;= 6.5%&#xD;
&#xD;
             iii. An oral glucose tolerance test glucose concentration of &gt;= 200 mg/dL at 2 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
             c. one of the above three criteria (bi.-biii.) meeting the T2DM cutoff on two&#xD;
             different days.&#xD;
&#xD;
             If only one of the above three criteria (bi.-biii.) meet the T2DM threshold during the&#xD;
             Screening Visit, that test will be repeated on another day to determine if the subject&#xD;
             has T2DM or not. As per ADA guidelines, The diagnosis [of T2DM] is made on the basis&#xD;
             of the confirmed test.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Moreover, because HbA1c has been shown to be higher in African Americans (AA) as&#xD;
             compared to other races for the same glycemia, AA who do not have diabetes may be&#xD;
             unfairly excluded by their HbA1c alone 96-98. Therefore, for AA subjects, if their&#xD;
             fasting glucose is in the non-diabetes range, and the HbA1c is &lt; 7.0%, we will&#xD;
             consider them not to have diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Recent or regular use of colchicine, anorexiant, or diabetic medications in the last 3&#xD;
             months, or plan to start in the following 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Recent or regular use of anti-inflammatory medications (e.g. prednisone, NSAIDs) in&#xD;
             the last 7 days, or plan to start in the following 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Current use of a strong or moderate CYP3A4 inhibitor or P-glycoprotein (P-gp), as this&#xD;
             may cause a significant increase in colchicine plasma concentrations and risk for side&#xD;
             effects. Oral contraceptive use will be permitted, provided the contraceptive has been&#xD;
             used for at least two months before starting study medication. The use of&#xD;
             over-the-counter and prescription medications will be reviewed on a case-by-case&#xD;
             basis; depending on the medication, subjects who have continued to take prescription&#xD;
             medication or have stopped taking an exclusionary medication for at least 3 months&#xD;
             prior to study entry may be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Known allergy to colchicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Previous history of agranulocytosis, gout, or significant myositis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Females who are pregnant, planning to become pregnant, currently nursing an infant, or&#xD;
             have irregular menses, defined as cycles less than 21 days or greater than 45 days in&#xD;
             premenopausal women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Individuals who have current substance abuse or a DSM 5 Axis I psychiatric disorder or&#xD;
             DSM Axis II Mental Retardation diagnosis that in the opinion of the investigators&#xD;
             would impede competence, compliance, or participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current users of tobacco or nicotine (e.g. nicotine patch, e-cigarettes) products.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participation in a formal weight loss program (e.g. Weight Watchers) or recent weight&#xD;
             change of more than 3% of body weight in the past two months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for subjects who are evaluated but not eligible for randomization&#xD;
        (Evaluation Only Arm):&#xD;
&#xD;
        We will use the same exclusion criteria as employed for randomized participants (see&#xD;
        above).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jack A Yanovski, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sheila M Brady, C.R.N.P.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-3783</phone>
    <email>sb575j@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000235-CH.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demidowich AP, Davis AI, Dedhia N, Yanovski JA. Colchicine to decrease NLRP3-activated inflammation and improve obesity-related metabolic dysregulation. Med Hypotheses. 2016 Jul;92:67-73. doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2016.04.039. Epub 2016 Apr 25.</citation>
    <PMID>27241260</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demidowich AP, Levine JA, Apps R, Cheung FK, Chen J, Fantoni G; CHI Consortium, Patel TP, Yanovski JA. Colchicine's effects on metabolic and inflammatory molecules in adults with obesity and metabolic syndrome: results from a pilot randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes (Lond). 2020 Aug;44(8):1793-1799. doi: 10.1038/s41366-020-0598-3. Epub 2020 May 27.</citation>
    <PMID>32461554</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demidowich AP, Levine JA, Onyekaba GI, Khan SM, Chen KY, Brady SM, Broadney MM, Yanovski JA. Effects of colchicine in adults with metabolic syndrome: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019 Jul;21(7):1642-1651. doi: 10.1111/dom.13702. Epub 2019 Apr 2.</citation>
    <PMID>30869182</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 16, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>comorbidities</keyword>
  <keyword>Microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>C-Reactive Protein</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colchicine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

