<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03077542</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>170069</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>17-H-0069</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03077542</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nonmyeloablative Haploidentical Peripheral Blood Mobilized Hematopoietic Precursor Cell Transplantation for Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Nonmyeloablative Haploidentical Peripheral Blood Mobilized Hematopoietic Precursor Cell Transplantation for Sickle Cell Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peripheral blood stem cell transplantation procedures are used for people with sickle cell&#xD;
      disease. Researchers want to improve the success and reduce the complications for these&#xD;
      procedures. This might allow more people to have a transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see if a new transplant regime is effective, safe and well tolerated in people with sickle&#xD;
      cell disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults at least 18 years old with sickle cell disease and certain complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A relative who is a half tissue match.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with medical history, physical exam, and blood tests.&#xD;
      Recipients will also have:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heart, lung, and mental health tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Chest x-rays&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bone marrow taken from the pelvic bone&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Eyes and teeth checked&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recipients will have a large central line inserted into a vein for up to 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Donors will have their veins tested and have an IV inserted for 1 day or on rare occasions 2&#xD;
      days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Donors will get a drug to activate bone marrow. It will be injected for about 6 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Donors will have at least 1 five-hour procedure where bone marrow stem cells will be&#xD;
      collected. Blood will be taken from a vein in one arm or in rare cases from a groin vein and&#xD;
      put through a machine. Some blood will be saved and the rest will be returned. Stem cells&#xD;
      will be taken from the saved blood in a lab and frozen until ready to give to the recipient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recipients will have:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Stems cells collected and frozen&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hygiene lessons&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bone density scans&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low-dose radiation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Drugs for their immune system&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Donor cells infused through their central line&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Transfusions&#xD;
&#xD;
      After about 30 days, recipients will leave the hospital. They must stay near NIH for 3 months&#xD;
      after the transplant and have frequent visits. After returning home, they will have 8 visits&#xD;
      over 5 years, then be contacted yearly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nonmyeloablative allogeneic peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) transplants are currently being&#xD;
      investigated in phase I/II trials assessing engraftment, efficacy, and toxicity at a number&#xD;
      of transplant centers. Our ongoing protocol for patients with severe congenital anemias,&#xD;
      particularly sickle cell disease (SCD), and an HLA-matched sibling donor has had excellent&#xD;
      preliminary results. None of the patients who engrafted had sickle-related events or any&#xD;
      evidence of graft versus host disease (GVHD). There was no significant toxicity associated&#xD;
      with the conditioning regimen. An additional protocol is ongoing for patients with high risk&#xD;
      of graft rejection which employs pentostatin and oral cyclophosphamide (PC) pre-transplant to&#xD;
      further deplete recipient lymphocytes in an attempt to decrease the rate of graft rejection.&#xD;
      Four of 4 patients transplanted remain free of SCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our main limitation has been a lack of HLA-matched sibling donors in the majority of&#xD;
      patients. We performed a study in which patients with severe SCD who lacked a suitable donor&#xD;
      underwent a search for a matched unrelated donor or umbilical cord donor. The vast majority&#xD;
      of patients were not found to have an appropriate alternative donor. We therefore seek to&#xD;
      develop a safe nonmyeloablative regimen to be applied to the haploidentical setting so that&#xD;
      family members can serve as donors and greatly expand the donor pool.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We developed a nonmyeloablative haploidentical PBSC transplant protocol which included 3&#xD;
      cohorts, with stopping rules built in for regimen failure, defined as graft rejection or&#xD;
      severe GVHD. All included 400 cGy total body irradiation (TBI) in divided doses 1 and 2 days&#xD;
      prior to transplant, alemtuzumab, and sirolimus. The first cohort included no&#xD;
      cyclophosphamide. The 2nd included one dose of cyclophosphamide given at 50mg/kg on day 3&#xD;
      post-transplant, and the 3rd included 100mg/kg cyclophosphamide given in divided doses on&#xD;
      days 3 and 4 post-transplant. The engraftment rate and percentage of patients who remained&#xD;
      free of SCD improved with each successive cohort. However, the graft rejection rate in the&#xD;
      3rd cohort remained high at 50%. To attempt to reduce the rate of graft rejection in the&#xD;
      haploidentical setting, this protocol will add PC to the conditioning regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this protocol, we propose PBSC transplantation in patients with SCD considered at high&#xD;
      risk for complications from or ineligible for standard bone marrow transplantation, with&#xD;
      allogeneic peripheral blood stem cells from a haploidentical donor using a novel&#xD;
      immunosuppressive regimen without myeloablation in an attempt to further decrease the&#xD;
      transplant-related morbidity/mortality. The low intensity nonmyeloablative conditioning&#xD;
      regimen will consist of a relatively low radiation dose for therapeutic radiation,&#xD;
      Alemtuzumab (Campath ), Sirolimus (Rapamune ), Cyclophosphamide (Cytoxan ), and pentostatin&#xD;
      (Nipent ) as a strategy to provide adequate immunosuppression to allow sufficient engraftment&#xD;
      for clinical remission with a lower risk of GVHD development. T-cell replete, donor-derived,&#xD;
      granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF)- mobilized PBSC will be used to establish&#xD;
      hematopoietic and lymphoid reconstitution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint of this study is the percentage of patients at 100 days post-transplant&#xD;
      who have not rejected their grafts, and who are without severe GVHD (defined as grade 3 and&#xD;
      higher acute GVHD and moderate to severe chronic GVHD). Other endpoints include degree of&#xD;
      donor-host chimerism necessary for long-term graft survival and disease amelioration,&#xD;
      incidence of acute and chronic GVHD, incidence of graft rejection, transplant-related&#xD;
      morbidity, as well as disease-free and overall survival.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Adverse event reported to DSMB&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of patients at 100 days (+/- 1 week) post-transplantwith sustained donor type hemoglobin on hemoglobin electrophoresis (HbS less than 50% when donors have sickle cell trait and &lt;10% when donors have normal hemoglobin), who d...</measure>
    <time_frame>100 days post transplant</time_frame>
    <description>The absence of graft rejection and no severe GVHD</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chimeric Status of Recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>+30, +60, +100, 6months, 12 months, 18months, 24months annually</time_frame>
    <description>The level of chimerism required to maintain both graft survival as well as hematologic normalcy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">43</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>recipient</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>haploidentical stem cell transplant</intervention_name>
    <description>haploidentical stem cell transplant</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sirolimus</intervention_name>
    <description>conditioning regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>campath</intervention_name>
    <description>conditioning regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pentostatin</intervention_name>
    <description>conditioning regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cyclophosphamide</intervention_name>
    <description>conditioning regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxyurea</intervention_name>
    <description>conditioning regimen</description>
    <arm_group_label>recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA-RECIPIENTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with any type of sickle cell disease who are at high risk for disease-related&#xD;
        morbidity or mortality, defined by having severe end-organ damage (A, B, or C) or&#xD;
        potentially modifiable complication(s) not ameliorated by hydroxyurea (D):&#xD;
&#xD;
        A. Stroke defined as a clinically significant neurologic event that is accompanied by an&#xD;
        infarct or hemorrhage on cerebral MRI or cerebral arteriopathy requiring chronic&#xD;
        transfusion therapy; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        B. Tricuspid regurgitant jet velocity (TRV) of greater than or equal to 2.5 m/s at baseline&#xD;
        (without vaso-occlusive crisis) and/or pulmonary hypertension; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        C. Sickle hepatopathy defined as either ferritin &gt;1000 mcg/L and platelet count &lt;&#xD;
        250,000/uL (without vaso-occlusive crisis) OR direct bilirubin &gt; 0.4 mg/dL and platelet&#xD;
        count &lt;250,000/uL (without vaso-occlusive crisis)&#xD;
&#xD;
        D. Any one of the below complications:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complication-Vaso-occlusive crises; Eligible for HSCT-Recurrent vaso-occlusive pain&#xD;
             crises (at least 2 per year for the last 2 years) despite hydroxyurea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complication-Acute chest syndrome; Eligible for HSCT-any ACS while on hydroxyurea.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-disease specific:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A. Age greater than or equal to 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        B. Haploidentical relative donor available&#xD;
&#xD;
        C. Ability to comprehend and willing to sign an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        D. Negative serum beta-HCG&#xD;
&#xD;
        E. Ejection fraction greater than or equal to 35%&#xD;
&#xD;
        F. Glomerular filtration rate &gt;60 mL/min/1.73m^2 by cystatin C-based or iothalamate-based&#xD;
        or other equivalent GFR testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        G. Adjusted DLCO greater than or equal to 35%&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA RECIPIENT: (any of the following would exclude the subject from&#xD;
        participating)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Available 6/6 HLA-matched sibling donor&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECOG performance status of 3 or more (See Appendix A)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infections (currently taking&#xD;
             medication and progression of clinical symptoms) within one month prior to starting&#xD;
             the conditioning regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with fever or suspected minor infection should await resolution of symptoms&#xD;
             before starting the conditioning regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Major anticipated illness or organ failure incompatible with survival from PBSC&#xD;
             transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Donor specific anti-HLA antibodies (DSAs) greater than or equal to 2000 Mean&#xD;
             Fluorescence Intensity (MFI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients seronegative for EBV who have EBV seropositive donors&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA-DONOR:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Haploidentical relative donor deemed suitable and eligible, and willing to donate, per&#xD;
        clinical evaluations who are additionally willing to donate blood for research. Related&#xD;
        donors will be evaluated in accordance with existing Standard NIH Policies and Procedures&#xD;
        for determination of eligibility and suitability for clinical donation. Note that&#xD;
        participation in this study is offered to all related donors, but is not required for a do&#xD;
        le that not all related donors will enroll onto this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA-DONOR:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Courtney D Fitzhugh, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2017-H-0069.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 10, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 10, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 13, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Peripheral Blood Stem Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Host-Donor Chimerism</keyword>
  <keyword>Graft Versus Host Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Haploidentical</keyword>
  <keyword>Donor Apheresis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydroxyurea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pentostatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

