<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03074474</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TB2016.01.01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03074474</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ventral Hernia Study Using OviTex Reinforced Bioscaffold</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Single Arm, Multi-center Study Evaluating the Short-term Clinical Outcomes of Ventral Hernias Treated With OviTex Reinforced Bioscaffold.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tela Bio Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tela Bio Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to demonstrate that the use of OviTex® 1S material for a ventral hernia&#xD;
      repair leads to the same or a lower percentage of early post-operative complications and true&#xD;
      hernia recurrences when compared to other types of available meshes. 100 subjects will be&#xD;
      included from 5-7 participating investigator sites. Within 30 days prior to the hernia repair&#xD;
      surgery, a baseline visit will be performed during which the patient's eligibility for the&#xD;
      study will be evaluated. The surgical technique used for the repair will be determined by the&#xD;
      investigator/surgeon. Additional study data will be collected during the hospital stay, 30&#xD;
      and 90 days post-operatively and 12 and 24 months post-operatively. At the follow up visits,&#xD;
      the surgical site will be evaluated by the surgeon, both the surgeon and patient will be&#xD;
      asked to rate their satisfaction with the repair and the subject will be asked to complete&#xD;
      two Quality of Life questionnaires.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is intended to evaluate the post-operative complications and re-herniations&#xD;
      following the use of OviTex® Permanent 1S reinforced bioscaffold in subjects with ventral&#xD;
      hernias. The study is designed to mirror surgical standard of care for ventral hernia&#xD;
      intervention, with the exception of asking for subjects to return for evaluation at longer&#xD;
      time points post-surgery than is typical for standard care. A baseline visit will be&#xD;
      performed for patients who are identified for and provide informed consent to participate in&#xD;
      the study. During this visit, a review of medical history, a physical exam and assessment of&#xD;
      the hernia site will be performed. The potential subject will also be asked to complete two&#xD;
      quality of life surveys; one that is disease specific and one that is a standard method of&#xD;
      health assessment. On the day of surgery, the ventral hernia will be repaired with the use of&#xD;
      OviTex® 1S reinforced bioscaffold. Perioperative data will be collected and the surgeon will&#xD;
      provide an assessment of the product's handling qualities. During the course of the hospital&#xD;
      stay, the subject will be assessed for incidence of early post-operative surgical site wound&#xD;
      events and complications, all necessary medical interventions and/or re-operations. On the&#xD;
      day of discharge, surgical site occurrences or wound related events noted at the hernia&#xD;
      repair site and the occurrence of other post-operative complications will be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Day 30 and Day 90 visits will have a visit window of +/- 2 weeks. At these visits, the&#xD;
      incidence of late surgical site occurrences or wound related events noted at the hernia&#xD;
      repair site will be assessed. If hernia recurrence is suspected, it will be confirmed via&#xD;
      diagnostic imaging with a CT scan. The occurrence of other late post-operative complications&#xD;
      will also be assessed. The subjects will be asked to complete the same disease specific&#xD;
      questionnaire and the same health assessment questionnaire as was done at the Baseline visit,&#xD;
      however the subject will also be asked to complete a pain assessment. Both the surgeon and&#xD;
      the subject will provide an assessment of his/her satisfaction with the hernia repair. The&#xD;
      activities at Months 12 and 24 mirror those of Days 30 and 90, however the visit window is&#xD;
      extended to +/- 4 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 24, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 3, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of early post-operative surgical site occurrences or wound related events occurring at the hernia repair site.</measure>
    <time_frame>within the first three months of the ventral hernia repair</time_frame>
    <description>events such as ileus, deep or superficial wound infection, seroma, hematoma, wound dehiscence, skin necrosis, fistula etc..</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of other early post-operative complications.</measure>
    <time_frame>within the first three months of the ventral hernia repair</time_frame>
    <description>This would include complications such as ileus, bowel obstruction, fistula etc..</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of later post-operative surgical site occurrences or wound related events noted at the hernia repair site.</measure>
    <time_frame>occurring greater than 3 months after the surgery</time_frame>
    <description>This would include events such as ileus, deep or superficial wound infection, serum, hematoma, wound dehiscence, skin necrosis, fistulae, bulging etc..</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of other later post-operative complications.</measure>
    <time_frame>occurring greater than 3 months after the surgery</time_frame>
    <description>This would include complications such as ileus, bowel obstruction, fistula etc..</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Reported Outcomes compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at Day 30, Day 90, Month 12 and Month 24</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Life and Pain Assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>True hernia recurrence at the surgery site</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at post-operative Day 90 and Months 12 and 24</time_frame>
    <description>Suspected hernia recurrence confirmed via CT scan</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Hernia, Ventral</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OviTex Permanent 1S</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects included in this post-market study will have a ventral hernia repaired with OviTex Permanent 1S reinforced bioscaffold.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OviTex Permanent 1S</intervention_name>
    <description>OviTex 1S is a reinforced bioscaffold consisting of layers of extra-cellular matrix derived from sheep stomachs. The layers are embroidered together with a monofilament polypropylene. One side of the mesh has blue polypropylene stitching, which provides a surface conducive to native tissue growth. The other side of the mesh is a smooth surface intended to minimize tissue attachment (adhesions).</description>
    <arm_group_label>OviTex Permanent 1S</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject suffers from an uncomplicated ventral hernia that requires surgical repair&#xD;
             (open, laparoscopic, or robotic) with the use of an implant to reinforce or replace&#xD;
             weakened or missing tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The size of the implant needed for repair is expected to be 18 x 22 cm, 20 x 20 cm or&#xD;
             less.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject meets CDC/SSI Wound Classification Class I (Clean) or Class II&#xD;
             (Clean-Contaminated) criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing and able to sign an informed consent for the study and has signed&#xD;
             the IRB approved Informed Consent form for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is able to complete Quality of Life (QoL) and pain Questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is at least 18 years old (or considered an adult per state law).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is able to participate fully in, and for the full duration of, the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a BMI of &gt; 40.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject meets CDC/SSI Wound Classification Class IV(Dirty-Infected) criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is female and is pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a life expectancy of &lt; 2 years making it unlikely that the subject will&#xD;
             successfully achieve two-year follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has recent history of drug or alcohol abuse (in last 3 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has an allergy to ovine-derived products.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has participated in another clinical trial within the past 30 days or is&#xD;
             currently involved in another clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is unable to receive OviTex® Permanent 1S reinforced bioscaffold at the time&#xD;
             of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Intra-operative Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject requires implant that exceeds 18 x 22 cm or 20 x 20 cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject unable to receive OviTex® Permanent 1S reinforced bioscaffold at time of&#xD;
             surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>George DeNoto, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Saint Francis Memorial Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Scripps Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarasota Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sarasota</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Luke's Hospital South</name>
      <address>
        <city>Overland Park</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Capital Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trenton</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08638</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Francis Hosptial</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roslyn</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11576</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Comanche County Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lawton</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73505</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 3, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 3, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>use of mesh</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernia, Ventral</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

