<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02035124</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCRI GU 79</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02035124</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cabazitaxel and BKM120 in Patients With Metastatic Castrate-Resistant Prostate Cancer (mCRPC) Previously Treated With Docetaxel</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cabazitaxel With BKM120 in Patients With Metastatic Castrate-Resistant Prostate Cancer Following Treatment With Docetaxel: Phase II Study With Safety Lead-in Cohort</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Although there have been advances in the treatment of patients with metastatic&#xD;
      castrate-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC), all patients eventually develop resistance to&#xD;
      available therapy. Docetaxel is the accepted first-line agent followed by cabazitaxel in the&#xD;
      post-docetaxel phase. In this study the investigators propose to evaluate BKM120, a PI3K&#xD;
      inhibitor, with cabazitaxel in the treatment of patients with advanced prostate cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be conducted in two parts. In a lead-in cohort, the feasibility and safety of&#xD;
      administering BKM120 with a standard dose of cabazitaxel will be assessed. If safety is&#xD;
      confirmed, a subsequent Phase II portion will assess the activity of the combination in&#xD;
      patients with mCRPC previously treated with docetaxel. The treatment will consist of 3-week&#xD;
      (21-day) cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ultimate purpose of this study will be to determine progression-free survival, response&#xD;
      rate, disease control rate and overall survival of patients treated with the combination&#xD;
      regimen and compare outcomes to historical results with single-agent cabazitaxel.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study withdrawn due to slow accrual. No patients were enrolled.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>April 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Subjects with Serious and Non-Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the optimal dose and safety of BKM120 given with cabazitaxel to patients with metastatic castrate-resistant prostate cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6 weeks, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>time to disease progression</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6 weeks, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of complete responders (CR) or partial responders (PR) among patients evaluable for response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time from first treatment until death from any cause using Kaplan-Meier methods.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BKM120 and Cabazitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BKM 120 orally once daily;&#xD;
Cabazitaxel 25 mg/m2 IV every 3 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BKM 120</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>BKM120 and Cabazitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BKM 120 (Buparlisib)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabazitaxel</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>BKM120 and Cabazitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Jevtana</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adenocarcinoma of the prostate confirmed histologically.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Metastatic disease confirmed by biopsy or imaging studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must have received treatment with docetaxel as the only previous chemotherapy&#xD;
             regimen. In addition, previous treatment with hormonal agents and/or immune therapy is&#xD;
             allowed (e.g., abiraterone). (Previous treatment with MDV3100 will also be allowed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must be castrate-resistant (i.e. developed progression of metastases&#xD;
             following surgical castration or during medical androgen ablation therapy) with&#xD;
             documented castrate levels of testosterone (&lt;50 ng/dl).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients receiving medical castration therapy with gonadotropin-releasing hormone&#xD;
             (GnRH) analogues should continue this treatment during this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) score of 0 to 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient must have progressive metastatic prostate cancer by at least 1 of the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Soft tissue disease progression defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid&#xD;
                  Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bone scan progression defined by 2 or more new lesions on bone scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prostate specific antigen (PSA) progression is determined by a minimum of three&#xD;
                  rising PSA levels with an interval of ≥1 week between each determination. The&#xD;
                  screening PSA measurement (documenting progression) must be ≥2 ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Screening PSA ≥2 ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate hematologic, renal and hepatic function:&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate serum chemistries.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Ability to swallow and retain oral medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Life expectancy of ≥6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients must be ≥18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients entering this study must be willing to provide tissue from a previous tumor&#xD;
             biopsy or 15 unstained slides (if available) for correlative testing. If tissue is not&#xD;
             available, a patient will still be eligible for enrollment into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Ability to understand the nature of this study and give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous treatment with PI3K inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known hypersensitivity to BKM120 or polysorbate-80 or any of the excipients or&#xD;
             taxanes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Use of an investigational drug ≤21 days or 5 half-lives (whichever is shorter) prior&#xD;
             to the first dose of BKM120. For investigational drugs for which 5 half-lives is ≤21&#xD;
             days, a minimum of 10 days between termination of the investigational drug and&#xD;
             administration of BKM120 is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous chemotherapy with any agent other than docetaxel. All patients must be ≥28&#xD;
             days after their most recent chemotherapy and have recovered from side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient has received wide field radiotherapy (including therapeutic radioisotopes such&#xD;
             as strontium 89) ≤28 days or limited field radiation for palliation ≤7 days prior to&#xD;
             starting study drug or has not recovered from side effects of such therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Major surgical procedures ≤28 days of beginning study drug, or minor surgical&#xD;
             procedures ≤7 days. No waiting required following port-a-cath placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Clinical significant peripheral neuropathy (defined as CTCAE v4.0 Grade ≥2) regardless&#xD;
             of causality.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Mood disorders as judged by the Investigator or a Psychiatrist, or who meets the&#xD;
             cut-off score of ≥12 in the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ)-9 or a cut-off score of&#xD;
             ≥ 15 in the Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD)-7 mood scale, respectively, or selects&#xD;
             a positive response of '1, 2, or 3' to question 9 regarding potential for suicidal&#xD;
             thoughts in the PHQ-9 (independent of the total score or the PHQ-9)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  anxiety or depression ≥ Grade 3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  medically documented history of or active major depressive episode, bipolar&#xD;
                  disorder (I or II), obsessive-compulsive disorder, schizophrenia, a history of&#xD;
                  suicidal attempt or ideation, or homicidal ideation, or patients with active&#xD;
                  severe personality disorders (defined according to DSM- IV) are not eligible.&#xD;
                  Note: for patients with psychotropic treatments ongoing at baseline, the dose and&#xD;
                  the schedule should not be modified&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Previously untreated brain metastases. Patients who have received radiation or surgery&#xD;
             for brain metastases are eligible if there is no evidence of central nervous system&#xD;
             (CNS) disease progression, and at least 28 days (4 weeks) have elapsed since&#xD;
             treatment. Patients are not permitted to receive enzyme inducing anti-epileptic drugs&#xD;
             (EIAEDs) during the study and should not be receiving chronic corticosteroid therapy&#xD;
             for CNS metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Leptomeningeal metastases or spinal cord compression due to disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Acute or chronic liver, renal disease or pancreatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus. Type II diabetics are eligible if they require only&#xD;
             oral hypoglycemic agents and fasting blood glucose level is ≤120. Type I diabetics are&#xD;
             eligible if HbAlc is &lt;8.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Presence of active gastrointestinal (GI) disease or other condition that will&#xD;
             interfere significantly with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of&#xD;
             oral therapy (e.g. ulcerative disease, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea Grade&#xD;
             ≥2, and malabsorption syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any of the following cardiac diseases currently or within the last 6 months:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) &lt;50% as determined by Multiple Gated&#xD;
                  acquisition (MUGA) scan or echocardiogram (ECHO)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QTc &gt; 480 ms on screening ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association [NYHA] ≥ Grade 2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Conduction abnormality not controlled with pacemaker or medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant ventricular or supraventricular arrhythmias (Patients with chronic&#xD;
                  rate-controlled atrial fibrillation in the absence of other cardiac abnormalities&#xD;
                  are eligible.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Valvular disease with significant compromise in cardiac function.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Family history of congenital long or short QT, or known history of QT/QTc prolongation&#xD;
             or Torsades de Pointes (TdP). Patients who are currently receiving treatment with&#xD;
             medication that has the potential to prolong the QT interval or induce TdP and the&#xD;
             treatment cannot either be discontinued or switched to a different medication prior to&#xD;
             starting study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Inadequately controlled hypertension (i.e., SBP&gt;180 mmHg or DBP&gt;100mmHg). (Patients&#xD;
             with values above these levels must have their BP controlled with medication prior to&#xD;
             starting treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patient receiving chronic treatment with systemic steroids or another&#xD;
             immunosuppressive agent at the start of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Topical applications (e.g. rash), inhaled sprays (e.g. obstructive airways&#xD;
             diseases), eye drops or local injections (e.g. intra-articular) are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patients receiving drugs known to be moderate and strong inhibitors or inducers or&#xD;
             isoenzyme cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A (CYP3A) that cannot be discontinued or switched to&#xD;
             different medication prior to starting study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients who have taken herbal medications and certain fruits ≤7 days prior to&#xD;
             starting study drug. Herbal medications include, but are not limited to St. John's&#xD;
             wort, Kava, ephedra (ma huang), gingko biloba, dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA), yohimbe,&#xD;
             saw palmetto, and ginseng. Fruits include the CYP3A inhibitors Seville oranges,&#xD;
             grapefruit, pummelos, or exotic citrus fruits.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Patients currently receiving treatment with therapeutic doses of warfarin sodium.&#xD;
             Patients receiving low molecular weight heparin are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. A serious active infection at the time of treatment, or another serious underlying&#xD;
             medical condition that would impair the ability of the patient to receive protocol&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), Hepatitis B (HBV) or Hepatitis&#xD;
             C (HCV).&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Presence of other active cancers, or history of treatment for invasive cancer ≤5&#xD;
             years. Patients with stage I cancer who have received definitive local treatment at&#xD;
             least 3 years previously, and are considered unlikely to recur are eligible. All&#xD;
             patients with previously treated in situ carcinoma (i.e. non-invasive) are eligible,&#xD;
             as are patients with history of non-melanoma skin cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Psychological, familial, sociological, or geographical conditions that do not permit&#xD;
             compliance with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Inability or unwillingness to comply with study and/or follow-up procedures outlined&#xD;
             in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Fertile male patients, defined as all males physiologically capable of conceiving&#xD;
             offspring must use a highly effective contraception during dosing any study agent + [5&#xD;
             x T1/2] +12 weeks = contraception through 16 weeks after final dosing of study therapy&#xD;
             and should not father a child during this period. In addition, female partners of male&#xD;
             patients must use a highly effective contraception during dosing of any study agent +&#xD;
             [5 x T1/2] +12 weeks = contraception through 16 weeks after the final dose of study&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John D. Hainsworth, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Florida Cancer Specialists-South</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ft. Myers</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33916</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nebraska Methodist Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennessee Oncology PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 10, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 10, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 10, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 11, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prostate</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
  <keyword>Refractory</keyword>
  <keyword>mCRPC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

