<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02030444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ExtStaging-2014.1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02030444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extensive Staging in Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>ExtStaging</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Study Comparing Standard Staging of Lung Cancer With Extended Staging Including EBUS-TBNA and PET-MRI</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Olavs Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Norwegian University of Science and Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Olavs Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall aim of this study is to compare standard staging of lung cancer (which includes&#xD;
      clinical examination, CT, MRI, bone scan and PET-CT) with comprehensive staging - which&#xD;
      includes the new staging methods (PET-MRI and systematic mapping of mediastinal and hilar&#xD;
      lymph nodes using endobronchial ultrasound) with respect to disease stage and outcomes of&#xD;
      therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The trial is a randomized, explorative study. Patients undergoing examinations for suspicions&#xD;
      of lung cancer (Stage I-III) are randomized to either standard diagnostic work-up for lung&#xD;
      cancer (Arm A, n=75) or comprehensive diagnostic work-up (Arm B, n=75) with standard&#xD;
      examinations plus endobronchial-screening for metastatic lymph nodes (EBUS-TBNA) and PET-MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will undergo todays' standard examination for diagnosing and staging lung&#xD;
      cancer. This will be individualized for each patient according to current guidelines. In&#xD;
      addition to the standard diagnostic work-up, patients in the interventional group (ArmB) will&#xD;
      undergo&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) PET-MRI 2) systematic mediastinal and hilar lymph node mapping using EBUS-TBNA&#xD;
      (endobronchial ultrasound transbronchial needle aspiration of lymph nodes)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. PET-MRI PET-MRI will be done immediate after the standard PET-CT using the same infusion&#xD;
           of tracer (18-fluorodeoxyglucose, FDG). The sequence protocols used for MRI will be&#xD;
           standardized for the study, according to each body compartment. Measurement of Standard&#xD;
           Uptake Values (SUV) of the tracer (FDG) will be recorded in pathological lesions. In the&#xD;
           mediastinum, each lymph node station will be evaluated with description of visible&#xD;
           nodes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Systematic mediastinal mapping The EBUS-TBNA will be done at the initial bronchoscopy&#xD;
           and using standard conscious sedation according to the local guidelines at St.Olavs&#xD;
           Hospital. Each lymph node station (station 2, 4, 7, 10 and 11 bilateral) will be&#xD;
           examined and all lymph nodes ≥ 0,5 cm in short diameter that is easily accessible will&#xD;
           be punctured for rapid on-site cytological evaluation (ROSE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the initial diagnostic work-up is completed, the patient will be given treatment&#xD;
      according to existing guidelines for lung cancer based on the given clinical stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients undergoing surgery all accessible lymph nodes will be resected according to&#xD;
      standard practice. Every resected lymph node will be carefully named according to the&#xD;
      standard lymph station for comparison with clinical findings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    due to difficulties with recruiting&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Progression free survival in one year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard diagnostic work-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will undergo todays' standard work-up (examination for diagnosing and staging) of lung cancer. This will be individualized for each patient according to current guidelines.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Extensive diagnostic work-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients will in addition to standard diagnostic work-up undergo PET-MRI and systematic mediastinal and hilar lymph node mapping using EBUS-TBNA (endobronchial ultrasound transbronchial needle aspiration of lymph nodes).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PET-MRI and EBUS-TBNA</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Extensive diagnostic work-up</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        1. Patients undergoing examinations on suspicion of lung cancer (both SCLC and NSCLC) at&#xD;
             St. Olavs Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Potentially curable disease at the referral time (Stage I-III, based on the first CT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG Performance 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No serious concomitant disorders (for example marked reduced respiratory capacity,&#xD;
             active infection, unstable cardiovascular disease, renal dysfunction) that in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator would compromise the patient's ability to complete the&#xD;
             study or interfere with the evaluation of the efficacy and safety of the study&#xD;
             procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No contraindication for study specific procedure - bronchoscopy, CT, MRI and PET.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No conditions - medical, social, psychological - which could prevent adequate&#xD;
             information and follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No pregnancy or lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Written informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sveinung Sørhaug, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St. Olavs Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St.Olavs Hospital, Trondheim University Hospital, Dept of Thoracic Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trondheim</city>
        <zip>7006</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 8, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 3, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 3, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Neoplasms Staging</keyword>
  <keyword>Bronchoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Nuclear Medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Radiology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

