<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02031965</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PBTC-037</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2013-00526</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PBTC-037</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PBTC-037</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U01CA081457</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02031965</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oncolytic HSV-1716 in Treating Younger Patients With Refractory or Recurrent High Grade Glioma That Can Be Removed By Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of Intratumoral/Peritumoral Herpes Simplex Virus-1 Mutant HSV1716 in Patients With Refractory or Recurrent High Grade Gliomas (HGG)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pediatric Brain Tumor Consortium</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pediatric Brain Tumor Consortium</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the side effects and the safety of injecting HSV1716 (a new&#xD;
      experimental therapy) into or near the tumor resection cavity. The injection will be done at&#xD;
      the time of surgery. HSV1716 is a virus that has a gene which has been changed or removed&#xD;
      (mutated) in such a way that lets the virus multiply in dividing cells of the tumor and kills&#xD;
      the tumor cells.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine whether intratumoral/peritumoral injection of HSV1716 (oncolytic HSV-1716) is&#xD;
      safe in children with recurrent high-grade gliomas amenable to resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To estimate the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or a recommended Phase II dose of&#xD;
      intratumoral/peritumoral injection of HSV1716.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To describe any dose-limiting toxicities (DLT) of intratumoral/peritumoral injection of&#xD;
      HSV1716 at the doses given to children with high-grade gliomas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To evaluate changes in tumor enhancement, quantitative magnetic resonance (MR) measures&#xD;
      of tumor perfusion (relative cerebral blood volume [rCBV], transfer coefficient [k^trans],&#xD;
      fractional blood-plasma volume [Vp] and extravascular extracellular space per unit volume&#xD;
      tissue [Ve] values and apparent diffusion coefficient [ADC]) in response to HSV1716&#xD;
      injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To measure antiviral immune response in patients with refractory high-grade gliomas&#xD;
      injected with HSV1716.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To measure the systemic viremia and viral shedding following intratumoral/peritumoral&#xD;
      administration of HSV1716.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To preliminarily describe the antitumor activity of HSV1716 injection within the&#xD;
      confines of a Phase I study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To evaluate anti-tumor immune cellular and humoral immune responses. V. To evaluate&#xD;
      changes in fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG)- positron emission tomography (PET) uptake in response to&#xD;
      HSV1716 injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. To evaluate changes in tumor choline values using magnetic resonance (MR) spectroscopy in&#xD;
      response to HSV1716 injection and further delineate from progressive disease versus&#xD;
      pseudo-progression post therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive oncolytic HSV-1716 intratumorally (IT) and peritumorally after undergoing&#xD;
      surgical tumor resection. Patients also receive dexamethasone intravenously (IV) prior to and&#xD;
      6 and 12 hours after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 2 months for 1 year,&#xD;
      every 6 months for 4 years, and then annually for 10 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MTD of oncolytic HSV-1716, defined as the highest dose level at which 0 out of 3 or at most one out of 6 patients have been treated experiencing a dose limiting toxicity and the next higher dose level has been determined to be too toxic</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
    <description>Graded according to the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) version 4.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antiviral immune responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Summarized and reported descriptively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systemic viremia and viral shedding</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 years</time_frame>
    <description>Summarized and reported descriptively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of initial protocol treatment to the earliest date of disease progression, second malignancy or death for patients who fail; and to the date of last contact for patients who remain at risk for failure, assessed up to 15 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of initial protocol treatment to the date of death for patients who fail; and to the date of last contact for patients who remain at risk for failure, assessed up to 15 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in MR parameters (including diffusion and perfusion studies) (optional)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 2 months post-injection</time_frame>
    <description>Summary statistics and graphs used to describe changes in these quantitative imaging parameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in MRS and PET parameters (including diffusion and perfusion studies) (optional)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 2 months post-injection</time_frame>
    <description>Summary statistics and graphs used to describe changes in these quantitative imaging parameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-tumor cellular responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Humoral immune responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Anaplastic Astrocytoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Anaplastic Oligoastrocytoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Anaplastic Oligodendroglioma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Giant Cell Glioblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Glioblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Gliomatosis Cerebri</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Childhood Gliosarcoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oncolytic HSV-1716)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive oncolytic HSV-1716 IT and peritumorally after undergoing surgical tumor resection. Patients also receive dexamethasone IV prior to and 6 and 12 hours after surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>oncolytic HSV-1716</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oncolytic HSV-1716)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>herpes simplex virus 1716</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oncolytic HSV-1716)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Aeroseb-Dex</other_name>
    <other_name>Decaderm</other_name>
    <other_name>Decadron</other_name>
    <other_name>DM</other_name>
    <other_name>DXM</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>therapeutic conventional surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo surgical resection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oncolytic HSV-1716)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>laboratory biomarker analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oncolytic HSV-1716)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Imaging evaluations necessary to establish eligibility for study entry must be done&#xD;
             within three (3) weeks prior to registration; all other evaluations necessary to&#xD;
             establish eligibility for study entry must be done within two (2) weeks prior to&#xD;
             registration; in the event that the patient's condition deteriorates (performance&#xD;
             score &lt; 60) within 48 hours prior to the injection the patient is no longer eligible&#xD;
             to receive HSV1716 injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a histologically-confirmed primary diagnosis of high-grade glioma&#xD;
             (HGG) (such as glioblastoma multiforme, gliosarcoma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma,&#xD;
             anaplastic ganglioglioma, high grade astrocytoma, not otherwise specified [NOS]) that&#xD;
             is recurrent or refractory to conventional therapy; patients with metastatic disease&#xD;
             are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be those for whom surgical resection is clinically indicated; the intent&#xD;
             of surgical resection may include debulking or attempt to resect as much of the tumor&#xD;
             as safely feasible; if a gross total or near total resection is not feasible, HSV1716&#xD;
             injection into the wall of the resection cavity, encompassing residual tumor, is&#xD;
             permissible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients must be amenable to receiving 1 dose of HSV1716 intra-operatively with&#xD;
                  planned HSV1716 injection sites &gt;= 1 cm from the ventricular system AND meet at&#xD;
                  least one of the criteria below based upon pre-surgical magnetic resonance&#xD;
                  imaging (MRI):&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Tumor is &gt;= 1 cm from the ventricular system&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Patients whose tumors that are =&lt; 1 cm from the ventricular system are&#xD;
                       eligible if there is sufficient space within the tumor cavity and/or&#xD;
                       residual tumor to perform the HSV 1716 injections that are &gt;= 1 cm from the&#xD;
                       ventricular system&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  An intraoperative MRI upon resection will confirm the distance of the planned&#xD;
                  injection sites from the ventricular system prior to the HSV1716 injection;&#xD;
                  intra-operatively, the neurosurgeon may decide to not inject the HSV1716 or may&#xD;
                  revise the sites of HSV1716 injection if injection cannot be guaranteed &gt;= 1 cm&#xD;
                  from the ventricular system; patient will removed from the study if there are not&#xD;
                  sufficient areas in the tumor cavity to guarantee injection of HSV1716 &gt;= 1 cm&#xD;
                  from the ventricular system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have received prior therapy other than surgery and must have fully&#xD;
             recovered from the acute treatment related toxicities of all prior chemotherapy,&#xD;
             immunotherapy, or radiotherapy prior to entering this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have received their last dose of known myelosuppressive anticancer&#xD;
             chemotherapy at least three (3) weeks prior to study registration treatment or at&#xD;
             least six (6) weeks if nitrosourea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigational/Biologic agent:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Biologic or investigational agent (anti-neoplastic): Patient must have recovered&#xD;
                  from any acute toxicity potentially related to the agent and received their last&#xD;
                  dose of the investigational or biologic agent &gt;= 7 days prior to study&#xD;
                  registration&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  For agents that have known adverse events occurring beyond 7 days after&#xD;
                       administration, this period must be extended beyond the time during which&#xD;
                       adverse events are known to occur&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Monoclonal antibody treatment: At least three half-lives must have elapsed prior&#xD;
                  to registration; Note: A list of the half-lives of commonly used monoclonal&#xD;
                  antibodies is available on the Pediatric Brain Tumor Consortium (PBTC) webpage&#xD;
                  under Generic Forms and Templates&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have had their last fraction of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Craniospinal irradiation (&gt; 24 Gray [Gy]) or total body irradiation &gt; 3 months&#xD;
                  prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Focal irradiation to symptomatic metastatic sites &gt; 4 weeks prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Local palliative external beam radiation therapy (XRT) (small port) &gt;= 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If prior total-body irradiation (TBI), craniospinal XRT or if &gt;= 50% radiation of&#xD;
                  pelvis &gt;= 6 months must have elapsed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If other substantial bone marrow (BM) radiation &gt;= 6 weeks must have elapsed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  &gt;= 6 months since allogeneic bone marrow transplant prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stem cell transplant or rescue without TBI: No evidence of active graft vs. host&#xD;
                  disease and &gt;= 3 months must have elapsed since transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance scale (KPS for &gt; 16 years of age) or Lansky performance score&#xD;
             (LPS for =&lt; 16 years of age) assessed within two weeks of registration must be &gt;= 60&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin: &gt;= 10 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count: &gt;= 1000/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets: &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 (transfusion independent defined as not receiving platelet&#xD;
             transfusions within 7 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin: &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of institutional normal for age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT]): =&lt; 2.5&#xD;
             × institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt;= 70&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m^2 or a serum creatinine based on age and gender as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age 10 to &lt; 13 years: maximum serum creatinine (mg/dL): 1.2 for males and 1.2 for&#xD;
                  females&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age 13 to &lt; 16 years: maximum serum creatinine (mg/dL): 1.5 for males and 1.4 for&#xD;
                  females&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age &gt;= 16 years: maximum serum creatinine (mg/dL): 1.7 for males and 1.4 for&#xD;
                  females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Albumin &gt;= 2.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partial thromboplastin time (PTT) &lt; 1.2 X institutional upper limits of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with neurological deficits should have deficits that are stable for a minimum&#xD;
             of 1 week prior to registration; this is to be documented at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with central nervous system (CNS) tumors who are receiving dexamethasone must&#xD;
             have been on a stable or decreasing dose of dexamethasone for the 7 days prior to&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Growth factors that support platelet or white cell number or function must not have&#xD;
             been administered within the past 7 days; growth factors include: GCSF (filgrastim),&#xD;
             PEG-GCSF (Neulasta), GM-CSF (sargramostim) and erythropoietin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented evidence of negative tests for the presence of hepatitis B surface antigen,&#xD;
             hepatitis C antibody, and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)1/2 antibodies within the&#xD;
             three months preceding study entry; subjects who do not have such evidence must&#xD;
             undergo appropriate testing prior to virus administration; HIV-positive patients on&#xD;
             combination antiretroviral therapy are ineligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document&#xD;
             according to institutional guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with metastatic disease i.e. leptomeninges, multi-focal lesions in the CNS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients whose tumor lies within 1 cm of the ventricular system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently receiving other anti-cancer agents are excluded from this&#xD;
             trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of prior HSV encephalitis or encephalitis due to other&#xD;
             etiologies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There is no available information regarding human fetal or teratogenic toxicities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded to avoid the risk of systemic intrauterine/neonatal HSV&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males or females of reproductive potential may not participate unless they have agreed&#xD;
             to use an effective contraceptive method from the time of study entry to a period of&#xD;
             no less than four months post the HSV1716 injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who participate in this study must agree not to breastfeed from study entry to a&#xD;
             period of no less than four months post the HSV1716 injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects whose primary physicians determine that anti-HSV antiviral therapy (such as&#xD;
             acyclovir, ganciclovir, foscarnet, etc.) cannot be safely discontinued from 2 days&#xD;
             prior to the injection to 28 days following the injection are excluded from this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on systemic anticoagulants are excluded from this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any clinically significant unrelated systemic illness (serious&#xD;
             infections or significant cardiac, pulmonary, hepatic or other organ dysfunction),&#xD;
             that would compromise the patient's ability to tolerate protocol therapy or would&#xD;
             likely interfere with the study procedures or results&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariko DeWire</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Pediatric Brain Tumor Consortium</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 7, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 30, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Neuroepithelial</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

