<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04629573</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB0000871248</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04629573</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Epidural Anesthesia and Myomectomy Associated Bleeding</brief_title>
  <official_title>Epidural Anesthesia and Myomectomy-Associated Blood Loss: A Prospective Randomised Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective study for abdominal myomectomies performed from June 2012 to June 2019&#xD;
      by a single surgeon in a tertiary care referral hospital. Large uterine myoma was defined as&#xD;
      the estimated diameter of dominant myoma equal to or larger than 10 cm by sonography.&#xD;
      Demographics, diagnosis, perioperative variables, operative outcomes and complications were&#xD;
      recorded. The Intraoperative anesthetic management, blood and blood products transfusion, and&#xD;
      total volume of blood loss, as well as postoperative follow-up, were reviewed for each&#xD;
      patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Randomization and Blinding: To allow randomization, researchers prepared the management&#xD;
      protocol for each group and sealed one protocol per envelope with a computer-generated number&#xD;
      assigned prior to study initiation. Randomization was performed by picking the numbered study&#xD;
      envelopes sequentially and opened before induction of anesthesia by the anesthesia doctor and&#xD;
      managing the participant based on the enclosed protocol. The study will not be&#xD;
      double-blinded, as it is impossible to blind the health care workers and women involved for&#xD;
      the strategy to which the woman is allocated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions Anesthesia technique: On arrival to the operative theatre, an 18 gauge IV&#xD;
      catheter was inserted and 500 ml of NaCl (0.9%) was infused, 1 mg midazolam was administered&#xD;
      iv as premedication. Patients were monitored with continuous electrocardiography and pulse&#xD;
      oximetry and intermittent non-invasive blood pressure measurements every 5 min.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lumbar epidural: Epidural procedure was performed by attending anesthesiologists who had&#xD;
      completed at least 50 epidural procedures during their training. Patient was placed in the&#xD;
      sitting position, the skin over the lumbar area was cleaned and a sterile technique was&#xD;
      observed throughout the procedure. Skin and subcutaneous tissue were infiltrated with 1%&#xD;
      lidocaine 2 mL at the intended site of epidural placement (L2-3 or L3-4 interspace). The&#xD;
      lumbar epidural space was then located, using a midline approach with an 18 gauge Tuohy&#xD;
      epidural needle via a loss of resistance technique with 2 mL of saline, 20 gauge epidural&#xD;
      catheter was placed in each patient. We deliver an initial bolus of 20 ml bupivacaine 0.5%&#xD;
      plus 100 mcg Fentanyl, followed by continuous infusion of bupivacaine 0.5% plus 1mcg/ml&#xD;
      Fentanyl (3-5 ml/hr.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      General anesthesia: Anesthesia was initiated with IV fentanyl 1 µg/kg, propofol 2 mg/kg and&#xD;
      cisatracurium 0.15 mg/kg to facilitate endotracheal intubation. After tracheal intubation,&#xD;
      anesthesia was maintained with sevoflurane in O2 and air (FiO2 of 0.5), cisatracurium&#xD;
      1µg/kg/min and fentanyl 0.5 µg/ kg /h were infused. Volume-Controlled ventilation was&#xD;
      performed in all patients. Cisatracurium and fentanyl infusion was stopped at the end of&#xD;
      surgery, neuromuscular blockade was reversed, and the patient was extubated and send to&#xD;
      post-anesthesia care unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Myomectomy: Abdominal myomectomy was performed in the standard conventional fashion. A single&#xD;
      surgeon handled all the surgical procedures. The myomectomy was performed by enucleating the&#xD;
      fibroid and closing the uterine defect in multiple layers. The use of energy devices, suture&#xD;
      type, and adhesion barriers were at the discretion of the surgeon.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood loss</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Intraoperative blood loss</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">78</enrollment>
  <condition>Epidural; Anesthesia, Headache</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Epidural Anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>General Anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lumber Epidural</intervention_name>
    <description>Epidural procedure was performed by attending anesthesiologists who had completed at least 50 epidural procedures during their training. Patient was placed in the sitting position, the skin over the lumbar area was cleaned and a sterile technique was observed throughout the procedure. Skin and subcutaneous tissue were infiltrated with 1% lidocaine 2 mL at the intended site of epidural placement (L2-3 or L3-4 interspace). The lumbar epidural space was then located, using a midline approach with an 18 gauge Tuohy epidural needle via a loss of resistance technique with 2 mL of saline, 20 gauge epidural catheter was placed in each patient. We deliver an initial bolus of 20 ml bupivacaine 0.5% plus 100 mcg Fentanyl, followed by continuous infusion of bupivacaine 0.5% plus 1mcg/ml Fentanyl (3-5 ml/hr.).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>General anesthesia</intervention_name>
    <description>Anesthesia was initiated with IV fentanyl 1 µg/kg, propofol 2 mg/kg and cisatracurium 0.15 mg/kg to facilitate endotracheal intubation. After tracheal intubation, anesthesia was maintained with sevoflurane in O2 and air (FiO2 of 0.5), cisatracurium 1µg/kg/min and fentanyl 0.5 µg/ kg /h were infused. Volume-Controlled ventilation was performed in all patients. Cisatracurium and fentanyl infusion was stopped at the end of surgery, neuromuscular blockade was reversed, and the patient was extubated and send to post-anesthesia care unit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women over 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologist (ASA) I and II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing myomectomy for treatment of large uterine leiomyomas with a minimum&#xD;
             diameter of 10 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with previous uterine surgery (myomectomy, cesarean delivery)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coagulopathy or other bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe anemia (Hb under 5.0 g/dl)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abdelrady S Ibrahim</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut university faculty of medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhang Y, Yu J, Yang F, Zhao L, Ma L, Zhang H, Chen X, Ma H. Effect of anesthetic technique on serum vascular endothelial growth factor C and prostaglandin E2 levels in women undergoing surgery for uterine leiomyomas. J Int Med Res. 2020 Apr;48(4):300060520918420. doi: 10.1177/0300060520918420.</citation>
    <PMID>32314939</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Abdelrady S Ibrahim, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Anesthesia</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Epidural anesthesia, Myomectomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

