<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04624399</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ABACUS-2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04624399</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase 2 Study of Neoadjuvant Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors in Urothelial Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>ABACUS-2</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase 2 Study of Neoadjuvant Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors in Urothelial Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Queen Mary University of London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hoffmann-La Roche</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Queen Mary University of London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is being carried out to see if the drug atezolizumab can reduce the size of&#xD;
      tumours in patients with types of urothelial cancer before surgery. Atezolizumab is designed&#xD;
      to stop a protein called PD-L1 (programmed death-ligand 1) being expressed on the cancer,&#xD;
      allowing the immune system to recognise the tumour cells as foreign bodies and attack them.&#xD;
      Atezolizumab has been shown to have activity in urothelial cancer which has spread.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There two cohorts for this trial. One cohort will investigate the most common histological&#xD;
      type of urothelial cancer (transitional cell carcinoma) outside the bladder, for example in&#xD;
      the upper urinary tract. The other cohort will investigate rarer histological subtypes (such&#xD;
      as such as squamous cell or adenocarcinoma) of urothelial cancer throughout the entire&#xD;
      urinary system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be recruiting patients from hospitals in the UK, France and Spain. If a&#xD;
      patient is eligible for the study and decides to take part, they will receive up to two&#xD;
      3-weekly cycles of atezolizumab. 4-8 weeks after being enrolled, the patient will have an&#xD;
      operation to remove the bladder (cystectomy) or the kidney, ureter and part of the bladder&#xD;
      (nephroureterectomy or distal ureteral resection) as per normal practice. Following surgery,&#xD;
      they will attend three hospital visits (4,12 and 24 weeks after surgery) and their disease&#xD;
      progress/survival will be followed over the next 2 years. The clinical team will compare the&#xD;
      patient's tumour tissue samples,scan results and blood results from before and after&#xD;
      treatment with atezolizumab in order to see how well the drug works and if it is safe. Many&#xD;
      of the procedures involved in this study are offered as standard care and participation in&#xD;
      this trial will not delay surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Screening (up to 28 days before day 1 of treatment):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Written informed consent will be obtained before potential participants undergo any study&#xD;
      specific procedures. Each potential participant will undergo screening during the 28 days&#xD;
      prior to recruitment in the study to confirm eligibility. Clinical data obtained as part of&#xD;
      their standard care prior to consent may be used to confirm eligibility if they fall within&#xD;
      the protocol specified timelines. Screening will involve standard of care and study specific&#xD;
      assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard care assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Demographics&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical Examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Height&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An assessment of how easily patients can carry out their daily activities (ECOG&#xD;
           performance score)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An assessment of the patient's fitness for surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Questions about what medicines including over the counter and herbal medicines the&#xD;
           potential participant is taking&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study specific assessments to be carried out once the potential participant has consented to&#xD;
      the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood samples will be taken for routine biochemistry, haematology, coagulation tests,&#xD;
           thyroid function testing, and hepatitis/HIV serology testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine sample for routine urinalysis testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Women of childbearing potential will be asked to take a pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An ECG to confirm cardiac function&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A CT scan or MRI of the disease area&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample (approximately 20ml/4 teaspoons) and urine sample (approximately 50ml) for&#xD;
           research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An archival FFPE tumour sample will also be collected as part of patient's normal&#xD;
           clinical care&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment period:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will undergo two cycle of atezolizumab treatment (1200 mg administered&#xD;
      by IV infusion every 3 weeks (21 days ±3 days for Cycle 2)). At each cycle, patients will&#xD;
      undergo the following assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical Examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECOG performance score&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood samples will be taken for biochemistry and haematology blood tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine sample for routine urinalysis testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs and symptoms (side effects) or other adverse events they may be experiencing and&#xD;
           any medications being taken&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample (approximately 20ml/4 teaspoons) and urine sample (approximately 50ml) for&#xD;
           research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There must be a minimum of 5 days between the last atezolizumab infusion and surgery.&#xD;
      Patients will undergo a pre-surgery visit, at which they will undergo the following&#xD;
      assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical Examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECOG performance score&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An assessment of the patient's fitness for surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A CT scan or MRI of the disease area&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs and symptoms (side effects) or other adverse events they may be experiencing and&#xD;
           any medications being taken&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample (approximately 20ml/4 teaspoons) and urine sample (approximately 50ml) for&#xD;
           research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
      An FFPE excision sample will be collected after the tumour has been surgically excised and&#xD;
      pathologically examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-surgery visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo follow-up visits at 4 weeks,12 weeks, and 24 weeks after surgery.&#xD;
      Patients who do not undergo radical surgery will attend safety follow up visits from the date&#xD;
      the decision was made to cancel surgery. At these visits, they will undergo the following&#xD;
      assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical Examination (4 week visit only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weight (4 week visit only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs (4 week visit only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECOG performance score (4 week visit only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood samples will be taken for routine biochemistry, haematology, coagulation tests (4&#xD;
           week visit only),and thyroid function testing (12 &amp; 24 week visits only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Signs and symptoms (side effects) or other adverse events they may be experiencing and&#xD;
           any medications being taken&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clavien-Dindo assessment of any surgical complications will be carried out as per normal&#xD;
           hospital practice (4 &amp; 12 week visits only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample (approximately 20ml/4 teaspoons) and urine sample (approximately 50ml) for&#xD;
           research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Survival, disease status and new anti-cancer treatment information (12 &amp; 24 week visits&#xD;
           only)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed up at 1 year and 2 years after surgery for details on survival,&#xD;
      disease status and new anti-cancer treatment information. This will be conducted via&#xD;
      telephone or review of patient medical notes on site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathological complete response rate (pCRR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At surgery (4-8 weeks after patient registration)</time_frame>
    <description>No microscopic evidence (pT0/Tis/Cis) of residual disease in the bladder based on histological evaluation of the resected bladder specimen collected during cystectomy (post-treatment) [Bladder Cohort]&#xD;
- No microscopic evidence (pT0/Tis/Cis) of residual disease in the renal pelvis or ureter in the resected sample collected during radical surgery for upper tract disease (post-treatment) [UTUC Cohort]</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment on immune parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Samples acquired at surgery (4-8 weeks after patient registration)</time_frame>
    <description>ynamic changes in T cell subpopulations (CD8 and/or CD3) measured in tumour samples collected pre- and post-treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the safety and tolerability of atezolizumab when given in the neoadjuvant setting</measure>
    <time_frame>Adverse Events will be collated during treatment and up to 24 weeks post-cystectomy or post-radical surgery. Surgical complications will be assessed at the 4wk and 12 week follow-up visits.</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence, nature and severity of Adverse Events graded according to NCI-CTCAE v5.0. Surgical complications will be assessed by the Clavien-Dindo scoring system.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the efficacy of atezolizumab given in the neoadjuvant setting with respect to anti-tumour effects as measured by Investigator assessed radiological response (RR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at CT scan pre-surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>RR defined as a ≥30% decrease in tumour diameter from the baseline scan based on local investigator assessments.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the efficacy of atezolizumab given in the neoadjuvant setting with respect to anti-tumour effects based on Investigator assessed disease-free survival (DFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated at 12 weeks, 24 weeks, 12 months, and 24 months post-surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>DFS defined as time between the date of enrolment to first evidence of relapse based on local investigator assessments or death, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the efficacy of atezolizumab given in the neoadjuvant setting with respect to overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated at 12 weeks, 24 weeks, 12 months, and 24 months post-surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>OS, defined as the time between the date of enrolment and death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">58</enrollment>
  <condition>Urogenital Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive 2 x 3-weekly cycles of Atezolizumab (one infusion on the first day of each cycle) prior to cystectomy surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atezolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients receive 2 x 3-weekly cycles of Atezolizumab (one infusion on the first day of each cycle) prior to cystectomy surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MPDL3280A</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort-Specific Inclusion Criteria • Bladder cohort: Histopathologically confirmed&#xD;
        carcinoma of the urothelium (T1 high grade -T4a) in the bladder with mixed or rare&#xD;
        histological subtypes such as squamous cell or adenocarcinoma. Patients with mixed&#xD;
        histologies are required to have a dominant non- transitional cell pattern.&#xD;
&#xD;
        • UTUC cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Histopathologically confirmed,high grade or high risk upper urinary tract urothelial&#xD;
        carcinoma (renal pelvis and ureter). This cohort includes all patients with upper tract&#xD;
        malignancy who in the opinion of the investigators qualify for radical surgery&#xD;
        (nephroureterectomy or distal ureter resection). Urothelial carcinoma of the upper urinary&#xD;
        tract qualifies as high-risk disease if any of the below factors are present:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hydronephrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumour size &gt;2cm on cross sectional imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High grade cytology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High grade biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multifocal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Variant histology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous radical cystectomy for urothelial cancer of the bladder&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients undergoing radical surgery with curative intent in the opinion of the&#xD;
        investigator are eligible. Radical surgical interventions include nephroureterectomy or&#xD;
        distal ureteral resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        General inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Willing and able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to comply with the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Residual disease after TURBT or URS (surgical opinion, endoscopy or radiological&#xD;
             presence).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Fit and planned for radical surgery with curative intent in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator (according to local guidelines).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. N0 or M0 disease CT or MRI (within 4 weeks of registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Representative formalin-fixed paraffin embedded (FFPE) tumour samples with an&#xD;
             associated pathology report that are determined to be available and sufficient for&#xD;
             central testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who refuse neoadjuvant cisplatin-based chemotherapy or in whom neoadjuvant&#xD;
             cisplatin-based therapy is not appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Negative pregnancy test within 2 weeks of Day 1 Cycle 1 for female patients of&#xD;
             childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. For female patients of childbearing potential to use a highly effecting form(s) of&#xD;
             contraception (i.e. one that results in a low failure rate [&lt;1% per year] when used&#xD;
             consistently and correctly) and to continue its use for 90 days after the last dose of&#xD;
             atezolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Adequate hematologic and end-organ function within 4 weeks prior to the first study&#xD;
             treatment defined by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. ANC ≥ 1500 cells/μL (without granulocyte colony-stimulating factor support within&#xD;
                  2 weeks prior to Cycle 1, Day 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. WBC counts &gt; 2500/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Lymphocyte count ≥ 500/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Platelet count ≥ 100,000/μL (without transfusion within 2 weeks prior to Cycle 1,&#xD;
                  Day 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Haemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL (patients may be transfused or receive erythropoietic&#xD;
                  treatment to meet this criterion).&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. AST or ALT,and alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times the institutional upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal (ULN) (patients with known Gilbert disease who have serum bilirubin level&#xD;
                  ≤ 3 × the institutional ULN may be enrolled).&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. INR and aPTT ≤ 1.5 × the institutional ULN. This applies only to patients who are&#xD;
                  not receiving therapeutic anticoagulation; patients receiving therapeutic&#xD;
                  anticoagulation should be on a stable dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 20 mL/min (Cockcroft-Gault formula)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant and lactating female patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major surgical procedure within 4 weeks prior to enrolment or anticipation of need for&#xD;
             a major surgical procedure during the course of the study other than for diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previously intravenous chemotherapy for urothelial cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with prior allogeneic stem cell or solid organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prior treatment with CD137 agonists,anti-CTLA-4,anti-programmed death-1 (PD-1),or&#xD;
             anti-PD-L1 therapeutic antibody or pathway-targeting agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must not have had oral or IV steroids for 14 days prior to study entry. The&#xD;
             use of inhaled corticosteroids, physiologic replacement doses of glucocorticoids&#xD;
             (i.e.,for adrenal insufficiency), and mineralocorticoids (e.g. fludrocortisone) is&#xD;
             allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Received therapeutic oral or intravenous (IV) antibiotics within 14 days prior to&#xD;
             enrolment (Patients receiving prophylactic antibiotics (e.g.,for prevention of a&#xD;
             urinary tract infection or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease) are eligible).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Administration of a live,attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks prior to enrolment or&#xD;
             anticipation that such a live,attenuated vaccine will be required during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Treatment with systemic immunostimulatory agents (including but not limited to&#xD;
             interferons or interleukin [IL]-2) within 4 weeks or five half-lives of the drug,&#xD;
             whichever is shorter, prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Treatment with any other investigational agent or participation in another clinical&#xD;
             trial with therapeutic intent within 4 weeks prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Evidence of significant uncontrolled concomitant disease that could affect compliance&#xD;
             with the protocol or interpretation of results, including significant liver disease&#xD;
             (such as cirrhosis, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, or superior vena cava&#xD;
             syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Malignancies other than UC within 5 years prior to Cycle 1,Day 1,with the exception of&#xD;
             those with a negligible risk of metastasis or death and treated with expected curative&#xD;
             outcome (such as adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix, basal or squamous&#xD;
             cell skin cancer, or ductal carcinoma in situ treated surgically with curative intent)&#xD;
             or localized prostate cancer treated with curative intent and absence of&#xD;
             prostate-specific antigen (PSA) relapse or incidental prostate cancer (Gleason score ≤&#xD;
             3 + 4 and PSA &lt; 10 ng/mL undergoing active surveillance and treatment naive).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Severe infections within 4 weeks prior to enrolment in the study including but not&#xD;
             limited to hospitalization for complications of infection, bacteraemia,or severe&#xD;
             pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Significant cardiovascular disease, such as New York Heart Association cardiac disease&#xD;
             (Class II or greater), myocardial infarction within 3 months prior to enrolment,&#xD;
             unstable arrhythmias, or unstable angina.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (including pneumonitis),drug-induced&#xD;
             pneumonitis, organizing pneumonia (i.e.,bronchiolitis obliterans, cryptogenic&#xD;
             organizing pneumonia), or evidence of active pneumonitis on screening chest CT scan&#xD;
             (History of radiation pneumonitis in the radiation field (fibrosis) is permitted).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patients with uncontrolled Type 1 diabetes mellitus. Patients with Type 1 diabetes&#xD;
             controlled on a stable insulin regimen are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients with active hepatitis infection (defined as having a positive hepatitis B&#xD;
             surface antigen [HBsAg] test at screening) or hepatitis C. Patients with past&#xD;
             hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection or resolved HBV infection (defined as having a&#xD;
             negative HBsAg test and a positive antibody to hepatitis B core antigen [anti-HBc]&#xD;
             antibody test) are eligible. Patients positive for hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody&#xD;
             are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is negative for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Positive test for HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients with active tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of gastrointestinal disorders (medical disorders or extensive surgery) which&#xD;
             may interfere with the absorption of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Uncontrolled hypercalcemia (&gt; 1.5 mmol/L ionized calcium or Ca &gt; 12 mg/dL or corrected&#xD;
             serum calcium &gt; the institutional ULN) or symptomatic hypercalcemia requiring&#xD;
             continued use of bisphosphonate therapy or denosumab. Patients who are receiving&#xD;
             bisphosphonate therapy or denosumab specifically to prevent skeletal events and who do&#xD;
             not have a history of clinically significant hypercalcemia are eligible. Patients who&#xD;
             are receiving denosumab prior to enrollment must be willing and eligible to receive a&#xD;
             bisphosphonate instead while on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. History of autoimmune disease including but not limited to myasthenia gravis,&#xD;
             myositis, autoimmune hepatitis, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, vascular thrombosis associated with antiphospholipid&#xD;
             syndrome, Wegener's granulomatosis, Sjögren's syndrome, Guillain-Barré syndrome,&#xD;
             multiple sclerosis, vasculitis, or glomerulonephritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Patients with a history of autoimmune-related hypothyroidism, unless on a stable dose&#xD;
             of thyroid-replacement hormone.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. History of severe allergic, anaphylactic,or other hypersensitivity reactions to&#xD;
             chimeric or humanized antibodies or fusion proteins&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Known hypersensitivity or allergy to biopharmaceuticals produced in Chinese hamster&#xD;
             ovary cells or any component of the atezolizumab formulation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Powles, MBBS MD MRCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Queen Mary University of London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>ABACUS-2 Trial Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>020 7882 8478</phone>
    <email>bci-abacus2@qmul.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kelly Mousa</last_name>
    <email>k.mousa@qmul.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sheffield</city>
        <state>South Yorkshire</state>
        <zip>S5 7AU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Syed Hussain, MD, FRCP</last_name>
      <email>syed.hussain@sheffield.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clatterbridge Cancer Centre NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barts and London Hospital NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southampton General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urogenital Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atezolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

