<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04625608</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>266252</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04625608</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Premedicant Oral Paracetamol on Gastric Volume and pH</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomised Controlled Trial Examining the Effect of Premedicant Oral Paracetamol on Gastric Residual Volume and pH in Children, in the Context of a 1-hour Clear Fluid Fast</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Barts &amp; The London NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients are asked to fast before general anaesthesia to reduce the risk that any gastric&#xD;
      contents could be regurgitated and aspirated into the lungs once anaesthetised. If aspiration&#xD;
      does occur, the volume and acidity of the fluid aspirated are thought to determine the extent&#xD;
      of any harm caused. Recent guidelines have reduced the required fasting time for children for&#xD;
      clear fluids from 2 hours to 1 hour before induction of anaesthesia, as it is understood that&#xD;
      this does not adversely affect the gastric residual volume or increase its acidity.&#xD;
      Paracetamol is commonly used to relieve pain during and after surgery. Paracetamol syrup&#xD;
      preparations used in children are viscous and not classified as clear fluid. This study seeks&#xD;
      to establish whether there is non-inferiority in gastric residual volume (GRV) and pH in&#xD;
      children receiving oral paracetamol one hour before induction of anaesthesia and those who do&#xD;
      not, when both groups have received a set volume of diluted orange cordial to drink. It is&#xD;
      anticipated that if shown to have little or no impact on GRV and pH, oral paracetamol syrup&#xD;
      can be given to children before surgery. This will omit the need for IV paracetamol to be&#xD;
      given in theatre, potentially reducing cost and the risk of drug errors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients are asked to fast before anaesthesia to reduce the risk that residual gastric&#xD;
      contents could be regurgitated and aspirated into the lungs once anaesthetised. In animal&#xD;
      studies, gastric contents that are less acidic (with a pH &gt;1.8) have been shown to be less&#xD;
      harmful when aspirated than those that are more acidic, even at higher gastric residual&#xD;
      volumes. Recent European and UK guidelines have reduced the length of the recommended clear&#xD;
      fluid fast to 1 hour for children, as there is no significant difference in GRV or pH in&#xD;
      children fasted for 1 hour compared to 2 hours. It is therefore believed to present no&#xD;
      additional risk of harm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some anaesthetists administer oral paracetamol syrup to children pre-operatively as an&#xD;
      alternative to intravenous administration of paracetamol during their surgery. The oral route&#xD;
      has been suggested to be pleasant for children, cheaper, more convenient, and reduce the risk&#xD;
      of drug errors associated with the IV preparation. Anderson et al found no significant&#xD;
      difference in gastric volume or pH in children with a mean age of 8.5 years given paracetamol&#xD;
      orally 90 minutes before surgery compared to children given paracetamol rectally. Burke et&#xD;
      al. demonstrated that giving paracetamol orally up to 8 minutes before induction of&#xD;
      anaesthesia was not associated with an increase in the volume of stomach contents, and that&#xD;
      the pH of stomach contents was higher than in control subjects who did not receive&#xD;
      paracetamol. This suggests that giving oral paracetamol before induction of anaesthesia may&#xD;
      not present any increased risk of harm from aspiration. This was in the context of a mean&#xD;
      fluid fast of 5 hours and a mean age of 5.1 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To our knowledge, no studies have assessed the effect of oral paracetamol syrup on gastric&#xD;
      residual volume (GRV) and pH in the context of the newly recommended reduced clear fluid&#xD;
      fasting time of 1 hour. Neither has this been studied in children as young as 44 weeks&#xD;
      post-conceptual age.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Residual volume of gastric contents following induction of general anaesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 5-10 minutes following the induction of general anaesthesia.</time_frame>
    <description>Gastric volume and pH of that fluid that can be aspirated via an oro-gastric tube, passed into the patient's stomach once general anaesthesia has been induced and the airway secured.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>pH of gastric contents following induction of general anaesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 5-10 minutes following the induction of general anaesthesia.</time_frame>
    <description>Gastric volume and pH of that fluid that can be aspirated via an oro-gastric tube, passed into the patient's stomach once general anaesthesia has been induced and the airway secured.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events at induction of anaesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes after the induction of anaesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events occurring around the time of induction of anaesthesia including regurgitation and aspiration of gastric contents</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events at emergence from anaesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes from removal of the patient's airway</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events occurring around the time of emergence from anaesthesia including regurgitation and aspiration of gastric contents</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Paracetamol drug errors</measure>
    <time_frame>For day case patients, until discharge. For inpatients, up to 24 hours post-operatively.</time_frame>
    <description>Paracetamol related drug errors</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Emergence delirium</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 minutes following patient arrival in PACU.</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of emergence delirium in post-anaesthesia care unit, measured with PAED score.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events in Post-Anaesthesia Care Unit</measure>
    <time_frame>From arrival in the post-anaesthesia care unit until patient is ready for discharge to the ward, up to 24 hours.</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse regurgitation or aspiration events occurring in the post-anaesthesia care unit, including requirements for additional analgesia, time to first analgesic request and time spent in the post-anaesthesia care unit.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">104</enrollment>
  <condition>Fasting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm shall receive 3.6 ml/kg of water a minimum of 1 hour prior to the induction of general anaesthesia. This is standard practice in the 2 participating institutions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paracetamol arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm shall receive 3 ml/kg of water plus 15 mg/kg of oral paracetamol suspension a minimum of 1 hour prior to the induction of general anaesthesia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paracetamol</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard care of 3 ml/kg water, plus 15 mg/kg oral paracetamol suspension, a minimum of 1 hour prior to the induction of general anaesthesia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Paracetamol arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard care</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard care of 3.6 ml/kg water, a minimum of 1 hour prior to the induction of general anaesthesia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elective surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring tracheal intubation for general anaesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent/guardian able to speak and understand written English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected gastro-intestinal disease including varices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous surgery which may alter gastric emptying or the anatomy of the oesophagus or&#xD;
             stomach&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated difficult airway&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant administration of any other medication orally prior to anaesthesia, but&#xD;
             excluding buccal sedative pre-medication eg midazolam&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients taking antacids or pro-kinetic drugs, or requiring them pre-operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to paracetamol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient weight greater than 25 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parental or patient refusal&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>44 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>8 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Emily Saffer, MB BS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emily Saffer, MB BS</last_name>
    <phone>+4420 3299 9000</phone>
    <email>emily.saffer@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Dominic PD Nielsen, MB ChB</last_name>
    <phone>02073777000</phone>
    <email>dominic.nielsen1@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Emily Saffer, MB BS</last_name>
      <phone>02032999000</phone>
      <email>emily.saffer@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thomas M, Morrison C, Newton R, Schindler E. Consensus statement on clear fluids fasting for elective pediatric general anesthesia. Paediatr Anaesth. 2018 May;28(5):411-414. doi: 10.1111/pan.13370. Epub 2018 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>29700894</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brady M, Kinn S, O'Rourke K, Randhawa N, Stuart P. Preoperative fasting for preventing perioperative complications in children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2005 Apr 18;(2):CD005285. Review. Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;(4):CD005285.</citation>
    <PMID>15846750</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>James CF, Modell JH, Gibbs CP, Kuck EJ, Ruiz BC. Pulmonary aspiration--effects of volume and pH in the rat. Anesth Analg. 1984 Jul;63(7):665-8.</citation>
    <PMID>6731893</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jibril F, Sharaby S, Mohamed A, Wilby KJ. Intravenous versus Oral Acetaminophen for Pain: Systematic Review of Current Evidence to Support Clinical Decision-Making. Can J Hosp Pharm. 2015 May-Jun;68(3):238-47. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26157186</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anderson BJ, Rees SG, Liley A, Stewart AW, Wardill MJ. Effect of preoperative paracetamol on gastric volumes and pH in children. Paediatr Anaesth. 1999;9(3):203-7.</citation>
    <PMID>10320598</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Burke CN, D'Agostino R, Tait AR, Malviya S, Voepel-Lewis T. Effect of Preemptive Acetaminophen Administered Within 1 Hour of General Anesthesia on Gastric Residual Volume and pH in Children. J Perianesth Nurs. 2019 Apr;34(2):297-302. doi: 10.1016/j.jopan.2018.05.015. Epub 2018 Sep 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30270047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>general anaesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>paracetamol</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

