<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04629950</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-07022368</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04629950</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rimegepant in Moderate Plaque-type Psoriasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study of Rimegepant in Moderate Plaque-type Psoriasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to examine the use of a new investigational medication for the&#xD;
      treatment of moderate plaque-type psoriasis. The study medication is rimegepant, an orally&#xD;
      administered small molecule competitive inhibitor of the calcitonin gene-related peptide&#xD;
      (CGRP) receptor. This medication, rimegepant, has been approved by the FDA under the trade&#xD;
      name Nurtec for the treatment of acute migraine. However, rimegepant has not been studied in&#xD;
      the treatment of moderate plaque-type psoriasis and is investigational for this indication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Severity of Psoriasis as Measured with the Psoriasis Area and Severity Index Instrument</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Total score of Psoriasis Area and Severity Index ranges from 0 to 72. Change = (Week 16 score - Baseline score). A low score means less severe disease while a high score reflects more severe disease. A score of 0 means no psoriasis. A PASI score of 5 to 10 is considered moderate disease and a score over 10 is considered severe. A score over 40 is rare.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average Change in Psoriasis Area and Severity Index Instrument Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>To Score Whether the Average PASI Score Improves by at Least 50% by Week 16 (Week 16 average score - Baseline average score) PASI range is 0-72 although PASI must be at least 5 for entry into the study. A score of 0 means no psoriasis. A PASI score of 5 to 10 is considered moderate disease and a score over 10 is considered severe. A score over 40 is rare.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Severity of Psoriasis as Assessed by the Investigator's Global Assessment Instrument.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Score of the Investigator's Global Assessment instrument ranges from 0 to 4.&#xD;
Average Change in Score of Each Group= (Week 16 average score - Baseline average score) 0=Clear, 1=Almost Clear, 2=Mild, 3=Moderate, 4=Severe.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Dermatology Quality of Life Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Dermatology Quality of Life Index score ranges from 0-30. Average Change in Score of Each Group= (Week 16 average score - Baseline average score). 0 - 1 no effect at all on patient's life, 2 - 5 small effect on patient's life, 6 - 10 moderate effect on patient's life, 11 - 20 very large effect on patient's life, 21 - 30 extremely large effect on patient's life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Degree of Itching Assessed by the Visual Analogue Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The Visual Analogue Scale ranges from 0 to 10. 0= no pruritus, &lt; 3= mild pruritus, ≥ 3-&lt;7= moderate pruritus, ≥ 7-&lt;9 = severe pruritus, ≥ 9= very severe pruritus.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Psoriasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rimegepant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive a rimegepant 75 mg tablet orally every other day for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive a placebo tablet matching rimegepant orally every other day for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rimegepant</intervention_name>
    <description>Active Agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rimegepant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo Comparator</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patients with at least 3% body surface are involved with psoriasis and&#xD;
             a PASI score &gt;5.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between 18 and 75 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documentation of a definite diagnosis of psoriasis by a dermatologist or biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of childbearing potential, a negative urine pregnancy test within 48 hours&#xD;
             of randomization. Female subjects should not have attempted to become pregnant in the&#xD;
             month prior to exposure to rimegepant and agree not to attempt to become pregnant for&#xD;
             8 weeks after exposure to rimegepant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A valid form of contraception must be documented for men and women of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The two methods for women of childbearing potential should include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  One barrier method (for example, Diaphragm with spermicidal gel, condom with&#xD;
                       spermicidal gel, cervical caps or intrauterine devices placed for at least&#xD;
                       four weeks before sexual intercourse); AND&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  One additional method. The other method could include hormonal&#xD;
                       contraceptives, or second barrier method as listed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The two options for men of childbearing potential should include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Simultaneous use of male condom, and for the female partner, hormonal&#xD;
                       contraceptives (for example, birth control pills, implants, patch, depot&#xD;
                       injection, used since at least 4 weeks) or intra-uterine contraceptive&#xD;
                       device (placed since at least 4 weeks) before sexual intercourse; OR&#xD;
                       simultaneous use of male condom, and for the female partner, diaphragm with&#xD;
                       intravaginally applied spermicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any ongoing medical illness or condition that places the participant at higher risk&#xD;
             for adverse outcomes or inability to complete study procedures in the opinion of the&#xD;
             study investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known autoimmune disorders other than psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of corticosteroids or immunosuppressive medications (for any reason).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunodeficiency diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any biologic agent/monoclonal antibody within 5 half-lifes prior to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ultraviolet light treatment, cyclosporine, oral corticosteroids, methotrexate, oral&#xD;
             retinoids, mycophenolate mofetil, thioguanine, hydroxyurea, sirolimus or azathioprine&#xD;
             within the 4 weeks prior to baseline or had topical psoriasis treatment within the&#xD;
             previous 2 weeks prior to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical trial involving an investigational drug within the&#xD;
             last 30 days prior to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability for woman of child-bearing potential to use an effective form of&#xD;
             contraception if sexually active.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any medication that is a strong or moderate inhibitor of CYP3A, a strong or&#xD;
             moderate inducer of CYP3A, or an inhibitor of glycoprotein (P-gp) or Breast Cancer&#xD;
             Resistance Protein (BCRP). Please see Section 7.8 for more information.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index greater than 31.0 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject history with current evidence of uncontrolled, unstable or recently diagnosed&#xD;
             cardiovascular disease, such as ischemic heart disease, coronary artery vasospasm, and&#xD;
             cerebral ischemia. Subjects with myocardial infarction (MI), acute coronary syndrome&#xD;
             (ACS), percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), cardiac surgery, stroke or transient&#xD;
             ischemic attack (TIA) during 6 months (24 weeks) prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension or uncontrolled diabetes (however, subjects can be included&#xD;
             who have stable hypertension and/or diabetes for 3 months (12 weeks) prior to&#xD;
             screening). Blood pressure greater than 150 mm Hg systolic or 100 mm Hg diastolic&#xD;
             after 10 minutes of rest is exclusionary&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with an active episode of major depressive episode within the last 6 months&#xD;
             are ineligible. Subjects with major depressive disorder or any anxiety disorder are&#xD;
             eligible only if they are on stable medication for each disorder for at least 3 months&#xD;
             prior to the Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a history or diagnosis of Gilbert's Syndrome or any other active hepatic&#xD;
             or biliary disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematologic or solid malignancy diagnosis within 5 years prior to screening. Subjects&#xD;
             with a history of localized basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer are eligible for&#xD;
             the study if they are cancer-free prior to the screening visit in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has current diagnosis of major depressive disorder requiring treatment with&#xD;
             atypical antipsychotics, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, or borderline personality&#xD;
             disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of gallstones or cholecystectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has current diagnosis of major depressive disorder requiring treatment with&#xD;
             atypical antipsychotics, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, or borderline personality&#xD;
             disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The use of CGRP antagonists (biologic [e.g. Aimovig™, Emgality® and Ajovy™, VyeptiTM]&#xD;
             or small molecule [ e.g. Ubrelvy™ {ubrogepant]]) other than rimegepant is prohibited&#xD;
             during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of atypical antipsychotics such as Abilify (aripiprazole), Zyprexa&#xD;
             (olanzapine), Seroquel (quetiapine), Geodon (ziprasidone), or Risperdal (risperidone).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Depakote/Depakene (divalproex/valproic acid/valproate) is prohibited during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of LAMICTAL (lamotrigine) is prohibited during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of Modafinil (PROVIGIL®) is prohibited during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusionary screening lab test findings:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin (Total, Direct or Indirect) &gt; 1 x ULN (Only abnormal values of&#xD;
                  between 1-1.5x ULN may be repeated once for assessment of eligibility prior to&#xD;
                  randomization)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST or ALT &gt; 1 x ULN (Only abnormal values of between 1-1.5x ULN may be repeated&#xD;
                  once for assessment of eligibility prior to randomization)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophil count ≤ 1000/μL (or equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HbA1c &gt; 6.5%&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard D Granstein, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer T Vu, BS</last_name>
    <phone>646-962-7275</phone>
    <email>jtv4002@med.cornell.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Morgan Lynch, BS</last_name>
    <phone>646-962-5565</phone>
    <email>mol9034@med.cornell.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richard D Granstein, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-962-7546</phone>
      <email>rdgranst@med.cornell.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Elise Tetelman, BA</last_name>
      <phone>6469625565</phone>
      <email>elt9059@med.cornell.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajguru JP, Maya D, Kumar D, Suri P, Bhardwaj S, Patel ND. Update on psoriasis: A review. J Family Med Prim Care. 2020 Jan 28;9(1):20-24. doi: 10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_689_19. eCollection 2020 Jan. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32110559</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Takeshita J, Grewal S, Langan SM, Mehta NN, Ogdie A, Van Voorhees AS, Gelfand JM. Psoriasis and comorbid diseases: Implications for management. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017 Mar;76(3):393-403. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2016.07.065. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28212760</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Greb JE, Goldminz AM, Elder JT, Lebwohl MG, Gladman DD, Wu JJ, Mehta NN, Finlay AY, Gottlieb AB. Psoriasis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2016 Nov 24;2:16082. doi: 10.1038/nrdp.2016.82. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27883001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kaushik SB, Lebwohl MG. Review of safety and efficacy of approved systemic psoriasis therapies. Int J Dermatol. 2019 Jun;58(6):649-658. doi: 10.1111/ijd.14246. Epub 2018 Sep 23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30246393</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rácz E, Prens EP. Phototherapy of Psoriasis, a Chronic Inflammatory Skin Disease. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2017;996:287-294. doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-56017-5_24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29124709</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Farber EM, Lanigan SW, Boer J. The role of cutaneous sensory nerves in the maintenance of psoriasis. Int J Dermatol. 1990 Jul-Aug;29(6):418-20.</citation>
    <PMID>2397964</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhu TH, Nakamura M, Farahnik B, Abrouk M, Lee K, Singh R, Gevorgyan A, Koo J, Bhutani T. The Role of the Nervous System in the Pathophysiology of Psoriasis: A Review of Cases of Psoriasis Remission or Improvement Following Denervation Injury. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2016 Jun;17(3):257-63. doi: 10.1007/s40257-016-0183-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26935938</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Perlman HH. Remission of psoriasis vulgaris from the use of nerve-blocking agents. Arch Dermatol. 1972 Jan;105(1):128-9.</citation>
    <PMID>5009614</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aschenbeck KA, Hordinsky MK, Kennedy WR, Wendelschafer-Crabb G, Ericson ME, Kavand S, Bertin A, Dykstra DD, Panoutsopoulou IG. Neuromodulatory treatment of recalcitrant plaque psoriasis with onabotulinumtoxinA. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018 Dec;79(6):1156-1159. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2018.07.058.</citation>
    <PMID>30420008</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostrowski SM, Belkadi A, Loyd CM, Diaconu D, Ward NL. Cutaneous denervation of psoriasiform mouse skin improves acanthosis and inflammation in a sensory neuropeptide-dependent manner. J Invest Dermatol. 2011 Jul;131(7):1530-8. doi: 10.1038/jid.2011.60. Epub 2011 Apr 7.</citation>
    <PMID>21471984</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reich A, Orda A, Wiśnicka B, Szepietowski JC. Plasma concentration of selected neuropeptides in patients suffering from psoriasis. Exp Dermatol. 2007 May;16(5):421-8.</citation>
    <PMID>17437485</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>He Y, Ding G, Wang X, Zhu T, Fan S. Calcitonin gene-related peptide in Langerhans cells in psoriatic plaque lesions. Chin Med J (Engl). 2000 Aug;113(8):747-51.</citation>
    <PMID>11776062</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riol-Blanco L, Ordovas-Montanes J, Perro M, Naval E, Thiriot A, Alvarez D, Paust S, Wood JN, von Andrian UH. Nociceptive sensory neurons drive interleukin-23-mediated psoriasiform skin inflammation. Nature. 2014 Jun 5;510(7503):157-61. doi: 10.1038/nature13199. Epub 2014 Apr 23.</citation>
    <PMID>24759321</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kashem SW, Riedl MS, Yao C, Honda CN, Vulchanova L, Kaplan DH. Nociceptive Sensory Fibers Drive Interleukin-23 Production from CD301b+ Dermal Dendritic Cells and Drive Protective Cutaneous Immunity. Immunity. 2015 Sep 15;43(3):515-26. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2015.08.016. Erratum in: Immunity. 2015 Oct 20;43(4):830.</citation>
    <PMID>26377898</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ding W, Stohl LL, Xu L, Zhou XK, Manni M, Wagner JA, Granstein RD. Calcitonin Gene-Related Peptide-Exposed Endothelial Cells Bias Antigen Presentation to CD4+ T Cells toward a Th17 Response. J Immunol. 2016 Mar 1;196(5):2181-94. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.1500303. Epub 2016 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>26829986</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc. will receive de-identified case report forms. De-identified data will not be shared with with individuals not involved in the research study.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The protocol, statistical analysis plan and informed consent form have already been provided. Case report forms and the clinical study report will be provided at the end of the study after unblinding and analysis of data. This is estimated to be in approximately 2 years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>This access was agreed upon in the agreement negotiated for funding of this trial by Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

