<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04623931</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019-0715</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2019-08264</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-0715</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04623931</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chemotherapy and Radiation Therapy for the Treatment of IDH Wildtype Gliomas or Non-histological (Molecular) Glioblastomas</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Treatment Intensification for IDH Wildtype, Non-Histological Glioblastoma, Gliomas (IDH Wildtype Lower Grade Glioma Treatment Intensification)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies how well temozolomide and radiation therapy work in treating&#xD;
      patients with IDH wildtype historically lower grade gliomas or non-histological molecular&#xD;
      glioblastomas. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to kill tumor cells and shrink&#xD;
      tumors. Giving chemotherapy with radiation therapy may kill more tumor cells. Drugs used in&#xD;
      chemotherapy, such as temozolomide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells,&#xD;
      either by killing the cells, by stopping them from dividing, or by stopping them from&#xD;
      spreading. The goal of this clinical research study is to compare receiving new radiation&#xD;
      therapy doses and volumes to the prior standard treatment for patients with historically&#xD;
      grade II or grade III IDH wild-type gliomas, which may now be referred to as IDH wildtype&#xD;
      molecular glioblastomas at some institutions. Receiving temozolomide in combination with&#xD;
      radiation therapy may also help to control the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the progression free survival (PFS) based on Response Assessment in&#xD;
      Neuro-Oncology (RANO) imaging criteria from start of treatment with concurrent chemoradiation&#xD;
      (CRT) and adjuvant temozolomide (TMZ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the 3-year overall survival (OS) of isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) wild-type&#xD;
      grade II and grade III gliomas with dose escalation radiation with concurrent chemoradiation&#xD;
      therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess local control patterns (site of 1st progression). II. To evaluate&#xD;
      neuro-cognitive function by the Neurocognitive Clinical Trial Battery (CTB).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To evaluate the treatment related symptoms, overall symptom impact, and disease related&#xD;
      factor groupings utilizing the M.D. Anderson Symptom Inventory Brain Tumor (MDASI-BT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To assess the quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive temozolomide orally (PO) daily and radiation therapy over 5 days a week&#xD;
      (weekdays only) for 6 weeks. Beginning 28 days after the last dose of radiation therapy,&#xD;
      patients receive temozolomide PO for 12 months in the absence of disease progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 12, 15, 18,&#xD;
      21, 24, 28, 32, and 36 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 6, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 6, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment until objective tumor progression or death, whichever happens first, assessed up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>Tumor progression is defined by the Response Assessment in Neuro-Oncology glioma criteria. PFS time will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The 1-year PFS rate will be estimated along with a 95% confidence interval. Patient or tumor characteristics (ex. grade, age, etc) will be compared within the single study cohort. Cox regression models will be applied to assess the effect of covariates of interest on PFS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment until death from any cause, assessed at 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The 3-year OS rate is defined as the proportion of participants that are alive at 3-year after the start of treatment, which will be estimated along a 95% confidence interval. OS time will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. Patient or tumor characteristics (ex. grade, age, etc) will be compared within the single study cohort. Cox regression models will be applied to assess the effect of covariates of interest on OS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Local control patterns (site of 1st progression)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be summarized with frequency and proportion.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Neuro-cognitive function</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Neurocognitive Clinical Trial Battery, and summarized with descriptive summary statistics.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom burden</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the M.D. Anderson Symptom Inventory Brain Tumor (MDASI-BT), and summarized using standard descriptive statistics such as mean, standard deviation, median and range. Wilcoxon rank-sum test or Kruskal Wallis test will be used to examine the difference on MDASI-BT between or among patients' characteristics groups.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by linear analog self-assessment (LASA) scale, will be summarized using standard descriptive statistics such as mean, standard deviation, median and range. Wilcoxon rank-sum test or Kruskal-Wallis test will be used to examine the difference on LASA scale between or among patients' characteristics groups.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Anaplastic Astrocytoma, IDH-Wildtype</condition>
  <condition>Anaplastic Oligoastrocytoma</condition>
  <condition>Anaplastic Oligodendroglioma</condition>
  <condition>Diffuse Astrocytoma, IDH-Wildtype</condition>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Oligoastrocytoma</condition>
  <condition>Oligodendroglioma</condition>
  <condition>WHO Grade II Glioma</condition>
  <condition>WHO Grade III Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (temozolomide, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive temozolomide PO daily and radiation therapy over 5 days a week (weekdays only) for 6 weeks. Beginning 28 days after the last dose of radiation therapy, patients receive temozolomide PO for 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quality-of-Life Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (temozolomide, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Quality of Life Assessment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (temozolomide, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo radiation therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (temozolomide, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cancer Radiotherapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Energy Type</other_name>
    <other_name>ENERGY_TYPE</other_name>
    <other_name>Irradiate</other_name>
    <other_name>Irradiated</other_name>
    <other_name>Irradiation</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiation</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiation Therapy, NOS</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiotherapeutics</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiotherapy</other_name>
    <other_name>RT</other_name>
    <other_name>Therapy, Radiation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Temozolomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (temozolomide, radiation therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CCRG-81045</other_name>
    <other_name>Imidazo[5,1-d]-1,2,3,5-tetrazine-8-carboxamide, 3, 4-dihydro-3-methyl-4-oxo-</other_name>
    <other_name>M &amp; B 39831</other_name>
    <other_name>M and B 39831</other_name>
    <other_name>Methazolastone</other_name>
    <other_name>RP-46161</other_name>
    <other_name>SCH 52365</other_name>
    <other_name>Temcad</other_name>
    <other_name>Temodal</other_name>
    <other_name>Temodar</other_name>
    <other_name>Temomedac</other_name>
    <other_name>TMZ</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Historical grade II and III gliomas IDH wildtype gliomas by including; diffuse&#xD;
             astrocytoma, anaplastic astrocytoma, oligodendroglioma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma,&#xD;
             oligoastrocytoma, anaplastic oligoastrocytoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IDH wildtype gliomas (molecularly defined high grade glioma or molecularly defined&#xD;
             glioblastoma [GBM])&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History &amp; physical exam, and Karnofsky performance status (KFS) of &gt;= 70 within 30&#xD;
             days prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-operative magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) with contrast is mandatory and&#xD;
             necessary for radiation therapy (RT) planning&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thin-slice (&lt; 1.5 mm) three-dimensional (3D) T1 pre and post contrast and axial&#xD;
             T2/fluid-attenuated inversion recovery (FLAIR) sequences for planning purposes are&#xD;
             highly encouraged to obtain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,500 cells/mm^3 (within 60 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000 cells/mm^3 (within 60 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 10.0 g/dl (within 60 days prior to registration) (Note: The use of&#xD;
             transfusion or other intervention to achieve hemoglobin [Hgb] &gt;= 10.0 g/dl is&#xD;
             acceptable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 upper limit of normal (ULN) (within 60 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 3 x ULN (within&#xD;
             60 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood urea nitrogen (BUN) &lt; 30 mg/dl (within 60 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 mg/dl (within 60 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Definitive clinical or radiologic evidence of metastatic disease; if applicable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior invasive malignancy (except non-melanomatous skin cancer) unless disease free&#xD;
             for a minimum of 3 years. (For example, carcinoma in situ of the breast, oral cavity&#xD;
             or cervix are permissible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior cranial radiotherapy or radiotherapy to the head and neck where potential field&#xD;
             overlaps would exist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior chemotherapy or radiotherapy for any brain tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologic diagnosis of gliosarcoma World Health Organization (WHO grade IV) or&#xD;
             pilocytic astrocytoma (WHO grade I)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multicentric glioblastoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to undergo MRI with and without contrast&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe, active co-morbidity defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina or congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within 6&#xD;
                  months prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Transmural myocardial infarction within the last 6 months prior to registration.&#xD;
                  Evidence of recent myocardial infarction or ischemia by the findings of S-T&#xD;
                  elevations of &gt;= 2 mm using the analysis of an electrocardiogram (EKG) performed&#xD;
                  within 28 days prior to registration. (Note: EKG to be performed only if clinical&#xD;
                  suspicion of cardiac issue)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  • New York Heart Association grade II or greater congestive heart failure&#xD;
                  requiring hospitalization within 12 months prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serious and inadequately controlled arrhythmia at step 2 registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serious or non-healing wound, ulcer or bone fracture or history of abdominal&#xD;
                  fistula, intra-abdominal abscess requiring major surgical procedure, open biopsy&#xD;
                  or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to registration, with the&#xD;
                  exception of the craniotomy for surgical resection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute bacterial or fungal infection requiring intravenous antibiotics at the time&#xD;
                  of registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatic insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects;&#xD;
                  note, however, that laboratory tests for coagulation parameters are not required&#xD;
                  for entry into this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness&#xD;
                  requiring hospitalization or precluding study therapy at the time of registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive with CD4 count &lt; 200&#xD;
                  cells/microliter. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) based upon current&#xD;
                  Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) definition; note, however, that&#xD;
                  HIV testing is not required for entry into this protocol. The need to exclude&#xD;
                  patients with AIDS from this protocol is because the treatments involved in this&#xD;
                  protocol may be significantly immunosuppressive with potentially fatal outcomes&#xD;
                  in patients already immunosuppressed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other severe immunocompromised condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active connective tissue disorders, such as lupus or scleroderma that in the opinion&#xD;
             of the treating physician may put the patient at high risk for radiation toxicity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  End-stage renal disease (i.e., on dialysis or dialysis has been recommended)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other major medical illnesses or psychiatric treatments that in the investigator's&#xD;
             opinion will prevent administration or completion of protocol therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Debra N Yeboa</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Debra N Yeboa</last_name>
    <phone>713-563-2300</phone>
    <email>dnyeboa@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Debra N. Yeboa</last_name>
      <phone>713-563-2300</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Debra N. Yeboa</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

