<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04624841</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRGC-05-NI-18-362</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1256-1361</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04624841</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Indocyanine Green to Visualize Critical View of Safety During Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy for Acute Cholecystitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Role of Indocyanine Green in Visualizing Critical View of Safety During Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy for Acute Cholecystitis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hamad Medical Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hamad Medical Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this prospective randomized trial is to study the role of Indocyanine green&#xD;
      (ICG) to visualize the Critical View of Safety during emergency Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy&#xD;
      for patients with Acute Cholecystitis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After informing about the study and obtaining consent to participate, patients who are&#xD;
      diagnosed with Acute Cholecystitis and posted for emergency Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy will&#xD;
      be randomly assigned to receive either ICG or not as a method to identify the Critical View&#xD;
      of Safety during the operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is whether there was a precise and satisfactory visualization of the&#xD;
      junction between the cystic duct, the common hepatic duct, and the common bile duct by&#xD;
      indocyanine green compared to the control group. The time taken to achieve this will be&#xD;
      measured in minutes from video recordings of the laparoscopic surgery. The process will be&#xD;
      further assessed by a surgeons' satisfaction score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The expected duration of the study will be 12 months involving a total of 80 patients&#xD;
      randomized into two groups- 40 patients in the intervention group and 40 patients in the&#xD;
      control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The expected outcome of the study is that ICG is more effective than the control group in&#xD;
      providing precise and satisfactory visualization of Critical View of Safety and takes less&#xD;
      time. We predict the surgeons to be equally or more satisfied with ICG compared to control.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective randomized controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The patient is blinded to the intervention S/he receives. The surgeon, investigator, and outcomes assessor are masked but not strictly blinded up to the point when the near-infrared camera is switched on</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of surgeries in which Critical View of Safety was achieved</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to clipping of the Cystic Duct and Cystic Artery or decision to perform conventional intraoperative cholangiography or convert to open.</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of surgeries where there was complete visualization of Critical View of Safety by intraoperative fluorescent cholangiography compared to the control group with no fluorescent imaging. Complete visualization of the Critical View of Safety is defined by the SAGS guidelines.&#xD;
The laparoscopic procedure is recorded &amp; assessed individually &amp; separately by two consultant surgeons who are not the operating surgeon whether the Critical View of Safety was achieved prior to clipping of Cystic Duct &amp; Cystic Artery.&#xD;
Failure of identification of Critical View of Safety is defined as the need for further conventional intraoperative cholangiography or open conversion due to inability to accurately identify the biliary anatomy to complete the cholecystectomy safely.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time taken to identify Critical View of Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>After securing working ports till Clipping of Cystic Duct or Artery.</time_frame>
    <description>Time taken by intraoperative fluorescent cholangiography or control group to identify Critical View of Safety. The laparoscopic procedure is recorded and Time taken is recorded by the Primary Investigator as the total time between successful introduction of the operative ports until the Critical View of Safety is achieved and Cystic Duct and Cystic Artery are clipped.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgeon's Satisfaction Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to clipping of the Cystic Duct and Cystic Artery or decision to perform conventional intraoperative cholangiography or convert to open.</time_frame>
    <description>Surgeon satisfaction survey will be completed by the operating surgeon intraoperatively by answering the question &quot;Are you satisfied to proceed with the laparoscopic cholecystectomy without a conventional intraoperative cholangiography?&quot;. The answers will be a binary Yes or No.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Cholecystitis</condition>
  <condition>Acute; Cholecystitis, Choledocholithiasis</condition>
  <condition>Acute Cholecystitis With Obstruction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ICG group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive an intravenous injection of 0.05 mg/kg of ICG 45 minutes preoperatively.&#xD;
A Pinpoint Endoscopic Fluorescence System (Novadac Technologies Inc., Canada) for ICG Fluorescence Observation with the easy switchable white light-fluorescent mode is used.&#xD;
Before dividing any tubular structure, the fluorescence imaging mode is routinely used again, and fluorescent angiography is performed by re-injecting the same dose of ICG as initially used.&#xD;
After the division of the cystic duct and artery, the fluorescence imaging mode is applied again to check for bile leakage.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No ICG Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No ICG is administered after randomization of the patient to a control group and hence will not produce any enhancement of the image on A Pinpoint Endoscopic Fluorescence System for ICG Fluorescence Observation. This will continue as a routine Laparoscopic cholecystectomy without fluorescent imaging enhancement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Indocyanine Green</intervention_name>
    <description>2.5-7.5 mg (0.05 mg/kg) injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>ICG group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ICG</other_name>
    <other_name>fluorescent Imaging</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient scheduled for emergency Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy for Acute Cholecystitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who consent to take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preoperative planned for Open Cholecystectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy towards iodine, iohexol or ICG&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Legally incompetent for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Withdrawal of inclusion consent at any time&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zia Aftab, MBBS, FACS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hamad Medical Corporation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zia Aftab, MBBS, FACS</last_name>
    <phone>00974-66233904</phone>
    <email>zahmed5@hamad.qa</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shameel Musthafa, MBBS, FACS</last_name>
    <phone>00974-77274577</phone>
    <email>drshameelmusthafa@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamad General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Doha</city>
        <zip>3050</zip>
        <country>Qatar</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zia Aftab</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Qatar</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ishizawa T, Bandai Y, Kokudo N. Fluorescent cholangiography using indocyanine green for laparoscopic cholecystectomy: an initial experience. Arch Surg. 2009 Apr;144(4):381-2. doi: 10.1001/archsurg.2009.9.</citation>
    <PMID>19380655</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Daskalaki D, Fernandes E, Wang X, Bianco FM, Elli EF, Ayloo S, Masrur M, Milone L, Giulianotti PC. Indocyanine green (ICG) fluorescent cholangiography during robotic cholecystectomy: results of 184 consecutive cases in a single institution. Surg Innov. 2014 Dec;21(6):615-21. doi: 10.1177/1553350614524839. Epub 2014 Mar 9.</citation>
    <PMID>24616013</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dip F, Roy M, Lo Menzo E, Simpfendorfer C, Szomstein S, Rosenthal RJ. Routine use of fluorescent incisionless cholangiography as a new imaging modality during laparoscopic cholecystectomy. Surg Endosc. 2015 Jun;29(6):1621-6. doi: 10.1007/s00464-014-3853-7. Epub 2014 Oct 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25277476</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pesce A, Piccolo G, La Greca G, Puleo S. Utility of fluorescent cholangiography during laparoscopic cholecystectomy: A systematic review. World J Gastroenterol. 2015 Jul 7;21(25):7877-83. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i25.7877. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26167088</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Overby DW, Apelgren KN, Richardson W, Fanelli R; Society of American Gastrointestinal and Endoscopic Surgeons. SAGES guidelines for the clinical application of laparoscopic biliary tract surgery. Surg Endosc. 2010 Oct;24(10):2368-86. doi: 10.1007/s00464-010-1268-7. Epub 2010 Aug 13.</citation>
    <PMID>20706739</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hamad Medical Corporation</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Zia Ahmed Aftab, MBBS,FRCS,FACS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant in Acute Care Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>acute cholecystitis</keyword>
  <keyword>laparoscopic cholecystectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>critical view of safety</keyword>
  <keyword>safe cholecystectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>indocyanine green</keyword>
  <keyword>operative cholangiogram</keyword>
  <keyword>fluorescent imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>near-infrared imaging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acalculous Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Choledocholithiasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

