<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04626245</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1679889-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04626245</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mindfulness &amp; Mechanisms Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mindfulness &amp; Daily Experiences Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lifespan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lifespan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hypertensive disorders of pregnancy (HDP) are the most common medical condition affecting&#xD;
      pregnancy and a leading cause of maternal morbidity and mortality in the Unites States. HDP&#xD;
      also increase lifetime cardiac disease risk in women and infants. Current interventions to&#xD;
      prevent HDP are limited, and interventions that do not include medications are minimally&#xD;
      effective at preventing HDP. Mindfulness interventions hold promise as a intervention to&#xD;
      prevent HDP that does not require pregnant women to take medications. Past research shows&#xD;
      that mindfulness interventions reduce blood pressure in adults with hypertension and&#xD;
      pre-hypertension. However, past studies of mindfulness interventions for pregnant women have&#xD;
      not allowed women at risk for HDP to participate. The preliminary study of prenatal&#xD;
      mindfulness training for women at risk for HDP demonstrated benefit on maternal blood&#xD;
      pressure and fetal growth. However, the mechanisms explaining effects of prenatal mindfulness&#xD;
      training on risk for HDP are unknown. Building upon these promising preliminary findings, the&#xD;
      proposed clinical trial will measure daily experiences of stress, physiological reactivity to&#xD;
      stress, and interpersonal processes before and after prenatal mindfulness training. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that mindfulness training will impact these processes, which may&#xD;
      lead to improved maternal cardiovascular parameters and reduced risk for HDP. N=150 pregnant&#xD;
      women at risk for HDP will be randomized to an 8-week phone-delivered mindfulness&#xD;
      intervention or usual care. For every participant, we will measure maternal cardiovascular&#xD;
      parameters (24-hour blood pressure and uterine artery resistance values by ultrasound&#xD;
      Doppler) before and after the 8-week period. All participants will complete surveys of daily&#xD;
      experiences for 2 weeks before and after the 8-week period to evaluate mechanisms of&#xD;
      mindfulness training on maternal cardiovascular parameters. Daily experiences will be&#xD;
      measured using surveys delivered via smartphone-app, ambient audio sampling, and wearable&#xD;
      wrist-worn biosensor monitoring (heart rate and heart rate variability).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypertensive disorders of pregnancy (HDP) are the most common medical conditions in pregnancy&#xD;
      and a leading cause of maternal morbidity and mortality in the United States. HDP are also&#xD;
      associated with significant financial costs to the US healthcare system; $2.18 billion is&#xD;
      spent on treatment of affected mothers and infants in the first year after delivery. Women&#xD;
      exposed to HDP are at increased lifetime risk for cardiovascular disease, dementia, and&#xD;
      all-cause mortality. Current interventions to prevent HDP are limited and do not target&#xD;
      underlying mechanisms of disease. Mindfulness training (MT) holds tremendous promise as a&#xD;
      mind-body intervention to prevent HDP. MT is effective at reducing blood pressure in&#xD;
      non-pregnant patients with pre-hypertension and hypertension and has proven more effective at&#xD;
      blood pressure reduction than other stress management interventions. Results from the pilot&#xD;
      RCT were the first to indicate that prenatal phone-delivered MT is feasible and had a medium&#xD;
      to large effect on cardiovascular parameters in women at risk for HDP. However, the&#xD;
      mechanisms through which prenatal MT affects cardiovascular parameters are not yet&#xD;
      understood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MT teaches participants to &quot;attend and respond in a non-judgmental way to ordinary, everyday&#xD;
      experiences.&quot; Theory and available evidence indicate that MT elicits relaxation, decreases&#xD;
      stress biomarkers and autonomic activation, and decreases loneliness --- dynamic processes&#xD;
      that may serve as pathways to improved cardiovascular parameters in women at risk for HDP.&#xD;
      The proposed RCT will harness subjective and objective ecological momentary assessment (EMA)&#xD;
      methodologies (in vivo repeated assessments) in combination with wearable biosensor&#xD;
      technology to capture rich epochs of ecologically-valid psychological, physiological, and&#xD;
      interpersonal processes through which MT may lead to improved maternal cardiovascular&#xD;
      parameters. Pregnant women at risk for HDP will be randomized to an 8-week phone-delivered MT&#xD;
      intervention or usual care. For every participant, the research team will measure maternal&#xD;
      cardiovascular parameters (24-hour blood pressure and uterine artery resistance values by&#xD;
      ultrasound Doppler) before and after the RCT. All participants will complete EMA for 2 weeks&#xD;
      'bursts' before and after the RCT to evaluate mechanisms of MT on cardiovascular parameters.&#xD;
      EMA will include smartphone-app based experience sampling of psychological processes;&#xD;
      smartphone-app based ambient audio sampling (i.e. the Electronically Activated Recorder [EAR]&#xD;
      method) and wearable wrist-worn biosensor monitoring of physiological responses (heart rate&#xD;
      and heart rate variability) to everyday experiences. Results will provide new insights into&#xD;
      1) effects of MT on cardiovascular parameters in pregnancy, 2) pathophysiological mechanisms&#xD;
      of HDP, and 3) targets for new HDP prevention strategies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomized to a mindfulness training condition or treatment as usual.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived stress and mood responses to momentary stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after the intervention, approximately 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ecological momentary assessment surveys will query for maternal mood and perceived stress throughout the day.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate response to momentary stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after the intervention, approximately 3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived and received support in response to momentary stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after the intervention, approximately 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ecological momentary assessment and audio recording will be used to measure perceived and received social support and loneliness throughout the day.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension in Pregnancy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phone-delivered mindfulness training</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prenatal care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness training</intervention_name>
    <description>Phone-delivered brief mindfulness training based on principles of MBSR</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Singleton pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  less than 20 weeks' gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood pressure &lt; 140/90&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One of the following: history of preeclampsia, diabetes, renal disease, autoimmune&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple gestations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current severe depression or psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ongoing mind-body practice (e.g., yoga, meditation, mindfulness =&gt; once a week).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Margaret H Bublitz</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Miriam Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Margaret H Bublitz, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>4017937884</phone>
    <email>margaret_bublitz@brown.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lifespan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Margaret Bublitz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Research Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>blood pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>ecological momentary assessment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Pregnancy-Induced</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

