<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04627311</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IAssistenciaSanitaria</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04627311</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-term Benefits of Cardiac Rehabilitation Programme</brief_title>
  <official_title>Long-term Benefits of Cardiac Rehabilitation Programme</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut d'Assistència Sanitària</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut d'Assistència Sanitària</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A retrospective observational study was conducted on a cohort of 213 patients referred to the&#xD;
      Cardiac Rehabilitation programme of Santa &quot;Caterina&quot; Hospital (&quot;Girona&quot;, Spain) following&#xD;
      acute coronary syndrome (ACS). We evaluated the long-term control of Cardiovascular Risk&#xD;
      Factors and the occurrence of major adverse cardiac events (MACE) in a 3-year period of&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A retrospective observational study was conducted on a cohort of 213 patients referred to the&#xD;
      Cardiac Rehabilitation programme of &quot;Santa Caterina&quot; Hospital (&quot;Girona&quot;, Spain) following&#xD;
      acute coronary syndrome (ACS). We evaluated the long-term control of Cardiovascular Risk&#xD;
      Factors and the occurrence of major adverse cardiac events (MACE) in a 3-year period of&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      we found that short-term CVRF control was significantly improved after discharge from the CR&#xD;
      unit for all CVRF analysed (LDLc, Systolic blood pressure, tobacco consumption, HbA1C and BMI&#xD;
      (body mass index)). Long-term control of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-c) and&#xD;
      tobacco consumption was maintained from post-CR to year three, although both showed a trend&#xD;
      towards deterioration. There was a significant increase in systolic blood pressure and&#xD;
      glycosylated haemoglobin (HbA1C) and body mass index (BMI) from post-CR to year three.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular Risk Factors control</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine whether the control of the CVRF (tobacco consumption, hypertension, hyperlipidaemia, diabetes mellitus type 2 and overweight) is maintained at long term (after 3 years of discharge of the CR unit), among all patients referred to the hospital-based CR programme of Santa &quot;Caterina&quot; Hospital from &quot;Girona&quot; area, after suffering an ACS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Major Adverse Cardiovascular Events (MACE)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the incidence of MACE (Major Adverse Cardiovascular Events:&#xD;
ACS, need for revascularization by percutaneous intervention or coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG), stroke, cardiovascular death and/or sudden death) among all patients post-ACS referred to the hospital-based CR programme of Santa &quot;Caterina&quot; Hospital, after 3 years of follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">213</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Risk Factor</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Rehabilitation</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consecutive individuals referred to the hospital-based Cardiac Rehabilitation programme&#xD;
        through the Cardiology unit at Santa Caterina Hospital of Girona, after suffering an ACS,&#xD;
        with a 3-year period follow-up. A target population of 227 patients were referred to the CR&#xD;
        unit during this period. According to inclusion and exclusion criteria, 213 patients were&#xD;
        recruited in the retrospective analysis of Girona's health region.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients enrolled in the hospital-based Cardiac Rehabilitation programme of Santa&#xD;
             Caterina Hospital of Girona from January 2008, with a 3-year period follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with ACS - including STEMI, NSTEMI and unstable angina (UA)&#xD;
             admitted in the cardiology unit of Santa Caterina Hospital of Girona and Hospital&#xD;
             Universitari Dr. Josep Trueta of Girona.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients able to read the information paper and to provide written informed consent of&#xD;
             the Cardiac Rehabilitation programme of the Santa Caterina Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients enrolled in the hospital-based Cardiac Rehabilitation programme of Santa&#xD;
             Caterina Hospital of Girona with a different diagnosis of heart disease:&#xD;
             cardiovascular surgery, congestive heart failure, heart valve disease, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Data unavailable for a 3-year follow-up study ± 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe comorbidities or limitation for physical activity, and thus,&#xD;
             inability to undergo Cardiac Rehabilitation programmes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stress test with induced significative ischemia with low charge of exercise,&#xD;
             arrhythmia induced with the exercise or hypotension response to this.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ventricular arrhythmias and other malignant arrhythmias&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

