<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04628117</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HospitalCJIM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04628117</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Oral Nutritional Supplementation on Oxidative Stress in Protein-energy Wasting Patients With Peritoneal Dialysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assess Effect of Oral Nutritional Supplementation on Oxidative Stress Levels in Protein-energy Wasting Patients With Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Civil Juan I. Menchaca</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Civil Juan I. Menchaca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      End-stage kidney disease (ESKD) represents a serious public health problem in Mexico. Data&#xD;
      from the United States Renal Data System (USRDS) have reported that the region of Jalisco&#xD;
      (Mexico) is one of the places with the highest incidence rate of treated ESKD and use of&#xD;
      peritoneal dialysis (PD). In patients with ESKD, oxidative stress (OS) has been recognized as&#xD;
      a potential source of morbidity and mortality, since it is involved in the pathogenesis of&#xD;
      atherosclerosis and other complications of ESRD. This can induce damage to DNA (nucleic&#xD;
      acid), proteins, carbohydrates, and lipids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another common complication in ESKD patients receiving PD is protein-energy wasting (PEW),&#xD;
      which is characterized by the decline in the body stores of protein and energy fuels (that&#xD;
      is, body protein and fat masses) due to the multiple nutritional and catabolic alterations&#xD;
      that occur in this condition. Diverse factors can affect the nutritional and metabolic status&#xD;
      of patients with PD, for which they require interventions to reverse protein and energy&#xD;
      depletion. Nutritional counseling can be a useful tool in PD patients in order to improve&#xD;
      compliance with nutritional recommendations. The strategies more used for PEW include oral&#xD;
      nutritional supplementation. Therefore, the purpose of this study is assess the effect of&#xD;
      oral nutritional supplementation on OS in PEW patients with PD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The detection of patients is carried out in the Nephrology Service of the Hospital Civil de&#xD;
      Guadalajara Dr. Juan I. Menchaca where the selection and exclusion criteria are evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The probabilistic group assignment is carried out using a sealed and opaque envelope.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control group: only nutritional counselling for 8 weeks. Intervention group: nutritional&#xD;
      counselling plus 237 mls per day of oral nutritional supplement for kidney disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Initial evaluation includes, anthropometric parameters and dietary intake. Demographic&#xD;
      characteristics and OS levels, such as oxidants, antioxidants and oxidative DNA damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All nutritional counselling, dietary intake, medical nutrition theraphy (oral nutritional&#xD;
      supplementation), assessment of OS levels, and anthropometric parameters will perform at 0, 4&#xD;
      and 8 weeks of follow up. Protein-energy wasting assessment only in the 0 and 8 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 11, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized clinical trial with two-parallel-group in stable continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis patients.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in oxidative stress levels, oxidants (products of Lipoperoxidation, 8-IP, NO), antioxidants (SOD, catalase, GPx, TAC), and oxidative DNA damage (8-OHdG, hOGG1).</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As measured by the of OS markers, 10 mL of blood samples will be taken prior to nutritional evaluation, 5 mL with 0.1% of ethylenediaminetetraacetic (EDTA) tube and other 5 mL in dry tube. The blood will be centrifuged at 10,000 rpm for 10 min at room temperature; supernatants were stored in aliquots at -80°C until its final processing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change protein-energy wasting and dietary intake</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Description: As measured by 7-point Subjective Global Assesment (SGA), SGA of 1-2 for severe PEW, 3-5 for mild-moderate protein energy wasting will be considered as presence of protein-energy wasting and malnutrition inflammation score (MIS) a score ≥ 6 will be considered as the presence of protein-energy wasting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Oxidative Stress</condition>
  <condition>Protein-Energy Wasting</condition>
  <condition>Malnutrition</condition>
  <condition>Protein-Energy Malnutrition</condition>
  <condition>Oral Nutritional Supplements</condition>
  <condition>Peritoneal Dialysis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nutritional counselling by individualized nutritional plan for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral nutritional supplementation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nutritional counselling by individualized nutritional plan plus oral nutritional supplementation for renal disease (237 mls per day) for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oral nutritional supplementation for kidney disease</intervention_name>
    <description>237 mls per day for 8 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral nutritional supplementation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of protein-energy wasting evaluated by 7-point Subjective Global Assessment&#xD;
             (moderate/severe), and Malnutrition-inflammation Score (a score ≥ 6).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 and &lt;60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receive continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis with at least 3 months of initiation&#xD;
             of renal replacement therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without clinical or biochemical evidence of any infectious process&#xD;
             (peritonitis, urosepsis, endocarditis, soft tissue infection, pneumonia, etc) or&#xD;
             inflammatory systemic disease (systemic lupus erythematosus, vasculitis, connective&#xD;
             tissue disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supplementation with exogenous antioxidants 2 months prior&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking less than 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intermittent peritoneal dialysis or automated peritoneal dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD catheter dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or intolerance to oral nutritional supplement for renal disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sung CC, Hsu YC, Chen CC, Lin YF, Wu CC. Oxidative stress and nucleic acid oxidation in patients with chronic kidney disease. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2013;2013:301982. doi: 10.1155/2013/301982. Epub 2013 Aug 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24058721</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Liakopoulos V, Roumeliotis S, Gorny X, Eleftheriadis T, Mertens PR. Oxidative Stress in Patients Undergoing Peritoneal Dialysis: A Current Review of the Literature. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2017 Dec 27;2017:3494867. doi: 10.1155/2017/3494867. eCollection 2017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29750088</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Roumeliotis S, Eleftheriadis T, Liakopoulos V. Is oxidative stress an issue in peritoneal dialysis? Semin Dial. 2019 Sep;32(5):463-466. doi: 10.1111/sdi.12818. Epub 2019 May 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31044475</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kochlik B, Grune T, Weber D. New findings of oxidative stress biomarkers in nutritional research. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2017 Sep;20(5):349-359. doi: 10.1097/MCO.0000000000000388. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28562491</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Domenici FA, Vannucchi MT, Jordão AA Jr, Meirelles MS, Vannucchi H. DNA oxidative damage in patients with dialysis treatment. Ren Fail. 2005;27(6):689-94.</citation>
    <PMID>16350819</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fouque D, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Kopple J, Cano N, Chauveau P, Cuppari L, Franch H, Guarnieri G, Ikizler TA, Kaysen G, Lindholm B, Massy Z, Mitch W, Pineda E, Stenvinkel P, Treviño-Becerra A, Wanner C. A proposed nomenclature and diagnostic criteria for protein-energy wasting in acute and chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int. 2008 Feb;73(4):391-8. Epub 2007 Dec 19. Erratum in: Kidney Int. 2008 Aug;74(3):393. Trevinho-Becerra, A [corrected to Treviño-Becerra, A].</citation>
    <PMID>18094682</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carrero JJ, Stenvinkel P, Cuppari L, Ikizler TA, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Kaysen G, Mitch WE, Price SR, Wanner C, Wang AY, ter Wee P, Franch HA. Etiology of the protein-energy wasting syndrome in chronic kidney disease: a consensus statement from the International Society of Renal Nutrition and Metabolism (ISRNM). J Ren Nutr. 2013 Mar;23(2):77-90. doi: 10.1053/j.jrn.2013.01.001. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23428357</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ikizler TA, Cano NJ, Franch H, Fouque D, Himmelfarb J, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Kuhlmann MK, Stenvinkel P, TerWee P, Teta D, Wang AY, Wanner C; International Society of Renal Nutrition and Metabolism. Prevention and treatment of protein energy wasting in chronic kidney disease patients: a consensus statement by the International Society of Renal Nutrition and Metabolism. Kidney Int. 2013 Dec;84(6):1096-107. doi: 10.1038/ki.2013.147. Epub 2013 May 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23698226</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mah JY, Choy SW, Roberts MA, Desai AM, Corken M, Gwini SM, McMahon LP. Oral protein-based supplements versus placebo or no treatment for people with chronic kidney disease requiring dialysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020 May 11;5:CD012616. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD012616.pub2.</citation>
    <PMID>32390133</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Prasad N, Gupta A, Sinha A, Sharma RK, Kumar A, Kumar R. Changes in nutritional status on follow-up of an incident cohort of continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis patients. J Ren Nutr. 2008 Mar;18(2):195-201. doi: 10.1053/j.jrn.2007.08.002.</citation>
    <PMID>18267212</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martín-Del-Campo F, González-Espinoza L, Rojas-Campos E, Ruiz N, González J, Pazarín L, Cueto-Manzano AM. Conventional nutritional counselling maintains nutritional status of patients on continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis in spite of systemic inflammation and decrease of residual renal function. Nephrology (Carlton). 2009 Aug;14(5):493-8. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1797.2008.01081.x.</citation>
    <PMID>19674317</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ikizler TA, Burrowes JD, Byham-Gray LD, Campbell KL, Carrero JJ, Chan W, Fouque D, Friedman AN, Ghaddar S, Goldstein-Fuchs DJ, Kaysen GA, Kopple JD, Teta D, Yee-Moon Wang A, Cuppari L. KDOQI Clinical Practice Guideline for Nutrition in CKD: 2020 Update. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020 Sep;76(3 Suppl 1):S1-S107. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2020.05.006. Erratum in: Am J Kidney Dis. 2021 Feb;77(2):308.</citation>
    <PMID>32829751</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital Civil Juan I. Menchaca</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Francisco Gerardo Yanowsky Escatell</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wasting Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Protein-Energy Malnutrition</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cachexia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

