<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02979769</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PVO-1A-204</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016-002526-36</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02979769</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Open-Label Extension Study of Palovarotene to Prevent Heterotopic Ossification in People With Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP) in France</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Open-Label Extension, Efficacy and Safety Study of a Retinoic Acid Receptor Gamma (RARγ)-Specific Agonist (Palovarotene) in the Treatment of Preosseous Flare-ups in Subjects With Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clementia Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ipsen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP) is a rare, severely disabling disease&#xD;
      characterized by heterotopic ossification (HO), i.e., abnormal bone formation, often&#xD;
      associated with painful, recurrent episodes of soft tissue swelling (flare-ups). Lesions&#xD;
      begin in early childhood and lead to progressive ankyloses of major joints with resultant&#xD;
      loss of movement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the ability of different palovarotene dosing regimens to prevent the formation&#xD;
      of new HO will be evaluated in adult and pediatric participants with FOP in France.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this Phase 2, open-label study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy&#xD;
      of different palovarotene dosing regimens in participants with FOP in France. Efficacy will&#xD;
      be assessed based on the ability of palovarotene to prevent the formation of new heterotopic&#xD;
      ossification (HO) as assessed by low-dose whole body computed tomography (WBCT) scan,&#xD;
      excluding head.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants who successfully completed study PVO-1A-201 as well as up to two new adult&#xD;
      participants were followed for up to 24 months. Participants under Amendment 1 will be&#xD;
      followed for up to an additional 48 months. No new participants will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Adult Cohort will include all participants with at least 90% skeletal maturity,&#xD;
      regardless of age. The Pediatric Cohort will include all participants with less than 90%&#xD;
      skeletal maturity. Any Pediatric Cohort participants who achieves ≥90% skeletal maturity&#xD;
      during the study can be considered for enrollment into the Adult Cohort at the discretion of&#xD;
      then Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants that were skeletally immature at their last assessment will be invited back to&#xD;
      participate in a safety follow-up (Part D) that includes yearly visits for up to a 2-year&#xD;
      follow-up period following last dose. No dosing will occur in Part D.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 28, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Annualized change in new HO volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 12 months until the end of the study (up to 72 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by low-dose whole body computed tomography (WBCT) (excluding head)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of participants with new HO</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 12 months for up to 72 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in range of motion (ROM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 6 months for up to 72 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by Cumulative Analogue Joint Involvement Scale (CAJIS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in physical function</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 6 months for up to 72 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by age-appropriate forms of the FOP-Physical Function Questionnaire (FOP-PFQ)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in physical and mental function for participants ≥15 years old and mental function for participants &lt;15 years old</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 6 months for up to 72 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by age-appropriate forms of the Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Global Health Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">9</enrollment>
  <condition>Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Palovarotene</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participants will receive non-flare-up based treatment of 5 mg palovarotene once daily for 24 months.&#xD;
Participants who continued non-flare-up based treatment under Amendment 1 will receive non-flare-up based treatment for up to an additional 48 months (therefore 72 months over the entire study).&#xD;
Participants who start non-flare-up based treatment under Amendment 1 will receive non-flare-up based treatment for up to 48 months.&#xD;
Participants that are skeletally immature will receive weight-adjusted doses.&#xD;
In the event of an eligible flare-up all participants will receive 20 mg palovarotene for 28 days, followed by 10 mg palovarotene for 56 days. Participants under the age of 18 years will receive weight-adjusted doses.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Palovarotene</intervention_name>
    <description>Palovarotene will be taken orally once daily at approximately the same time each day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Palovarotene</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior participation in Amendment 1 of the current study (PVO-1A-204).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written, signed, and dated informed consent and, for participants who are minors,&#xD;
             age-appropriate participant assent (performed according to local regulations).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Accessible for treatment with palovarotene and follow-up (able and willing to travel&#xD;
             to a site for the initial and all follow-up clinic visits).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to undergo low-dose, WBCT scan, excluding head.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of child-bearing potential (FOCBP) must have a negative blood or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test (with sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL) prior to administration of&#xD;
             palovarotene.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and FOCBP participants must agree to remain abstinent from heterosexual sex&#xD;
             during treatment and for 1 month after treatment or, if sexually active, to use two&#xD;
             effective methods of birth control during and for 1 month after treatment.&#xD;
             Additionally, sexually active FOCBP participants must already be using two effective&#xD;
             methods of birth control 1 month before treatment is to start. Specific risk of the&#xD;
             use of retinoids during pregnancy, and the agreement to remain abstinent or use two&#xD;
             effective methods of birth control will be clearly defined in the informed consent and&#xD;
             the participant or legally authorized representatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any reason that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would lead to the inability of&#xD;
             the participant and/or family to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amylase or lipase &gt;2x above the upper limit of normal or with a history of&#xD;
             pancreatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elevated aspartate aminotransferase or alanine aminotransferase &gt;2.5x the upper limit&#xD;
             of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting triglycerides &gt;400 mg/dL with or without therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If currently using vitamin A or beta carotene, multivitamins containing vitamin A or&#xD;
             beta carotene, herbal preparations containing vitamin A or beta carotene, or fish oil,&#xD;
             and unable or unwilling to discontinue use of these products during palovarotene&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants experiencing suicidal ideation (type 4 or 5) or any suicidal behavior&#xD;
             within the past month as defined by the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale&#xD;
             (C-SSRS).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ipsen Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Ipsen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Necker-Enfants Malades, Department of Genetics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://ifopa.org</url>
    <description>Website for the International FOP Association</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://fopfrance.fr</url>
    <description>Website for the French FOP Association</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://clementiapharma.com</url>
    <description>Click here for more information about this study: A Phase 2, Open-Label Extension, Efficacy and Safety Study of a RARγ-Specific Agonist (Palovarotene) in the Treatment of Preosseous Flare-ups in Subjects with Fibrodysplasia Ossificans Progressiva (FOP)</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shimono K, Tung WE, Macolino C, Chi AH, Didizian JH, Mundy C, Chandraratna RA, Mishina Y, Enomoto-Iwamoto M, Pacifici M, Iwamoto M. Potent inhibition of heterotopic ossification by nuclear retinoic acid receptor-γ agonists. Nat Med. 2011 Apr;17(4):454-60. doi: 10.1038/nm.2334. Epub 2011 Apr 3. Erratum in: Nat Med. 2012 Oct;18(10):1592.</citation>
    <PMID>21460849</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 29, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 2, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Open-label extension study</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical trial Phase 2</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy and safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Heterotopic ossification</keyword>
  <keyword>Flare-up</keyword>
  <keyword>Palovarotene</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinoic acide receptor agonist</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinoic acide receptor gamma agonist</keyword>
  <keyword>Clementia</keyword>
  <keyword>Myositis Ossificans</keyword>
  <keyword>Munchmeyer's Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>FOP</keyword>
  <keyword>Ipsen</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myositis Ossificans</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

