<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01496976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCC-16622</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>COMB157BUS21T</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>RV-CLL-PI-0560</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01496976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ofatumumab, High Dose Methylprednisolone, Ofatumumab and Lenalidomide Consolidative Therapy for Untreated CLL/SLL</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Ofatumumab in Combination With High Dose Methylprednisolone Followed by Ofatumumab and Lenalidomide Consolidative Therapy for the Treatment of Untreated CLL/SLL The HiLOG Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Celgene Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main purpose of this study is to see if ofatumumab with methylprednisolone followed by&#xD;
      additional treatment with ofatumumab and lenalidomide can help people with Chronic&#xD;
      Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) get rid of their CLL for a long period of time. Researchers also&#xD;
      want to find out if the combination of ofatumumab with methylprednisolone followed by&#xD;
      additional treatment with ofatumumab and lenalidomide is safe and tolerable.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II, single institution, and non-randomized study of patients with untreated&#xD;
      CLL/SLL, utilizing a two-stage trial design. The primary endpoint for this trial is the&#xD;
      combined complete and partial response rate (at 3 months-the end of cycle 3) to the protocol&#xD;
      therapy. We anticipate this trial will have a complete response (CR) and partial response&#xD;
      (PR) rate of at least 80%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A two-stage design is employed for this trial. The null/unacceptable CR+PR response rate is ≤&#xD;
      60% while the anticipated true response rate to the protocol treatment is at least 80% for&#xD;
      each disease cohort. At the first stage, 26 patients will be accrued to the trial. If 15 or&#xD;
      fewer of these patients respond, then the trial will be terminated early and the response&#xD;
      rate to the protocol treatment will be deemed unacceptable (≤ 60%). Otherwise, if more than&#xD;
      15 patients respond during the first stage, an additional 19 patients will be enrolled to&#xD;
      this trial during stage 2 for a total of 45 patients. If 32 or fewer of these 45 patients&#xD;
      respond to the protocol treatment at the end of stage 2, no further investigation of the&#xD;
      protocol treatment is considered warranted. On the other hand, if more than 32 patients out&#xD;
      of the 45 enrolled patients respond, the protocol treatment will be considered promising. If&#xD;
      the true response rate is ≤ 60%, the probability of ending the trial at stage 1 is 0.48. If,&#xD;
      however, the true response rate is at least 80%, then the probability of ending the trial at&#xD;
      stage 1 is only 0.01. This two-stage design has an overall alpha level of 0.045 and a power&#xD;
      of 0.90.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 30, 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Complete Response (CR)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint for this trial is the combined complete and partial response rate to the protocol therapy at 3 months, which is also the end of Cycle 3. The objective response (CR+PR) rate will be summarized using both a point estimate and its exact confidence interval based on the binomial distribution.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Partial Response (PR)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint for this trial is the combined complete and partial response rate to the protocol therapy at 3 months, which is also the end of Cycle 3. The objective response (CR+PR) rate will be summarized using both a point estimate and its exact confidence interval based on the binomial distribution.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Progression/Relapse Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS), defined as the time from study entry to disease progression, relapse or death due to any cause, whichever is earlier, will be summarized with the Kaplan-Meier curve. Confidence intervals for the median and survival rates at different time points will be constructed if needed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival will be summarized with the Kaplan-Meier curve.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combination Regimen Followed by Consolidative Therapy: Ofatumumab/High Dose Methylprednisolone (HDMP) plus Ofatumumab/Lenalidomide</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>High Dose Methylprednisolone (HDMP)</intervention_name>
    <description>HDMP will be administered at 1 gm/m^2 IV over 90 minutes daily with ofatumumab infusions 1-8.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HDMP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ofatumumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ofatumumab infusion will be administered immediately after HDMP.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Arzerra®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>The Lenalidomide Starting Dose (Cycle 4) Based on Renal Function Prior to Cycle 4 of Treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Revlimid®</other_name>
    <other_name>IMiD® compound</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed CD5+/CD20+ B-Cell chronic&#xD;
             lymphocytic leukemia or small lymphocytic lymphoma. The diagnosis of CLL is based upon&#xD;
             the National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) guidelines. Any outside pathology&#xD;
             slides used as inclusion criteria for the patient will be reviewed at this institution&#xD;
             to confirm the diagnosis. The patient must meet all of the following CLL criteria to&#xD;
             participate in this study: absolute lymphocyte count &gt; 5000/μL; CD20+ and CD5+; Bone&#xD;
             marrow lymphocytes ≥ 30%; Or previous confirmed diagnosis of CLL/SLL with less than&#xD;
             5000/μl or less than 30% lymphocytes in bone marrow.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are eligible if they have stage III or IV disease. Patients with stage 0, I&#xD;
             or II disease will be eligible if they have evidence of active disease defined as one&#xD;
             or more of the following signs/symptoms: Documented weight loss of ≥ 10% over a 6&#xD;
             month period; Febrile episodes of 38 degrees Celsius (100.5 degrees F) or greater for&#xD;
             greater than 2 weeks without evidence of infection; Massive or progressive&#xD;
             splenomegaly defined as &gt; 6 cm below the left costal margin; Massive (&gt; 10 cm in&#xD;
             longest diameter) or progressive lymphadenopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has not received any prior treatment for CLL in the past.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of ≤ 2 at study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory test results within these ranges: Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1000/mm³;&#xD;
             Platelet count ≥ 50,000 /mm³; Renal function assessed by calculated creatinine&#xD;
             clearance ≥ 30ml/min by Cockcroft-Gault formula; Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN); aspartic transaminase (AST/SGOT) and alanine transaminase (ALT/SGPT)&#xD;
             ≤ 2.5 x ULN; Alkaline phosphatase &lt;2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease free of prior malignancies for ≥ 5 years with exception of currently treated&#xD;
             basal cell, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma &quot;in situ&quot; of the cervix&#xD;
             or breast&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All study participants must be registered into the mandatory REMS® program, and be&#xD;
             willing and able to comply with the requirements of REMS®.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential (FCBP)† must have a negative serum or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL within 10 - 14 days and again&#xD;
             within 24 hours prior to prescribing lenalidomide for Cycle 1 (prescriptions must be&#xD;
             filled within 7 days) and must either commit to continued abstinence from heterosexual&#xD;
             intercourse or begin TWO acceptable methods of birth control, one highly effective&#xD;
             method and one additional effective method AT THE SAME TIME, at least 28 days before&#xD;
             she starts taking lenalidomide. FCBP must also agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men&#xD;
             must agree to use a latex condom during sexual contact with a FCBP even if they have&#xD;
             had a successful vasectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to take aspirin (81 or 325 mg) daily as prophylactic anticoagulation (patients&#xD;
             intolerant to acetylsalicylic acid (ASA) may use warfarin or low molecular weight&#xD;
             heparin).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious medical condition, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric illness that&#xD;
             would prevent the subject from signing the informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding females. (Lactating females must agree not to breast feed&#xD;
             while taking lenalidomide).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which places the&#xD;
             patient at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study or confounds&#xD;
             the ability to interpret data from the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of laboratory Tumor Lysis Syndrome (TLS) by Cairo-Bishop Definition. Patients&#xD;
             may be enrolled upon correction of electrolyte abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any other experimental drug or therapy within 28 days of baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to thalidomide&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The development of erythema nodosum if characterized by a desquamating rash while&#xD;
             taking thalidomide or similar drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any prior use of lenalidomide&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent use of other anti-cancer agents or treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known seropositive for or active viral infection with human immunodeficiency virus&#xD;
             (HIV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serology for hepatitis B (HB) defined as a positive test for HBsAg. In&#xD;
             addition, if negative for HBsAg but HBcAb positive and HBsAb negative, a HB DNA test&#xD;
             will be performed and if positive the patient will be excluded. Note: If HBcAb&#xD;
             positive and HBsAb positive, which is indicative of a past infection, the patient can&#xD;
             be included. Patients who are seropositive because of hepatitis B virus vaccine are&#xD;
             eligible. Consult with a physician experienced in care &amp; management of subjects with&#xD;
             hepatitis B to manage/treat subjects who are anti-HBc positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serology for hepatitis C (HC) defined as a positive test for hepatitis C&#xD;
             antibody (HCAb), in which case reflexively perform a HC recombinant immunoblot assay&#xD;
             (RIBA) on the same sample to confirm the result&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have current active hepatic or biliary disease (with exception of&#xD;
             patients with Gilbert's syndrome, asymptomatic gallstones, liver metastases or stable&#xD;
             chronic liver disease per investigator assessment) are ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic or current infectious disease requiring systemic antibiotics, antifungal, or&#xD;
             antiviral treatment such as, but not limited to, chronic renal infection, chronic&#xD;
             chest infection with bronchiectasis, tuberculosis and active Hepatitis C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of significant cerebrovascular disease in the past 6 months or ongoing event&#xD;
             with active symptoms or sequelae&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant cardiac disease including unstable angina, acute myocardial&#xD;
             infarction within 6 months prior to randomization, congestive heart failure [New York&#xD;
             Heart Association (NYHA) III-IV], and arrhythmia unless controlled by therapy, with&#xD;
             the exception of extra systoles or minor conduction abnormalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant concurrent, uncontrolled medical condition including, but not limited to,&#xD;
             renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, neurological, cerebral or&#xD;
             psychiatric disease which in the opinion of the investigator may represent a risk for&#xD;
             the patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Celeste Bello, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.moffitt.org/research--clinical-trials/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Moffitt Cancer Center Clinical Trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 22, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>consolidative therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>combination regimen</keyword>
  <keyword>CLL</keyword>
  <keyword>SLL</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ofatumumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>November 4, 2021</submitted>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

