<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01497444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N1153</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCCTG-N1153</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CDR0000720022</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2012-00095</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U10CA031946</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01497444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sorafenib Tosylate and Hypoxia-Activated Prodrug TH-302 in Treating Patients With Advanced Kidney Cancer or Liver Cancer That Cannot Be Removed By Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study of Sorafenib + TH-302: Phase I in Advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC) and Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) and Phase II in 1st Line Advanced HCC</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Threshold Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alliance for Clinical Trials in Oncology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE: Sorafenib tosylate may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the&#xD;
      enzymes needed for cell growth by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Drugs used in&#xD;
      chemotherapy, such as hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302, work in different ways to stop the&#xD;
      growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving&#xD;
      sorafenib tosylate together with hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302 may kill more tumor cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE: This phase I/II trial studies the side effects and best dose of giving sorafenib&#xD;
      tosylate together with hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302 and to see how well they work in&#xD;
      treating patients with advanced kidney cancer or liver cancer that cannot be removed by&#xD;
      surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the maximum-tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended Phase II dosing (RP2D) for&#xD;
           the combination of sorafenib tosylate and hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302 (TH-302) in&#xD;
           patients with hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and renal cell carcinoma (RCC; non-HCC)&#xD;
           advanced solid tumors. (Phase I)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the overall response rate (RR) determined based on modified RECIST criteria&#xD;
           (Lencioni and Llovet 2010) in patients with advanced HCC receiving sorafenib tosylate&#xD;
           with TH-302. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To characterize overall toxicity profile of sorafenib tosylate + TH-302 within patients&#xD;
           with HCC and RCC (non-HCC) advanced solid tumors. (Phase I)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To characterize the responses of sorafenib tosylate + TH-302 within patients with HCC&#xD;
           and RCC (non-HCC) advanced solid tumors. (Phase I)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the adverse events (AEs) profile and safety profile of sorafenib tosylate in&#xD;
           combination with TH-302 in patients with advanced HCC. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the overall response rate based on standard RECIST criteria in the study&#xD;
           population. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the duration of response based on modified (standard) RECIST criteria in the&#xD;
           study population. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the progression free survival (PFS) in the study population. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the overall survival (OS) in the study population. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) response rate (defined as &gt; 20% decrease of AFP&#xD;
           from baseline) in the study population. (Phase II)&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, phase I dose-escalation study followed by a phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive sorafenib tosylate orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-28 and&#xD;
      hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302 IV over 30 minutes on days 8, 15, and 22. Courses repeat&#xD;
      every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some patients undergo blood sample collection periodically during study for alpha-fetoprotein&#xD;
      analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of dose-limiting toxicity incidents as assessed by CTCAE version 4.0 (Phase I)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MTD of sorafenib tosylate and TH-302 (Phase I)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events as assessed by NCI CTCAE version 4.0 (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate based on standard RECIST criteria (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response based on modified (standard) RECIST criteria (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OS (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AFP response rate (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Kidney Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sorafenib and TH-302</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be administered sorafenib tablets to take twice daily by mouth, every day of each cycle. Patients will also be given TH-302 intravenously (IV) on days 8, 15 and 22 of each cycle. A cycle is 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>hypoxia-activated prodrug TH-302</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>sorafenib and TH-302</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sorafenib tosylate</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>sorafenib and TH-302</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Phase I Registration - Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cytological or histological confirmed diagnosis of advanced hepatocellular or renal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma. HCC patients should not be amenable to treatment with surgery or to&#xD;
             orthotopic liver transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease as defined in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RCC patients only: Tumor progression after receiving standard/approved chemotherapy&#xD;
             and/or targeted agent, where there is no approved therapy or for tumors where&#xD;
             sorafenib based therapy would be standard therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HCC patients only:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  First line (i.e., no prior systemic therapy) or second line (with prior first&#xD;
                  line sorafenib therapy only) advanced HCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Child Pugh class A or B7 liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior chemoembolization, radioembolization, radiofrequency ablation (RFA), or&#xD;
                  other local ablative therapies are permissible if ≥6 weeks from procedure with&#xD;
                  evidence of progression or new metastatic disease, if applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status (PS) 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following laboratory values obtained ≤14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1200/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Peripheral Platelet Count (PLT) ≥75,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (HgB) &gt;8.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤3.0 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SGOT (AST) ≤2.5 x ULN, if subject has HCC or liver metastases ≤5 x UL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SGPT (ALT) ≤2.5 x ULN, if subject has HCC or liver metastases ≤5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  INR ≤1.5 x ULN. Patients receiving anti-coagulation therapy are permitted as long&#xD;
                  as they have a stable INR≤3.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test done ≤7 days prior to registration, for women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential only.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Provide informed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willing to return to Alliance enrolling institution for follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Life expectancy ≥3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase I Registration - Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following because this study involves an investigational agent whose&#xD;
             genotoxic, mutagenic and teratogenic effects on the developing fetus and newborn are&#xD;
             unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men or women of childbearing potential who are unwilling to employ adequate&#xD;
                  contraception for the duration of study participation. Men and women should&#xD;
                  continue to use adequate birth control after the last administration of sorafenib&#xD;
                  and TH-302 under the guidance of their treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-morbid systemic illnesses or other severe concurrent disease which, in the judgment&#xD;
             of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study or&#xD;
             interfere significantly with the proper assessment of safety and toxicity of the&#xD;
             prescribed regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any other investigational agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other active malignancy ≤3 years prior to registration. EXCEPTIONS: Non-melanotic skin&#xD;
             cancer or carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix. NOTE: If there is a history or prior&#xD;
             malignancy, they must not be receiving other specific treatment (other than hormonal&#xD;
             therapy) for their cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequately controlled hypertension (systolic blood pressure of &gt;150 mmHg or&#xD;
             diastolic pressure &gt;100 mmHg on anti-hypertensive medications).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedures, or significant traumatic injury ≤14 days prior to&#xD;
             registration or anticipation of need for elective or planned major surgical procedure&#xD;
             during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification III or IV congestive heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received treatment with radiation therapy or investigational therapy ≤28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RCC patients only: Having received chemotherapy prior to study entry within 5&#xD;
             half-lives of the agent (as described in the package insert), or 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             registration (whichever is shorter) with resolution of side effects from therapy to&#xD;
             ≤grade 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known central nervous system or brain metastasis that are either symptomatic or&#xD;
             untreated. Note: Patients with neurological symptoms must undergo a CT scan/MRI of the&#xD;
             brain to exclude brain metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Subjects with CNS metastases that have been treated and are stable without&#xD;
                  symptoms for ≥ 4 weeks after completion of treatment are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HCC patients only: Cancer potentially amenable to local modalities of therapy or&#xD;
             surgical resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected allergy or hypersensitivity to any component of TH-302, sorafenib,&#xD;
             or any of the sorafenib excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that severely impairs patient's ability to swallow whole pills.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  QTc interval &gt;500 msec on baseline EKG.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented history of prolonged QTc interval ≤ 6 months prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any medication that has documented data or is generally accepted as having&#xD;
             increased risk of QT prolongation and/or Torsades de Pointes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any medications or substances that are inducers or strong or moderate&#xD;
             inhibitors of CYP3A4, see the protocol for a complete listing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fibrolamellar histology HCC, mixed hepatocholangiocarcinoma, hepatic sarcomas and&#xD;
             other non-HCC primary liver tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of lobectomy involving &gt;50% of lobe.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radioembolization within 8 weeks of Day 1 dosing of sorafenib.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase II Registration - Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cytological or histological confirmed diagnosis of hepatocellular carcinoma that is&#xD;
             locally advanced or metastatic and is not amenable to treatment with surgery or to&#xD;
             orthotopic liver transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease as defined in Section 11.0 must have at least&#xD;
             one non-nodal lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First line advanced HCC (i.e., no prior systemic therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child Pugh class A or B7 liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior chemoembolization, radioembolization, radiofrequency ablation (RFA), or other&#xD;
             local ablative therapies are permissible if ≥6 weeks from procedure with evidence of&#xD;
             progression or new metastatic disease, if applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status (PS) 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following laboratory values obtained ≤14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1200/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Peripheral Platelet Count (PLT) ≥75,000/mm^3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (HgB) &gt;8.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤3.0 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SGOT (AST) ≤5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SGPT (ALT) ≤5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤1.5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  INR ≤1.5 x ULN. Patients receiving anti-coagulation therapy are permitted as long&#xD;
                  as they have a stable INR≤3.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test done ≤7 days prior to registration, for women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential only.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide informed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to return to Alliance enrolling institution for follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy ≥3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to receive intravenous contrast for the purpose of imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase II Registration - Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following because this study involves an investigational agent whose&#xD;
             genotoxic, mutagenic and teratogenic effects on the developing fetus and newborn are&#xD;
             unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men or women of childbearing potential who are unwilling to employ adequate&#xD;
                  contraception for the duration of study participation. Men and women should&#xD;
                  continue to use adequate birth control after the last administration of sorafenib&#xD;
                  and TH-302 under the guidance of their treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-morbid systemic illnesses or other severe concurrent disease which, in the judgment&#xD;
             of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study or&#xD;
             interfere significantly with the proper assessment of safety and toxicity of the&#xD;
             prescribed regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any other investigational agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other active malignancy ≤3 years prior to registration. EXCEPTIONS: Non-melanotic skin&#xD;
             cancer or carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix. NOTE: If there is a history or prior&#xD;
             malignancy, they must not be receiving other specific treatment (other than hormonal&#xD;
             therapy) for their cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequately controlled hypertension (systolic blood pressure of &gt;150 mmHg or&#xD;
             diastolic pressure &gt;100 mmHg on anti-hypertensive medications).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedures, or significant traumatic injury ≤14 days prior to&#xD;
             registration or anticipation of need for elective or planned major surgical procedure&#xD;
             during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification III or IV congestive heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received treatment with radiation therapy or investigational therapy ≤28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known central nervous system or brain metastasis that are either symptomatic or&#xD;
             untreated. Note: Patients with neurological symptoms must undergo a CT scan/MRI of the&#xD;
             brain to exclude brain metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Subjects with CNS metastases that have been treated and are stable without&#xD;
                  symptoms for ≥ 4 weeks after completion of treatment are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fibrolamellar histology HCC, mixed hepatocholangiocarcinoma, hepatic sarcomas and&#xD;
             other non-HCC primary liver tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer potentially amenable to local modalities of therapy or surgical resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected allergy or hypersensitivity to any component of TH-302, sorafenib,&#xD;
             or any of the sorafenib excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that severely impairs patient's ability to swallow whole pills.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  QTc interval &gt;500 msec on baseline EKG.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented history of prolonged QTc interval ≤ 6 months prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any medication that has documented data or is generally accepted as having&#xD;
             increased risk of QT prolongation and/or Torsades de Pointes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any medications or substances that are inducers or strong or moderate&#xD;
             inhibitors of CYP3A4, please see protocol for a complete listing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of lobectomy involving &gt;50% of lobe.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radioembolization within 8 weeks of Day 1 dosing of sorafenib.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mitesh J. Borad, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Scottsdale</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85259-5499</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 20, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 20, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 22, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>recurrent adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>recurrent renal cell cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>localized unresectable adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>adult primary hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

