<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01492985</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2009-018198-30</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>ANRS 149 LIGHT</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01492985</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lipopeptide Immunisation With GTU-multiHIV Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a Therapeutic Immunization Strategy Associating a DNA Vaccine (GTU-MultiHIV B) Followed by a Lipopeptide Vaccine (LIPO-5) in the Control of Viral Replication Following Antiretroviral Treatment Interruption in HIV-1 Infected Patients With a CD4 Cell Count ≥ 600/mm3</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ANRS, Emerging Infectious Diseases</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ANRS, Emerging Infectious Diseases</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The combination of GTU-MultiHIV B DNA and LIPO-5 vaccines in a prime-boost strategy is&#xD;
      expected to induce strong and diverse HIV-specific immune responses in HIV-infected patients.&#xD;
      The investigators will carry out the clinical therapeutic immunization &quot;proof of concept&quot;&#xD;
      trial in HIV infected patients. The investigators propose a multi-center double blind&#xD;
      randomized versus placebo phase II clinical trial in patients who are chronic asymptomatic&#xD;
      HIV-infected patients, with undetectable viral load while treated with a potent combination&#xD;
      of antiviral drugs. Patients will continue antiviral therapy combined with either therapeutic&#xD;
      vaccination or placebo vaccination. Patients will undergo the procedure which includes a&#xD;
      prime with the GTU-MultiHIV B DNA vaccine or placebo administered by IM injections via&#xD;
      Biojector (a needle-free injection system) followed by a boost of LIPO-5 vaccine or placebo&#xD;
      also given IM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In total, 105 HIV-1 patients will be enrolled: 35 in the placebo arm and 70 in the vaccine&#xD;
      arm. Patients will receive antiretroviral treatments and 3 administrations of DNA vaccine or&#xD;
      its placebo at weeks 0, 4 and 12 (corresponding to prime vaccinations). They also receive 2&#xD;
      doses of LIPO-5 vaccines or its placebo at week 20 and 24 (corresponding to boost&#xD;
      vaccinations). At week 36 antiretroviral treatments will be interrupted until week 48.&#xD;
      Patients will be intensely monitored during the treatment interruption period. After start of&#xD;
      cART treatment (at the latest in W48), a data collection from clinical car will be carried&#xD;
      out. A blood sample with W74 will allow to study the persistence ot the immunizing responses,&#xD;
      1 year after the injection of the last vaccine/placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary efficacy endpoint is a plasma HIV-1 RNA level at week 48 (e.g. 12 weeks after&#xD;
      stopping all antiviral treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main hypothesis for conducting a phase II randomized trial is that immune responses in&#xD;
      vaccinated patients may be associated with a better control of viral replication following&#xD;
      c-ART interruption as compared to placebo-vaccinated patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 8, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma HIV-1 RNA level</measure>
    <time_frame>week 48 (W48)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma HIV-RNA after stopping antiviral treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>W40, W44, W48 and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with plasma HIV-RNA below 10 000 copies/mL</measure>
    <time_frame>W48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ultrasensitive proviral DNA</measure>
    <time_frame>W-3, W20, W32 and W44</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CD4 T cell counts</measure>
    <time_frame>W40, W44 and W48 or prior HAART resumption and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentages of patients who resumed HAART</measure>
    <time_frame>between W36 and W48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentages of patients who reached CD4 cell counts &lt; 350/mm3 confirmed two weeks apart</measure>
    <time_frame>between W36 and W48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Strength of HIV-specific CD4/CD8 responses</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W16, W28, W48 or at the time of failure anw W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of responders to at least one HIV peptide pool</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W16, W28, W48 or at the time of failure and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Breadth of CD4/CD8+ HIV-specific responses defined as the number of HIV pools recognized among the 18 pools</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W16, W28, W48 or at the time of failure and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Polyfunctionality of HIV specific T cell responses evaluated by the mean proportion of CD4/CD8+ T cells producing IL-2 and/or IFN-g following ex-vivo stimulation with HIV-1 peptide pools</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W16, W28, W48 and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events &gt; grade 2</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W4, W12, W16, W20, W24, W28, W32, W36, W38, W40, W42, W44, W48 and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AIDS-defining events and serious non-AIDS events defined as cardiovascular diseases, kidney diseases, end stage liver diseases, non-AIDS defining malignancies except basal cellular skin cancer, and bacterial infections</measure>
    <time_frame>W0, W4, W12, W16, W20, W24, W28, W32, W36, W38, W40, W42, W44, W48 and W74</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of predictive factors for plasma HIV-RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>W48</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">103</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV-1 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine placebos</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vaccine placebos corresponding to the dilutant of these vaccines</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebos of GTU-multiHIV B and LIPO-5 vaccines</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebos corresponds respectively to 1X PBS pH = 7.2 and glucose 5%</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine placebos</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GTU-multHIV B vaccine and LIPO-5 vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Vaccines are respectively an HIV-DNA plasmid and a mixture of 5 HIV-lipopeptides.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented HIV-1 infection (ELISA and Western blot)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years and &lt; 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of CDC category C clinical events (1993), including cutaneous Kaposi's&#xD;
             sarcoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CD4 Nadir ≥ 300/mm3 Under antiretroviral treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CD4 ≥ 600/mm3 on all measurements within the previous 6 months* prior to W-3 screening&#xD;
             visit (one single CD4 value between 550-600 cells/ mm3 is permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CD4 value ≥ 600/ mm3 at W-3 screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plasma HIV1-RNA &lt; 50 copies/mL on all measurements within the previous 6 months* (An&#xD;
             occasional measurement of HIV-1 RNA (so-called &quot; blip &quot; between 50 and 200 copies/mL&#xD;
             is permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV1-RNA &lt; 50 copies/mL at W-3 screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
             * In the absence of measurement in the last 6 months, a measurement performed in the&#xD;
             last 12 months is accepted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with a combination of antiviral drugs (cART) for at least 18 months&#xD;
             regardless of the combination, under condition that :&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  in the W24 visit the non-nucleoside inhibitors are replaced by a protease&#xD;
                  inhibitor potentiated by ritonavir&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  no failure or resistance to the protease inhibitor was previously reported&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With adequate method of contraception and negative pregnancy test (βHCG plasma) for&#xD;
             women of childbearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory parameters at W-3:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  polynuclear neutrophils ≥ 1,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  haemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  platelets ≥ 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  creatinine ≤ 1.5 x N&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST, ALT, bilirubin ≤ 2.5 x N&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  proteinuria ≤ 1 g/L (++)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  anti-nuclear antibodies ≤ 1/320&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  anticardiolipin antibodies ≤ 30 U&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  no lupus anticoagulant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agreeing to be treated and followed for at least 74 weeks according to the&#xD;
             protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agreeing to interrupt his/her cART treatment and, if applicable, to&#xD;
             replace the non-nucleoside inhibitors by a protease inhibitor potentiated by ritonavir&#xD;
             at W24&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agreeing to the use of condom, in particular during ART interruption&#xD;
             period (between the visit S36 and the visite S48)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant covered by HealthInsurance (article L1121-11 of Code de la Santé Publique)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent (at the latest the day of pre-inclusion and before all exams&#xD;
             to be done in the context of the trial) (article L1122-1-1 of Code de la Santé&#xD;
             Publique).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV-2 infection (isolated or associated with HIV-1),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of (experimental) vaccinations against HIV,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with chemotherapy or interferon alpha (IFN-α-2b), sargramostim (GM-CSF),&#xD;
             IL-2 or IL-7 ongoing or in the previous12 weeks before inclusion (W0),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with corticoids or immunosuppressive agents ongoing or in the previous12&#xD;
             weeks before inclusion in the trial (W0),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of a live vaccine within 60 days prior to inclusion in the trial (W0)&#xD;
             or any other inactivated vaccine within 14 days before W0 visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned administration, during the follow-up of participants, of a vaccine other than&#xD;
             those recommended in France as part of the usual care of patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cancer (except basal cellular skin carcinoma),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiovascular disease (angina, myocardial infarction, transient ischemic&#xD;
             attack, stroke),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of renal failure related to HIV,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of thrombocytopenia related to HIV (&lt;50,000/mm3),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing cardiac, pulmonary, thyroid, renal or neurological (peripheral or central)&#xD;
             diseases,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive infection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-infection with hepatitis B (HBsAg + or isolated anti-HBc antibodies +) or hepatitis&#xD;
             C (anti-HCV antibody and PCR +),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to aminoglycosides,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person placed under juridical protection (article L1122-2 of Code de la Santé&#xD;
             Publique)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person participating in another biomedical research with an exclusion period always&#xD;
             ongoing at screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yves Lévy, PU-PH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpital Henri Mondor - Créteil - France</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Geneviève Chêne, PU-PH</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>CMG-EC de l'INSERM U897 / ANRS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service d'Immunologie clinique, Centre de vaccination anti-VIH ANRS Mondor Ile-de-France, Hôpital Henri Mondor</name>
      <address>
        <city>Créteil</city>
        <zip>94010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 13, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 15, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 2, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 2, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 5, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

