<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03440008</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>F2318-W</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03440008</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving the Detection, Classification and Treatment of Misaligned Arthritic Ankles</brief_title>
  <acronym>IDCT</acronym>
  <official_title>Improving the Detection, Classification and Treatment of Misaligned Arthritic Ankles</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Veteran population is prone to foot and ankle maladies from common injuries such as&#xD;
      sprains, and diseases such as ankle osteoarthritis (cartilage damage). More specific to&#xD;
      Veterans are prior service injuries of the foot and ankle, which historically account for&#xD;
      nearly a quarter of injuries received. These injuries include bone fractures and ligament&#xD;
      damage. Some of these injuries may lead to poor ankle joint alignment, which over time could&#xD;
      lead to osteoarthritis due to abnormal wear on a day to day basis. The goal of this proposal&#xD;
      is to use a novel technology - biplane fluoroscopy, to study the movement of ankles which are&#xD;
      misaligned in subjects with ankle osteoarthritis. This proposal will also benefit current&#xD;
      diagnostic methods with additional information. Last, this proposal will test the&#xD;
      effectiveness of a conservative treatment (modified shoe insoles) to correct or reduce the&#xD;
      misalignment in ankles. This proposal will create evidence about: the nature of ankle&#xD;
      osteoarthritis, the accuracy of diagnosing alignment, and conservative treatment for patients&#xD;
      with ankle OA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ankle osteoarthritis (OA) is a debilitating and mobility limiting condition. It can commonly&#xD;
      stem from the result of a traumatic injury - such trauma has a high prevalence in military&#xD;
      service. If cartilage is not severely damaged in that trauma, the stability and alignment of&#xD;
      the joint may be. Over time, an unstable or misaligned ankle joint can experience abnormal&#xD;
      rates of cartilage wear and tear due to aberrant kinematics. While OA may take decades to&#xD;
      develop, the resulting arthritic state from this trauma will ultimately require ankle&#xD;
      replacement or fusion, consequences with a tremendous financial burden and quality of life&#xD;
      impact.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With regards to alignment, particularly in the coronal plane, current clinical diagnosis&#xD;
      relies on static X-ray of the ankle joint. Static images may not indicate dynamic&#xD;
      misalignment during gait. Further, the effect of wedged insoles, a potential conservative&#xD;
      treatment, on the restoration of ankle function is undocumented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This proposal aims to use biplane fluoroscopy, an X-ray based dynamic imaging approach, to&#xD;
      measure ankle kinematics in OA subjects (with varus, neutral and valgus ankle alignment) and&#xD;
      controls. With this method, tibio-talar kinematics during gait can be measured. Furthermore,&#xD;
      subjects classified as neutral from their static radiograph, but that exhibit ankle varus or&#xD;
      valgus alignment during gait, will be identified. Improving the accuracy of a diagnostic&#xD;
      outcome provides a patient group with additional avenues for treatment. The investigators&#xD;
      will investigate correlations between the investigators' 3D kinematics and clinical 2D&#xD;
      imaging - to the benefit of clinical diagnostics. The investigators will also be able to&#xD;
      measure the effect of wedged insoles on the restoration of ankle function. With this in mind,&#xD;
      the following aims and methodology are proposed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1: To investigate ankle kinematics in controls and subjects with OA. In support&#xD;
      of Specific Aim 1, 90 ankle OA subjects will be recruited (30 each of varus, neutral or&#xD;
      valgus aligned ankles). The investigators will also recruit 20 control subjects. Subjects&#xD;
      will receive CT scans of their feet to quantify bone geometry (a step necessary for biplane&#xD;
      fluoroscopy). Subjects will then be imaged in the biplane system during gait trials and while&#xD;
      wearing neutral study shoes. This will yield tibio-talar kinematics during gait for these&#xD;
      populations. Specific Aim 2: To identify dynamically misaligned ankles in OA subjects who are&#xD;
      currently classified as neutrally aligned using static analysis. The investigators will&#xD;
      compare the static X-ray and the gait kinematics of OA subjects, particularly those with&#xD;
      clinically determined neutral alignment. The investigators will determine what proportion of&#xD;
      neutral OA subjects actually exhibit misalignment during gait and are thus improperly&#xD;
      categorized. The investigators will also re-create 2D clinical X-ray views from the&#xD;
      investigators' 3D data in an attempt to translate the investigators' improvement (with 3D&#xD;
      fluoroscopy) to more accurately classify alignment to clinical 2D diagnostics. Specific Aim&#xD;
      3: To evaluate the potential of lateral or medial wedging to restore alignment in misaligned&#xD;
      ankle OA subjects. OA subjects will be imaged wearing shoes with wedged insoles which&#xD;
      correspond to their type of misalignment. Neutral OA subjects, who demonstrate misalignment&#xD;
      during gait, will be recalled for a wedged insole session. This yields conservative treatment&#xD;
      kinematics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will generate baseline data describing the kinematics of control and ankle OA&#xD;
      subjects. This data is not currently available in the literature, and represents a novel&#xD;
      contribution to the field. Second, this proposal determines how accurate current 2D X-ray&#xD;
      methods are at detecting dynamic misalignment. This information can inform clinicians about&#xD;
      the accuracy of their diagnostic tools, and may lead to improvements. Third, this proposal&#xD;
      will generate data to evaluate the utility of wedged insoles for the conservative management&#xD;
      of ankle misalignment. In Summary, this study has immediate impact potential on the diagnosis&#xD;
      and treatment of ankle OA. Last, there are numerous additional avenues of classification,&#xD;
      diagnostic, and preventative research for the benefit of the Veterans which will stem from&#xD;
      this Career Development Award.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;As a consequence of the COVID-19 pandemic, and after consultation with the appropriate&#xD;
      research oversight, regulatory and monitoring entities, screening and enrollment has been&#xD;
      placed on temporary administrative hold as of 03/16/2020.&quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 13, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tibio-talar kinematics during gait</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hour session</time_frame>
    <description>The 3D movement between the tibia and talus bones will be assessed using biplane fluoroscopy, for OA and control subjects during shod gait.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Static ankle alignment sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hour session</time_frame>
    <description>The sensitivity to correctly diagnose dynamic misalignment by using static x-ray images, will be determined for the OA population.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decrease in misalignment during gait using wedged insoles</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hour session</time_frame>
    <description>The effect that wedged insoles have on varus / valgus misalignment will be assessed using dynamic 3D x-ray</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Ankle Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Able-bodied, age matched subjects with no foot and ankle pathology</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OA</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects with ankle OA, with all classifications of ankle misalignment (varus, neutral, valgus)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dynamic 3D bone motion capture</intervention_name>
    <description>Two x-ray systems will image the subjects ankle while they walk, allowing us to calculate ankle joint angle and alignment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>OA</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Biplane fluoroscopy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>wedged insole</intervention_name>
    <description>medial or lateral wedge (appropriate for varus or valgus misalignment) will be applied during 1 data collection session to evaluate effect of wedging on misalignment</description>
    <arm_group_label>OA</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>orthotic/insole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>None Retained</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      No biospecimens will be collected for this study&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Controls and those with ankle osteoarthritis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be ambulatory (able to walk at least 15 m, and tolerate ~1 hour of standing and&#xD;
             walking with rest periods)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (&lt;1 year) surgical, neurological, metabolic or lower limb musculoskeletal&#xD;
             problem that might impair the ambulation measures in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Such as severe knee or hip osteoarthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with diabetes, peripheral neuropathy, or peripheral vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For OA subjects, a radiographic discontinuity of the cartilage of the tibial plafond&#xD;
             or talar dome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Also for OA subjects, rapid onset of OA (&lt;3 years) following ankle fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of severe ankle instability or deformity such as pes planus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequate cognitive or language function to consent or to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph Iaquinto, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 14, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

