<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03449381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1403-0001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-003210-95</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03449381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>This Study Aims to Find the Best Dose of BI 907828 in Patients With Different Types of Advanced Cancer (Solid Tumors)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ia/Ib, Open Label, Multicenter, Dose-escalation Study of BI 907828 in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boehringer Ingelheim</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boehringer Ingelheim</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is open to adults with different types of advanced cancer (solid tumours).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to find out the highest dose of BI 907828 the participants can&#xD;
      tolerate. In the second part, the study also tests whether BI 907828 makes tumours shrink.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, BI 907828 is given to humans for the first time. BI 907828 is a so-called MDM2&#xD;
      inhibitor that is being developed to treat cancer. BI 907828 is taken as a tablet.&#xD;
      Participants either take a dose of BI 907828 on one day every 3 weeks or on one day in 2&#xD;
      consecutive weeks every 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants are in the study for as long as they benefit from and can tolerate&#xD;
      treatment. The doctors regularly check the participants' general health during the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 21, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 13, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 21, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ia- Maximum tolreated dose (MTD) based on number of patients with dose limiting toxicities (DLTs) during first treatment cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ia - Number of patients with DLTs during first treatment cycle (21 days, Arm A; 28 days, Arm B)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - Number of patients with DLTs during the first treatment cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ia - Cmax: Maximum measured concentration of BI 907828 in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ia - AUC0-∞: Area under the concentration-time curve in plasma over the time interval from 0 extrapolated to infinity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - Objective response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - Number of patients with Grade ≥3 treatment-related adverse events observed during the entire treatment period</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - Cmax: Maximum measured concentration of BI 907828 in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib - AUC0-∞: Area under the concentration-time curve in plasma over the time interval from 0 extrapolated to infinity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">114</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BI 907828</intervention_name>
    <description>Film-coated tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of signed and dated, written informed consent form ICF in accordance with&#xD;
             ICH-GCP and local legislation prior to any trial-specific procedures, sampling, or&#xD;
             analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathologically documented, advanced solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiologically documented disease progression or relapse during or after all standard&#xD;
             of care treatments. Patients who are not eligible to receive standard of care&#xD;
             treatments, and for whom no proven treatments exist, are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ia (dose escalation) only:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Patient has a tumor with either a known TP53 wild type status, or unknown TP53&#xD;
             status, and regardless of MDM2 amplification status, at the time of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ib (expansion phase) only:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cohort 1: TP53 wt and MDM2-non-amplified solid tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cohort 2: TP53 wt and MDM2- amplified solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ia (dose escalation) only:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient with either measurable or non-measurable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-evaluable disease allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ib (expansion phase) only:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --At least one target lesion that can be accurately measured per RECIST v.1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be willing to submit the blood sampling for the PK, PD, biomarker, and&#xD;
             PGx analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability and willingness to provide a fresh tumor tissue sample obtained after&#xD;
             relapse or progression during or after prior therapy. In case a fresh biopsy cannot be&#xD;
             obtained (e.g. inaccessible lesions or patient safety concern), an archived specimen,&#xD;
             collected before screening, may be submitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female ≥18 years old (for Japan, ≥20 years old) at the time of signature of&#xD;
             the ICF&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status of 0 or 1 (an ECOG of 2 is acceptable, if it is due to&#xD;
             noncancer-related disability, and after agreement with Sponsor).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks after the start of the treatment according to the&#xD;
             Investigator's judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patients. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP, defined as female&#xD;
             patients who are premenopausal or who had no cessation of menses within 12 months&#xD;
             without an alternative medical cause, but not including female patients who are&#xD;
             permanently sterilized) and men able to father a child must be ready and able to use&#xD;
             two highly effective methods of birth control per ICH M3 (R2) that result in a low&#xD;
             failure rate of less than 1% per year when used consistently and correctly beginning&#xD;
             at screening, during trial participation and until 35 days and 3 months, respectively&#xD;
             for women and men, after trial completion (i.e. after the last administration of trial&#xD;
             medication). A list of contraception methods meeting these criteria is provided in the&#xD;
             patient information.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous administration of BI 907828 or any other MDM2-p53 or MDMX (MDM4)- p53&#xD;
             antagonist.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a tumor with a documented mutation in the TP53 gene determined previously&#xD;
             or at screening irrespective of MDM2 amplification status. For dose escalation part&#xD;
             only, patients who have tumors with unknown TP53 and/or MDM2 status at the time of&#xD;
             screening are eligible at investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or untreated brain metastases from non-brain tumors; Note: Patients with&#xD;
             previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are stable, without&#xD;
             evidence of progression by imaging (using the identical imaging modality for each&#xD;
             assessment, either MRI or computed tomography (CT) scan), for at least four weeks&#xD;
             prior to the first dose of trial treatment, and any neurologic symptoms have returned&#xD;
             to baseline; have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases. Patients on&#xD;
             corticosteroids must have a stable dose for at least 5 days prior to baseline MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of warfarin, factor Xa inhibitors and direct thrombin inhibitors. Note:&#xD;
             Low molecular weight heparin and prophylactic low dose warfarin are permitted; PT/PTT&#xD;
             must meet the inclusion criteria; patients taking low dose warfarin must have their&#xD;
             INR followed according to institutional guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of bleeding diathesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery (major according to the Investigator's assessment) performed within 12&#xD;
             weeks prior to start of study treatment, or planned within 12 months after screening&#xD;
             (e.g. hip replacement).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other documented active or suspected malignancy or history of malignancy within 3&#xD;
             years prior to screening, except appropriately treated basal cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
             skin or in situ carcinoma of uterine cervix, or other local tumors considered cured by&#xD;
             local treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who must or wish to continue the intake of restricted medications (see&#xD;
             Section 4.2.2.1) or any drug considered likely to interfere with the safe conduct of&#xD;
             the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in another investigational device or drug trial, or less than 30&#xD;
             days since receiving other investigational treatments. Patients who are in followup/&#xD;
             observation for another clinical trial are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have been treated with any other anticancer drug other than antibodies&#xD;
             within 4 weeks or within 5 half-life periods (whichever come earlier) prior to first&#xD;
             administration of BI 907828. For patients who have been previously treated with&#xD;
             antibodies, within approximately 3 half-life periods prior to first administration of&#xD;
             BI 907828.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent toxicity from previous treatments that has not resolved to ≤ CTCAE Grade 1&#xD;
             (except for alopecia and CTCAE Grade 2 neuropathy, or asthenia/fatigue).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, acute or chronic viral hepatitis.&#xD;
             Patients with a history of hepatitis B virus infection, irrespective of their&#xD;
             reactivation risk status, should also be excluded. The testing at screening is not&#xD;
             mandatory and left at the discretion of investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to the trial drug or its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious concomitant disease or medical condition affecting compliance with trial&#xD;
             requirements or which are considered relevant for the evaluation of the efficacy or&#xD;
             safety of the trial drug, such as neurologic, psychiatric, infectious disease or&#xD;
             active ulcers (gastro-intestinal tract, skin) or laboratory abnormality that may&#xD;
             increase the risk associated with trial participation or trial drug administration,&#xD;
             and in the judgment of the Investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for&#xD;
             entry into the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic alcohol or drug abuse or any condition that, in the Investigator's opinion,&#xD;
             makes them an unreliable trial patient or unlikely to complete the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, nursing, or who plan to become pregnant while in the trial;&#xD;
             female patients who do not agree to the interruption of breast feeding from the start&#xD;
             of study treatment to within 30 days after the last study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following cardiac criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mean resting corrected QT interval (QTcF) &gt;470 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any clinically important abnormalities (as assessed by the investigator) in&#xD;
                  rhythm, conduction, or morphology of resting ECGs, e.g., complete left bundle&#xD;
                  branch block, third degree heart block&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any factors that increase the risk of QTc prolongation or risk of arrhythmic&#xD;
                  events such as heart failure, hypokalaemia, congenital long QT syndrome, family&#xD;
                  history of long QT syndrome or unexplained sudden death under 40 years-of-age, or&#xD;
                  any concomitant medication known to prolong the QT interval&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ejection fraction (EF) &lt;50% or the lower limit of normal of the institutional&#xD;
                  standard. Only in cases where the Investigator (or the treating physician or&#xD;
                  both) suspects cardiac disease with negative effect on the EF, will the EF be&#xD;
                  measured during screening using an appropriate method according to local&#xD;
                  standards to confirm eligibility (e.g., echocardiogram, multi-gated acquisition&#xD;
                  scan). A historic measurement of EF no older than 6 months prior to first&#xD;
                  administration of study drug can be accepted provided that there is clinical&#xD;
                  evidence that the patient's cardiac disease has not significantly worsened since&#xD;
                  this measurement in the opinion of the Investigator or of the treating physician&#xD;
                  or both.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of concomitant medications that are narrow therapeutic index drugs that are&#xD;
                  substrates of P-gp or BCRP (e.g. digoxin, dabigatran, etexilate).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Boehringer Ingelheim</last_name>
    <phone>1-800-243-0127</phone>
    <email>clintriage.rdg@boehringer-ingelheim.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennessee Oncology, PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Todd Bauer</last_name>
      <phone>+001 (615) 329-7272</phone>
      <email>tbauer@tnonc.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patrick Schöffski</last_name>
      <phone>+32 (0)16 34 69 00</phone>
      <email>patrick.schoffski@uzleuven.be</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ottawa Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ottawa</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>K1H 8L6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Scott Laurie</last_name>
      <phone>613-737-7700 x70175</phone>
      <email>slaurie@toh.on.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Helios Klinikum Berlin-Buch</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13125</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter Reichardt</last_name>
      <phone>+49 3(0) 9401-54801</phone>
      <email>peter.reichardt@helios-gesundheit.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Center Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tokyo, Chuo-ku</city>
        <zip>104-0045</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Noboru Yamamoto</last_name>
      <phone>+81 3 35422511</phone>
      <email>nbryamam@ncc.go.jp</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínic de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Javier García Corbacho</last_name>
      <phone>+34932275400 ext.380748</phone>
      <email>garcia33@clinic.cat</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mystudywindow.com</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 22, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 28, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Clinical studies sponsored by Boehringer Ingelheim, phases I to IV, interventional and non-interventional, are in scope for sharing of the raw clinical study data and clinical study documents, except for the following exclusions:&#xD;
studies in products where Boehringer Ingelheim is not the license holder;&#xD;
studies regarding pharmaceutical formulations and associated analytical methods, and studies pertinent to pharmacokinetics using human biomaterials;&#xD;
studies conducted in a single center or targeting rare diseases (because of limitations with anonymization).&#xD;
For more details refer to: https://www.mystudywindow.com/msw/datasharing</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

