<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03448718</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HCRN GU15-262</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03448718</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial of Olaparib in Patients With Metastatic Urothelial Cancer Harboring DNA Damage Response Gene Alterations</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 2 Trial of Olaparib in Patients With Metastatic Urothelial Cancer Harboring DNA Damage Response Gene Alterations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Matthew Galsky</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a single arm open label multi-institutional phase II trial of olaparib monotherapy in&#xD;
      subjects with metastatic urothelial cancer harboring somatic DNA damage response (DDR)&#xD;
      alterations. The primary objective of the study is to estimate the objective response rate&#xD;
      (per RECIST 1.1) to treatment with olaparib.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 17, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Estimate the objective response rate (per RECIST 1.1 or MD Anderson Criteria for bone-only metastatic disease) to treatment with olaparib in subjects with metastatic urothelial cancer harboring somatic DDR alterations. Objective response rate will include confirmed complete response (CR) + confirmed partial response (PR) and will be determined as per RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival is defined as the time from Day 1 of treatment until the criteria for disease progression is met as defined by RECIST 1.1 or death as a result of any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as the time from Day 1 of treatment until death as a result of any cause.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Event Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>36 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess all grade 3 and 4 adverse events as defined by the NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) v4.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Urothelial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Olaparib Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The starting dose of olaparib tablets will be dependent on the subject's calculated creatinine clearance (CrCl). Subjects with a CrCl of ≥ 40 mL/min will start at a dose of olaparib tablets of 300 mg twice a day. Subjects with a CrCl of &gt; 30 to &lt; 40 mL/min will start at a dose of olaparib tablets 200 mg twice a day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib</intervention_name>
    <description>1 cycle = 28 days. Subject's with calculated creatinine clearance (CrCl) of ≥ 40 mL/min will start at a dose of olaparib tablets of 300 mg twice a day. Subjects with a CrCl of &gt; 30 to &lt; 40 mL/min will start at a dose of olaparib tablets 200 mg twice a day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Olaparib Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lynparza</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent and HIPAA authorization for release of personal health&#xD;
             information prior to registration. NOTE: HIPAA authorization may be included in the&#xD;
             informed consent or obtained separately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status of ≤ 1 within 14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
             Cisplatin-ineligible chemotherapy-naïve subjects (see inclusion criteria #8) may have&#xD;
             an ECOG Performance Status of ≤ 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological evidence/confirmation of urothelial cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metastatic and/or unresectable (cT4b) urothelial cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metastatic disease evaluable on imaging studies. Subjects may have measurable disease&#xD;
             according to RECIST 1.1 or bone-only disease within 30 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Bone-only subjects are eligible if their disease can be documented/&#xD;
                  evaluated by bone scans, CT or MRI. Their disease will be assessed using MD&#xD;
                  Anderson criteria.34&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Previously irradiated lesions are eligible as a target lesion only if there&#xD;
                  is documented progression of the lesion after irradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Somatic alteration considered pathogenic/likely pathogenic in one of the following DDR&#xD;
             genes as determined by genomic sequencing performed in a Clinical Laboratory&#xD;
             Improvement Amendments (CLIA) laboratory. Somatic alterations will include nonsense,&#xD;
             frameshift, splice-site or missense mutations or homozygous deletions. Subjects with&#xD;
             alterations in DDR genes not included in the list below will be considered on a case&#xD;
             by case basis after discussion with the sponsor-investigator(s). Subjects with&#xD;
             germline alterations in DDR genes will be considered on a case by case basis and will&#xD;
             be reviewed by the sponsor-investigator(s). At least 6 subjects will have BRCA or ATM&#xD;
             alterations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nucleotide Excision Repair: ERCC2, ERCC3,ERCC4, ERCC5, ERCC6&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Homologous Recombination: BRCA1, RAD52, BRCA2, RAD54L, RAD50, NBN RAD51, MRE11A,&#xD;
             RAD51B, RAD51D, RAD51C, CTIP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DNA Sensor: ATM, ATR, MDC1, ATRX, CHEK1, CHEK2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fanconi Anemia Pathway: PALB2, FANCE, BRIP1, FANCF, FANCA, FANCG FANCB, BLM, FANCC,&#xD;
             FANCD2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Base Excision Repair: XRCC2, XRCC3, XRCC4, XRCC5, XRCC6&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other: MUTYH, RECQL4, POLQ, POLE, WRN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A subject with prior brain metastasis may be considered if they have completed their&#xD;
             treatment for brain metastasis at least 4 weeks prior to study registration, have been&#xD;
             off of corticosteroids for ≥ 2 weeks, and are asymptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have progressed despite at least 1 prior line of treatment for&#xD;
             metastatic and/or unresectable urothelial cancer. However, cisplatin-ineligible&#xD;
             (defined by a calculated creatinine clearance of &gt;30 but &lt; 60 mL/min OR CTCAE v4 Grade&#xD;
             ≥ 2 audiometric hearing loss OR CTCAE v4 Grade ≥ 2 peripheral neuropathy OR ECOG PS =&#xD;
             2), and chemotherapy-naïve subjects are also eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior cancer treatment (systemic therapy or radiation therapy) must be completed at&#xD;
             least 3 weeks prior to registration and the subject must have recovered from all&#xD;
             reversible acute toxic effects of the regimen (other than alopecia) to Grade ≤ 1 or&#xD;
             baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrate adequate organ function as defined in the table below. All screening labs&#xD;
             to be obtained within 28 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 × ULN (or ≤ 5 × ULN if liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 × ULN (or ≤ 5 × ULN if liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects must be postmenopausal or there must be evidence of non-childbearing&#xD;
             status for women of childbearing potential: negative urine or serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 28 days of study treatment and confirmed prior to treatment on day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential must be willing to abstain from heterosexual&#xD;
             activity or to use 2 forms of highly effective methods of contraception from the time&#xD;
             of informed consent until 90 days after treatment discontinuation. The two&#xD;
             contraception methods can be comprised of two barrier methods, or a barrier method&#xD;
             plus a hormonal method. Males must be willing to abstain from heterosexual activity or&#xD;
             to use 2 forms of highly effective methods of contraception from the time of informed&#xD;
             consent until 90 days after treatment discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  As determined by the enrolling physician or protocol designee, ability of the subject&#xD;
             to understand and comply with study procedures for the entire length of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  15. All subjects must have adequate archival tissue available prior to registration&#xD;
             (i.e., at least 15 unstained slides or paraffin block). Archival tissue should&#xD;
             represent invasive or metastatic urothelial cancer with a preference for metastatic&#xD;
             tissue if available. Archival tissue should be identified at screening and shipped by&#xD;
             C1D1. Subjects without adequate tissue may be considered on a case by case basis after&#xD;
             discussion with the sponsor-investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding (NOTE: breast milk cannot be stored for future use while the&#xD;
             mother is being treated on study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known additional malignancy that is active and/or progressive requiring treatment;&#xD;
             subjects with other malignancies that have been definitively treated and who have been&#xD;
             rendered disease free will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with a PARP inhibitor, including olaparib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study (applies to both AstraZeneca&#xD;
             staff and/or staff at the study site).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resting ECG with QTc &gt; 470 msec on 2 or more time points within a 24 hour period or&#xD;
             family history of long QT syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of known strong CYP3A inhibitors (eg. itraconazole, telithromycin,&#xD;
             clarithromycin, protease inhibitors boosted with ritonavir or cobicistat, indinavir,&#xD;
             saquinavir, nelfinavir, boceprevir, telaprevir) or moderate CYP3A inhibitors (eg.&#xD;
             ciprofloxacin, erythromycin, diltiazem, fluconazole, verapamil). The required washout&#xD;
             period prior to starting olaparib is 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant use of known strong (eg. phenobarbital, enzalutamide, phenytoin,&#xD;
             rifampicin, rifabutin, rifapentine, carbamazepine, nevirapine and St John's Wort) or&#xD;
             moderate CYP3A inducers (eg. bosentan, efavirenz, modafinil). The required washout&#xD;
             period prior to starting olaparib is 5 weeks for enzalutamide or phenobarbital and 3&#xD;
             weeks for other agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with myelodysplastic syndrome/acute myeloid leukemia or with features&#xD;
             suggestive of MDS/AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 2 weeks of starting study treatment and subjects must have&#xD;
             recovered from any effects of any major surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects considered a poor medical risk due to a serious, uncontrolled medical&#xD;
             disorder, non-malignant systemic disease or active, uncontrolled infection. Examples&#xD;
             include, but are not limited to, uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmia, recent (within 3&#xD;
             months) myocardial infarction, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, unstable spinal&#xD;
             cord compression, superior vena cava syndrome, extensive interstitial bilateral lung&#xD;
             disease on High Resolution Computed Tomography (HRCT) scan, history of pneumonitis, or&#xD;
             any psychiatric disorder that prohibits obtaining informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects unable to swallow orally administered medication and subjects with&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disorders likely to interfere with absorption of the study&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised subjects, e.g., subjects who are known to be serologically positive&#xD;
             for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a known hypersensitivity to olaparib or any of the excipients of the&#xD;
             product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with known active hepatitis (i.e. Hepatitis B or C) due to risk of&#xD;
             transmitting the infection through blood or other body fluids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous allogeneic bone marrow transplant or double umbilical cord blood&#xD;
             transplantation (dUCBT)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matthew Galsky, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mt Sinai School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karmanos Cancer Center (Wyane State University)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029-6542</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt-Ingran Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Huntsman Cancer Institute University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112-5550</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 22, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 22, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 28, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hoosier Cancer Research Network</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matthew Galsky</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Sponsor Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

