<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03478579</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC 31/16/8763</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03478579</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Non-technical Skills of Emergency Physicians in a Virtual Emergency Department</brief_title>
  <acronym>3D-QUAMU</acronym>
  <official_title>Nontechnical Skills Assessment of Emergency Physicians and Quality of Care in a Virtual Emergency Department</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Toulouse</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will study nontechnical skills of emergency physicians in a virtual&#xD;
      standardized emergency room and their impact on quality of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ability to manage multiple patients and anticipate the risk of error related to task&#xD;
      interruptions or disruptions has been identified among relevant non-technical skills (NTS)&#xD;
      for practicing emergency medicine. However, the link between these skills and the quality of&#xD;
      care has not been quantified. NTS are usually analyzed by qualitative methods such as&#xD;
      interviews, direct observations, or questionnaires that have low performance according to the&#xD;
      GRADE system (Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have created and validated an experimental model of a virtual, authentic&#xD;
      and realistic Emergency Department (ED). The platform has been modelled in a &quot;Second Life&quot;&#xD;
      environment. The NTS of emergency physicians will be assessed and recorded during simulated&#xD;
      care of multiple virtual patients. The NTS association with ED length of stay and disposition&#xD;
      decision will be analyzed. This study will be an internal pilot study and will include 30&#xD;
      emergency physicians who practice emergency medicine for at least two years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sessions will be performed in the Toulouse Institute of Health Care Simulation, Toulouse&#xD;
      University Hospital. They will be composed of three stages: briefing (30 minutes), simulated&#xD;
      practice (3 hours), and debriefing with an explicit interview (30 minutes). Two researchers&#xD;
      and a computer technician will supervise the sessions. The data will be obtained by analyzing&#xD;
      the video recorded during the simulated practice and the interview.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nontechnical skills</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The nontechnical skills will be assessed by the Anaesthetists' Non-Technical Skills (ANTS) system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of care will be measured by a composite criteria (process and result)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of care will be measured by a composite criterion associating a process indicator and a result indicator :&#xD;
The process indicator is the average time to medical care of patients&#xD;
The result indicator corresponds to the relevance of the choice of the orientation of each patient by the emergency doctor at the end of medical care</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ED length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The quality of care will be assessed by ED length of stay : ED length of stay will be measured from triage completion to disposition decision</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The authenticity of the virtual emergency medicine service</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the consistency : perceived internal consistency in the proposed rules and situations will be assessed using a 4-item questionnaire by answering yes or no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The authenticity of the virtual emergency medicine service</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the realism (the assumed resemblance with a real life reference) will be evaluated through a questionnaire containing 3 areas of comparison between the virtual and real environment (layout of the premises, duration of the actions, staff / patient ratio) with as answer possible for each comparison: Realistic or not realistic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The authenticity of the virtual emergency medicine service</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the relevance (necessary to allow users to take ownership of the problems posed by the designers) will be assessed through direct observation with a yes / no evaluation of the acceptance to use the virtual environment, to test the environment, to make choices during the scenario and to control the environment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Emergencies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emergency physicians</arm_group_label>
    <description>The observational group will be composed of emergency physicians working in the French Midi-Pyrenees region. Physicians must work since 2 years in emergency service</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>observational</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention, it is observational study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emergency physicians</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Emergency physicians working in the French Midi-Pyrénées region&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active emergency physicians working in an ED of the French Midi-Pyrenees region&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Two years of practice in emergency medicine or more&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteer to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergency physician working in another setting than ED, outside the Midi-Pyrenees&#xD;
             region, or practicing emergency medicine for less than 2 years.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dominique Lauque, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Toulouse CHU</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Toulouse</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 8, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 6, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 6, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>serious game</keyword>
  <keyword>simulation</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual emergency department</keyword>
  <keyword>nontechnical skills</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

