<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03477643</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GEM-POMCIDEX</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03477643</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retrospective Viability Study of the PETHEMA-POMCIDEX Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Treatment of Patients With Relapsed and Refractory Multiple Myeloma (RRMM)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Retrospective Viability Study of the PETHEMA-POMCIDEX Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Treatment of Patients With Relapsed and Refractory Multiple Myeloma (RRMM)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>PETHEMA Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>PETHEMA Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multiple myeloma (MM) is a plasma cell neoplasm representing the second most common type of&#xD;
      hematologic tumor after lymphomas. The incorporation of novel agents such as bortezomib,&#xD;
      lenalidomide, or thalidomide into first-line treatment as well as in relapse settings has led&#xD;
      to a significant improvement in survival rates for MM patients, which have doubled in the&#xD;
      last 5-7 years (1,2). However, except for a small percentage of patients (10-30%)(3) that may&#xD;
      achieve a cure after first-line treatment, in the majority of cases, MM behaves as an&#xD;
      incurable disease whose clinical course is characterized by repeated relapses, shorter and&#xD;
      shorter periods of remission, and by becoming refractory to succesive treatments (bortezomib&#xD;
      or lenalidomide). In this situation, survival is generally less than 9 months, which&#xD;
      underscores the need to develop new drugs for MM patients Pomalidomide, a third-generation&#xD;
      immunomodulatory drug (IMiD), has demonstrated efficacy in patients with relapsed and&#xD;
      refractory MM, with an overall response rate that fluctuates between 30-60% depending on&#xD;
      whether it is administered in combination with low-dose dexamethasone or in association with&#xD;
      treatment with a cytostatic agent such as cyclophosphamide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In clinical trial CC-4047-MM-003, treatment with pomalidomide and low-dose dexamethasone in&#xD;
      patients with relapsed and refractory MM or those intolerant to bortezomib or lenalidomide&#xD;
      was a successful rescue treatment in 30% of patients with a median progression-free survival&#xD;
      of 4 months. The association of cyclophosphamide at dose of 400mg/day on days 1, 8, and 15 of&#xD;
      each cycle is able to increase the overall response rate from 39% for combination&#xD;
      pomalidomide-dexamethasone to up to 65% for the triple regimen (pomalidomide,&#xD;
      cyclophosphamide, dexamethasone - POMCIDEX), as well as the median PFS from 4.4 mo. to 9.2&#xD;
      mo. respectively. As well, the tolerance and safety profiles of the triple combination&#xD;
      pomalidomide, cyclophosphamide, and dexamethasone were acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The association of bortezomib with pomalidomide-dexamethasone also increases the overall&#xD;
      response rate (85%) and prolongs PFS (10.7 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The BiRD study (lenalidomide, dexamethasone, and clarithromycin) suggests that clarithromycin&#xD;
      intensifies the effect of corticosteroids, increasing their anti-myeloma effect . A study&#xD;
      evaluating the combination of clarithromycin with pomalidomide and low-dose dexamethasone in&#xD;
      RRMM patients showed an overall response rate of 57% and clinical benefit rate (considered&#xD;
      equal or superior to minor response) of 66%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since July 2014, pomalidomide (Imnovid®) in combination with dexamethasone has been approved&#xD;
      for the treatment of adult patients with relapsed and refractory MM who have received at&#xD;
      least two prior lines of therapy (including bortezomib and lenalidomide) and who have shown&#xD;
      progressive disease to the last line of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Spain in January of 2015, and in the Spanish Myeloma Group (GEM) context, we implemented&#xD;
      clinical practice guidelines for the treatment of RRMM patients who are candidates for&#xD;
      pomalidomide treatment with a triple therapy combination pomalidomide + cyclophosphamide +&#xD;
      low-dose dexamethasone (POMCIDEX) (Appendix 1). The goal of the clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
      was to increase the overall response rate, quality of response, and progression-free survival&#xD;
      in patients treated with POMCIDEX. In patients with suboptimal response (defined as stable&#xD;
      disease in the first 3 cycles, or inferior to partial response after six cycles according to&#xD;
      International Myeloma Working Group Uniform Response Criteria [7]), clarithromycin can be&#xD;
      added to their treatment at a dose of 500mg/12hrs on days 1-28 of each cycle. Treatment can&#xD;
      be administered until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or based on patient&#xD;
      decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keeping in mind the time that has passed since the approval of pomalidomide for use in Spain&#xD;
      and the publication of the clinical practice guidelines, we believe it is now time for a&#xD;
      retrospective evaluation of the results of the therapeutic guidelines for Spanish MM patients&#xD;
      and to review the viability of the recommendations contained in the guidelines with respect&#xD;
      to compliance with the same, and effectiveness of the planned course of treatment. Once the&#xD;
      viability of the proposed therapy regimen has been evaluated, other analyses for the purpose&#xD;
      of studying the clinical results of treatment can be carried out as a separate analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The therapeutic paradigm for MM is rapidly changing due to the availability of new drugs for&#xD;
      the treatment of patients with refractory or relapsed disease, making clinical decisions more&#xD;
      challenging. For this reason, the availability of data obtained from real-life settings,&#xD;
      outside of clinical trials, is essential in order to choose the appropriate treatment for&#xD;
      each patient&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a national, multicentre, observational, retrospective, open-label, non-randomized,&#xD;
      non-interventional study to evaluate the degree of compliance at PETHEMA centres in Spain&#xD;
      with the clinical practice guidelines proposed by the Spanish Myeloma Group for the treatment&#xD;
      of relapsed and refractory MM with POMCIDEX.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, all patients will be included retrospectively who met the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      for the GEM clinical practice guidelines and who were treated with POMCIDEX. The period of&#xD;
      retrospective data collection will be from 01/01/2015 to 01/04/2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The period of data collection for the study includes a maximum period of three months to&#xD;
      allow each centre to collect the necessary clinical and demographic data for each patient in&#xD;
      order to fulfill the different study objectives. Patient data will be anonymized and recorded&#xD;
      in the electronic Case Report Form (eCRF) using the RedCap platform. Afterward, data&#xD;
      cleansing and verification will be carried out on all data recorded by the study&#xD;
      investigators. This procedure will be carried out in the six months after database lock.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the process of recording and verification of patient data is complete, extraction and&#xD;
      statistical analysis of the data will be carried out.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 27, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 14, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 14, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of compliance at PETHEMA centres in Spain with the clinical practice guidelines proposed by the Spanish Myeloma Group for the treatment of relapsed and refractory MM with POMCIDEX.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the viability of the therapeutic guidelines, measured in terms of compliance and the effectiveness of the treatment planned.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsed and Refractory Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Refractory Multiple Myeloma</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with relapsed and refractory multiple myeloma who have received treatment with pomalidomide, cyclophosphamide, and dexamethasone following the GEM-PETHEMA clinical practice guidelines between 01/01/2015 to 01/04/2018</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients treated with POMCIDEX during the period 01/01/2015 and 01/04/2018 in accordance&#xD;
        with the PETHEMA clinical practice guidelines. The inclusion criteria in the guidelines are&#xD;
        those specified in the clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated with POMCIDEX during the period 01/01/2015 and 01/04/2018 in&#xD;
             accordance with the PETHEMA clinical practice guidelines. The inclusion criteria in&#xD;
             the guidelines are those specified in the clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have not been treated according to the clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
             during the specified period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Sant Joan de Déu</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Donostia-Donostia Ospitalea</name>
      <address>
        <city>Donostia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen de Las Nieves</name>
      <address>
        <city>Granada</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General San Jorge - Huesca</name>
      <address>
        <city>Huesca</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Jaén</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jaén</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Lucus Augusti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lugo</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínico San Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Del Tajo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Marañón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Ramón Y Cajal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de La Princesa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Infanta Leonor</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen de La Arrixaca</name>
      <address>
        <city>Murcia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Hospitalario de Especialidades Virgen de La Victoria</name>
      <address>
        <city>Málaga</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Central de Asturias</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oviedo</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari Son Espases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palma De Mallorca</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Hospitalario de Navarra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital El Bierzo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ponferrada</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de Salamanca</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salamanca</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Mutua Terrassa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Terrassa</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Hospitalario de Toledo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toledo</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Dr. Peset Aleixandre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valence</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Arnau de Vilanova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario La Fe</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HOSPITAL CLíNICO UNIVERSITARIO DE VALLADOLID</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valladolid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Txagorritxu</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vitoria</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://fundacionpethema.es</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 13, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

