<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03474770</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BNI-02-1b</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03474770</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BIS-001-ER for the Treatment of Adult Focal Impaired Awareness Seizures</brief_title>
  <acronym>FIAS</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Safety and Efficacy of BIS-001-ER for the Treatment of Adult Focal Impaired Awareness Seizures</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to examine safety signals and demonstrate seizure reduction in&#xD;
      adults with FIAS treated with BIS-001ER as an add-on therapy in an in-patient and out-patient&#xD;
      study design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 10, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of BIS-001ER on Seizure Count</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in average daily seizure count between baseline (pre-treatment) and evaluation (on treatment) video EEG monitoring periods.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of BIS-001ER on Percent Reduction in Daily Seizure Count</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Percent reduction in average daily seizure count from the baseline VEM period compared to the evaluation video EEG monitoring period (on treatment).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of BIS-001ER on Seizure Count vs Titration Period (Diary)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Percent reduction in average number of seizures from the baseline period. (screening/retrospective diary) compared to the last week of the titration treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of Treatment Responders</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Percent of participants considered treatment responders defined as those with a ≥25%, ≥50%, ≥75% reduction in seizures from the baseline VEM period compared to the VEM treatment evaluation period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of BIS-001ER on Seizure Count During Extension Phase</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent reduction of average number of seizures vs. baseline/retrospective diary at 1, 3, 6, 12 months during the extension period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Seizure Protection</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects with 100% seizure reduction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for Rescue Medication</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects requiring rescue medication at different dosages.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Focal Impaired Awareness Seizures</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BIS-001ER</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose administration for each participant will begin at 0.25mg b.i.d. escalating sequentially every 4 days to a maximum tolerated dose or target dose of 1.75mg b.i.d. Upon reaching the target dose or maximum tolerated dose, participants will maintain that dose for the balance of the 1 month out-patient titration period, after which they will begin a 96-hour in-patient video EEG monitoring treatment period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BIS-001ER</intervention_name>
    <description>BIS-001 ER is an extended release formulation of the nutritional supplement Huperzine A.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BIS-001ER</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Huperzine A ER</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak English with sufficient proficiency to read and comprehend the Informed Consent&#xD;
             document, and to communicate with study staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to consent to participate by signing the Informed Consent document after a&#xD;
             full explanation of the nature and purpose of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have signed the Informed Consent before any study-specific procedures are performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be males or females between 18 - 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a diagnosis of FIAS type epilepsy with or without additional focal aware or&#xD;
             non-aware seizures with generalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a current minimum average of 5 countable seizures / week to enroll in study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have at least 5 focal impaired awareness seizures during the 96-hour baseline VEM&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be receiving stable doses (for at least 4 weeks) of one to four currently marketed&#xD;
             anti-epileptic drugs (AEDs), with or without vagus nerve stimulation (in which case&#xD;
             the patient should be on the same stimulation parameters for at least 4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a negative urinary pregnancy test upon admission to the site on Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be in good general health in the judgment of the Principal Investigator based upon&#xD;
             medical history, physical examination, standard 12-lead ECG, and clinical laboratory&#xD;
             evaluations obtained within the two weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to comply with all study-specified procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight between 40 and 120 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has taken Huperzine A within the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is planning to become pregnant or impregnate spouse, not using an acceptable method of&#xD;
             birth control (defined as use of double-barrier birth control methods, use of oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, or surgical sterilization), pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have non-epileptic events that could be confused by the patient and/or study staff as&#xD;
             epileptic seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has seizures that are difficult to count; for example, seizure clusters defined as&#xD;
             multiple seizures with at least one seizure within 30 minutes of the previous seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have less than the 5 minimum accepted seizures required during baseline evaluation&#xD;
             period screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of only seizure clusters, for example, seizure clusters defined as&#xD;
             multiple seizures with at least one seizure within 30 minutes of the previous seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has attempted suicide within the past 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of status epilepticus in the 6 months previous to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a pre-existing medical condition (including an existing progressive or&#xD;
             degenerative neurological disorder including brain tumor, active encephalitis, active&#xD;
             meningitis or abscess) or takes medications that, in the Principal Investigator's&#xD;
             opinion, could interfere with the participant's suitability for participation in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history or evidence of significant psychiatric disturbance or illness, including&#xD;
             alcohol or drug abuse within the past 2 years, or symptoms of psychosis&#xD;
             (hallucinations, delusions) in the last 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had any clinical laboratory abnormalities within the past two months, prior to&#xD;
             screening, considered of clinical significance by the Principal Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is on concomitant therapy with non-AEDs that are cholinergic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has participated in any clinical investigational drug or device study within four&#xD;
             weeks prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to complete seizure diary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently taking or has taken Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) within the past 14&#xD;
             days, or consume foods or drinks containing EGCG; including green, white, oolong teas&#xD;
             and certain black teas, or food containing &gt;100grams of carob powder within the past&#xD;
             14 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Azmi Nasser, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Alfred Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3050</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3050</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 12, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Huperzine A</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

