<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03478865</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>180067</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>18-EI-0067</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03478865</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vitamin A Palmitate Supplementation in People With Age-Related Macular Degeneration (and Without Reticular Pseudodrusen) and Delayed Dark Adaptation</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Investigation of Vitamin A Palmitate Supplementation in Patients With Age-Related Macular Degeneration (and Without Reticular Pseudodrusen) and Delayed Dark Adaptation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) is an eye disease. It is the leading cause of vision&#xD;
      loss in people over 55 in the U.S. Changes in the eye can make it difficult for the eye to&#xD;
      adjust to low light. This is known as dark adaptation. Identifying and watching the early to&#xD;
      middle stages of AMD and changes in dark adaptation might help researchers develop new&#xD;
      treatments to stop the disease before it becomes severe. Taking vitamin A might help improve&#xD;
      vision in people with AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see if taking 16,000 IU of vitamin A per day improves vision in people with AMD. Also to&#xD;
      improve understanding of AMD and associated dark adaptation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 50 and older with AMD and normal liver function&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical and eye disease history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eye exam: The pupil will be dilated with eye drops. Pictures will be taken of the retina and&#xD;
      the inside of the eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Including the screening visit, participants will have at least 5 visits. They will be about&#xD;
      once a month over 6 months. Visits include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questions about eye problems in certain light&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eye exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dark adaptation protocol: Participants will sit at a machine in a dark room. They will look&#xD;
      into the machine and push a button when they see a light. This lasts 20-30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take a vitamin A supplement by mouth once a day for 2 months. They will&#xD;
      record when they take the pills in a diary.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to investigate the potential efficacy and safety of vitamin A&#xD;
      palmitate dosing in improving dark adaptation in participants with age-related macular&#xD;
      degeneration (AMD) and abnormal dark adaptation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first cohort consists of five participants with AMD who meet the eligibility criteria.&#xD;
      The second cohort will consist of five participants with AMD who meet the eligibility&#xD;
      criteria. Up to five additional participants may be accrued in the second cohort to account&#xD;
      for participants who withdraw from the study prior to receiving one month of study&#xD;
      supplementation for a reason unrelated to an adverse reaction. Up to 18 participants may be&#xD;
      enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, uncontrolled, single center, pilot study to investigate the potential&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of vitamin A palmitate dosing in improving dark adaptation in&#xD;
      participants with AMD and abnormal dark adaptation. Participants in the first cohort were&#xD;
      instructed to take 16,000 IU of vitamin A palmitate daily for two months. Enrollment for&#xD;
      Cohort 1 ended on May 24, 2019. Participants in the second cohort will be instructed to take&#xD;
      48,000 IU of vitamin A palmitate daily for one month. Participants in both cohorts will&#xD;
      continue in the study for one month after ending Vitamin A supplementation. Participants in&#xD;
      Cohort 1 may enroll into Cohort 2 as long as their last intake of vitamin A palmitate was&#xD;
      greater than two months prior to their enrollment into Cohort 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each cohort, the primary outcome is the measurement of dark adaptation parameters&#xD;
      (thresholds and kinetics) by the following: dark adaptation times as measured by the AdaptDx&#xD;
      comparing before and after vitamin A palmitate supplementation and dark adaptation parameters&#xD;
      as measured by the Medmont comparing before and after vitamin A palmitate supplementation.&#xD;
      The primary outcome will be assessed at Month 2 in the first cohort and Month 1 in the second&#xD;
      cohort. For both cohorts, the secondary outcomes include changes in low luminance visual&#xD;
      acuity (LLVA) and changes in patient reported outcomes as measured by the low luminance&#xD;
      questionnaire (LLQ). The secondary outcomes also include measurement of dark adaptation&#xD;
      parameters (thresholds and kinetics) comparing baseline and one month after completing&#xD;
      supplementation (Month 3 in Cohort 1 and Month 2 in Cohort 2).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 20, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cohort 2: The measurement of dark adaptation parameters (threshold and kinetics)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Two months</time_frame>
    <description>Measuring dark adaptation changes by AdaptDx and Medmont before and after vitamin A palmitate supplementation in Cohort 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cohort 1: The measurement of dark adaptation parameters (threshold and kinetics)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and One month</time_frame>
    <description>Measuring dark adaptation changes by AdaptDx and Medmont before and after vitamin A palmitate supplementation in Cohort 2.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cohort 2: Changes in LLVA and LLQ</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and two months, baseline and three months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in LLVA and patient reported outcomes measured by LLQ for Cohort 1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cohort 1: Changes in LLVA and LLQ</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and one month, baseline and two months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes and patient reported outcomes measured by LLQ in LLVA for Cohort 2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in dark adaptation measures by AdaptDx and Medmont</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and one month after completing supplementation</time_frame>
    <description>Dark adaptation parameters (threshold and kinetics) comparing baseline and one month after completing supplementation (Month 3 in Cohort 1 and Month 2 in Cohort 2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>AMD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with age-related macular degeneration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin A palmitate</intervention_name>
    <description>Provide vitamin A to participants with pre/post assessments of vision.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible, the following inclusion criteria must be met, where applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be 50 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must understand and sign the protocol s informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant of childbearing potential must be willing to undergo urine pregnancy&#xD;
             tests throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant of childbearing potential and any participant able to father children&#xD;
             must have (or have a partner who has) had a hysterectomy or vasectomy, be completely&#xD;
             abstinent from intercourse, or must agree to practice two acceptable methods of&#xD;
             contraception throughout the course of the study and for one week after study&#xD;
             supplement discontinuation. Acceptable methods of contraception include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hormonal contraception (i.e. birth control pills, injected hormones, dermal patch&#xD;
                  or vaginal ring),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine device,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Barrier methods (diaphragm, condom) with spermicide, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Surgical sterilization (tubal ligation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must agree to notify the study investigator or coordinator if any of&#xD;
             their doctors initiate a new prescription medication during the course of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must agree to not take greater than or equal to 8000 IU vitamin A&#xD;
             palmitate outside the study supplementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For supplementation eligibility, participant must have normal liver function as&#xD;
             demonstrated by the Chemistry 20 panel, or have mild abnormalities not above grade 1&#xD;
             as defined by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events v4.0 (CTCAE).&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A participant is not eligible if any of the following exclusion criteria are present:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is in another investigational study and actively receiving study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is unable to comply with study procedures or follow-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is already taking vitamin A palmitate supplements greater than or equal to&#xD;
             8,000 IU.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of vitamin A deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude&#xD;
             participation in the study (e.g., unstable medical status including blood pressure and&#xD;
             glycemic control).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of hepatitis or liver failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has chronic gastrointestinal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant will be excluded if the participant has serologic evidence of an active&#xD;
             hepatitis infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant was in Cohort 1 and took his/her last dose of vitamin A palmitate less&#xD;
             than two months prior to enrolling in Cohort 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The participant must have at least one eye meeting all inclusion criteria and none of the&#xD;
        exclusion criteria listed below.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The eye must have a best-corrected ETDRS visual acuity score better than or equal to&#xD;
             20/80 (i.e., equal to or better than 54 letters).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must have at least one large druse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal dark adaptation, which is defined as having an Adapt Dx test with a RIT of 16&#xD;
             minutes or more at the screening visit. This is at least one standard deviation&#xD;
             greater than the average normal RIT and includes room to account for variability in&#xD;
             testing. If at any point during current testing or under a previous NEI protocol, a&#xD;
             participant has exceeded the 40 minute test ceiling, they will have satisfied the&#xD;
             inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STUDY EYE EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of advanced macular degeneration with central geographic atrophy or choroidal&#xD;
             neovascularization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of definite reticular pseudodrusen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An ocular condition is present (other than retinal vein occlusion) that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator, might alter visual acuity during the course of the study&#xD;
             (e.g., vein occlusion, uveitis or other ocular inflammatory disease, neovascular&#xD;
             glaucoma, Irvine-Gass Syndrome, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substantial cataract that, in the opinion of the investigator, is likely to be&#xD;
             decreasing visual acuity by three lines or more (i.e., cataract would be reducing&#xD;
             acuity to 20/40 or worse if eye was otherwise normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of major ocular surgery (e.g. cataract extraction, scleral buckle, any&#xD;
             intraocular surgery, etc.) within three months prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of YAG (Yttrium-Aluminum Garnet) capsulotomy performed within two months prior&#xD;
             to study entry.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Catherine A Cukras, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Angel H Garced, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 594-3141</phone>
    <email>garceda@nei.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2018-EI-0067.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 16, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 15, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Eye Examinations</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinal Pigment Epithelium</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

