<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04609553</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro2019002784</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R01HD099125-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04609553</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Literacy Promotion for Latinos Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Addressing Disparities in Language and Social-emotional Skill Acquisition Through Literacy Promotion in Primary Care: Literacy Promotion for Latinos Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study tests the extent to which tailored outreach text messages that provide a cue to&#xD;
      action and an intervention that enhances access to poverty-reducing resources, in combination&#xD;
      with standard primary care literacy promotion, can improve child language and social-&#xD;
      emotional skill acquisition among low-income Latino children.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators propose a 3 arm randomized clinical trial to test strategies designed to&#xD;
      enhance literacy promotion for low-income Latino families. The investigators will recruit 630&#xD;
      parent-child dyads from community health centers that serve low-income, Latino families.&#xD;
      Parents will be randomly assigned to one of 3 arms (1) Reach Out and Read (ROR) an&#xD;
      evidence-based literacy promotion intervention that is widely disseminated in primary care;&#xD;
      (2) ROR plus tailored outreach text messages; (3) ROR plus tailored outreach text messages&#xD;
      and enhanced access to poverty-reducing resources using a widely disseminated model that&#xD;
      simplifies access and provides care coordination. In Aim 1, the investigators will test their&#xD;
      hypotheses that (1) children in the ROR plus text message arm will have higher scores on&#xD;
      validated assessments of language and social-emotional development compared to standard ROR&#xD;
      alone and (2) children who receive both text messages and enhanced access to poverty-reducing&#xD;
      resources will have higher scores compared to the other two arms. In Aim 2, the investigators&#xD;
      will examine mechanisms that underlie the effects of the interventions. In Aim 3, the&#xD;
      investigators will use mixed methods to conduct a process evaluation to understand how the&#xD;
      interventions are implemented, identify barriers, facilitators, and modifications, and&#xD;
      explore parents' experiences with the interventions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Child language skills</measure>
    <time_frame>18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Preschool Language Scale is a direct assessment of children's auditory comprehension and expressive language skills. Standard scores are calculated (M=100; SD=15) with higher scores indicating stronger skills.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in child communicative skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of non-verbal communication and early expressive language assessed using the MacArthur Bates Communicative Development Inventories. The Words &amp; Gestures short form is an 89-word vocabulary checklist with separate columns for comprehension and production for children 8-18 months. The Words &amp; Sentences versions contain a 100-word productive vocabulary checklist and a question about combining words for children 16-30 months. Scores are summed and measured in percentiles ranging &lt;1st to 99th. Higher scores denote stronger skills.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in child social-emotional skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of infant and toddler social-emotional skills assessed using the Devereux Early Childhood Assessment (DECA). Total Protective Factors scale is a composite of Attachment/Relationships, Initiative, and Self-Regulation scales. Scores are standardized on a T-distribution (M=50;SD=10). Higher scores denote strengths.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in caregiver cognitive stimulation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The StimQ is a caregiver-reported measure of cognitive stimulation for children that includes domains on the home literacy environment (Reading scale) and responsiveness (Parental Verbal Responsiveness scale). The Reading scale includes 3 subdimensions (Book Reading Quantity, Diversity of Content, Book Reading Quality). Scores on the Reading scale range from 0 to 19. The Parental Verbal Responsiveness scale is composed of two subdimensions (Everyday Routines and Play and Pretend). Scores range from 0 to 15). Higher scores indicate more cognitive stimulation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dialogic reading</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The DialogPR is a caregiver report measure of shared reading quality. Score range from 0 to 30 with higher scores indicating more interactive reading.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in caregiver positive parenting</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Parenting Your Baby (PYB) &amp; Parenting Your Toddler (PYT) are based on the Parenting Young Children (PARYC) measure, which is caregiver report instrument designed to assess caregiving practices by measuring the frequency of different caregiving behaviors. Scores on the PYB range from 7 to 56 and scores on the PYT range from 7 to 49. Higher scores indicate more positive parenting behaviors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in caregiver discipline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>This questionnaire was modified from the National Survey of Early Childhood Health and asks two questions about verbal and physical discipline. Scores range from 0 to 6 and higher scores indicate harsher discipline strategies.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Caregiver attitudes about reading</measure>
    <time_frame>9-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Parent Reading Belief Inventory is a caregiver reported measure of attitudes and knowledge about reading with children that includes subdimensions of positive affect (scores range from 0 to 33) and knowledge (scores range from 0 to 15). Higher scores indicate more favorable attitudes and greater knowledge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Caregiver attitudes about reading</measure>
    <time_frame>18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Parent Reading Belief Inventory is a caregiver reported measure of attitudes and knowledge about reading with children that includes subdimensions of positive affect (scores range from 0 to 33) and knowledge (scores range from 0 to 15). Higher scores indicate more favorable attitudes and greater knowledge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in community resource participation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>A series of questions that ask about caregiver and child participation in different types of community resources (e.g. food/nutrition support, income support, childcare assistance, etc.).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in caregiver-clinician relationship</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Physician-Parent Communication Survey is a caregiver reported measure of the caregiver-clinician relationship that examines subdimensions including interest and caring. Items are scored from 1 to 8 with higher scores indicating stronger relationships.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in social needs and stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver report of social needs and stressors. Caregivers rate statements on social needs and stress from 0 to 4 with higher scores indicating greater needs and stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in parent stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Parental Stress Scale is an eighteen-item measure that assesses parental stress. Scores range from 5 to 90 with higher scores indicating greater stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in child media use</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 9-month follow-up, 18-month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The ScreenQ is a caregiver report measure of media use in children. Scores range from 0 to 26 with higher score indicating more media use.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>ROR receipt</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 9-month follow up; 18-month follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Caregiver's report of receipt of literacy promotion components during healthcare visits.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">630</enrollment>
  <condition>Language Development</condition>
  <condition>Behavior, Child</condition>
  <condition>Parenting</condition>
  <condition>Literacy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care including ROR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Literacy promotion is a pediatric standard of care. Participants in this group will receive usual care that includes ROR, a primary care literacy promotion intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In addition to ROR, participants will receive three text messages per week, plus one interactive follow-up message per month, for the study period with scheduled breaks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages plus connection to community resources</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In addition to ROR and text messages, participants will be referred to a county-based single point of entry system for referrals to community resources. This system simplifies access to poverty-reducing resources by creating a centralized access point, maintaining an updated data base of resources with existing capacity to support families, and providing case management.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Usual care including ROR</intervention_name>
    <description>Usual care which includes ROR.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages plus connection to community resources</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care including ROR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Text messages</intervention_name>
    <description>3 text messages per week and one interactive text per month.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages plus connection to community resources</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Connection to community resources</intervention_name>
    <description>Referral to a non-profit that connects families with community resources and provides families with case management.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ROR plus text messages plus connection to community resources</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary caregiver of a child age 6 months to 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Identifies as Latino/a/x&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary language English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cell phone ownership&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to receive text messages&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to accept being placed into one of three study groups&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with multiple congenital anomalies or genetic disorders and previously&#xD;
             identified developmental delays&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manuel E Jimenez, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Hemler, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>732 235 7875</phone>
    <email>hemlerje@rwjms.rutgers.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rutgers Robert Wood Johnson Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Brunswick</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Hemler, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Manuel E. Jimenez, MD, MS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>literacy promotion, early childhood, Latino, primary care</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Deidentified quantitative data and associated documentation may be made available to users conducting non-profit research under a written data-sharing agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will become available after the study is completed and primary study findings are published in peer-reviewed journals.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Researchers from accredited institutions may request access to the data for non-profit research. Permission and access will be granted on an ad hoc basis. Only deidentified data will be made available.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

