<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04604145</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FWH20200198H</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04604145</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Self-Collected Saliva Samples Without Viral Transport Media for COVID-19 Testing Via RT-PCR</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Self-Collected Saliva Samples Without Viral Transport Media for SARS-CoV-2 Testing Via RT-PCR</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a study that will attempt to validate the process for detecting SARS-CoV-2 (COVID19)&#xD;
      on a non-FDA-approved technology using self-collected saliva as the specimen. Investigators&#xD;
      will compare self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      samples (Nasal swabs) to see if the self-collected saliva samples are similar in terms of&#xD;
      diagnostic accuracy. Investigators will be performing this testing at the site where patients&#xD;
      regularly go for COVID19 testing. There will be minimal risk of harm as consenting patients&#xD;
      will only have to provide a small amount of saliva into a tube.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a descriptive study that will attempt to validate the procedure for detecting&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system using self-collected saliva as the&#xD;
      specimen. Investigators will calculate the percent agreement and the 95% confidence intervals&#xD;
      (ie, overall agreement, percent positive agreement, and percent negative agreement) between&#xD;
      self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and&#xD;
      healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire®&#xD;
      FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard). Participants&#xD;
      without usable results for both the saliva and nasopharyngeal methods will not be included in&#xD;
      the analyses. Currently, DGMC uses both FDA Emergency Use Authorization systems&#xD;
      interchangeably to test for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using human volunteers to obtain positive and negative nasopharyngeal and saliva specimens of&#xD;
      SARS-COV-2, this is a test validation study. It uses the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system&#xD;
      to compare the test performance of saliva as a specimen to the standard nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      specimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol utilizes two different convenience samples of DGMC patients. Patients (i.e.&#xD;
      inpatient, outpatients) with a positive COVID-19 test in the past 72 hours, and those who&#xD;
      present for COVID-19 testing at DGMC and have negative results. Both groups of patients are&#xD;
      willing to provide a saliva sample for COVID-19 testing within 72 hours. The populations will&#xD;
      be comprised of active duty, DoD dependents, and retirees who are DGMC patients. This study&#xD;
      will enroll at least 60 individuals. Only saliva samples from 30 participants with negative&#xD;
      and 30 with positive NP results will be processed. The study will stop recruiting positive&#xD;
      patients after obtaining the paired saliva and NP results from 30 participants who are&#xD;
      COVID-19 positive by NP test. The study will stop actively recruiting negative patients after&#xD;
      obtaining the paired saliva and NP results from 30 participants who are COVID-19 negative by&#xD;
      NP test. More than 30 negative patients may be recruited in an attempt to capture 30 positive&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment efforts for positive patients will be conducted utilizing a HIPAA waiver to&#xD;
      identify potential study participants, as well as, targeting patients exposed to and/or with&#xD;
      symptoms related to COVID-19 who present for COVID-19 testing. The HIPAA Waiver will be used&#xD;
      to identify patients (inpatient, outpatient) who have had a positive COVID-19 NP test within&#xD;
      the past 72 hours. These patients, as well as others who will have COVID-19 testing at DGMC,&#xD;
      will be informed of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients interested in participation will make contact with study staff. Those eligible to&#xD;
      participate will be given study documents (consent and HIPAA Authorization Form), that will&#xD;
      later be reviewed and signed by the patient and study staff. Thereafter, additional&#xD;
      information (contact, demographic), and a self-collected saliva specimen will be obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To minimize contact with COVID-19 positive or potentially infected patients when signing&#xD;
      documents and obtaining the self-collected saliva sample, staff will wear scrubs (or a lab&#xD;
      coat), gloves, eye protection and N95 mask. Documents requiring signature will be signed by&#xD;
      the patient while wearing a mask and maintaining a distance of at least 6 feet from study&#xD;
      staff or from their vehicle. Consent and HIPAA Authorization Forms will be signed. The&#xD;
      original, signed documents will be maintained by study staff and a copy will be provided to&#xD;
      the participant. After both documents have been signed, study staff will obtain demographic&#xD;
      (age, ethnicity, race and sex) and contact information (name, email address if future contact&#xD;
      is desired), date of birth, and the self-collected saliva sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to collecting the saliva sample, study staff will ensure the participant has not&#xD;
      smoked, eaten or drank anything for the previous 10 minutes. Participants will be given a&#xD;
      biohazard bag, label (with a 6-digit numerical code), 25 ml plastic specimen tube without&#xD;
      transport medium inside. Then asked to fill it with approximately 2 mL of saliva. There will&#xD;
      be a marking on the tube to ensure a sufficient sample is collected. The participant will be&#xD;
      instructed to close the lid, place the label on the outside of the tube, then put the labeled&#xD;
      tube into the biohazard bag. Participants will then place the bagged specimen inside a second&#xD;
      biohazard bag held by either DGMC or a member of the study team. The double-bagged&#xD;
      self-collected saliva sample will then be placed into the study cooler containing an ice&#xD;
      pack. Saliva specimens will then be transported to the CIF in batch.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After obtaining the paired saliva and NP results from 30 participants who are COVID-19&#xD;
      negative by NP test, saliva testing will only be performed on samples collected from NP&#xD;
      positive participants. Patients with unknown COVID-19 status, enrolled in an attempt to&#xD;
      capture a COVID-19 positive patient, will have the medical record accessed to retrieve the NP&#xD;
      result prior to performing saliva testing. If the NP result is positive, saliva testing will&#xD;
      be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Testing will be performed on saliva samples using reverse-transcription polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (RTPCR). Natural and/or synthetic RNA will be acquired for use as a positive&#xD;
      control. RT-PCR will target the E-gene and N-gene of SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Within 5 minutes of sample collection the sample will be kept cold for stabilization. A&#xD;
           cooler with an ice pack inside will be taken to the location where the participant&#xD;
           provides the sample. The sample will be put in a biohazard bag, then immediately be&#xD;
           placed into the cooler for transport to the CIF Laboratory in batch.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) Extraction - Within 12 hours, RNA will be extracted from the&#xD;
           specimens using Invitrogen PureLink ® Viral RNA/DNA Mini Kit (Life Technologies). Sample&#xD;
           RNA will be stored at -80oC until used.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. SuperScriptTM III One-Step RT-PCR with PlatinumTM Taq (Life Technologies) will be used&#xD;
           for detection and amplification of viral RNA present in specimens using Eppendorf&#xD;
           Mastercyler Pro S (Eppendorf). Up to seven primer pairs that are based from CDC and&#xD;
           other publications will be used.18-19 Three from the envelope protein gene and four from&#xD;
           the nucleocapsid protein gene.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Frozen samples will be tested and run in batches.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. PCR products will be evaluated with gel electrophoresis using the Mini-Protein® Tetra&#xD;
           Cell (Bio-Rad).&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Sequencing - All PCR reactions that produce acceptable amplicons will be stored at -80oC&#xD;
           for possible sequencing confirmation using the ABI 3130 (Life Technologies).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once testing is completed, specimens will be aliquoted and stored at -80oC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Saliva samples will be interpreted as negative, positive or inconclusive. Negative will be&#xD;
      reported when there is no detection in any target; inconclusive when 1 target is detected;&#xD;
      and positive when 2 or more targets are detected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study staff will access the lab accession number associated with each SARS-CoV-2 positive NP&#xD;
      result to request a print out, from the DGMC clinical lab, of the raw data from the&#xD;
      instrument used to perform testing. This information will be used to evaluate any&#xD;
      discrepancies between the two testing methods.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 18, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 18, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent positive agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 week of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent positive agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent negative agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 week of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent negative agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent overall agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 week of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent overall agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Polymerase Chain Reaction</condition>
  <condition>Laboratory Testing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Positive NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>SARS-CoV-2 testing on self-collected saliva specimens, associated with a positive NP result, using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Negative NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>SARS-CoV-2 testing on self-collected saliva specimens, associated with a negative NP result, using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 testing on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system using self-collected saliva as the specimen</intervention_name>
    <description>Obtain self-collected saliva sample, perform SARS-CoV-2 testing using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system on 30 samples associated with a positive and 30 samples associated with a negative NP sample, then compare saliva results to healthcare worker collected NP sample results evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® (gold standard).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Negative NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Positive NP results</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients who have COVID-19 NP testing at DGMC and are willing to provide a&#xD;
             saliva sample within 72 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients (i.e., inpatient, outpatient) who have positive COVID-19 NP test&#xD;
             results at DGMC and are willing to provide a saliva sample within 72 hours of the&#xD;
             positive COVID-19 NP test&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling to wait or have eaten, drank or smoked within the past 10 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling or unable to provide 2 mls of saliva&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For positive control participants only, patients whose most recent positive COVID-19&#xD;
             NP test was collected more than 72 hours ago&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nolan R Hudson, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>David Grant Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>David Grant U.S. Airforce Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Travis Air Force Base</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94533</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fakheran O, Dehghannejad M, Khademi A. Saliva as a diagnostic specimen for detection of SARS-CoV-2 in suspected patients: a scoping review. Infect Dis Poverty. 2020 Jul 22;9(1):100. doi: 10.1186/s40249-020-00728-w.</citation>
    <PMID>32698862</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azzi L, Carcano G, Gianfagna F, Grossi P, Gasperina DD, Genoni A, Fasano M, Sessa F, Tettamanti L, Carinci F, Maurino V, Rossi A, Tagliabue A, Baj A. Saliva is a reliable tool to detect SARS-CoV-2. J Infect. 2020 Jul;81(1):e45-e50. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.005. Epub 2020 Apr 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32298676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McCormick-Baw C, Morgan K, Gaffney D, Cazares Y, Jaworski K, Byrd A, Molberg K, Cavuoti D. Saliva as an Alternate Specimen Source for Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in Symptomatic Patients Using Cepheid Xpert Xpress SARS-CoV-2. J Clin Microbiol. 2020 Jul 23;58(8). pii: e01109-20. doi: 10.1128/JCM.01109-20. Print 2020 Jul 23.</citation>
    <PMID>32414838</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Takeuchi Y, Furuchi M, Kamimoto A, Honda K, Matsumura H, Kobayashi R. Saliva-based PCR tests for SARS-CoV-2 detection. J Oral Sci. 2020;62(3):350-351. doi: 10.2334/josnusd.20-0267.</citation>
    <PMID>32581183</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nolan Hudson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Associate/Medical Technologist, Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>April 6, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/45/NCT04604145/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

