<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04608747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>703</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04608747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tahini, Antioxidant Status and Endothelial Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Tahini Consumption on Oxidative Stress and Inflammation Markers as Well as Endothelial Function and Arterial Stiffness in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Harokopio University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Harokopio University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD), a cluster of disorders that affect heart and blood vessels, is&#xD;
      the leading cause of morbidity and mortality around the world and is responsible for 17.9&#xD;
      million deaths annually worldwide. CVD risk factors can be modifiable (nutrition, physical&#xD;
      activity, obesity, smoking, hyperlipidemia, hypertension and diabetes) and non-modifiable&#xD;
      (age, gender, ethnicity, family history and socioeconomic status). Chronic exposure to CVD&#xD;
      risk factors induces oxidative stress and promotes inflammation. In addition, endothelial&#xD;
      cells in response to the inflammatory reaction secrete growth factors, leading to the&#xD;
      destruction of vascular endothelium and promoting atherogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oxidative stress refers to the imbalance between anti-oxidant and pro-oxidant compounds, with&#xD;
      predominance of the pro-oxidant ones. Reactive Oxygen Species overproduction has been&#xD;
      implicated in pathogenesis and complications of numerous diseases including diabetes,&#xD;
      cardiovascular diseases, cancer, neurodegenerative diseases and chronic kidney disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, endothelium consists of a single layer of endothelial cells; it is the natural&#xD;
      barrier between blood and tissues and also an endocrine organ. It plays a key role in&#xD;
      vascular homeostasis by maintaining a balance between vasodilation and vasoconstriction and&#xD;
      is responsible for fluid filtration, blood vessel tone, hormone trafficking, hemostasis,&#xD;
      regulation of blood flow and growth of blood vessels. Thus, reductions in endothelial&#xD;
      function are detrimental and predict and precede the development of overt CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sesame belongs to Pedaliaceae family and can be consumed in different forms such as seeds,&#xD;
      oil or tahini, i.e., a 100 % peeled, ground and roasted sesame paste. Sesame seeds are rich&#xD;
      in polyunsaturated fatty acids, proteins, vitamin E and lignans, such as sesamin, sesamolin&#xD;
      and sesamol. Recent studies have highlighted the antioxidant, antihypertensive, hypolipidemic&#xD;
      and appetite control properties of sesame seeds and sesame oil.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the consumption of tahini and its effect on human health, only three studies are&#xD;
      available in the current literature, one of them in patients with type 2 diabetes, one in&#xD;
      diabetic animal model and one in Alzheimer's disease animal model. Thus, the aim of the&#xD;
      present study is to investigate the effect of tahini consumption on oxidative stress, blood&#xD;
      pressure, endothelial function and arterial stiffness in healthy males postprandially.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD), a cluster of disorders that affect heart and blood vessels, is&#xD;
      the leading cause of morbidity and mortality around the world and is responsible for 17.9&#xD;
      million deaths annually worldwide. CVD includes coronary heart disease, peripheral arterial&#xD;
      disease, cerebrovascular disease, rheumatic heart disease, congenital heart disease, deep&#xD;
      vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism. CVD risk factors can be modifiable (nutrition,&#xD;
      physical activity, obesity, smoking, hyperlipidemia, hypertension and diabetes) and&#xD;
      non-modifiable (age, gender, ethnicity, family history and socioeconomic status). Chronic&#xD;
      exposure to CVD risk factors induces oxidative stress and promotes inflammation. In addition,&#xD;
      endothelial cells in response to the inflammatory reaction secrete growth factors, leading to&#xD;
      the destruction of vascular endothelium and promoting atherogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oxidative stress refers to the imbalance between anti-oxidant and pro-oxidant compounds, with&#xD;
      predominance of the pro-oxidant ones. These compounds are also called Reactive Oxygen Species&#xD;
      (ROS) or free radicals and are unstable atoms or molecules. Their generation, as products of&#xD;
      normal cellular metabolism, occurs naturally by endogenous sources (e.g. mitochondria,&#xD;
      peroxisomes and endoplasmic reticulum) through enzymatic and non-enzymatic reactions.&#xD;
      Furthermore, exogenous sources implicated in free radical production are air pollution,&#xD;
      alcohol consumption, tobacco smoking, ultraviolet light exposure, industrial solvents and&#xD;
      others. Free radical production is regulated by the well-organized human endogenous enzymatic&#xD;
      and non-enzymatic antioxidant system, along with the exogenous antioxidants found in food.&#xD;
      However, in some cases antioxidant system fails to eliminate ROS overproduction and can&#xD;
      consequently induce serious damage to important for life biomolecules (DNA, lipids,&#xD;
      proteins), leading to cell injury and death. Thus, ROS overproduction has been implicated in&#xD;
      pathogenesis and complications of numerous diseases including diabetes, cardiovascular&#xD;
      diseases, cancer, neurodegenerative diseases and chronic kidney disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, endothelium consists of a single layer of endothelial cells; it is the natural&#xD;
      barrier between blood and tissues and also an endocrine organ. It plays a key role in&#xD;
      vascular homeostasis by maintaining a balance between vasodilation and vasoconstriction.&#xD;
      Moreover, vascular endothelium is responsible for fluid filtration, blood vessel tone,&#xD;
      hormone trafficking, hemostasis, regulation of blood flow and growth of blood vessels. Thus,&#xD;
      reductions in endothelial function are detrimental and predict and precede the development of&#xD;
      overt CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sesame belongs to Pedaliaceae family and can be consumed in different forms such as seeds,&#xD;
      oil or tahini, i.e., a 100 % peeled, ground and roasted sesame paste. Sesame seeds are rich&#xD;
      in polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs), proteins, vitamin E and lignans, such as sesamin,&#xD;
      sesamolin and sesamol. Recent studies have highlighted the antioxidant, antihypertensive,&#xD;
      hypolipidemic and appetite control properties of sesame seeds and sesame oil. Moreover, few&#xD;
      studies have investigated the effect of sesame consumption on blood pressure, endothelial&#xD;
      function and arterial stiffness in human population. According to a metanalysis, sesame&#xD;
      consumed in form of seed, oil, capsule or bar decreased both systolic blood pressure (SBP)&#xD;
      and diastolic blood pressure (DBP), while sesame oil consumption was found to improve&#xD;
      endothelial function both in the postprandial state and after long term consumption in&#xD;
      hypertensive men.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the consumption of tahini and its effect on human health, only three studies are&#xD;
      available in the current literature, one of them in patients with type 2 diabetes, one in&#xD;
      diabetic animal model and one in Alzheimer's disease animal model. Thus, the aim of the&#xD;
      present study is to investigate the effect of tahini consumption on oxidative stress, blood&#xD;
      pressure, endothelial function and arterial stiffness in healthy males postprandially.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of oxidative stress biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>Four hours after tahini consumption</time_frame>
    <description>concentration of urinary 8-iso-prostaglandin F2a</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Oxidative Stress</condition>
  <condition>Endothelial Function</condition>
  <condition>Blood Pressure</condition>
  <condition>Arterial Stiffness</condition>
  <condition>Blood Glucose</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After an overnight fast, participants subjected to baseline measurements and blood and urine collection and then consumed an amount of 50 g of tahini. Blood and urine collection and other measurements were repeated 4 h postprandially.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tahini</intervention_name>
    <description>Fifty grams of tahini were consumed by 20 healthy males</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 20 and 40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index (BMI)&lt;30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  alcohol or drug abuse,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any medication or vitamin/mineral supplementation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  alternative diet (vegetarian, macrobiotic, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recent use of antibiotics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of any chronic disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>NIKOLAOS K TENTOLOURIS, PROF</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Diabetes CeMedical School, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Laiko General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diabetes Center, First Department of Propaedeutic Internal Medicine, Medical School, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Laiko General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>11527</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sies H. Oxidative stress: a concept in redox biology and medicine. Redox Biol. 2015;4:180-3. doi: 10.1016/j.redox.2015.01.002. Epub 2015 Jan 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25588755</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kumar, S., &amp; Pandey, A. (2015). Free Radicals: Health Implications and their Mitigation by Herbals. British Journal Of Medicine And Medical Research, 7(6), 438-457. doi: 10.9734/bjmmr/2015/16284</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Phaniendra A, Jestadi DB, Periyasamy L. Free radicals: properties, sources, targets, and their implication in various diseases. Indian J Clin Biochem. 2015 Jan;30(1):11-26. doi: 10.1007/s12291-014-0446-0. Epub 2014 Jul 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25646037</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Birben E, Sahiner UM, Sackesen C, Erzurum S, Kalayci O. Oxidative stress and antioxidant defense. World Allergy Organ J. 2012 Jan;5(1):9-19. doi: 10.1097/WOX.0b013e3182439613. Epub 2012 Jan 13.</citation>
    <PMID>23268465</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Willcox JK, Ash SL, Catignani GL. Antioxidants and prevention of chronic disease. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2004;44(4):275-95. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15462130</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ravarotto V, Simioni F, Pagnin E, Davis PA, Calò LA. Oxidative stress - chronic kidney disease - cardiovascular disease: A vicious circle. Life Sci. 2018 Oct 1;210:125-131. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2018.08.067. Epub 2018 Aug 31. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30172705</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zoumpoulakis, P., Sinanoglou, V., Batrinou, A., Strati, I., Miniadis-Meimaroglou, S., &amp; Sflomos, K. (2012). A combined methodology to detect γ-irradiated white sesame seeds and evaluate the effects on fat content, physicochemical properties and protein allergenicity. Food Chemistry, 131(2), 713-721. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2011.09.049</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Namiki M. Nutraceutical functions of sesame: a review. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2007;47(7):651-73. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17943496</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Raeisi-Dehkordi, H., Mohammadi, M., Moghtaderi, F., &amp; Salehi-Abargouei, A. (2018). Do sesame seed and its products affect body weight and composition? A systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled clinical trials. Journal Of Functional Foods, 49, 324-332. doi: 10.1016/j.jff.2018.08.036</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pathak N, Rai AK, Kumari R, Bhat KV. Value addition in sesame: A perspective on bioactive components for enhancing utility and profitability. Pharmacogn Rev. 2014 Jul;8(16):147-55. doi: 10.4103/0973-7847.134249. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25125886</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gouveia Lde A, Cardoso CA, de Oliveira GM, Rosa G, Moreira AS. Effects of the Intake of Sesame Seeds (Sesamum indicum L.) and Derivatives on Oxidative Stress: A Systematic Review. J Med Food. 2016 Apr;19(4):337-45. doi: 10.1089/jmf.2015.0075. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27074618</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Virani SS, Alonso A, Benjamin EJ, Bittencourt MS, Callaway CW, Carson AP, Chamberlain AM, Chang AR, Cheng S, Delling FN, Djousse L, Elkind MSV, Ferguson JF, Fornage M, Khan SS, Kissela BM, Knutson KL, Kwan TW, Lackland DT, Lewis TT, Lichtman JH, Longenecker CT, Loop MS, Lutsey PL, Martin SS, Matsushita K, Moran AE, Mussolino ME, Perak AM, Rosamond WD, Roth GA, Sampson UKA, Satou GM, Schroeder EB, Shah SH, Shay CM, Spartano NL, Stokes A, Tirschwell DL, VanWagner LB, Tsao CW; American Heart Association Council on Epidemiology and Prevention Statistics Committee and Stroke Statistics Subcommittee. Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2020 Update: A Report From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2020 Mar 3;141(9):e139-e596. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000757. Epub 2020 Jan 29.</citation>
    <PMID>31992061</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Park KH, Park WJ. Endothelial Dysfunction: Clinical Implications in Cardiovascular Disease and Therapeutic Approaches. J Korean Med Sci. 2015 Sep;30(9):1213-25. doi: 10.3346/jkms.2015.30.9.1213. Epub 2015 Aug 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26339159</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Krüger-Genge A, Blocki A, Franke RP, Jung F. Vascular Endothelial Cell Biology: An Update. Int J Mol Sci. 2019 Sep 7;20(18). pii: E4411. doi: 10.3390/ijms20184411. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31500313</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajendran P, Rengarajan T, Thangavel J, Nishigaki Y, Sakthisekaran D, Sethi G, Nishigaki I. The vascular endothelium and human diseases. Int J Biol Sci. 2013 Nov 9;9(10):1057-69. doi: 10.7150/ijbs.7502. eCollection 2013. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24250251</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alipoor B, Haghighian MK, Sadat BE, Asghari M. Effect of sesame seed on lipid profile and redox status in hyperlipidemic patients. Int J Food Sci Nutr. 2012 Sep;63(6):674-8. doi: 10.3109/09637486.2011.652077. Epub 2012 Jan 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22263599</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khosravi-Boroujeni H, Nikbakht E, Natanelov E, Khalesi S. Can sesame consumption improve blood pressure? A systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. J Sci Food Agric. 2017 Aug;97(10):3087-3094. doi: 10.1002/jsfa.8361. Epub 2017 May 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28387047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kamal-Eldin A, Frank J, Razdan A, Tengblad S, Basu S, Vessby B. Effects of dietary phenolic compounds on tocopherol, cholesterol, and fatty acids in rats. Lipids. 2000 Apr;35(4):427-35.</citation>
    <PMID>10858028</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu WH, Kang YP, Wang NH, Jou HJ, Wang TA. Sesame ingestion affects sex hormones, antioxidant status, and blood lipids in postmenopausal women. J Nutr. 2006 May;136(5):1270-5.</citation>
    <PMID>16614415</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khalesi S, Paukste E, Nikbakht E, Khosravi-Boroujeni H. Sesame fractions and lipid profiles: a systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Br J Nutr. 2016 Mar 14;115(5):764-73. doi: 10.1017/S0007114515005012. Epub 2016 Jan 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26758593</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hirata F, Fujita K, Ishikura Y, Hosoda K, Ishikawa T, Nakamura H. Hypocholesterolemic effect of sesame lignan in humans. Atherosclerosis. 1996 Apr 26;122(1):135-36.</citation>
    <PMID>8724120</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Neves Ribeiro D, Gonçalves Alfenas Rde C, Bressan J, Brunoro Costa NM. The effect of oilseed consumption on appetite and on the risk of developing type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nutr Hosp. 2013 Mar-Apr;28(2):296-305. doi: 10.3305/nh.2013.28.2.6309. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23822678</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karatzi K, Stamatelopoulos K, Lykka M, Mantzouratou P, Skalidi S, Zakopoulos N, Papamichael C, Sidossis LS. Sesame oil consumption exerts a beneficial effect on endothelial function in hypertensive men. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2013 Apr;20(2):202-8. doi: 10.1177/2047487312437625. Epub 2012 Jan 25.</citation>
    <PMID>22345690</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Harokopio University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>PANAGIOTIS KANELLOS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>tahini</keyword>
  <keyword>sesame</keyword>
  <keyword>antioxidants</keyword>
  <keyword>postprandial</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

