<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04608643</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>infection in malnutrition</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04608643</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Inflammatory Markers and Cbc Indices in Severely Malnourished Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>Correlation Between Inflammatory Markers and Complete Blood Film Indices (White Blood Cells and Platelets ) in Severely Malnourished Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objectives of this study were to correlate between inflammatory markers and cbc&#xD;
      indices in severly malnourished children and to determine whether children with SAM can mount&#xD;
      an acute phase reactant response namely CRP and to evaluate the usefulness of quantitative&#xD;
      CRP as a predictor of severe infections in children with SAM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      And to correlate between inflammatory markers and CBC indices (mainly white blood cells and&#xD;
      platelets in those children .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Malnutrition remains one of the most common causes of morbidity and mortality among children&#xD;
      throughout the world.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnutrition is a pathological state resulting from a relative or absolute deficiency or&#xD;
      excess of one or more essential nutrients it may be clinically manifested or detected by&#xD;
      biochemical ,anthropometric measurements In 2009, the World Health Organization (WHO)&#xD;
      estimated that 20 million children under 5 years suffered from severe acute malnutrition&#xD;
      (SAM) worldwide, which is associated to more than half of their deaths each year in&#xD;
      developing countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Severe acute malnutrition is defined by a very low weight for height ( below -3z scores of&#xD;
      the median WHO growth standards ,by visible severe wasting or by presence of nutritional&#xD;
      edema It diminishes immune function and prevents the host from mounting an adequate&#xD;
      protective response to infectious agents. In turn, infections alter nutrient status and can&#xD;
      create a deficiency state. Thus, malnutrition and infection often act synergistically to&#xD;
      increase morbidity and mortality, particularly among infants and children The usual signs of&#xD;
      infection are absent or nonspecific in children with acute severe malnutrition (SAM),&#xD;
      Furthermore, laboratory diagnostic capacity is often limited in regions with the highest&#xD;
      burdens of malnutrition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnourished patients maintain the capacity to release inflammatory markers such as CRP &amp;&#xD;
      Interleukin-6 which can be considered favorable for combating infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnourished patients maintain the capacity to release inflammatory markers such as CRP which&#xD;
      can be considered favorable for combating infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (CRP) as a diagnostic tool of infection in children by the fact that SAM, particularly&#xD;
      edematous malnutrition, can be associated with reduced levels of acute phase proteins.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnutrition results in various changes in the body including changes in haematologic profile&#xD;
      of the body. White cell changes seen in protein energy malnutrition varies and such changes&#xD;
      have been attributed to various factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These include the synergist relationship which protein energy malnutrition has with&#xD;
      infections and thymic atrophy seen in children with PEM also platlet count and function&#xD;
      affected in SAM Various authors correlate blood platelet activation with infections and&#xD;
      concluded that Platelet destruction occurs in infection and hypercoagulable state . Moreover,&#xD;
      blood platelet has immunological functions and participate in the interaction between&#xD;
      pathogens and host defenses . Other studies revealed that some platelets functions (ADP and&#xD;
      collagen - induced platelets aggregations) have been decreased in protein energy malnutrition&#xD;
      .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>correlate between inflammatory markers and cbc indices in severly malnourished children</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>to determine whether children with SAM can mount an acute phase reactant response namely CRP and to evaluate the usefulness of quantitative CRP as a predictor of severe infections in children with SAM.&#xD;
And to correlate between inflammatory markers and CBC indices (mainly WBCS and platelets in those children .</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Inflammatory Response</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBC _inflammatory markers _ platelet function test</intervention_name>
    <description>CBC , Erythrocte sedimentation rate (ESR) ,CRP, platlet functions tests ( adhesions, 'aggregations ristocetin).</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        all patients who are included with inclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - All children aged 6 months up to 5 years who were admitted with the diagnosis of SAM .&#xD;
&#xD;
        The diagnosis of SAM was made using the recent WHO criteria measuring weight for&#xD;
        length/height and mid-upper arm circumference (MUAC) and the presence of bilateral pitting&#xD;
        oedema and severe wasting. Two forms of SAM exist in children: nonoedematous malnutrition,&#xD;
        also known as marasmus, characterized by severe wasting and currently defined by weight for&#xD;
        length/height z score &lt; -3 of the WHO growth standard, or MUAC &lt;11.5 cm; and edematious&#xD;
        malnutrition defined by bilateral pitting edema also known as Kwashiorkor.10 The term&#xD;
        marasmic kwashiorkor, has been used to describe children with both wasting and edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Children below 6 months or above 5 years 2. Children with mild and moderate&#xD;
             malnutrition, 3. Children with malnutrition secondary to serious underlying conditions&#xD;
             including&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congenital anomalies, inborn errors of metabolism, malignancies, inherited&#xD;
                  autosomal disorders like cystic fibrosis, chronic diarrhial diseases like coeliac&#xD;
                  disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congenital cardiac diseases, chronic kidney disease were excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>meret michael, doctor</last_name>
    <phone>01024189397</phone>
    <email>meretmichael@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>emad el daly, professor</last_name>
    <phone>01223559943</phone>
    <email>emadeldeen.ail@med.au.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19087431/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=Pneumonia+in+severely+malnourished+children+in+developing+countries</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23874731/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18568246/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18510818/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24199802/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Calder PC, Jackson AA. Undernutrition, infection and immune function. Nutr Res Rev. 2000 Jun;13(1):3-29. doi: 10.1079/095442200108728981.</citation>
    <PMID>19087431</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chisti MJ, Tebruegge M, La Vincente S, Graham SM, Duke T. Pneumonia in severely malnourished children in developing countries - mortality risk, aetiology and validity of WHO clinical signs: a systematic review. Trop Med Int Health. 2009 Oct;14(10):1173-89. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2009.02364.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19772545</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Page AL, de Rekeneire N, Sayadi S, Aberrane S, Janssens AC, Rieux C, Djibo A, Manuguerra JC, Ducou-le-Pointe H, Grais RF, Schaefer M, Guerin PJ, Baron E. Infections in children admitted with complicated severe acute malnutrition in Niger. PLoS One. 2013 Jul 17;8(7):e68699. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0068699. Print 2013.</citation>
    <PMID>23874731</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Delgado AF, Okay TS, Leone C, Nichols B, Del Negro GM, Vaz FA. Hospital malnutrition and inflammatory response in critically ill children and adolescents admitted to a tertiary intensive care unit. Clinics (Sao Paulo). 2008 Jun;63(3):357-62.</citation>
    <PMID>18568246</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jahoor F, Badaloo A, Reid M, Forrester T. Protein metabolism in severe childhood malnutrition. Ann Trop Paediatr. 2008 Jun;28(2):87-101. doi: 10.1179/146532808X302107. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18510818</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Speth C, Löffler J, Krappmann S, Lass-Flörl C, Rambach G. Platelets as immune cells in infectious diseases. Future Microbiol. 2013 Nov;8(11):1431-51. doi: 10.2217/fmb.13.104. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24199802</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Meret Michael Fahmy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>inflammatory markers in severly malnourished children</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

