<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04601870</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0717</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>A534253</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>SMPH/MEDICINE/GEN INT MD</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>Protocol Version 1/6/2021</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>3R35CA197573-06S1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04601870</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Financial Incentives for Smoking Cessation Treatment Engagement</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Test of Financial Incentives for Smoking Cessation Treatment Engagement Among A Healthcare System's Universal Primary Care Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Wisconsin, Madison</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Wisconsin, Madison</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is being done to see if financial incentives increase the rate at which smokers&#xD;
      engage in cessation treatment. A total of 540 participants will be enrolled by invitation&#xD;
      from 6 primary care clinics of the participating healthcare system. Participants will be in&#xD;
      the study for approximately 28 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this randomized controlled trial, each patient of participating Group Health Cooperative&#xD;
      of South Central Wisconsin (GHC-SCW) primary care clinics who is listed in the Cigarette User&#xD;
      Registry receiving standard telephone contact from their GHC-SCW Tobacco Cessation Outreach&#xD;
      Specialist (TCOS) to discuss tobacco use treatment options will be reminded of GHC-SCW's&#xD;
      commitment to helping them improve their health, advised to quit smoking, offered support to&#xD;
      quit smoking, recruited, screened, consented, and randomized over the phone to one of three&#xD;
      conditions of financial engagement incentives. Smokers unwilling to participate in the&#xD;
      incentivized treatment program will be offered entry into the existing GHC-SCW standard&#xD;
      smoking cessation program. Participants in the research study will also receive smoking&#xD;
      treatment via the existing GHC-SCW standard smoking cessation program. Participants in the&#xD;
      research study will be told that they may receive a treatment engagement incentive, with the&#xD;
      amount consistent with their randomized incentive condition; receipt of their assigned&#xD;
      incentive amount is dependent upon their setting a quit date and completing two smoking&#xD;
      cessation treatment counseling contacts. The smoking cessation treatment includes medication&#xD;
      and 3 quit smoking counseling calls scheduled to occur after the recruitment contact call,&#xD;
      which is the standard smoking cessation program available to all GHC-SCW patients. This&#xD;
      program entails a brief counseling call a week (typically 5-7 days) pre-quit i.e., before the&#xD;
      patient's target quit date (TQD), approximately 5-7 days following the TQD (Week 1), and&#xD;
      about one month following the TQD (Week 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research participants will be asked to complete brief (3 to 5 minute) assessments during each&#xD;
      standard care smoking treatment counseling call by GHC-SCW, plus 15-25 minute research study&#xD;
      phone interviews 3- and 6-months post-TQD for study purposes. Those claiming abstinence at&#xD;
      the 6-month post-TQD phone interview will be asked to return to their primary care clinic to&#xD;
      complete breath, urine, and/or saliva testing to verify abstinence from combustible tobacco.&#xD;
      This will entail providing breath samples for carbon monoxide testing and/or a urine or&#xD;
      saliva sample for immediate cotinine testing (no samples will be stored). Participants may&#xD;
      also be asked to collect a saliva sample at home and return it in the mail if they do not&#xD;
      attend a biochemical verification visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the relations between treatment engagement financial incentive amounts&#xD;
           offered and likelihood of patient engagement in smoking cessation treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Primary outcome measure: Patient engagement in smoking cessation treatment (defined&#xD;
                as setting a TQD and completing two phone counseling calls).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Conduct exploratory analyses on the effects of the different incentive engagement&#xD;
           amounts on biochemically confirmed point-prevalence abstinence 6 months post-quit-date,&#xD;
           and determine whether incentive condition affects abstinence via effects on smoking&#xD;
           treatment engagement (i.e., whether smoking treatment engagement mediates the relations&#xD;
           between different engagement incentive conditions and 6-month smoking abstinence).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the incremental cost-effectiveness of the different financial engagement&#xD;
           incentive amounts with regard to total program costs vs. usual care, net monetary&#xD;
           benefit (NMB), cost per quit, and incremental cost-effectiveness ratios (ICERs), with&#xD;
           the last determined with regard to cost of additional smoker recruited and each&#xD;
           additional individual who quits smoking.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the representativeness of smoking treatment reach and smoking abstinence&#xD;
           outcomes generated by the various engagement incentive amounts with regard to different&#xD;
           groups of smokers: e.g., those low in socio-economic status, priority populations,&#xD;
           different racial and ethnic groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Who Set A Target Quit Date (TQD) and Complete Phone Counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 60 days from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The relation between treatment engagement financial incentive amounts offered and likelihood of patient engagement in smoking cessation treatment will be assessed by the number of participants who set a TQD and complete two phone counseling calls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>6 month smoking abstinence rates</measure>
    <time_frame>between 6.5 months and 8 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory analysis on the effects of the different incentive engagement amounts on biochemically confirmed abstinence 6-month post quit date.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">540</enrollment>
  <condition>Quitting Smoking</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Financial Incentive</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>N=180 participants randomized to not be offered monetary incentive to participate in an intervention to quit smoking.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Financial Incentive (100 dollars)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>N=180 randomized participants will be offered a 100 dollar incentive to participate in an intervention to quit smoking.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Financial Incentive (50 dollars)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>N=180 randomized participants will be offered a 50 dollar incentive to participant in an intervention to quit smoking.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No Financial Incentive</intervention_name>
    <description>No monetary incentive to participate in quit planning and quit counseling with a tobacco cessation specialist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>No Financial Incentive</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Financial Incentive (100 dollars)</intervention_name>
    <description>Financial incentive (100 dollars) to participate in quit planning and quit counseling with a tobacco cessation specialist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Financial Incentive (100 dollars)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Financial Incentive (50 dollars)</intervention_name>
    <description>Financial incentive (50 dollars) to participate in quit planning and quit counseling with a tobacco cessation specialist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Financial Incentive (50 dollars)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On Cigarette User Registry at a participating clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to speak English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activated healthcare power of attorney or cognitive impairment that would preclude&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Existing target quit date approximately 30 days from date of call to TCOS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current billable insurance status in EHR of Medicare or non-BadgerCare Medicaid&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior screening for Treatment Engagement incentive enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael C Fiore, MD, MPH, MBA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Wisconsin, Madison</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53711</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>smoking cessation</keyword>
  <keyword>financial incentives</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data collected during the trial, after deidentification. Researchers whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, for independent verification of study outcomes, or to conduct subsequent clinical research.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Beginning 12 months after publication of primary outcomes, and ending 5 years after that date.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Proposals should be directed to [PI Michael Fiore, MD at UW-CTRI (mcf@ctri.wisc.edu)]. If approved after review by regulatory counsel, requestors will enter into a formal data sharing agreement. Data will be shared via encrypted single-user file transmission protocol.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

