<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04607954</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MC1923</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-08088</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>MC1923</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA015083</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04607954</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Durvalumab and Topotecan for the Treatment of Relapsed or Refractory Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Clinical Trial of Durvalumab (MEDI4736) and Topotecan in Patients With Relapsed Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer Previously Treated With Chemotherapy and Immunotherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies the effects of durvalumab and topotecan in treating patients with&#xD;
      extensive stage small cell lung cancer that has come back (relapsed) or has not responded to&#xD;
      previous treatment with chemotherapy and immunotherapy (refractory). Monoclonal antibodies,&#xD;
      such as durvalumab, may interfere with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread.&#xD;
      Topotecan may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell&#xD;
      growth Giving durvalumab and topotecan may help kill more tumor cells and help patients live&#xD;
      longer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate whether combination of durvalumab with topotecan can increase the 6-month&#xD;
      survival in patients with extensive stage small cell lung cancer who have progressed after&#xD;
      initial combination of chemotherapy and immunotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To describe the safety and toxicity of durvalumab and topotecan in patients with extensive&#xD;
      stage small cell lung cancer who have progressed after initial combination of chemotherapy&#xD;
      and immunotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess in a preliminary fashion antitumor efficacy of this approach by assessing&#xD;
      overall survival, progression-free survival, and response rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CORRELATIVE RESEARCH OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Blood and tissue will be banked for future studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive durvalumab intravenously (IV) over 60 minutes on day 1 and topotecan&#xD;
      hydrochloride IV over 30 minutes on days 1-5. Cycles repeat every 21 days in the absence of&#xD;
      disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients without disease progression are followed up at&#xD;
      30 days, every 6 weeks until disease progression, and then every 3 months thereafter for up&#xD;
      to 5 years from enrollment. After completion of study treatment, patients with disease&#xD;
      progression are followed every 3 months for up to 5 years from enrollment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>6-month survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of successes for 6-month overall survival (OS) rate will be estimated by the number of successes divided by the total number of evaluable patients. Ninety percent confidence intervals for the true success proportion will be calculated according to the exact binomial method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>AEs will be monitored using the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0. The maximum grade for each type of AE will be recorded for each patient, and frequency tables will be reviewed to determine AE patterns.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with a confirmed tumor response per Immune Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (iRECIST) criteria. Response rate and 90% confidence intervals will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From registration to the first of either disease progression or death from any cause, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>PFS will be estimated using the method of Kaplan-Meier. Medians and 90% confidence intervals will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From registration to death from any cause, assessed to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>OS will be estimated using the method of Kaplan Meier. Medians and 90% confidence intervals will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">43</enrollment>
  <condition>Platinum-Sensitive Lung Small Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Extensive Stage Lung Small Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Extensive Stage Lung Small Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (durvalumab, topotecan hydrochloride)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive durvalumab IV over 60 minutes on day 1 and topotecan hydrochloride IV over 30 minutes on days 1-5. Cycles repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (durvalumab, topotecan hydrochloride)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Imfinzi</other_name>
    <other_name>Immunoglobulin G1, Anti-(Human Protein B7-H1) (Human Monoclonal MEDI4736 Heavy Chain), Disulfide with Human Monoclonal MEDI4736 Kappa-chain, Dimer</other_name>
    <other_name>MEDI-4736</other_name>
    <other_name>MEDI4736</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Topotecan Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (durvalumab, topotecan hydrochloride)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hycamptamine</other_name>
    <other_name>Hycamtin</other_name>
    <other_name>SKF S-104864-A</other_name>
    <other_name>Topotecan HCl</other_name>
    <other_name>topotecan hydrochloride (oral)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological confirmation of small cell lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Relapsed or progressed after only one prior chemotherapy and PD-1 or PD-L1&#xD;
                  inhibitor regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior therapy must have been an etoposide platinum doublet combined with PD-1 or&#xD;
                  PD-L1 inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Must have &quot;platinum-sensitive&quot; disease according to the following definitions:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  &quot;Sensitive&quot; disease: Relapse occurred &gt; 90 days after completion of prior&#xD;
                       therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  &quot;Refractory&quot; disease: No response to therapy or relapse occurred =&lt; 90 days&#xD;
                       after completion of prior therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &gt; 30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/mm^3 (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Albumin &gt;= 2.5 mg/dL (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or direct bilirubin =&lt; ULN if&#xD;
             total bilirubin is &gt; 1.5 x ULN (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate transaminase (AST) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN (=&lt; 5 x&#xD;
             ULN for patients with liver involvement) (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine OR glomerular filtration rate (GFR) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN OR GFR &gt; 60 mL/min for&#xD;
             patients with creatinine &gt; 1.5 x ULN (obtained =&lt; 15 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test done =&lt; 7 days prior to registration, for persons of&#xD;
             childbearing potential only&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons able to become pregnant OR able to father a child must be willing to use an&#xD;
             adequate method of contraception while on treatment and for 120 days after last&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy &gt;= 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to provide mandatory blood specimens for correlative research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to provide mandatory tissue specimens for correlative research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to return to Mayo Clinic for follow-up (during the active monitoring phase of&#xD;
             the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following because this study involves an investigational agent whose&#xD;
             genotoxic, mutagenic and teratogenic effects on the developing fetus and newborn are&#xD;
             unknown:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant persons&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nursing persons&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persons of childbearing potential OR able to father a child who are unwilling to&#xD;
                  employ adequate contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following prior therapies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Live vaccine &lt; 30 days prior to registration, including intranasal flu vaccine&#xD;
                  (e.g. Flu-Mist[R]) (Note: Injected seasonal influenza vaccine is not &quot;live&quot;)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Surgery &lt; 28 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chemotherapy or targeted small molecule therapy &lt; 21 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation therapy &lt; 21 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Investigational therapy or investigational device &lt; 14 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to recover to =&lt; grade 1 (or baseline) from adverse events due to previously&#xD;
             administered therapies or prior surgery. Exceptions: Neuropathy, fatigue, and/or&#xD;
             alopecia may be grade 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases. NOTE: Patients with previously&#xD;
             treated brain metastases may participate provided all of the following are true:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  They are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging =&lt; 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
                  registration and any neurologic symptoms have returned to baseline)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Are not using steroids =&lt; 14 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-morbid systemic illnesses or other severe concurrent disease which, in the judgment&#xD;
             of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study or&#xD;
             interfere significantly with the proper assessment of safety and toxicity of the&#xD;
             prescribed regimens&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection (defined as patients who are&#xD;
             not on anti-retroviral treatment and have detectable viral load and CD4+ &lt; 500/ml).&#xD;
             NOTE: HIV-positive patients who are well controlled on anti-retroviral therapy are&#xD;
             allowed to enroll&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic treatment, documented history of severe&#xD;
             autoimmune disease, or a syndrome that requires systemic steroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             agents. NOTE: Exceptions are allowed for:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vitiligo&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Resolved childhood asthma/atopy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intermittent use of bronchodilators or inhaled steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Daily steroids at dose of =&lt; 10mg of prednisone (or equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Local steroid injections&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stable hypothyroidism on replacement therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stable diabetes mellitus on non-insulin therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sjogren's syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication &lt; 14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
             The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g.,&#xD;
                  intraarticular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or its equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., premedication for&#xD;
                  computed tomography [CT] scans)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ongoing or active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Interstitial lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serious, chronic gastrointestinal conditions associated with diarrhea (e.g.,&#xD;
                  Crohn's disease or others)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known active hepatitis B (i.e., known positive hepatitis B virus [HBV] surface&#xD;
                  antigen [HBsAg] reactive)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known active hepatitis C (i.e., positive for hepatitis C virus ribonucleic acid&#xD;
                  [HCV RNA] detected by polymerase chain reaction [PCR])&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known active tuberculosis (TB)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic congestive heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable cardiac arrhythmia or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study&#xD;
                  requirements (e.g., substance abuse)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myocardial infarction =&lt; 6 months, or congestive heart failure requiring&#xD;
             use of ongoing maintenance therapy for life-threatening ventricular arrhythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving any other investigational agent which would be considered as a treatment for&#xD;
             the primary neoplasm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to durvalumab or any of its excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous adverse event attributed to durvalumab or other PD-1 or PD-L1 directed&#xD;
             therapy that led to drug discontinuation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of grade &gt;= 3 immune-related adverse event or any grade of immune-related&#xD;
             neurologic or ocular adverse event while receiving immunotherapy. Note: Patients who&#xD;
             had endocrine adverse events =&lt; grade 2 are allowed to enroll if they are stable on&#xD;
             appropriate replacement therapy and asymptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other active malignancy &lt; 6 months prior to registration. EXCEPTIONS: Non-melanotic&#xD;
             skin cancer, papillary thyroid cancer, or carcinoma-in-situ of the cervix, or others&#xD;
             curatively treated and now considered to be at less than 30% risk of relapse&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Konstantinos Leventakos</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic in Rochester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocliniccancerstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Konstantinos Leventakos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Small Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Topotecan</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

