<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04609761</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IVIGPANSOpen</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04609761</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open-label Trial of IVIG in Children With PANS</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intravenous Immunoglobulin (IVIG) Treatment in Children With Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS): an Open-label Trial in South-western Sweden</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Göteborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Göteborg University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Open-label prospective trial to study efficacy, safety and tolerability of intravenous&#xD;
      immunoglobulin (IVIG) once monthly for 6 months in children and adolescents with PANS. Number&#xD;
      of subjects: 10. Age range: 4-17 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS) is a recently defined research&#xD;
      diagnosis describing an abrupt, dramatic onset of neuropsychiatric symptoms including&#xD;
      obsessions/compulsions and/or food restriction in children. Immunologic mechanisms are&#xD;
      suspected, but treatment trials are few.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Open-label prospective trial to study efficacy, safety and tolerability of intravenous&#xD;
      immunoglobulin (IVIG) once monthly for 6 months in children and adolescents with PANS&#xD;
      (including the subgroup PANDAS). Number of subjects: 10. Age range: 4-17 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS) is a recently defined research&#xD;
      diagnosis describing an abrupt, dramatic onset of neuropsychiatric symptoms including&#xD;
      obsessions/compulsions and/or food restriction in children. Immunologic mechanisms are&#xD;
      suspected, but treatment trials are few.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of intravenous immunoglobulin&#xD;
      (IVIG), 2 g/kg given every 4 weeks for 6 months, to patients with post-infectious&#xD;
      PANS/PANDAS, in improving neuropsychiatric symptoms and impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives of this study are to evaluate changes from baseline to follow-up at&#xD;
      3 months, 6 months and 12 months in:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  adaptive functioning&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  quality of life&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  cognitive functioning&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  for patients with baseline inflammation signs on cerebral Magnetic Resonance Imaging&#xD;
           (MRI) to evaluate changes in these measures after IVIG therapy after 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  number of days of work/school/daily activities missed per subject year due to&#xD;
           PANS/PANDAS before and after IVIG therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  parental care load, e.g. need for sick leave, before and after IVIG therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Immunoglobulin (IgG, IgM and IgA) levels at baseline, 3 months, 6 months and 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  sustainability of any improvement at 12 months after initiation of IVIG measured with&#xD;
           the PANS scale, CGI-S and CGI-I&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the safety and tolerability of high dose IVIG therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical signs and symptoms (nausea, headache, local reactions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ALAT&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hemoglobin, complete blood count including leucocyte differential&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigational product: Intravenous immunoglobulin IVIG (Privigen), 2 g/kg BW every 4th week&#xD;
      for 6 months (= 6 infusions).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open-label single-arm trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS) scale symptoms and impairment</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Investigator-rated scale measuring symptom severity and impairment in Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS), score range 0-50, lower is better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in CGI-S</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>CGI-S (Clinical Global Impression-Severity) measures global symptom severity, score range 1-7, lower is better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CGI-I</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>CGI-I (Clinical Global Impression-Improvement) measures global improvement, score range 1-7, lower is better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in CY-BOCS scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>CY-BOCS scale measures Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) Symptoms, investigator-rated, score range 0-40, lower is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change on ABAS (Adaptive Behavior Assessment System) II scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures level of functioning in everyday life, parent- and teacher-rated, score range 40-160, higher is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change on Child Health Inventory (CHIP-CE) scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures quality of life, parent-rated, standardized T-score, mean 50, standard deviation 10, higher score is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change on 5-15 scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures neuropsychiatric symptoms, score range 1-543, lower is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in neuromotor functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Neuromotor examination by investigator</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cognitive function</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Working memory test from Wechsler scale, standardized scores age norms, mean 100, standard deviation 10, higher is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in School-PANS (Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome) Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Short version of PANS-scale rated by teacher or school assistant, score range 0-50, lower is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>School absence</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Days absent from school past 3 months or since last visit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental care load</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Sick leave number of days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in laboratory assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammatory measures as specified in CRF, lower is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/child report</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>In a subgroup who can tolerate MRI without general anaesthesia. Specially developed protocol for measuring inflammation signs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>PANS Pediatric Acute-Onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IVIG treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-arm open-label</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Privigen Injectable Product (Intravenous Immunoglobulin)</intervention_name>
    <description>Privigen, 2 g/kg BW every 4th week for 6 months (= 6 infusions).</description>
    <arm_group_label>IVIG treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>IVIG</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The subject and parents/caregivers have given written consent or assent to participate&#xD;
             in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Children and adolescents between the ages of 4 and 17 years at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented and confirmed pre-existing diagnosis of post-infectious PANS/PANDAS&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The subject has not been treated with IVIG previously or not been treated for the last&#xD;
             6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. If the patient is on long-term antibiotic prophylaxis, this should be unchanged one&#xD;
             month before baseline and during the trial. Throat culture for Group A Streptococcus&#xD;
             (GAS) should be performed before study start and standard phenoxymethyl penicillin&#xD;
             treatment given if positive culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Infections occurring during the trial should be treated according to standard clinical&#xD;
             practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Treatment with COX-inhibitors or corticosteroids should be discontinued at least one&#xD;
             month before baseline and during the trial. Two-three days treatment with&#xD;
             corticosteroids during and after IVIG treatment is allowed to reduce IVIG side effects&#xD;
             such as headache and nausea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any psychopharmacological treatment (e.g. SSRI, antipsychotics), if considered&#xD;
             essential for the subject, should be kept at a stable and unchanged dose from one&#xD;
             month before baseline and during the trial. If not considered essential, it should be&#xD;
             discontinued at least one month before baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The medical records for all subjects should be available to document diagnosis,&#xD;
             previous infections and treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. For female participants, adequate contraception should be used, see exclusion&#xD;
             criteria. A negative pregnancy test can possibly be a requirement, specify&#xD;
             requirement/type of pregnancy test. Contraceptive requirements may also apply to male&#xD;
             participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical evidence of any significant acute or chronic disease that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator, may interfere with successful completion of the trial or place the&#xD;
             subject at undue medical risk. If encephalitis cannot be excluded by clinical history&#xD;
             alone, spinal tap results are required before study start to rule out encephalitis&#xD;
             (which would need to be treated according to encephalitis treatment guidelines). MRI&#xD;
             should have been performed if clinically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The subject has had a known serious adverse reaction to immunoglobulin or any severe&#xD;
             anaphylactic reaction to blood or any blood-derived product&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Females of childbearing potential who are pregnant, have a positive pregnancy test at&#xD;
             Baseline (human chorionic gonadotropin [HCG]-based assay), are breastfeeding, or&#xD;
             unwilling to practice a highly effective method of contraception (oral, injectable or&#xD;
             implanted hormonal methods of contraception, placement of an intrauterine device [IUD]&#xD;
             or intrauterine system [IUS], condom or occlusive cap with spermicidal&#xD;
             foam/gel/film/cream/suppository, male sterilization, or true abstinence) throughout&#xD;
             the study Note: True abstinence: When this is in line with the preferred and usual&#xD;
             lifestyle of the subject. (Periodic abstinence [e.g., calendar, ovulation,&#xD;
             symptothermal, post-ovulation methods], declaration of abstinence for the duration of&#xD;
             a trial, and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of contraception.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The subject has significant proteinuria (dipstick proteinuria ≥ 3+, known urinary&#xD;
             protein loss &gt; 1 g/24 hours, or nephrotic syndrome), has a history of acute renal&#xD;
             failure, has severe renal impairment (blood urea nitrogen [BUN] or creatinine more&#xD;
             than 2.5 times the upper limit of normal [ULN]), and/or is on dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subject has Screening Visit values of aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine&#xD;
             aminotransferase (ALT) levels exceeding 2.5 times the ULN for the expected normal&#xD;
             range for the testing laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The subject has hemoglobin &lt; 90 g/L at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The subject has a known previous infection with or clinical signs and symptoms&#xD;
             consistent with current hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The subject has a history of or current diagnosis of deep venous thrombosis or&#xD;
             thromboembolism (e.g., myocardial infarction, cerebrovascular accident, or transient&#xD;
             ischemic attack); history refers to an incident in the year prior to Baseline or 2&#xD;
             episodes over lifetime.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The subject currently has a known hyperviscosity syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The subject has an acquired medical condition that is known to cause secondary immune&#xD;
             deficiency, such as chronic lymphocytic leukemia, lymphoma, multiple myeloma, chronic&#xD;
             or recurrent neutropenia (absolute neutrophil count less than 1.0 x 109/L], or HIV&#xD;
             infection/acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The subject is HIV positive by NAT based on a Screening blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The subject has non-controlled arterial hypertension at a level of greater than or&#xD;
             equal to the 90th percentile blood pressure (either systolic or diastolic) for their&#xD;
             age and height&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The subject is receiving any of the following medications: (a) immunosuppressants&#xD;
             including chemotherapeutic agents, (b) immunomodulators, (c) long-term systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids defined as daily dose &gt; 1 mg of prednisone equivalent/kg/day for &gt; 30&#xD;
             days. Note: Intermittent courses of corticosteroids of not more than 10 days would not&#xD;
             exclude a subject. Inhaled or topical corticosteroids are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. The subject has known substance or prescription drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. The subject has participated in another clinical trial within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             Baseline (observational studies without investigative treatments [non-interventional]&#xD;
             are permitted) or has received any investigational blood product within the previous 3&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. The subject/caregiver is unwilling to comply with any aspect of the protocol,&#xD;
             including IV infusions, blood sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Mentally challenged subjects who cannot give independent informed consent In the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator the subject may have compliance problems with the protocol&#xD;
             and the procedures of the protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher Gillberg, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Gillberg Neuropsychiatry, Centre Sahlgrenska Academy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ingrid Vinsa, Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>+4631-3425971</phone>
    <email>ingrid.vinsa@gnc.gu.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Klara Jakobsson, Study Nurse</last_name>
    <phone>031-3425971</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gillberg Neuropsychiatry Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gothenburg</city>
        <zip>411 19</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ingrid Vinsa</last_name>
      <phone>031-3425970</phone>
      <email>ingrid.vinsa@gnc.gu.se</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 29, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/61/NCT04609761/Prot_SAP_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

