<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04601597</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IVTEAM2020-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04601597</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multicentre Pilot Study of Midline Catheter's Tip at Different Position</brief_title>
  <official_title>Observational Multicentre Pilot Study of Outcomes of Midline Catheter's Tip at Different Position</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Observe and compare the incidence of complications when midline catheter's tip at 3 different&#xD;
      location . such as thrombosis, infection, occulsion, phlebitis, and damage to the vascular&#xD;
      intima, and catheter's indwelling time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prospective case-control observation study method was adopted. The investigators of each&#xD;
      center included patients who met the inclusion and exclusion criteria, and fully informed&#xD;
      about the content of the study, possible benefits and risks. After obtaining informed&#xD;
      consent, the patients were included in the method of continuous sampling and convenient&#xD;
      sampling. According to the method of random control, the patients were grouped. In the&#xD;
      control group, the length of catheter insertion is measured from the pre-puncture point to&#xD;
      the shoulder or armpit. In the experimental group 1, the catheter insertion length is&#xD;
      measured from the pre-puncture point to the midpoint of the clavicle, and in the experimental&#xD;
      group 2 catheter insertion length is measured from the pre-puncture point to the&#xD;
      sternoclavicular joint. With a single blind design, patients do not know the enrollment&#xD;
      situation. The catheter was inserted by a full-time specialist nurse of intravenous therapy&#xD;
      under ultrasound guidance combined with the modified Seedinger technique. The catheter was&#xD;
      inserted according to the length of different measurement methods in different groups. After&#xD;
      the catheter was inserted, X-ray examination was performed to determine the catheter tip&#xD;
      position again. Data collection and follow-up observation will be conducted by researchers&#xD;
      who have been uniformly trained. Record the baseline data of the patients in the group before&#xD;
      catheterization, record the insertion status during catheterization, record the patient's&#xD;
      catheter use and catheter sealing frequency every day during catheter placement, and evaluate&#xD;
      catheter function and complications until extubation daily. Within 24 hours after extubation,&#xD;
      the sonographer performed vascular ultrasound to check the endometrial condition of the&#xD;
      catheter indwelling path.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phlebitis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Prolonged veins appear red, swollen, hot, and painful, with severe cord-like changes and indurations when touching. Mechanical phlebitis, infectious phlebitis, and thrombophlebitis are collected as phlebitis data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Catheter-related thrombosis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PICC-related thrombosis in this study refers only to symptomatic thrombi, excluding asymptomatic thrombi. Catheter-related venous thrombosis was diagnosed by color Doppler ultrasound examination when the clinical manifestations were related symptoms such as swelling and pain in the upper arm of the catheterization side.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occlusion</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>According to the degree, it is divided into complete occlusion and incomplete occlusion. When there is resistance or difficulty in flushing the tube, poor blood withdrawal or even no blood return can indicate that the catheter is incompletely occlusion; if it is difficult to flush the tube and draw blood, it can indicate that the catheter is completely occlusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Catheter-Related Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Including local infection of the puncture site and catheter-related blood stream infection (Catheter-Related Blood stream Infection, CRBSI). Local infection refers to redness, swelling and pain around the puncture point, or even pus; Catheter-associated bloodstream infection: refers to patients with indwelling catheters who develop bacteremia and draw blood cultures through peripheral veins for at least one positive result, accompanied by fever (&gt; 380C), chills, or hypotension. Other clear sources of bloodstream infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Bloody fluid still leaks out of catheter puncture 48 hours after catheter insertion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dislodgment</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The catheter slipped more than 3cm above the exposed length of the first tube placement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>exudation</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>There is a slight yellow or clear liquid leakage from the catheter puncture site</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>dwell time</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Time from tube insertion to extubation, in days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endometrial conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours before intubation and after extubation</time_frame>
    <description>Ultrasound examination of the vascular intima before catheterization and within 24 hours after extubation was performed. No abnormality in the intimal smoothness was negative, and abnormalities in the intimal smoothness and hyperplasia were positive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">384</enrollment>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Infected patients, neurosurgery, respiratory, gastroenterology, orthopedics, cardiology,&#xD;
        general surgery and other inpatients in 6 general hospitals in china&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        expected intravenous infusion time over 1 week more than 14 years old full consciousness,&#xD;
        in line with the indications for the use of medium-length catheters, signed the study&#xD;
        informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        There is a source of infection at the place of catheterization History of radiation&#xD;
        therapy, history of thrombosis, history of trauma or vascular surgery at the site of&#xD;
        catheterization Irritating orhyperosmolar solutions Patients who need to be discharged with&#xD;
        catheter&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zhao Linfang, Master</last_name>
    <phone>8613588819123</phone>
    <email>3193159@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sir Runrun Shaw Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <state>Zhejiang</state>
        <zip>310016</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zhao Linfang, Master</last_name>
      <phone>8613588819123</phone>
      <email>3193159@zju.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yong Fang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 7, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/97/NCT04601597/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

