<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04600297</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>68869993-511.06-.E.150622</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04600297</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>3 Years Clinical Evaluation of 3D Printed Resin Composite Fixed Dental Prosthesis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Evaluation of 3D Printed Resin Composite Posterior Fixed Dental Prosthesis: A Prospective Clinical Trial up to 3 Years</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Saremco Dental AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In recent years there is a rapid increase in the use of computer aided design and production.&#xD;
      Two main types of materials are used in the production of indirect CAD/CAM restorations&#xD;
      namely resin composite based and ceramic ones. Mechanical properties and esthetics of ceramic&#xD;
      materials are superior to resin composites but the advantages of intraoral repair, easy&#xD;
      adjustments and polish of resin materials are undeniable. Improvements of mechanical&#xD;
      properties of resin-based materials resulted in the development of resin composite blocks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3D printed restorations, which can be performed as chairside in one session can be&#xD;
      manufactured in case of any broken / chipping / debonding cases, without the need for&#xD;
      repeated impression making. This saves time for the patient and the clinician. By using these&#xD;
      3D resin-based composite materials in fixed partial dentures, intraoral repairs can be&#xD;
      performed. In addition, the high costs of burs and possible damage to the CAD/CAM blocks used&#xD;
      in ceramic milling are eliminated when restoration are manufactured in printers with the DLP&#xD;
      technology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study was to evaluate the clinical outcome of 3D printed posterior&#xD;
      resin composite FDP restorations up to 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be carried out as a prospective study, with assessment of the restorations&#xD;
      after three year. The project includes 3-unit posterior fixed dental prosthesis (FDP) for 70&#xD;
      cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients participating in the investigation are going to be informed by the &quot;Clinicians&quot; on&#xD;
      the background and risk of the investigation. Patients have to give their written consent to&#xD;
      participate in the investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment procedure includes the following steps:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preparation scanning, colour determination, design of the restoration, printing the&#xD;
      restoration, adjusting occlusion, finishing and polishing and cementation of the FDP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The control procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two weeks after cementation, baseline control will be performed according to USPHS and FDI 2.&#xD;
      The restorations will be evaluated at 3 years recall.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Cases of one missing posterior tooth to be restored with 3D printed resin composite posterior FDP</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified FDI (World Dental Federation) criteria for dental restoration assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The FDI (World Dental Federation) criteria for dental restorations assessment, as it was published after consensus in 2007 and updated in 2010. The criteria were categorized into three groups: esthetic, functional and biological parameters. Each criterion can be expressed with five scores, three for acceptable and two for non-acceptable (one for reparable and one for replacement). The worst score of all items is retained as the overall score of the restoration, thus resulting in a single (ordinal) primary outcome. Two independent evaluators will evaluate the restorations by using modified FDI criteria.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plaque accumulation according to the Silness &amp; Löe (1964) Plaque Index</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>0 = No plaque in the gingival area.&#xD;
= A film of plaque adhering to the free gingival margin and adjacent area of the tooth. The plaque may only be recognized by running a probe across the tooth surface.&#xD;
= Moderate accumulation of soft deposits within the gingival pocket, on the gingival pocket, on the gingival margin and/or adjacent tooth surface, which can be seen by the naked eye.&#xD;
= Abundance of soft matter within the gingival pocket and/or on the gingival margin and adjacent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gingival Inflammation according to the Silness &amp; Löe (1964) Gingival Index.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>0 = Normal gingival.&#xD;
= Mild inflammation-slight change in colour, slight oedema. No bleeding on probing&#xD;
= Moderate inflammation-redness, oedema and glazing. Bleeding on probing.&#xD;
= Severe inflammation-marked redness and oedema. Ulceration. Tendency to spontaneous bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Composite Resins</condition>
  <condition>Dental Prosthesis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3D printed resin composite posterior FDP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Three units posterior fixed dental prosthesis made with 3D printed resin composite material</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ELS Even Stronger (3D Printed Resin Composite)</intervention_name>
    <description>Missing of one premolar cases will be restored using the 3D Printed resin composite (ELS Even Stronger, Saremco, Switzerland). The steps of the procedure: Preparation, scanning, colour determination, design of the restoration, printing the restoration, adjusting occlusion, finishing and polishing, cementation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>3D printed resin composite posterior FDP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need for a three-unit posterior FDP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One missing tooth from the second premolar to the second molar where 1st molar is&#xD;
             missing (pontic replacing 1st molar)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of opposing natural dentition (either intact or restored with intracoronal or&#xD;
             extracoronal fixed restorations), and with a minimum of 20 teeth)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only FPD s with end abutments (No cantilever)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient length of the clinical crown (&gt;5 mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No obvious untreated caries, dental health problems (regularly checked by a dentist)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good or moderate oral hygiene (plaque score of less than 30% in anterior region&#xD;
             be-fore treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No untreated periodontal disease (only DPSI 1, 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abutment teeth are vital or endodontically treated with a sealed root filling to the&#xD;
             apical region, and have to be without apical periodontitis for the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects had to be over the age of 18, be classified according to the American Society&#xD;
             of Anesthesiologists (ASA) as ASA I or ASA II, present with good oral hygiene, and be&#xD;
             free of periodontal disease (probing depth and attachment levels within normal limits,&#xD;
             no furcation involvement, and no mobility)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects had to agree to keep the scheduled recall appointments for data collection&#xD;
             and maintenance and plan to stay in the area for at least 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients suffering from general health impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considerable horizontal and/or vertical mobility of teeth: tooth mobility index score&#xD;
             2 or - Considerable periodontal disease without treatment (DPSI 3-, 3+ and 4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Endodontic treatment with extensive loss of tooth tissue&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who presented with severe wear facets and/or reported parafunctional&#xD;
             activi-ties such as clenching or nocturnal bruxism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who were restored with a removable partial dental prosthesis (RPDP), unless&#xD;
             the RPDP replaced the tooth that was planned to be restored in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who were pregnant during the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are known to be allergic to the ingredients of resin materials&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mutlu Özcan, Prof.Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Zurich</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mehmet Muzaffer Ateş, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+90 212 453 48 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>4969</phone_ext>
    <email>mates@medipol.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tuğba Toz-Akalın, Assos. Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+90 212 453 48 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>4946</phone_ext>
    <email>tuuuuba@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>İstanbul Medipol University, School of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34083</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Muzaffer Ateş, Prof.Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+905326134765</phone>
      <email>mates@medipol.edu.tr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tuğba Toz, Assos. Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+905433242554</phone>
      <email>tuuuuba2008@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rekow ED. Dental CAD/CAM systems: a 20-year success story. J Am Dent Assoc. 2006 Sep;137 Suppl:5S-6S.</citation>
    <PMID>16950931</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miyazaki T, Hotta Y, Kunii J, Kuriyama S, Tamaki Y. A review of dental CAD/CAM: current status and future perspectives from 20 years of experience. Dent Mater J. 2009 Jan;28(1):44-56. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19280967</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ruse ND, Sadoun MJ. Resin-composite blocks for dental CAD/CAM applications. J Dent Res. 2014 Dec;93(12):1232-4. doi: 10.1177/0022034514553976. Epub 2014 Oct 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25344335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zimmermann M, Ender A, Egli G, Özcan M, Mehl A. Fracture load of CAD/CAM-fabricated and 3D-printed composite crowns as a function of material thickness. Clin Oral Investig. 2019 Jun;23(6):2777-2784. doi: 10.1007/s00784-018-2717-2. Epub 2018 Oct 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30368664</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alharbi A, Ardu S, Bortolotto T, Krejci I. Stain susceptibility of composite and ceramic CAD/CAM blocks versus direct resin composites with different resinous matrices. Odontology. 2017 Apr;105(2):162-169. doi: 10.1007/s10266-016-0258-1. Epub 2016 Jul 25.</citation>
    <PMID>27456684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kamonwanon P, Hirose N, Yamaguchi S, Sasaki JI, Kitagawa H, Kitagawa R, Thaweboon S, Srikhirin T, Imazato S. SiO(2)-nanocomposite film coating of CAD/CAM composite resin blocks improves surface hardness and reduces susceptibility to bacterial adhesion. Dent Mater J. 2017 Jan 31;36(1):88-94. doi: 10.4012/dmj.2016-135. Epub 2016 Dec 6.</citation>
    <PMID>27928105</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mitra SB, Wu D, Holmes BN. An application of nanotechnology in advanced dental materials. J Am Dent Assoc. 2003 Oct;134(10):1382-90.</citation>
    <PMID>14620019</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Deliperi S, Bardwell DN. Clinical evaluation of direct cuspal coverage with posterior composite resin restorations. J Esthet Restor Dent. 2006;18(5):256-65; discussion 266-7.</citation>
    <PMID>16987320</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yesil ZD, Alapati S, Johnston W, Seghi RR. Evaluation of the wear resistance of new nanocomposite resin restorative materials. J Prosthet Dent. 2008 Jun;99(6):435-43. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3913(08)60105-5.</citation>
    <PMID>18514665</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zimmermann M, Koller C, Reymus M, Mehl A, Hickel R. Clinical Evaluation of Indirect Particle-Filled Composite Resin CAD/CAM Partial Crowns after 24 Months. J Prosthodont. 2018 Oct;27(8):694-699. doi: 10.1111/jopr.12582. Epub 2017 Apr 19.</citation>
    <PMID>28422359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shembish FA, Tong H, Kaizer M, Janal MN, Thompson VP, Opdam NJ, Zhang Y. Fatigue resistance of CAD/CAM resin composite molar crowns. Dent Mater. 2016 Apr;32(4):499-509. doi: 10.1016/j.dental.2015.12.005. Epub 2016 Jan 8.</citation>
    <PMID>26777092</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schlichting LH, Maia HP, Baratieri LN, Magne P. Novel-design ultra-thin CAD/CAM composite resin and ceramic occlusal veneers for the treatment of severe dental erosion. J Prosthet Dent. 2011 Apr;105(4):217-26. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3913(11)60035-8.</citation>
    <PMID>21458646</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Magne P, Schlichting LH, Maia HP, Baratieri LN. In vitro fatigue resistance of CAD/CAM composite resin and ceramic posterior occlusal veneers. J Prosthet Dent. 2010 Sep;104(3):149-57. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3913(10)60111-4.</citation>
    <PMID>20813228</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Magne P, Stanley K, Schlichting LH. Modeling of ultrathin occlusal veneers. Dent Mater. 2012 Jul;28(7):777-82. doi: 10.1016/j.dental.2012.04.002. Epub 2012 May 9.</citation>
    <PMID>22575740</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>El-Damanhoury HM, Haj-Ali RN, Platt JA. Fracture resistance and microleakage of endocrowns utilizing three CAD-CAM blocks. Oper Dent. 2015 Mar-Apr;40(2):201-10. doi: 10.2341/13-143-L. Epub 2014 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>25268039</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mehmet Muzaffer Ateş</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof.Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>3D printed fixed prosthesis</keyword>
  <keyword>resin composite dental prosthesis</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

