<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04601974</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18/0202</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04601974</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lentiviral Gene Therapy for Epilepsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/IIa, First-in-human, Open-label, Single-site Trial of In-vivo Lentiviral Engineered Potassium (K+) Channel (EKC) Gene Therapy for Refractory Epilepsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medical Research Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College, London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/IIa clinical trial investigating the safety of a lentiviral epilepsy gene&#xD;
      therapy using an engineered potassium channel in patients with refractory epilepsy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Epilepsy affects about 1% of the population. One third of affected individuals continue to&#xD;
      have seizures despite optimal medication. The only realistic prospect of seizure freedom,&#xD;
      feasible in very few cases, is surgery to remove the brain area where seizures arise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with refractory neocortical epilepsy who are being evaluated for surgical resection&#xD;
      of the seizure focus will be invited to join the trial. The non-integrating lentiviral&#xD;
      vector, which has been engineered to deliver an engineered potassium channel, will be&#xD;
      administered via intracerebral infusion to the area scheduled for resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective in this study is to test the safety of the lentiviral gene therapy&#xD;
      treatment, including the surgical procedures required for vector administration. Secondary&#xD;
      objectives will look at delayed onset adverse events and indicators of efficacy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety (serious adverse events causally related to lentiviral gene therapy only)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 12 months after trial treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of serious adverse events deemed causally related to lentiviral gene therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety (serious adverse events causally related to surgical procedures only)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 12 months after trial treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of serious adverse events deemed causally related to any of the surgical trial procedures required for vector administration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety (all adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>From registration until 12 months after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number, severity, and causal relationship of any adverse event (to either the lentiviral gene therapy and/or surgical trial procedures required for vector administration) using the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety (delayed onset serious adverse events causally related to lentiviral gene therapy only)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 12 months after treatment discontinuation until end of the trial</time_frame>
    <description>Number of delayed onset serious adverse events causally related to the lentiviral gene therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety (delayed onset serious adverse events causally related to surgical procedures only)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 12 months after treatment discontinuation until end of the trial</time_frame>
    <description>Number of delayed onset serious adverse events causally related to any of the surgical trial procedures required for vector administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seizure frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years after trial treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of epileptic seizures measured using IALE classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seizure severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years after trial treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of epileptic seizures measured using IALE classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who decline surgical resection</measure>
    <time_frame>At three months after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who decline surgical resection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reasons for declining surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>At three months after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative measure capturing reasons why patients decline resective brain surgery (if applicable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lentiviral gene therapy treatment (Intervention Arm)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive a single dose of lentiviral gene therapy treatment administered once intracranially</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lentiviral gene therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>lentiviral gene therapy to treat drug resistant epilepsy</description>
    <arm_group_label>lentiviral gene therapy treatment (Intervention Arm)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        SCREENING/PRE-CONSENT:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female and male patients with drug-resistant refractory focal neocortical epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged ≥ 18 years (no upper age limit but deemed medically fit for surgery with a life&#xD;
             expectancy of at least 5 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Being considered for resective brain surgery (to remove the epileptogenic focus) based&#xD;
             on first-stage preoperative assessments carried out as part of routine clinical care&#xD;
             within 2 years of registration, showing: 3.1. Absence of vascular brain lesions or&#xD;
             vascular malformations and/or cancer in the resection area (as confirmed on MRI) 3.2.&#xD;
             Absence of active, untreated psychiatric disease in the opinion of the treating&#xD;
             clinician (as confirmed by neuropsychiatric assessment) 3.3. Patient requires&#xD;
             second-stage investigations carried out as part of routine clinical care (intracranial&#xD;
             EEG) to further assess eligibility for resective brain surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
             PRE-REGISTRATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Following consent, patients undergo intracranial EEG investigations, and only those&#xD;
             patients in whom the seizure focus can be identified and are deemed eligible for&#xD;
             resective brain surgery can continue to registration provided they continue to meet&#xD;
             all the inclusion/exclusion criteria. Please note, we will attempt to recruit from&#xD;
             both sexes, but will give priority to patients where the focus is clear, and&#xD;
             accessible to treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Deemed medically fit for anaesthesia and surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female patients of childbearing potential (WOCBP), or male patients with female&#xD;
             partners who are WOCBP or pregnant must agree to use highly effective methods of&#xD;
             contraception from the time consent is signed until three months after treatment. Men&#xD;
             (if applicable), must also advise their female partners regarding contraceptive&#xD;
             requirements as listed for female patients who are WOCBP or pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Female patients who are WOCBP must have a negative pregnancy test within 7 days prior&#xD;
             to being registered&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients will be asked about the donation of resected brain tissue for translational&#xD;
             work (only applicable if they later proceed with surgery) during informed consent, but&#xD;
             this is optional i.e. patients may still join the trial if they do not consent to the&#xD;
             donation of resected brain tissue for translational work&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Able and willing to give written informed consent to join trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Failure to identify a single region of seizure onset in the neocortex with a surface&#xD;
             area of less than 16 cm2&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Vascular brain lesions or vascular malformations in area of planned resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Detection of active cancer or on systemic treatment for cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous surgery to the treatment area&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient deemed medically unfit for anaesthesia and surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active, untreated psychiatric disease in the opinion of the treating clinician&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Concurrent and/or recent involvement in another clinical trial of an investigational&#xD;
             medicinal product (within last 3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Females who are pregnant (confirmed by serum/urine ß-HCG)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Allergies to excipients of gene therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient unlikely to cooperate with a 5-year follow-up; medical or psychological&#xD;
             condition at the discretion of the investigator which would not permit compliance with&#xD;
             the protocol or meaningful written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any other known condition which is assessed as an intolerable risk by the investigator&#xD;
             upon inclusion in the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Senior Clinical Project Manager</last_name>
    <phone>0207 679 5020</phone>
    <email>ekctrial@ucl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lentiviral gene therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>brain</keyword>
  <keyword>surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>drug resistant epilepsy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data may be shared with other researchers who are working in the public and charitable sector (universities, research institutes) or commercial companies involved in health care research in the UK or overseas. Participant data will be fully anonymised prior to data sharing. This means there will be no way to link the data to the original data set, or to individual participants. Anonymisation will be done by the trial statistician. Data shared in this way will be protected by a contractual agreement put in place between UCL (the Sponsor) and any respective institution.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

