<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04600752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>213514</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04600752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety and Clinical Efficacy of Augmentin® Extra Strength-600 in Children With Acute Otitis Media in India</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-label, Non-comparative Phase IV Clinical Study to Evaluate the Safety and Clinical Efficacy of Augmentin Extra Strength (ES)-600 in Children With Acute Otitis Media (AOM) in India</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Iqvia Pty Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Augmentin (ES)-600 is a high-dose amoxicillin/clavulanic acid 14:1 formulation that allows&#xD;
      administration at 90/6.4 milligrams (mg)/kilograms (kg)/day in two divided doses. Most&#xD;
      physicians in India use the standard Augmentin (amoxicillin:clavulanic acid 7:1) (45/6.4&#xD;
      mg/kg/day) formulation and double the dose to achieve higher dose of amoxicillin/clavulanic&#xD;
      acid at 90 mg/kg/day in pediatric acute otitis media (AOM) due to non-availability of&#xD;
      Augmentin (ES)-600. Using the 7:1 formulation causes unnecessary exposure to higher&#xD;
      proportionate dose of clavulanic acid (12.8 mg/kg/day) as a unit dose of 6.4 mg/kg/day of&#xD;
      clavulanic acid is only required for efficacy against beta-lactamase producing AOM pathogens.&#xD;
      Hence, there is an unmet need for availability of Augmentin (ES)-600 in India. This is an&#xD;
      open label, single arm, multicenter, non-comparative study in participants aged 6 months to&#xD;
      12 years with AOM. It aims to assess the safety and clinical efficacy of Augmentin (ES)-600&#xD;
      administered in two divided doses, every 12 hours in pediatric population in India. AUGMENTIN&#xD;
      is a registered trademark of the GlaxoSmithKline group of companies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 11, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 10, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a single arm, multicenter, non-comparative study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>This is an open-label study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment emergent adverse events (TEAE) and serious adverse events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment (Day 1) to follow-up visit at Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>TEAEs and SAEs will be collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants achieving Primary Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment (Day 1) to end of therapy visit at Day 12-14</time_frame>
    <description>Primary clinical response will be assessed at the end of therapy (EOT) visit (Day 12 to 14) in terms of success or failure to study intervention. A treatment success at EOT will be defined as either clinical cure or improvement. A treatment failure will be defined as a participant whose clinical outcome will be clinical failure (due to worsening or non-improvement in symptoms) or &quot;unable to determine&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants achieving Secondary Clinical response</measure>
    <time_frame>From end of treatment visit (Day 12-14) to follow up visit at Day 22-28</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary clinical response will be assessed at follow-up (Day 22 to 28) in terms of success or failure to study intervention. A treatment success at follow-up will be defined as persistent clinical cure and treatment failure will be clinical recurrence or unable to determine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with protocol defined diarrhea (PDD) (due to study medication)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment (Day 1) to end of therapy visit at Day 12-14</time_frame>
    <description>Protocol-defined diarrhea is 3 or more watery stools in one day or 4 or more loose/watery stools in one day or 2 watery stools per day for two consecutive days or 3 loose/watery stools per day for two consecutive days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">310</enrollment>
  <condition>Otitis Media</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants receiving Augmentin (ES)-600</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Eligible participants will receive Augmentin (ES)-600 at 90/6.4 mg/kg/day administered in two divided doses, every 12 hours with food for 10 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Augmentin (ES)-600</intervention_name>
    <description>Augmentin ES will be administered as reconstituted oral suspension containing Amoxicillin and Potassium Clavulanate 600 mg/42.9 mg per 5 milliliters.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants receiving Augmentin (ES)-600</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants aged: 6 months to 12 years; no gender restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of AOM on basis of otoscopic findings as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Purulent otorrhea of less than 24 hours duration or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Middle ear effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Middle ear effusion is evidenced by at least two of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Decreased or absent tympanic mobility measured by pneumatic otoscopy,&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Yellow or white discoloration of the tympanic membrane, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Opacification of the tympanic membrane plus&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least one of the following indicators of acute inflammation:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ear pain within 24 hours, including unaccustomed tugging or rubbing of ear,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Marked redness of the tympanic membrane, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Distinct fullness or bulging of the tympanic membrane.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The participant and parent(s)/legal guardian(s) are willing and able to comply&#xD;
                  with the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  In accordance with regional/local laws and regulations, the parent(s)/legal&#xD;
                  guardian(s) has given signed informed, dated consent; and the participant has&#xD;
                  given written assent, if applicable, to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight more than 40 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Spontaneous perforation of the tympanic membrane and drainage for longer than 24&#xD;
             hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tympanoplastic tube(s) in place, or has anatomic abnormalities associated with&#xD;
             recurrent AOM, prolonged middle ear effusion, including cleft palate or repair,&#xD;
             high-arched palate or Down's syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A serious underlying disease as per clinician's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant infection which would preclude evaluation of the response of his/her acute&#xD;
             otitis media to the study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing renal insufficiency (plasma creatinine greater than [&gt;]1.5 times upper&#xD;
             limit of normal range for age).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing liver disease(s) and/or hepatic dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of leukopenia and/or thrombocytopenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of previous hypersensitivity reaction to penicillins, cephalosporins or other&#xD;
             beta-lactam antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Augmentin-associated cholestatic jaundice/hepatic dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of phenylketonuria or a known hypersensitivity to aspartame.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received, within 48 hours of study entry, or is scheduled to receive during the study&#xD;
             period, any medication which may alter bowel function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving or has received more than one dose of systemic antibiotic therapy&#xD;
             within one week prior to the initiation of the study. AOM treatment failures with&#xD;
             Amoxicillin, erythromycin, sulfamethoxazole or Trimethoprim-Sulfamethoxazole are not&#xD;
             subject to this criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of an investigational compound (non-Food and Drug Administration [FDA] and&#xD;
             non- Drugs Controller General Of India [DCGI] approved) or device within the previous&#xD;
             30 days or five half-lives, whichever is longer, preceding the first dose of study&#xD;
             intervention or during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with symptoms suggestive of active Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19)&#xD;
             infection (fever, cough, et cetera).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with known COVID-19 positive contacts within the past 14 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>US GSK Clinical Trials Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>877-379-3718</phone>
    <email>GSKClinicalSupportHD@gsk.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>EU GSK Clinical Trials Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0) 20 89904466</phone>
    <email>GSKClinicalSupportHD@gsk.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acute otitis media</keyword>
  <keyword>Augmentin Extra Strength</keyword>
  <keyword>Amoxicillin-clavulanic acid</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Beta-lactamase</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Otitis Media</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Amoxicillin-Potassium Clavulanate Combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD for this study will be made available via the Clinical Study Data Request site.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>IPD will be made available within 6 months of publishing the results of the primary endpoints, key secondary endpoints and safety data of the study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access is provided after a research proposal is submitted and has received approval from the Independent Review Panel and after a Data Sharing Agreement is in place. Access is provided for an initial period of 12 months but an extension can be granted, when justified, for up to another 12 months.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://clinicalstudydatarequest.com</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

