<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04604210</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020P002296</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04604210</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Symptom-specific TMS Targets for Depression and Anxiety</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Randomized Trial of Distinct Symptom-specific Targets for Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Patients With Depression and Anxiety</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study aims to compare two different treatment targets for transcranial magnetic&#xD;
      stimulation, an FDA-approved treatment for major depressive disorder (MDD), in terms of their&#xD;
      relative efficacy for depression versus anxiety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) is a safe, noninvasive FDA-cleared technique that is&#xD;
      commonly used as a treatment for MDD. It has been shown to focally activate specific brain&#xD;
      regions that are believed to be underactive in these patients. This study aims to compare two&#xD;
      different TMS targets in the prefrontal cortex. TMS will be administered within FDA-approved&#xD;
      guidelines under the supervision of a physician with experience in administering the&#xD;
      treatment and monitoring for complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a prospective double-blind randomized controlled trial to assess the comparative&#xD;
      efficacy of two different TMS targets within the prefrontal cortex (PFC). The &quot;dysphoric&quot;&#xD;
      target in the dorsolateral PFC is believed to be more effective for depression, while the&#xD;
      &quot;anxiosomatic&quot; target in the dorsomedial PFC is believed to be more effective for anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with comorbid depression and anxiety will receive 6 weeks of TMS following standard&#xD;
      clinical parameters (30 treatments over 6 weeks, 10 Hz frequency, 3000 pulses) with&#xD;
      MRI-guided neuronavigation. Participants will be randomized to either the dysphoric or&#xD;
      anxiosomatic target. Both targets are believed to be effective treatments for this patient&#xD;
      population. Participants and raters will remain blinded to the group assignment. All&#xD;
      participants will receive resting-state functional MRI scans before and after the course of&#xD;
      treatment in order to study physiological changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The dysphoric target is expected to induce greater relative improvement in depression, while&#xD;
      the anxiosomatic target is expected to induce greater relative improvement in anxiety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parallel-group double-blind randomized, controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants will be blinded to which target is expected to improve which symptom.&#xD;
Study investigators (with the exception of the treatment administrator), including the outcomes assessor, will be blinded to which participant is receiving which treatment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Depression Inventory (BDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment), 3 weeks (after 15 treatments), and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome will be the rank-transformed ratio of BDI change to BAI change</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment), 3 weeks (after 15 treatments), and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome will be the rank-transformed ratio of BDI change to BAI change</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting-state functional MRI (rsfMRI) scan</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>Functional MRI scan will be conducted before and after treatment in order to assess for treatment-induced changes in brain connectivity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Temperament and Character Inventory, Revised 140-item (TCI-R 140)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>Psychobiologically-based personality inventory which measures seven personality dimensions (harm avoidance, novelty seeking, reward dependence, persistence, self-directedness, cooperativeness, and persistence). For each dimension, this yields a scaled T-score (mean score of 50 with standard deviation of 10). This is an overall estimate of personality traits, and there are no &quot;better&quot; or &quot;worse&quot; traits.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>NIH Toolbox cognitive battery</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>An interactive computerized battery of cognitive tasks which is used to compute an overall index of crystallized and fluid cognition. For each cognitive subscale, this yields a scaled T-score (mean score of 100 with standard deviation of 10).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Multidimensional task-based emotional assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>An interactive computerized battery of emotional tasks, including Aversion-Reward Conflict, Emotion Conflict Resolution, Multiple Source Interference, Fear Conditioning/Extinction, Gambling, and Associative Learning Tasks. Each task will yield results for accuracy and reaction time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain at the stimulation site</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will be asked to rate treatment-induced pain/discomfort on a scale of 1 to 10</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Multidimensional battery of emotional questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (before treatment) and 6 weeks (after 30 treatments)</time_frame>
    <description>A computerized battery of questionnaires including the Anxiety Sensitivity Index, Adult Temperament Questionnaire, State-Trait Anxiety Inventory, Behavioral Inhibition/Activation Scale, Temporal Experience of Pleasure Scale, Positive and Negative Affect Scale, Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale, Emotion Reactivity Scale, Barratt Impulsivity Scale, Adult ADHD Self-Rating Scale, Brief Inventory of Executive Functioning, and Trait Rumination Scale. Each scale yields a raw score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dysphoric target</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;dysphoric&quot; target is a region in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. TMS targeted to this region has been shown to be more effective for depression than anxiety.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anxiosomatic target</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The &quot;anxiosomatic&quot; target is a region in the dorsomedial prefrontal cortex. TMS targeted to this region has been shown to be more effective for anxiety than depression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcranial magnetic stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) is a noninvasive FDA-approved technique that is commonly used as a treatment for depression. It has been shown to focally activate specific brain regions that are believed to be underactive in patients suffering from depression. In this study, TMS will be administered within FDA-approved guidelines under the supervision of a physician with experience in administering the treatment and monitoring for complications.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anxiosomatic target</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dysphoric target</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TMS</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults age 18 to 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meeting FDA guidelines for clinical TMS (DSM-5 diagnosis of major depressive disorder&#xD;
             with at least one failed antidepressant trial)1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Beck Depression Inventory (BDI) score of 20 or higher&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI) score of 16 or higher&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate or severe substance use disorder in the past six months as defined by&#xD;
                  DSM-5 criteria, with the exception of cannabis and nicotine use disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dementia, as defined by treating neurologist&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate or severe autism spectrum disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bipolar disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Schizophrenia spectrum disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current evidence of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Substance-induced mood disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active psychotic symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to rTMS treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Seizure disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significantly elevated seizure risk, as determined by clinician assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of metallic objects within the head&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of an implanted neurostimulation device within the head&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe claustrophobia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe pain/illness exacerbated by lying prone in the scanner&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of non-MRI compatible metal foreign bodies or implants&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Weight in excess of 350 lbs&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Shoulder width in excess of maximum tolerable width for scanner&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shan H Siddiqi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jing Li, BS</last_name>
    <phone>6173567481</phone>
    <email>jli110@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham &amp; Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jing Li, BS</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Shan Siddiqi, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Psychiatric Neuromodulation Research, Center for Brain Circuit Therapeutics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>TMS</keyword>
  <keyword>Transcranial</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuromodulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified survey response data and/or neuroimaging data may be shared with collaborators for further analysis.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

