<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03890484</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00006279</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>F31AA027471-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03890484</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The College, Alcohol and Peers Study (CAPS)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Peer Groups and Broad Social Motives' Influence on College Student Drinking: A Multimethod Approach Using Alcohol Administration and Daily Diary</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present study will evaluate college students (N=100) from 2- and 4-year&#xD;
      colleges/universities between 21-24 years old to assess anxiety, affect, broad social motives&#xD;
      (BSM) and peer group influences on drinking and other risk-taking behaviors. This study will&#xD;
      employ two sound scientific methods for testing behavior during drinking events (i.e., lab&#xD;
      alcohol administration and daily diary) and use novel strategies to compare results of these&#xD;
      two methods in the same sample. Using an ad-lib drinking paradigm, students' risk-taking, as&#xD;
      measured by the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART), will be assessed when alone and during one&#xD;
      of two randomly assigned peer group conditions (close friends or new peers). Participants&#xD;
      will be allowed to freely drink (within safety limits) with their peer group prior to&#xD;
      completing the BART again. These same students will complete daily electronic diaries on four&#xD;
      weekends (Thursday - Sunday; total 24 assessments) regarding BSM, motives to drink, peers in&#xD;
      their social group, alcohol use and consequences, and if/how their social group changed&#xD;
      (e.g., few close friends to large party with many new peers) during the drinking event.&#xD;
      Competing hypotheses will be tested such that: 1) anxiety is expected to be a stronger&#xD;
      predictor of drinking behavior and greater differences in risk-taking in the new peer&#xD;
      condition than close friend condition or 2) BSM is expected to be a stronger predictor of&#xD;
      drinking behavior and greater differences in risk-taking in the close friend condition than&#xD;
      new peers condition. Results are expected to be replicated in the daily diary reports.&#xD;
      Further, this multimethod approach will allow us to evaluate how behavior assessed in the lab&#xD;
      predicts naturally occurring behaviors in an uncontrolled setting. For example, the&#xD;
      investigators will assess whether greater increases in self-reported risk-taking from&#xD;
      baseline to after entering peer groups in the bar lab setting will predict heavier drinking&#xD;
      on nights when most drinking companions are close friends reported during daily diary.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants (N=100) will be recruited through direct outreach to University of Washington&#xD;
      (UW) students via the UW Registrar's directory list, as well as community flyers distributed&#xD;
      at colleges in the local area, online advertisements, and word of mouth. Participants will&#xD;
      complete screening measures online. Eligible participants will be stratified on sex, age, and&#xD;
      past 30-day peak alcohol use and randomly assigned to one of two conditions: close friends&#xD;
      (N=50), where participants will recruit two of their existing friends, or new peers (N=50),&#xD;
      where participants will drink with two strangers. To ensure at least two eligible friends,&#xD;
      those in the close friend group will be asked to provide email and phone numbers of five to&#xD;
      seven close friends. Close friends will have to meet the same inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria as target participants and will go through the same procedures as target&#xD;
      participants during alcohol administration. For each pair of participants matched on the&#xD;
      three strata (age, sex, alcohol use), strangers in the new peer group will be matched to the&#xD;
      sex of the close friends of the other matched participant's group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked not to travel to the bar together to ensure they are not exposed&#xD;
      to their peer group before entry to the bar, and must get to the lab without operating any&#xD;
      vehicle with wheels (e.g. car, bike). Upon arriving to the lab, all participants and peers&#xD;
      will review and sign the consent form, and provide a baseline breath alcohol content (BrAC)&#xD;
      reading. Female participants and friends will also be asked to take a urine pregnancy test.&#xD;
      Participants and friends will complete baseline measures and the Balloon Analogue Risk Task&#xD;
      (BART) individually prior to entry to the bar. Then they will be taught the procedures for&#xD;
      the daily diary portion of the study (see below). Participants will join their close friends&#xD;
      or new peers in the bar and be given 20 minutes to relax while the researcher prepares the&#xD;
      materials. After entering groups but prior to receiving alcohol, participants and peers will&#xD;
      complete pre-alcohol measures and the BART. They will then be allowed to order anything from&#xD;
      the bar menu for the following hour. Participants and close friends will be allowed to drink&#xD;
      freely within limits (BrAC = .12%), for safety. During ad-lib, estimated BAC levels based on&#xD;
      age, sex, and weight will be calculated prior to each drink served to ensure the safety of&#xD;
      consuming each drink without interrupting social interaction and making the participant's BAC&#xD;
      more salient by taking BrAC readings regularly. Participants or close friends whose BAC may&#xD;
      exceed .12% will only be served placebo beverages for the remainder of the hour. BrAC&#xD;
      readings will be taken at the end of ad-lib, every 10 minutes until peak BrAC is reached and&#xD;
      readings are descending, and every 30 minutes thereafter. After ad-lib, participants will&#xD;
      complete post-alcohol measures and the BART, then provided entertainment until they reach a&#xD;
      BAC below .03%. The full protocol will take approximately 2.5 hours. On average, alcohol&#xD;
      metabolizes at a rate of .015% per hour, so a participant who reaches .12% will be in the lab&#xD;
      on average 8.5 hours. Once sober, participants and friends will be taken home in a taxi or&#xD;
      ride share service (e.g. Uber, Lyft). Close friends will not complete the following daily&#xD;
      diary protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Daily diary measures will start on the Thursday following each participant's alcohol&#xD;
      administration appointment and be collected for potential drinking events on Thursday,&#xD;
      Friday, and Saturday over the following four consecutive weeks. Each day, participants will&#xD;
      be notified of surveys by text message at 4 pm and the following morning at 11am (Friday,&#xD;
      Saturday, and Sunday) for a total of 24 assessments. Surveys will be available for 2 hours&#xD;
      and reminders sent via text 30 minutes before closing. Afternoon assessments take&#xD;
      approximately 5 minutes and measure BSM, motives to drink, motives to refrain from drinking,&#xD;
      evening plans, and what type of peers they plan to spend the evening with (e.g. close&#xD;
      friends, new peers, family, alone). For the daily diary, BSM items have been modified to&#xD;
      select experiences which may vary daily (e.g. &quot;making social plans got me excited and&#xD;
      energized today) and drinking motives have been modified into a brief prospective measure&#xD;
      consistent with modifications used in other studies15. At morning assessments, participants&#xD;
      will retrospectively report amount of drinks and other substances consumed, time spent&#xD;
      drinking, and consequences experienced while drinking or currently (morning after drinking).&#xD;
      Participants will be asked how many times their social group changed during the event defined&#xD;
      as the majority of their drinking companions being of a different peer type than before. For&#xD;
      instance, a participant may be at a house party with primarily close friends, but someone&#xD;
      invites several people the participant does not know well and they are now drinking with&#xD;
      mostly new peers. For each peer group reported (up to five groups), participants will report&#xD;
      the following characteristics of the group: size (i.e. number of people they had direct&#xD;
      contact with), number of drinking companions of each peer type (e.g. close friends, new&#xD;
      peers, family), gender composition of the group (same-sex vs. mixed-sex), time spent with and&#xD;
      drinks consumed with each group. On non-drinking evenings, participants will report similar&#xD;
      information regarding their social groups and other activities. This survey will take&#xD;
      approximately 5-7 minutes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 25, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomly assigned to one of two conditions, which will run in parallel.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>During ad-lib</time_frame>
    <description>Number of drinks consumed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol use - Daily Diary</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks following ad-lib.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of drinks consumed, self-reported the morning after drinking events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol consequences</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks following ad-lib.</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report of the Young Adult Alcohol Problems Screening Test (YAAPST). Count of number of consequences experienced. Range: 0-27. Higher scores represent more consequences experienced.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk-taking</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (alone) to 20 minutes following Peer Type intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART). Scores are calculated by adding the number of pumps for unexploded balloons, with higher scores reflecting greater risk-taking. Range varies - explosions are at a random point between 1 and 128 pumps.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk-taking</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (alone) to immediately following ad-lib, an average of 2 hours after baseline.</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Balloon Analogue Risk Task (BART). Scores are calculated by adding the number of pumps for unexploded balloons, with higher scores reflecting greater risk-taking. Range varies - explosions are at a random point between 1 and 128 pumps.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Drinking</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>New Peers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will drink with two new peers (i.e. strangers), who they did not know prior to the study and their Peer Type.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Close Friends</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will recruit and drink with two of their close friends and their Peer Type</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peer Type</intervention_name>
    <description>The type of peers (close friends or new peers) will be manipulated between arms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Close Friends</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>New Peers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  currently enrolled in college&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  has consumed 3 or more alcoholic drinks in one sitting at least once in the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  drinking frequency of once a week&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  past-month alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  past-month other substance dependence,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  past-month mood disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  past-month anxiety disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  past-moth suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  excessive alcohol use reaching a BAC greater than .30% in past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of serious medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  regular use of prescription psychotropic or pain medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of negative reactions to alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of treatment for alcohol use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  nursing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mary E Larimer, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jessica R Canning, BS</last_name>
    <phone>(206) 543-6974</phone>
    <email>jrcannin@uw.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Center for the Study of Health and Risk Behaviors</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Em Chapple</last_name>
      <email>echapple@uw.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Mary Larimer</last_name>
      <phone>206-543-3513</phone>
      <email>larimer@uw.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 20, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Washington</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mary Larimer</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, School of Medicine, Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Alcohol use</keyword>
  <keyword>Risk-taking</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Motives</keyword>
  <keyword>Multimethod</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

