<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02112201</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DA025857</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02112201</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The ProGirls Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Preventing HIV/STI Risk Behavior in Girls With Delinquency, Drug Abuse, &amp; Trauma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oregon Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oregon Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Girls in the juvenile justice system who have high rates of delinquency, drug abuse, and&#xD;
      trauma are particularly at risk for engaging in risky sexual behavior and for contracting&#xD;
      HIV/AIDS or other sexually transmitted infections (STIs). No effective prevention programs&#xD;
      for girls who have this combination of behaviors is known to exist at this time. Researchers&#xD;
      are developing, assessing, and implementing a family-centered prevention program to decrease&#xD;
      girls' participation in the risky behaviors associated with the spread of HIV and STIs. The&#xD;
      program also includes a group-based training and support program for parents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to test an intervention to reduce HIV/STI risk behavior among girls in the&#xD;
      juvenile justice system with the triple-threat risk of delinquency, drug abuse, and trauma.&#xD;
      This is a competing continuation of the ProTeens study (Preventing Drug Abuse &amp; HIV/AIDS in&#xD;
      Delinquent Youths: An Integrated Intervention) which focused on testing a family-centered&#xD;
      intervention for treating HIV risk, drug use, and delinquency in boys. The current study will&#xD;
      adapt the ProTeens intervention for girls. Girls and their parent(s) will be randomly&#xD;
      assigned to either a family-centered intervention condition (INT; n = 100) or to an active&#xD;
      comparison condition (n = 100) consisting of group therapy and case management (GCM). The INT&#xD;
      condition will consist of individually administered HIV preventive intervention for&#xD;
      adolescent girls involved in the juvenile justice system that integrally addresses&#xD;
      delinquency, drug abuse, and trauma exposure, along with group-based training and support for&#xD;
      parents. The girl and parent components will run concurrently for three months. The GCM&#xD;
      condition will consist of group therapy and case management for girls provided as usual by&#xD;
      the juvenile justice department. We will examine intervention effects on proximal outcomes&#xD;
      measured at 12 months, the effects of childhood adversity on proximal outcomes, and the&#xD;
      mediation of intervention effects. Longer term outcomes will be measured at 24 months. Data&#xD;
      will be collected through in-person interviews and questionnaires from focal participants and&#xD;
      their parents, official arrest records, and urinary analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in HIV/STIs risk behavior in delinquent girls</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and post intervention (6 mos); 12 &amp; 24 month follow-ups</time_frame>
    <description>Girls in the intervention condition are expected to have significantly lower rates of HIV/STI risk behaviors compared to girls in the control condition at each of the time-points post-baseline. Data will be collected through in-person interviews and questionnaires from focal participants and their parents.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in criminal offending</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and post intervention (6 mos); 12 &amp; 24 month follow-ups</time_frame>
    <description>Girls in the intervention condition are expected to have significantly lower rates of criminal offending behavior compared to girls in the control condition at each of the time points post-baseline. Data will be collected through in-person interviews and questionnaires from focal participants and their parents and official arrest records.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in substance use</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and post intervention (6 mos); 12 &amp; 24 month follow-ups</time_frame>
    <description>Girls in the intervention condition are expected to have significantly lower rates of substance use compared to girls in the control condition at each of the time-points post-baseline. Data will be collected through in-person interviews and questionnaires from focal participants and their parents and urinary analysis.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">416</enrollment>
  <condition>Delinquency</condition>
  <condition>HIV Risk</condition>
  <condition>Substance Use</condition>
  <condition>Trauma Exposure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Integrated intervention for parents and adolescent girls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Twelve session parent education and support group; twelve session one-on-one adolescent skills training intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment as usual</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Integrated intervention for parents and adolescent girls</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention will consist of individually administered preventive curriculum for adolescent girls involved in the juvenile justice system that integrally addresses delinquency, drug abuse, and trauma exposure, along with group-based training and support for parents.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Integrated intervention for parents and adolescent girls</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  female, age 13-18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  living in Lane County, Oregon&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  living at home (biological/adoptive, foster, or other relative care)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  at least one criminal referral and on probation or a formal accountability contract&#xD;
             with the juvenile justice system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  documented drug use from juvenile justice risk assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  traumatic exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no imminent plans to be placed in out-of-home care&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  meet criteria for posttraumatic stress disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dana K Smith, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oregon Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eugene</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97403</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 3, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 9, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 11, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

